<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/category/commodities/commodity-news/page/656/</forum>
<forum_title>Commodity News | Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide - Part 656</forum_title>
<discussion_title>The federal government has revealed that it is making strate</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/fgs-strategic-devt-plans-for-steel-sector/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The federal government has revealed that it is making strategic plans for the development of the nation’s steel sector and has given full assurance of its interest to ensure the revival of the Ajaokuta Steel Development Company Limited. RUTH TENE NATSA unveils some of the plans.
In the drive towards ensuring the nation’s industrial revolution, the minister of mines and steel development, Mr Mohammed Musa Sada, led a delegation, in a joint courtesy call with the minister of industry, trade and investment, Mr Olusegun Olutoyin Aganga, and the director-general of the Bureau for Public Enterprises, Mr Benjamin Dikki, to the governor of Kogi state, Mr Idris Wada, in the state capital, Lokoja, on June 10, 2014.
Sada and his entourage joined the governor in working visits to the Ajaokuta Steel Development Company (ASDC) Limited, National Iron Ore Mining Company (NIOMCO), Itakpe, West African Ceramics Company site, KCM Company exploration site and African Resources Company exploration site in Kogi State to synergise strategies and actions towards the realisation of the federal government’s Industrial Revolution Plan (IRP).
Speaking on the many strategies employed by the federal government, Sada said that the invitation of private investors to invest in the integrated steel plant was a strategy aimed at ensuring that the steel sector is opened for development and investment.
He noted that private investors had shown interests and signed memoranda of understanding (MoU) with the management of the ASDC Limited to reactivate and operate already completed plants at the company such as the thermal power plant, rolling mills, metallurgical training centre and the engineering workshops.He noted that other strategic plans aimed at moving the steel industry forward is avoiding past mistakes that militated against the development of the sector and value addition by operators in the sector.
He said, “Part of the strategy is to dovetail the operations at the ASDC Limited to the actualisation of the industrial revolution plan of the federal government.”
He reiterated the desire of the federal government to attain self-sufficiency in the production of ceramic tiles and the availability of iron ore and other solid mineral resources for the production of steel and other allied products in the country.
He said, “We are very serious about seeing the ASDC Limited move forward and we are here to review the activities of the company, and dovetail its economic activities into the nation’s economic industrial revolution as well as appreciate the steel infrastructure on ground.”
He added that other purposes for the visit was to follow up and actualise the vision of reviving the company. “We want to look at the ASDC Limited as the cell and nucleus to be fine-tuned for the total industrial revolution of the country,” Sada said.
Speaking on the success of the mineral and steel sector, he said that in the past year, Nigeria had not only improved on the production of cement from one million metric tonnes (mts) to 30 million mts but is now exporting to other countries. He assured that “the nation has produced a little over 30 million mts of cement and is looking at the probabilities of starting a ceramic plates and tiles company as the raw materials are abundant in Kogi state.”
Sada also assured that “their visit was focused on three issues which included looking at the business opportunities which exist there, looking at the environmental issues to ensure the environment is protected from the devastation that can result from mining activities as well as to looking at community issues to ensure that the community members are protected and profit from investments made in their communities.”
The state governor, in his response, reiterated the need for an active and operational Ajaokuta Steel Development Company Limited for the realisation of Nigeria’s industrial development. He said a vibrant steel industry was germane for the achievement of the IRP of Nigeria, adding that he was “elated with the plan of the federal government to make the ASDC Limited operational in line with its IRP.” He expressed happiness with the information that the legal encumbrances surrounding the company with the former concessionaires had been resolved, thereby opening way for the reactivation and operationalisation of the steel integrated plant by private investors.”
Wada assured that the government and people of Kogi State would give the necessary cooperation and support towards the actualisation of the IRP in line with the transformation agenda of the federal government and thanked President Goodluck Jonathan for sending the two ministers on the working visit to the state.
Source: Leadership
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/fgs-strategic-devt-plans-for-steel-sector/</post_url>
<post_date>20140620</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>hellenicshippingnews</username>
<post>
The federal government has revealed that it is making strategic plans for the development of the nation’s steel sector and has given full assurance of its interest to ensure the revival of the Ajaokuta Steel Development Company Limited. RUTH TENE NATSA unveils some of the plans.
In the drive towards ensuring the nation’s industrial revolution, the minister of mines and steel development, Mr Mohammed Musa Sada, led a delegation, in a joint courtesy call with the minister of industry, trade and investment, Mr Olusegun Olutoyin Aganga, and the director-general of the Bureau for Public Enterprises, Mr Benjamin Dikki, to the governor of Kogi state, Mr Idris Wada, in the state capital, Lokoja, on June 10, 2014.
Sada and his entourage joined the governor in working visits to the Ajaokuta Steel Development Company (ASDC) Limited, National Iron Ore Mining Company (NIOMCO), Itakpe, West African Ceramics Company site, KCM Company exploration site and African Resources Company exploration site in Kogi State to synergise strategies and actions towards the realisation of the federal government’s Industrial Revolution Plan (IRP).
Speaking on the many strategies employed by the federal government, Sada said that the invitation of private investors to invest in the integrated steel plant was a strategy aimed at ensuring that the steel sector is opened for development and investment.
He noted that private investors had shown interests and signed memoranda of understanding (MoU) with the management of the ASDC Limited to reactivate and operate already completed plants at the company such as the thermal power plant, rolling mills, metallurgical training centre and the engineering workshops.He noted that other strategic plans aimed at moving the steel industry forward is avoiding past mistakes that militated against the development of the sector and value addition by operators in the sector.
He said, “Part of the strategy is to dovetail the operations at the ASDC Limited to the actualisation of the industrial revolution plan of the federal government.”
He reiterated the desire of the federal government to attain self-sufficiency in the production of ceramic tiles and the availability of iron ore and other solid mineral resources for the production of steel and other allied products in the country.
He said, “We are very serious about seeing the ASDC Limited move forward and we are here to review the activities of the company, and dovetail its economic activities into the nation’s economic industrial revolution as well as appreciate the steel infrastructure on ground.”
He added that other purposes for the visit was to follow up and actualise the vision of reviving the company. “We want to look at the ASDC Limited as the cell and nucleus to be fine-tuned for the total industrial revolution of the country,” Sada said.
Speaking on the success of the mineral and steel sector, he said that in the past year, Nigeria had not only improved on the production of cement from one million metric tonnes (mts) to 30 million mts but is now exporting to other countries. He assured that “the nation has produced a little over 30 million mts of cement and is looking at the probabilities of starting a ceramic plates and tiles company as the raw materials are abundant in Kogi state.”
Sada also assured that “their visit was focused on three issues which included looking at the business opportunities which exist there, looking at the environmental issues to ensure the environment is protected from the devastation that can result from mining activities as well as to looking at community issues to ensure that the community members are protected and profit from investments made in their communities.”
The state governor, in his response, reiterated the need for an active and operational Ajaokuta Steel Development Company Limited for the realisation of Nigeria’s industrial development. He said a vibrant steel industry was germane for the achievement of the IRP of Nigeria, adding that he was “elated with the plan of the federal government to make the ASDC Limited operational in line with its IRP.” He expressed happiness with the information that the legal encumbrances surrounding the company with the former concessionaires had been resolved, thereby opening way for the reactivation and operationalisation of the steel integrated plant by private investors.”
Wada assured that the government and people of Kogi State would give the necessary cooperation and support towards the actualisation of the IRP in line with the transformation agenda of the federal government and thanked President Goodluck Jonathan for sending the two ministers on the working visit to the state.
Source: Leadership
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
