<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.shelbystar.com/lifestyle?template=rss&amp;mime=xml</forum>
<forum_title>Lifestyle - Shelby Star</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Home Help: 5 ways to turn your deck from drab to fab</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.shelbystar.com/news/20160822/home-help-5-ways-to-turn-your-deck-from-drab-to-fab</topic_url>
<topic_text>
subscribe 
TIP OF THE WEEKIs your deck living up to its full potential? After a few years of wind, rain and general use, a deck might begin to lose its beauty, making it tough to relax on deck or entertain your friends and loved ones. Although it may seem like an overwhelming project to take on, restoring your deck to its former glory is probably much easier than you think. If you’re ready to enjoy your deck again, here are five ways you can turn it from drab to fab.1. Clean before you dream. Many decks can be restored to fab with a simple, routine cleaning. However, if you have a wood deck that’s been around for years, your boards are likely showing their age and it might be time for a total surface update. With many different materials to choose from, high-quality products that last — like ChoiceDek composite decking — can be a great alternative to wood. Many of these composite decking options can be easily cleaned with just soap, hot water and a soft bristle brush and have no need for annual painting, staining or sealing.2. Make room for more. Increasing the size of your deck can enhance its function and style. Extending the surface area into multiple levels creates unique vantage points into the rest of the yard and differentiates your space from the rest. If your deck feels too traditional, try adding some curves to its edges to personalize the space and fit your needs.3. Beautify borders. If you have recently finished a deck addition or are able to buy decking boards to match your current deck, you can add built-in seating and privacy structures to define the boards of your outdoor space and bring your personality into the design. Adding various plants to provide colors along the border of the deck can also bring an inviting feel to the space.4. Lounge in style. Sometimes the best way to bring life and character to your outdoor living space is to make it an extension of the interior of your home. Adding mood lighting or custom fabrics and patterns that match your interior design can easily transform your deck into an inviting space for guests to enjoy.5. Brighten up the outdoors. The design of an outdoor living space does not have to sacrifice style for function. When decorating the interior of a home, you look for warm and inviting features to bring life to a room, and the same care should be taken for the exterior. Let your creativity guide you by adding warm colored fabrics, accent pillows, comfy cushions and similar enhancements to your space.— BrandpointHOME-SELLING TIPRenovate with cautionOne of the biggest myths about renovating a home you are looking to sell is that you will earn back what you spend on renovations. Although a kitchen or a bathroom renovation can sell your house more quickly, it’s highly unlikely you will recoup the amount you spent upgrading those areas. According to Remodeling magazine’s 2015 Cost vs. Value Report, a seller is likely to only recoup 67.8 percent of what might spent on a kitchen renovation and just 70 percent on a bathroom remodel. The report also stated that the only renovation that is likely to net as much spent is installing a new front door.— BrandpointDECORATING TIPPicking a color paletteWith more and more colors out there to choose from, it can be a daunting task trying to decide what color palette you want to work with when decorating your home. Experts say one of the easiest places to start is to pull ideas from a favorite item. Whether your favorite item is a piece of art or a blanket or a pair of shoes or you have an obsession with a particular color, these colors can give you a starting point to build off of. Although your chosen palette could contain bright colors, be sure to use neutral colors for bigger pieces like a sofa or dining room table and save the brighter colors for art pieces or throw pillow or lamps. — More Content NowGARDEN GUIDEProper tree or shrub plantingAn old piece of advice for planting a new tree or shrub was to dig a hole twice as wide and twice as deep as the root-ball for the plant, but you don’t need to remove that much soil for your new addition. Experts now say that while planting a tree or shrub, the hole should be twice as wide as the root-ball, but not deeper than the root-ball. By keeping the root-ball closer to the surface, it encourages the roots to grow out and create stability for the tree or shrub. In order to get the correct depth, place the top roots so that they are parallel with the surface of the soil. Once you’ve placed your tree or shrub in the hole, apply 2 inches of mulch over the roots. Be sure to backfill the hole with the existing soil instead of compost or potting soil.— More Content Now
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.shelbystar.com/news/20160822/home-help-5-ways-to-turn-your-deck-from-drab-to-fab</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0701</post_time>
<username>More Content Now</username>
<post>
subscribe 
TIP OF THE WEEKIs your deck living up to its full potential? After a few years of wind, rain and general use, a deck might begin to lose its beauty, making it tough to relax on deck or entertain your friends and loved ones. Although it may seem like an overwhelming project to take on, restoring your deck to its former glory is probably much easier than you think. If you’re ready to enjoy your deck again, here are five ways you can turn it from drab to fab.1. Clean before you dream. Many decks can be restored to fab with a simple, routine cleaning. However, if you have a wood deck that’s been around for years, your boards are likely showing their age and it might be time for a total surface update. With many different materials to choose from, high-quality products that last — like ChoiceDek composite decking — can be a great alternative to wood. Many of these composite decking options can be easily cleaned with just soap, hot water and a soft bristle brush and have no need for annual painting, staining or sealing.2. Make room for more. Increasing the size of your deck can enhance its function and style. Extending the surface area into multiple levels creates unique vantage points into the rest of the yard and differentiates your space from the rest. If your deck feels too traditional, try adding some curves to its edges to personalize the space and fit your needs.3. Beautify borders. If you have recently finished a deck addition or are able to buy decking boards to match your current deck, you can add built-in seating and privacy structures to define the boards of your outdoor space and bring your personality into the design. Adding various plants to provide colors along the border of the deck can also bring an inviting feel to the space.4. Lounge in style. Sometimes the best way to bring life and character to your outdoor living space is to make it an extension of the interior of your home. Adding mood lighting or custom fabrics and patterns that match your interior design can easily transform your deck into an inviting space for guests to enjoy.5. Brighten up the outdoors. The design of an outdoor living space does not have to sacrifice style for function. When decorating the interior of a home, you look for warm and inviting features to bring life to a room, and the same care should be taken for the exterior. Let your creativity guide you by adding warm colored fabrics, accent pillows, comfy cushions and similar enhancements to your space.— BrandpointHOME-SELLING TIPRenovate with cautionOne of the biggest myths about renovating a home you are looking to sell is that you will earn back what you spend on renovations. Although a kitchen or a bathroom renovation can sell your house more quickly, it’s highly unlikely you will recoup the amount you spent upgrading those areas. According to Remodeling magazine’s 2015 Cost vs. Value Report, a seller is likely to only recoup 67.8 percent of what might spent on a kitchen renovation and just 70 percent on a bathroom remodel. The report also stated that the only renovation that is likely to net as much spent is installing a new front door.— BrandpointDECORATING TIPPicking a color paletteWith more and more colors out there to choose from, it can be a daunting task trying to decide what color palette you want to work with when decorating your home. Experts say one of the easiest places to start is to pull ideas from a favorite item. Whether your favorite item is a piece of art or a blanket or a pair of shoes or you have an obsession with a particular color, these colors can give you a starting point to build off of. Although your chosen palette could contain bright colors, be sure to use neutral colors for bigger pieces like a sofa or dining room table and save the brighter colors for art pieces or throw pillow or lamps. — More Content NowGARDEN GUIDEProper tree or shrub plantingAn old piece of advice for planting a new tree or shrub was to dig a hole twice as wide and twice as deep as the root-ball for the plant, but you don’t need to remove that much soil for your new addition. Experts now say that while planting a tree or shrub, the hole should be twice as wide as the root-ball, but not deeper than the root-ball. By keeping the root-ball closer to the surface, it encourages the roots to grow out and create stability for the tree or shrub. In order to get the correct depth, place the top roots so that they are parallel with the surface of the soil. Once you’ve placed your tree or shrub in the hole, apply 2 inches of mulch over the roots. Be sure to backfill the hole with the existing soil instead of compost or potting soil.— More Content Now
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.shelbystar.com/storyimage/NC/20160822/NEWS/160829988/AR/0/AR-160829988.jpg</main_image>
</document>
