<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>All you want to know about J1 visa to work in USA</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://soegjobs.com/2016/06/01/want-know-j1-visa-usa/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Prev post Next post Shares 
In this post we will discuss in detail all about J-1 Visa for USA or J1 as is used in common terminology. To start with it is important to know that it’s not very easy to get a J1 visa for United States of America (USA) and it is not for everyone. 
USA issues J1 visa to promote cultural exchange thus, all the candidates or applicants applying for this visa category should meet certain criteria. If they meet the eligibility criteria, they still need to follow a few steps to secure J-1 Visa. 
J1 visa is basically for the foreign nationals travelling to USA for any purpose, be it internship, work, scholarly research, social work, entrepreneurial/business research or any other purpose. They will have to leave USA after the purpose is over or the work is completed as decided by US authorities and sponsors. 
In this post we will discuss J1 visa of USA through the following points: Basics of J1 visa Common queries and questions about J1 Visa Who can apply for J1 visa Eligibility Criteria and documents for J1 visa Overview of Hospitality industry of USA How should hospitality professionals apply for J1 visa 
Here is an infographic by Whatthefaculty on the basic process of getting J-1 Visa. 
Getting back to our list in further detail. 1. Basics of J1 Visa of USA 
There are 13 types of privately funded J-1 Visa programmes. 300,000 participants from over 200 countries participate through these programmes. More than 250,000 of these visitors are younger than 30 years. Over 150,000 of these participants are female. There are 1,400 designated sponsors all over USA to participate in J-1 visa scheme. The sponsorship is approved by the bureau of Educational and Cultural affairs. Most J-1 visas are of the duration of 12 months which can be extended by additional 12 months. Image from- U.S Department of State 

The purpose of these programmes is to connect people and make them understand the culture of US. Also, this visa category helps in giving students, scholars, entrepreneurs, social workers etc. an exposure to one of the biggest markets of the world and an opportunity to be a part of the biggest economy of the world. 
Full details can be obtained from the official website of J-1 Visa. 
2. Common questions about J1 Visa 
There are several myths that surrounds J-1 visa process and US visas in General. There are a lot of consultancies in various countries who claim to be sponsors of J-1 visa and this is incorrect. Sponsors are from US only and authorized by the bureau of Educational and Cultural affairs. 
Please find below a few facts that answers general queries about J1 visas. Only authorized sponsors can provide DS-2019 (certificate by sponsor) and all of these sponsors are based in U.S Application timeline is variable from country to country and depends on time of the year and number of applications in queue. You can check the information about visa timelines of your country from Travel.State.Gov site . Many J-1 Visa category doesn’t allow you to carry your spouse or family along with you. In few categories when spouse and children are allowed, they need J-2 visa which normally doesn’t allow them to take up a work. You can’t arrive earlier than 30 days of the start of your programme and have to exit USA within 30 days of completion of the programme. Your sponsor can extend your J-1 Visa by 12 months. In worst case of termination, employee have to leave USA immediately. You are not allowed to take up any other work as a J1 visa holder. 
You can get more information from the official website about the common questions on J1 visa. 
3. Who can apply for J1 visa 
There is a big range of who can apply with a limited number. If you fall under any of the categories below, you are eligible to apply for J-1 Visa. Categories that might be of greater interest to hospitality industry professionals are highlighted in bold and italics. Summer intern as a part of University exchange programmes. Students of colleges and Universities within USA. Professors and research scholars who have established links with US Universities can travel to exchange ideas and to work on various research projects. Interns – This is of interest to Hospitality professionals. Whether you are a hospitality management student, a young Chef or a recent graduate of hospitality and tourism industry, you are eligible to apply. This is paid internship programme normally of a shorter duration than 12 months. Trainees – Hospitality and tourism professionals along with those of other trades are exposed to US culture and business approaches through a guided work based training programme. This is normally paid and is of 12 months’ duration which can be extended by the sponsor. Experts – Experts from any field are called under the route to share their expertise. This might be of some interest to the master Chefs. Physicians Teachers- Those involved in teaching and training in the hospitality and tourism sector can apply through this route. Social service and Philanthropist 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.30</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://soegjobs.com/2016/06/01/want-know-j1-visa-usa/</post_url>
<post_date>20160601</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Soeg Jobs</username>
<post>
Prev post Next post Shares 
In this post we will discuss in detail all about J-1 Visa for USA or J1 as is used in common terminology. To start with it is important to know that it’s not very easy to get a J1 visa for United States of America (USA) and it is not for everyone. 
USA issues J1 visa to promote cultural exchange thus, all the candidates or applicants applying for this visa category should meet certain criteria. If they meet the eligibility criteria, they still need to follow a few steps to secure J-1 Visa. 
J1 visa is basically for the foreign nationals travelling to USA for any purpose, be it internship, work, scholarly research, social work, entrepreneurial/business research or any other purpose. They will have to leave USA after the purpose is over or the work is completed as decided by US authorities and sponsors. 
In this post we will discuss J1 visa of USA through the following points: Basics of J1 visa Common queries and questions about J1 Visa Who can apply for J1 visa Eligibility Criteria and documents for J1 visa Overview of Hospitality industry of USA How should hospitality professionals apply for J1 visa 
Here is an infographic by Whatthefaculty on the basic process of getting J-1 Visa. 
Getting back to our list in further detail. 1. Basics of J1 Visa of USA 
There are 13 types of privately funded J-1 Visa programmes. 300,000 participants from over 200 countries participate through these programmes. More than 250,000 of these visitors are younger than 30 years. Over 150,000 of these participants are female. There are 1,400 designated sponsors all over USA to participate in J-1 visa scheme. The sponsorship is approved by the bureau of Educational and Cultural affairs. Most J-1 visas are of the duration of 12 months which can be extended by additional 12 months. Image from- U.S Department of State 

The purpose of these programmes is to connect people and make them understand the culture of US. Also, this visa category helps in giving students, scholars, entrepreneurs, social workers etc. an exposure to one of the biggest markets of the world and an opportunity to be a part of the biggest economy of the world. 
Full details can be obtained from the official website of J-1 Visa. 
2. Common questions about J1 Visa 
There are several myths that surrounds J-1 visa process and US visas in General. There are a lot of consultancies in various countries who claim to be sponsors of J-1 visa and this is incorrect. Sponsors are from US only and authorized by the bureau of Educational and Cultural affairs. 
Please find below a few facts that answers general queries about J1 visas. Only authorized sponsors can provide DS-2019 (certificate by sponsor) and all of these sponsors are based in U.S Application timeline is variable from country to country and depends on time of the year and number of applications in queue. You can check the information about visa timelines of your country from Travel.State.Gov site . Many J-1 Visa category doesn’t allow you to carry your spouse or family along with you. In few categories when spouse and children are allowed, they need J-2 visa which normally doesn’t allow them to take up a work. You can’t arrive earlier than 30 days of the start of your programme and have to exit USA within 30 days of completion of the programme. Your sponsor can extend your J-1 Visa by 12 months. In worst case of termination, employee have to leave USA immediately. You are not allowed to take up any other work as a J1 visa holder. 
You can get more information from the official website about the common questions on J1 visa. 
3. Who can apply for J1 visa 
There is a big range of who can apply with a limited number. If you fall under any of the categories below, you are eligible to apply for J-1 Visa. Categories that might be of greater interest to hospitality industry professionals are highlighted in bold and italics. Summer intern as a part of University exchange programmes. Students of colleges and Universities within USA. Professors and research scholars who have established links with US Universities can travel to exchange ideas and to work on various research projects. Interns – This is of interest to Hospitality professionals. Whether you are a hospitality management student, a young Chef or a recent graduate of hospitality and tourism industry, you are eligible to apply. This is paid internship programme normally of a shorter duration than 12 months. Trainees – Hospitality and tourism professionals along with those of other trades are exposed to US culture and business approaches through a guided work based training programme. This is normally paid and is of 12 months’ duration which can be extended by the sponsor. Experts – Experts from any field are called under the route to share their expertise. This might be of some interest to the master Chefs. Physicians Teachers- Those involved in teaching and training in the hospitality and tourism sector can apply through this route. Social service and Philanthropist 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://soegjobs.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/All-about-J1-visa-for-USA.png</main_image>
</document>
