<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.pr.com/rss/press-releases.xml</forum>
<forum_title>PR.com Press Releases</forum_title>
<discussion_title>New Hampshire Resident Celebrates Her Birthday by Giving Back</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.pr.com/press-release/684458</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Receive press releases from Denise Robbins: By Email RSS Feeds: New Hampshire Resident Celebrates Her Birthday by Giving Back Instead of a birthday present or party, Salem, NH resident, Denise Robbins plans to celebrate her birthday by hosting a special meal for Veterans at the New England Center and Home for Veterans. Her way of saying, &quot;Thank you.&quot; Salem, NH,   In January of this year, Salem, NH resident, Denise Robbins decided she wanted to spend her birthday giving back to Veterans.Starting January 1st, she has put away every $10 bill she received in the hopes of coming up with a way to do some little part to thank our Veterans for their service and sacrifice.“I racked my brain on just how to do this. I wanted it to be personal. Finally, I reached out to a friend of mine whose son works at The New England Center and Home for Veterans,” said Denise Robbins.The New England Center and Home for Veterans (http://nechv.org/) is dedicated to ending homelessness for our Nation&apos;s Veterans. Each year, NECHV serves over 100,000 resident meals.This year NECHV implemented a program where a person or persons or organization can sponsor a meal for Veterans. The sponsored meals are special in that the food is not the standard fare served on a daily basis at the center. The sponsored lunch or dinner offers the opportunity to provide a unique and healthy meal to Veteran residents and connect with the population through direct service.“The best part of this sponsored meal is I get to be a server. I get to serve Veterans who served our country. Woot. Count me in,” Denise exclaimed.Denise Robbins recruited a couple of friends to help in this give back birthday celebration. Renee Hoyt and Nancy Wallace will be serving approximately 130 Veterans their dinner at the New England Center and Home for Veterans on September 11, 2016. Nancy, owner of Nancy’s Marshview Café in Salisbury, MA (www.nancysmarshview.com) is also donating dessert for the Veterans meal.In Denise’s excitement about this birthday meal for Veterans, she thought, “Hey, maybe there are more people out there who would like to give back to Veterans, but don’t have a clue how.&quot;Here’s your chance.You can help fund a sponsored meal for Veterans as a way of saying, &quot;Thank you for your service,” by donating to Denise’s fundraiser page. https://www.youcaring.com/new-england-center-and-home-for-veterans-578096For more information on New England Center and Home for Veterans visit their website at http://nechv.org/. Contact Information
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.pr.com/press-release/684458</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0700</post_time>
<username>Denise Robbins</username>
<post>
Receive press releases from Denise Robbins: By Email RSS Feeds: New Hampshire Resident Celebrates Her Birthday by Giving Back Instead of a birthday present or party, Salem, NH resident, Denise Robbins plans to celebrate her birthday by hosting a special meal for Veterans at the New England Center and Home for Veterans. Her way of saying, &quot;Thank you.&quot; Salem, NH,   In January of this year, Salem, NH resident, Denise Robbins decided she wanted to spend her birthday giving back to Veterans.Starting January 1st, she has put away every $10 bill she received in the hopes of coming up with a way to do some little part to thank our Veterans for their service and sacrifice.“I racked my brain on just how to do this. I wanted it to be personal. Finally, I reached out to a friend of mine whose son works at The New England Center and Home for Veterans,” said Denise Robbins.The New England Center and Home for Veterans (http://nechv.org/) is dedicated to ending homelessness for our Nation&apos;s Veterans. Each year, NECHV serves over 100,000 resident meals.This year NECHV implemented a program where a person or persons or organization can sponsor a meal for Veterans. The sponsored meals are special in that the food is not the standard fare served on a daily basis at the center. The sponsored lunch or dinner offers the opportunity to provide a unique and healthy meal to Veteran residents and connect with the population through direct service.“The best part of this sponsored meal is I get to be a server. I get to serve Veterans who served our country. Woot. Count me in,” Denise exclaimed.Denise Robbins recruited a couple of friends to help in this give back birthday celebration. Renee Hoyt and Nancy Wallace will be serving approximately 130 Veterans their dinner at the New England Center and Home for Veterans on September 11, 2016. Nancy, owner of Nancy’s Marshview Café in Salisbury, MA (www.nancysmarshview.com) is also donating dessert for the Veterans meal.In Denise’s excitement about this birthday meal for Veterans, she thought, “Hey, maybe there are more people out there who would like to give back to Veterans, but don’t have a clue how.&quot;Here’s your chance.You can help fund a sponsored meal for Veterans as a way of saying, &quot;Thank you for your service,” by donating to Denise’s fundraiser page. https://www.youcaring.com/new-england-center-and-home-for-veterans-578096For more information on New England Center and Home for Veterans visit their website at http://nechv.org/. Contact Information
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
