<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://m.theboltonnews.co.uk/news/rss/</forum>
<forum_title>The Bolton News | News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>&apos;To me, to you, to Bolton&apos; — Chuckle Brothers among famous names to visit nightclub</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theboltonnews.co.uk/news/14696412._To_me__to_you__to_Bolton______Chuckle_Brothers_among_famous_names_to_visit_nightclub/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
IF you are heading out for a drink in Bolton next month you may run into some unexpected visitors. 
Not usually known as party animals, television&apos;s Chuckle Brothers will be hitting Level Nightclub in Nelson Square. 
The comedy duo will visit for a meet and greet on Wednesday, September 21, as part of a programme of events at the club to welcome new students to the town. 
Joining them on a line-up of events is RnB star Lethal Bizzle and DJ Tom Zanetti. 
Charles McGrath, who co-owns Level Nightclub in Nelson Square, said: &quot;The nights have been organised in partnership with Bolton University student union. 
&quot;The Chuckle Brothers are very popular and Lethal Bizzle has been headlining at a lot of festivals this summer while Tom Zanetti is really popular on the dance scene right now. 
&quot;We just wanted to make sure we had something for everyone, with nostalgia, RnB, dance music . We want to make sure students arriving in Bolton have a good welcome to the town.&quot; 
Paul and Barry Chuckle are the stars of popular BBC children’s comedy series ChuckleVision, which ran for 32 years. 
The moustached brothers are famous for spawning signature catchphrases: &quot;To me, to you&quot; and &quot;oh dear, oh dear&quot;. 
They are not strangers to the music world either, collaborating with grime MC Tinchy Stryder in 2014 for charity single &quot;To Me, To You (Bruv)&quot;, in aid of the African-Caribbean Leukaemia Trust. 
Meanwhile, English rapper Lethal Bizzle boasts a little more chart experience, hitting the music scene back in 2004 with his single &quot;Pow (Forward)&quot;. 
The single reached notoriety after it was banned from airplay by some mainstream radio stations because it contained lyrics about gun culture. 
Bizzle, who will be performing live at Level on Saturday, September 24, later went on to be part of the More Fire Crew with top ten track Oi! 
Leeds DJ and MC Tom Zanetti is behind dancefloor anthem Darlin&apos; and has performed at events alongside the likes of Calvin Harris and Fat Boy Slim. 
He will be lighting up the Level dancefloor on Saturday, September 17, alongside producer K.O Kane. 
The growing list of events adds to a line-up for the nightclub which is used to welcoming popular names from the music and television scene. 
Mr McGrath added: &quot;Getting names in that people recognise from television really works and we like to keep as much of a mix as possible so different people can enjoy it.&quot; 
The club nights will be open to both students and non students.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theboltonnews.co.uk/news/14696412._To_me__to_you__to_Bolton______Chuckle_Brothers_among_famous_names_to_visit_nightclub/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0504</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
IF you are heading out for a drink in Bolton next month you may run into some unexpected visitors. 
Not usually known as party animals, television&apos;s Chuckle Brothers will be hitting Level Nightclub in Nelson Square. 
The comedy duo will visit for a meet and greet on Wednesday, September 21, as part of a programme of events at the club to welcome new students to the town. 
Joining them on a line-up of events is RnB star Lethal Bizzle and DJ Tom Zanetti. 
Charles McGrath, who co-owns Level Nightclub in Nelson Square, said: &quot;The nights have been organised in partnership with Bolton University student union. 
&quot;The Chuckle Brothers are very popular and Lethal Bizzle has been headlining at a lot of festivals this summer while Tom Zanetti is really popular on the dance scene right now. 
&quot;We just wanted to make sure we had something for everyone, with nostalgia, RnB, dance music . We want to make sure students arriving in Bolton have a good welcome to the town.&quot; 
Paul and Barry Chuckle are the stars of popular BBC children’s comedy series ChuckleVision, which ran for 32 years. 
The moustached brothers are famous for spawning signature catchphrases: &quot;To me, to you&quot; and &quot;oh dear, oh dear&quot;. 
They are not strangers to the music world either, collaborating with grime MC Tinchy Stryder in 2014 for charity single &quot;To Me, To You (Bruv)&quot;, in aid of the African-Caribbean Leukaemia Trust. 
Meanwhile, English rapper Lethal Bizzle boasts a little more chart experience, hitting the music scene back in 2004 with his single &quot;Pow (Forward)&quot;. 
The single reached notoriety after it was banned from airplay by some mainstream radio stations because it contained lyrics about gun culture. 
Bizzle, who will be performing live at Level on Saturday, September 24, later went on to be part of the More Fire Crew with top ten track Oi! 
Leeds DJ and MC Tom Zanetti is behind dancefloor anthem Darlin&apos; and has performed at events alongside the likes of Calvin Harris and Fat Boy Slim. 
He will be lighting up the Level dancefloor on Saturday, September 17, alongside producer K.O Kane. 
The growing list of events adds to a line-up for the nightclub which is used to welcoming popular names from the music and television scene. 
Mr McGrath added: &quot;Getting names in that people recognise from television really works and we like to keep as much of a mix as possible so different people can enjoy it.&quot; 
The club nights will be open to both students and non students.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://www.theboltonnews.co.uk/resources/images/5399090/</main_image>
</document>
