<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.4-traders.com/rss/FeedNews.php</forum>
<forum_title>Stock market news - Company News  - 4-Traders.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Interglobe Aviation : UP UP AND AWAY | 4-Traders</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.4-traders.com/INTERGLOBE-AVIATION-LTD-25531239/news/Interglobe-Aviation-UP-UP-AND-AWAY-22935502/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
D traffic shot up by 26 per cent in July as commercial airlines slashed fares to attract more flyers in the lean monsoon season. Latest data released by aviation regulator DGCA shows that domestic airlines flew 85.08 lakh passengers in July compared to 67.62 lakh fliers recorded in the same month last year.
This is the 24th month in a row that domestic air traffic has registered a doubledigit growth as a price war has broken out in Indian skies with airlines competing for a bigger share of the market pie. The decline in jet fuel prices has helped the airlines in cutting costs and enabled them to offer cheaper fares.
`` Indian aviation continues to soar. July passenger growth reaches a record breaking 25 per cent,’’ Civil Aviation Minister Ashok Gajapathi Raju said in a tweet. Leading low- cost carrier IndiGo saw its market share increase to 39.8 per cent during the month from 37.9 per cent in June.
It was followed by Jet Airways ( 16.3 per cent), Air India ( 14.8 per cent), SpiceJet ( 11.7 per cent), GoAir ( 8.4 per cent), Vistara ( 2.6 per cent) and AirAsia ( 2.2 per cent).
When it comes to load factor low- cost carrier SpiceJet emerged on top with 92 per cent seat occupancy in July on the back of an aggressive airfares policy. This is only a wee bit lower than the 93 per cent logged in June which is considered a busy month.
During July, IndiGo&apos;s load factor stood at 83.6 per cent, higher than 77.9 per cent seen in the previous month. Among other airlines, GoAir registered a load factor of 90.3 per cent, followed by Air Asia with 85.7 per cent while that of Jet Airways and Vistara were 83.8 per cent and 75.2 per cent, respectively.
National carrier Air India registered a lower load factor of 80.3 per cent in July.
Scheduled domestic airlines also shelled out compensation to the tune of Rs 35.56 lakh for denying boarding to confirmed passengers last month. For cancellations, the carriers gave a total compensation of Rs 23.22 lakh while a total amount of Rs 61.33 lakh was given towards compensation and facilities for delayed flights.
According to DGCA, 1,111 passengers were affected by denied boarding, 4,796 people by cancellations and delays impacted 65,953 passengers.
Last month, as many as 948 passenger- related complaints were received by the scheduled domestic airlines with maximum number coming against Air Pegasus due to disruptions in its operations amid financial problems.
As many as 34.2 per cent complaints were related to flight problems, followed by customer service ( 27.4 per cent) and baggage ( 17.5 per cent).
Passengers carried by domestic airlines during Jan- Jul 2016 were 560.87 lakh as against 455.95 lakh during the corresponding period of previous year, thereby registering a growth of 23.01 per cent, DGCA said.
SpiceJet said that in July it registered best On- Time Performance ( OTP) and highest Passenger Load Factor ( PLF) among major carriers having sizeable operations in the four metros of Bengaluru, Delhi , Hyderabad and Mumbai .
OTP for the month of July 2016 stood at 79.2 per cent; while the airline again topped the PLF chart registering 92 per cent for the same period, it said in a release.
(c) 2016 India Today Group. All Rights Reserved. Provided by SyndiGate Media Inc. (Syndigate.info)., source Middle East &amp; North African Newspapers
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.4-traders.com/INTERGLOBE-AVIATION-LTD-25531239/news/Interglobe-Aviation-UP-UP-AND-AWAY-22935502/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>www.4-traders.com</username>
<post>
D traffic shot up by 26 per cent in July as commercial airlines slashed fares to attract more flyers in the lean monsoon season. Latest data released by aviation regulator DGCA shows that domestic airlines flew 85.08 lakh passengers in July compared to 67.62 lakh fliers recorded in the same month last year.
This is the 24th month in a row that domestic air traffic has registered a doubledigit growth as a price war has broken out in Indian skies with airlines competing for a bigger share of the market pie. The decline in jet fuel prices has helped the airlines in cutting costs and enabled them to offer cheaper fares.
`` Indian aviation continues to soar. July passenger growth reaches a record breaking 25 per cent,’’ Civil Aviation Minister Ashok Gajapathi Raju said in a tweet. Leading low- cost carrier IndiGo saw its market share increase to 39.8 per cent during the month from 37.9 per cent in June.
It was followed by Jet Airways ( 16.3 per cent), Air India ( 14.8 per cent), SpiceJet ( 11.7 per cent), GoAir ( 8.4 per cent), Vistara ( 2.6 per cent) and AirAsia ( 2.2 per cent).
When it comes to load factor low- cost carrier SpiceJet emerged on top with 92 per cent seat occupancy in July on the back of an aggressive airfares policy. This is only a wee bit lower than the 93 per cent logged in June which is considered a busy month.
During July, IndiGo&apos;s load factor stood at 83.6 per cent, higher than 77.9 per cent seen in the previous month. Among other airlines, GoAir registered a load factor of 90.3 per cent, followed by Air Asia with 85.7 per cent while that of Jet Airways and Vistara were 83.8 per cent and 75.2 per cent, respectively.
National carrier Air India registered a lower load factor of 80.3 per cent in July.
Scheduled domestic airlines also shelled out compensation to the tune of Rs 35.56 lakh for denying boarding to confirmed passengers last month. For cancellations, the carriers gave a total compensation of Rs 23.22 lakh while a total amount of Rs 61.33 lakh was given towards compensation and facilities for delayed flights.
According to DGCA, 1,111 passengers were affected by denied boarding, 4,796 people by cancellations and delays impacted 65,953 passengers.
Last month, as many as 948 passenger- related complaints were received by the scheduled domestic airlines with maximum number coming against Air Pegasus due to disruptions in its operations amid financial problems.
As many as 34.2 per cent complaints were related to flight problems, followed by customer service ( 27.4 per cent) and baggage ( 17.5 per cent).
Passengers carried by domestic airlines during Jan- Jul 2016 were 560.87 lakh as against 455.95 lakh during the corresponding period of previous year, thereby registering a growth of 23.01 per cent, DGCA said.
SpiceJet said that in July it registered best On- Time Performance ( OTP) and highest Passenger Load Factor ( PLF) among major carriers having sizeable operations in the four metros of Bengaluru, Delhi , Hyderabad and Mumbai .
OTP for the month of July 2016 stood at 79.2 per cent; while the airline again topped the PLF chart registering 92 per cent for the same period, it said in a release.
(c) 2016 India Today Group. All Rights Reserved. Provided by SyndiGate Media Inc. (Syndigate.info)., source Middle East &amp; North African Newspapers
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>FR</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
