<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Secrets of my success: Harold Mitchell |The Weekly Review</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/secrets-of-my-success-harold-mitchell/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Share Media buying guru and philanthropist Harold Mitchell. Photo: Michael Rayner One of Australia’s wealthiest and most highly regarded businessmen, Harold Mitchell turned the small media buying business he founded in 1976 with just $2000 into a national advertising powerhouse, Mitchell &amp; Partners. In 2010 he sold the company to London-based Aegis for $363 million. A passionate patron of the arts, he has been chairman of the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra and the National Gallery, and has sat on the board of the New York Philharmonic. He is also a former vice-president of Tennis Australia and one-time owner of the Melbourne Rebels rugby union team. When did you first realise you were successful? In the early years success was getting through to the next day. I sometimes didn’t have enough money to get through the whole week. Completing a week was a success. Secrets of success? You will never be successful at achieving something unless you decide what it is. I always say to people, ‘Let us decide which mountain we’re trying to climb. ‘Let’s isolate it down to one mountain rather than trying to climb five little ones’. Has success changed you? In two ways. First it has given me a greater power to get things done. People respect someone who’s achieved something. You have to be careful of that because if you abuse that sort of power you don’t have it any more. Sadly it’s also made me a little wary because people tend to look to take an advantage where they can. I try to put that into the background. People ask, ‘How and why are you successful?’ The only thing that has ever driven me – and I suspect anybody like me – is a fear of failure. How do you measure success in other people ? More often than not success is measured by the usual values of money. I never have. In the middle years of our business I can remember twice a year I would have a Chinese dinner in Melbourne with a man who had the greatest grasp of people that I couldn’t quite get. He was a sergeant in the police force and he saw real people up close. I was fascinated by the stories he told of real people. He was fascinated with the stories I had about rich people and we had the best hour and a half you’ve ever had. I thought he was as successful as you could ever get. Tips for success? Every Saturday morning I’d drive from St Andrews into the city and make up the accounts for the week or month. That started a pattern. I sat down with a pencil and paper and had a review, for about an hour, of how it was going. LISA MESSENGER JOHN BERTRAND CAROLYN CRESWELL 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.29</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/secrets-of-my-success-harold-mitchell/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Share Media buying guru and philanthropist Harold Mitchell. Photo: Michael Rayner One of Australia’s wealthiest and most highly regarded businessmen, Harold Mitchell turned the small media buying business he founded in 1976 with just $2000 into a national advertising powerhouse, Mitchell &amp; Partners. In 2010 he sold the company to London-based Aegis for $363 million. A passionate patron of the arts, he has been chairman of the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra and the National Gallery, and has sat on the board of the New York Philharmonic. He is also a former vice-president of Tennis Australia and one-time owner of the Melbourne Rebels rugby union team. When did you first realise you were successful? In the early years success was getting through to the next day. I sometimes didn’t have enough money to get through the whole week. Completing a week was a success. Secrets of success? You will never be successful at achieving something unless you decide what it is. I always say to people, ‘Let us decide which mountain we’re trying to climb. ‘Let’s isolate it down to one mountain rather than trying to climb five little ones’. Has success changed you? In two ways. First it has given me a greater power to get things done. People respect someone who’s achieved something. You have to be careful of that because if you abuse that sort of power you don’t have it any more. Sadly it’s also made me a little wary because people tend to look to take an advantage where they can. I try to put that into the background. People ask, ‘How and why are you successful?’ The only thing that has ever driven me – and I suspect anybody like me – is a fear of failure. How do you measure success in other people ? More often than not success is measured by the usual values of money. I never have. In the middle years of our business I can remember twice a year I would have a Chinese dinner in Melbourne with a man who had the greatest grasp of people that I couldn’t quite get. He was a sergeant in the police force and he saw real people up close. I was fascinated by the stories he told of real people. He was fascinated with the stories I had about rich people and we had the best hour and a half you’ve ever had. I thought he was as successful as you could ever get. Tips for success? Every Saturday morning I’d drive from St Andrews into the city and make up the accounts for the week or month. That started a pattern. I sat down with a pencil and paper and had a review, for about an hour, of how it was going. LISA MESSENGER JOHN BERTRAND CAROLYN CRESWELL 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/TWR-Cover-Harold-Mitchell-PW-05-650x433.jpg</main_image>
</document>
