<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Moretrench’s Greg Landry Leads Compilation of 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/geotechnicalconstruction/dewateringNJ/prweb13625593.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Moretrench’s Greg Landry Leads Compilation of 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure Share Article Moretrench Chief Dewatering Engineer Greg Landry, P.E. contributed to the 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure. Overall, the state received a D+. &apos;The committee is hopeful that bipartisan legislation, which proposes to increase New Jersey’s gas tax, is a smart first step toward getting our state’s infrastructure back on track,&apos; said Landry. Rockaway NJ (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Moretrench Chief Dewatering Engineer Greg Landry, P.E. is recognized as a key player in compiling the 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure . Released on June 16, the report provides a snapshot of New Jersey’s current infrastructure conditions and needs. It was compiled by civil engineering professionals and educators in New Jersey. Landry, a former resident of ASCE’s North Jersey branch and the New Jersey Section, was a member of the three-person steering committee that managed the report, along with Luis Barragan, P.E. and Michael Sears, P.E., also former North Jersey branch presidents. They drew from experts across the state to compile each of the following categories: Water, Wastewater, Parks, Dams , Levees, Ports, Roads, Rail, Transit, Bridges, Energy, Hazardous Waste and Solid Waste. Grades were assigned on an A to F basis according to the following criteria: capacity, condition, funding, future need, operation and maintenance, public safety, resilience and innovation. The report also outlined a vision for what New Jersey’s infrastructure will look like in the future and some of the actions needed to get there. Overall, New Jersey infrastructure earned a cumulative GPA of D+ in the 13 categories. Among the lowest grades were transit (D-), bridges (D+) and roads (D), all of which are funded by the state’s Transportation Trust Fund. Following the statewide release, a press conference was hosted at the State House by Assembly Majority Leader Louis D. Greenwald, which focused on the need to fix the state’s Transportation Trust Fund, which will go bankrupt on July 1 if state lawmakers do not act. “The committee is hopeful that bipartisan legislation, which proposes to increase New Jersey’s gas tax, is a smart first step toward getting our state’s infrastructure back on track,&quot; said Landry. To learn more about Landry and his work at Moretrench, visit http://www.moretrench.com or call (973) 627-2100. The company is located at 100 Stickle Ave in Rockaway, N.J. 07866. Moretrench specializes in underground construction in the Rockaway, N.J. area. They offer services for deep foundations, dewatering, earth retention and anchors, environmental remediation, ground freezing, grouting, industrial construction and underpinning. They offer solutions to problems such as contaminated groundwater and soil, settlement control and dam rehabilitation and reconstruction. Created as a family business, Moretrench has been 100% employee owned since 1999. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.08</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/geotechnicalconstruction/dewateringNJ/prweb13625593.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Moretrench’s Greg Landry Leads Compilation of 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure Share Article Moretrench Chief Dewatering Engineer Greg Landry, P.E. contributed to the 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure. Overall, the state received a D+. &apos;The committee is hopeful that bipartisan legislation, which proposes to increase New Jersey’s gas tax, is a smart first step toward getting our state’s infrastructure back on track,&apos; said Landry. Rockaway NJ (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Moretrench Chief Dewatering Engineer Greg Landry, P.E. is recognized as a key player in compiling the 2016 Report Card for New Jersey’s Infrastructure . Released on June 16, the report provides a snapshot of New Jersey’s current infrastructure conditions and needs. It was compiled by civil engineering professionals and educators in New Jersey. Landry, a former resident of ASCE’s North Jersey branch and the New Jersey Section, was a member of the three-person steering committee that managed the report, along with Luis Barragan, P.E. and Michael Sears, P.E., also former North Jersey branch presidents. They drew from experts across the state to compile each of the following categories: Water, Wastewater, Parks, Dams , Levees, Ports, Roads, Rail, Transit, Bridges, Energy, Hazardous Waste and Solid Waste. Grades were assigned on an A to F basis according to the following criteria: capacity, condition, funding, future need, operation and maintenance, public safety, resilience and innovation. The report also outlined a vision for what New Jersey’s infrastructure will look like in the future and some of the actions needed to get there. Overall, New Jersey infrastructure earned a cumulative GPA of D+ in the 13 categories. Among the lowest grades were transit (D-), bridges (D+) and roads (D), all of which are funded by the state’s Transportation Trust Fund. Following the statewide release, a press conference was hosted at the State House by Assembly Majority Leader Louis D. Greenwald, which focused on the need to fix the state’s Transportation Trust Fund, which will go bankrupt on July 1 if state lawmakers do not act. “The committee is hopeful that bipartisan legislation, which proposes to increase New Jersey’s gas tax, is a smart first step toward getting our state’s infrastructure back on track,&quot; said Landry. To learn more about Landry and his work at Moretrench, visit http://www.moretrench.com or call (973) 627-2100. The company is located at 100 Stickle Ave in Rockaway, N.J. 07866. Moretrench specializes in underground construction in the Rockaway, N.J. area. They offer services for deep foundations, dewatering, earth retention and anchors, environmental remediation, ground freezing, grouting, industrial construction and underpinning. They offer solutions to problems such as contaminated groundwater and soil, settlement control and dam rehabilitation and reconstruction. Created as a family business, Moretrench has been 100% employee owned since 1999. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
