<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2014/oct/18/mainsection/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Guardian</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Budapest to Berlin: stranger on a train | Travel</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/aug/22/budapest-to-berlin-stranger-on-a-train</topic_url>
<topic_text>
I n early June, when everyone in Britain was arguing about Europe, I found myself in Budapest . I had fond memories of my only previous visit, in 2013, when I’d been there for a literary festival. After one of the endless drinks parties I’d fallen into step with a group in search of dinner and wound up talking to a tall man with prominent eyebrows and burgundy trousers. “I got married in there,” he said casually, pointing at St Stephen’s Basilica .
“It must have been hard to fill,” I replied with a certain froideur. This was a bit like someone nodding at Wembley Stadium and mentioning their seven-night run there. I wasn’t about to wave it through unchecked.
“Not really. In fact, people crowded outside and it was shown on television.”
“I see. Why was that?” “Well, my grandfather was the last emperor,” he explained, moments before I fell back to Google him. Though the Habsburgs no longer rule, I learned later that the name still secures preferential treatment in a steakhouse.

Facebook Twitter Pinterest ‘Brooklynite dream for a tenth of the price’: a ruin bar in the Jewish quarter. Photograph: Alamy 
My other enduring impression was of an anarchic day that began as a walking tour of the old city and ended with hamburgers and beer in a pedal cart. My guide Zsuzsi and I stayed in touch through Facebook, and I looked her up as soon as I arrived this time.
If you haven’t been to Budapest recently, you probably have the wrong idea about it. For my parents’ generation it was a cheap weekend behind the Iron Curtain, where your interest was pitched against your growing boredom with goulash. Since joining the EU it has become a cheap favourite for stag and hen dos, a fact not unrelated to pints of beer that adhere stubbornly to a price of less than £1. But a smarter and more interesting scene is emerging, too.
The ruin bars – dilapidated buildings, mainly in the Jewish quarter, given new life over the past decade by canny entrepreneurs – have become markedly smarter and hipper. At bars like Mazel Tov, Racskert and Most you can sit in designer furniture in airy atriums, enjoying the kind of night out Brooklynites dream of, for a tenth of the price. “The local owners complain about the noise but their apartments are worth five times what they were,” Zsuzsi’s boyfriend Alex told me. He owns a hostel himself, Casa de La Musica , in an old dance school.
The seats were all burgundy. I settled into mine and waited for a stranger to ask me to murder his father

The next morning I woke at six to catch a train to Berlin. I was excited about the journey. Over 11 and a half hours it would take me through four countries, three of which I hadn’t visited before. My first-class ticket, bought the day before, was just €60. Take that, easyJet. The seats were wide and comfortable, with a plug for my devices. The next carriage along had old-fashioned private compartments with a corridor down the outside. Beyond that was a dining car. All were upholstered in deep burgundy. As we rolled out of the city, tracing the Danube back towards its source, a man served coffee and handed out newspapers. I settled into my chair and waited for a stranger to ask me to murder his father.

Facebook Twitter Pinterest City lights: the banks of the River Spree at sunset. Photograph: Getty Images 
After half an hour we crossed into Slovakia towards Bratislava. From there we turned north towards the Czech Republic , close enough to look into Austria but not quite crossing its frontier. At each border a new conductor got on to stamp my ticket. I was the only one in the carriage going the whole way. Nobody asked for a passport. As we left Brno I was peckish, so went to the dining car and ordered paprika chicken with dumplings and a cold beer. Sweeping crumbs off the tablecloth I pondered how many BLTs I’d eaten on British trains. A hundred? What a sad waste of life.
At Prague the platform was three-deep with Interrailers, who piled on to the train. Luckily none of them had booked into first class except for one American girl with a suspiciously new-looking backpack. We exchanged a glance which conveyed what we thought about the passengers at the back of the train, specifically that they were suckers.
The physical geography of this part of the continent is quite uniform, at least to a man seeing it for the first time with half an eye on his WhatsApp. It slid past as a kind of Mittel-European diorama. Meadows and mountains grew darker-green as we trundled north under a breathless blue sky, the Bohemian landscape carved by rivers of flashing silver. More noticeable was the human geography. The nearer you get to Germany the newer the cars, the more neat the gardens, the fresher the paint on the walls. It’s like seeing a history of neglect in reverse. As we crossed the Elbe at Dresden two rowing eights beat a lazy pace upstream.

Facebook Twitter Pinterest A cafe in the heart of Kreuzberg. Photograph: Maremagnum/Getty Images 
We pulled into Berlin in the early evening, two minutes later than scheduled. I have been delayed for longer between Charing Cross and Embankment. At Hauptbahnhof I tried to buy a ticket for the S-Bahn. The ticket machine listed options for refugees and those interested in a gay tour of the city but not, as far as I could tell, for “single journey to specific station”. I chose something that promised “all access” but it wouldn’t take my Visa. Cursing, I made a mental note never again to be rude about Oyster cards and went to look for a cab. Time was tight: I had an early train to Paris to catch the next day and I wanted to spend some time with my cousin Kate.
She moved to Berlin last year with her boyfriend, lured by cheap rent and exhilarating, keenly priced nightlife. They insisted on showing me some of the latter, or at least the parts of it in walking distance of their flat in Kreuzberg. I only recall the first two bars with any clarity. One was decorated with pictures of the Muppets. “We are the same, you and I,” said the owner, with his hand on his heart in a gesture of solidarity. He seemed to have sampled some of his own wares. “Me – Saxony. You – Saxon,” he said. We ordered more beer.
The ticket machine in Berlin listed options for refugees and those interested in gay tours of the city

The train to Paris left just after seven the next morning. Or rather, I assume it did, but I can’t be sure because at the time I was lying with my mouth open on Kate’s futon. “You’re still here,” she said unhelpfully as I stumbled towards the bathroom in pursuit of my contact lenses. We passed the rest of the morning walking around Tempelhof Field, the former airport which since 2008 has been left to become a public park. My hangover eased enough to recognise what an extraordinary public space this is. The imposing terminal, planned by Albert Speer to be the hub of the 1,000-year Reich, now houses refugees. To the trilling of unseen skylarks, rollerbladers and joggers trundle up and down the runway that was once at the heart of the Berlin Airlift. Airlift. Planes. Struck by a cunning plan, I took out my phone. In less than 30 seconds I’d booked a ticket to Paris that afternoon. Sorry about what I said earlier, easyJet.
Essentials Train tickets from Budapest to Berlin start at £33 ( mavcsoport.hu ). Take a tour of Budapest with Zsuzsi Szoke through curiocity budapest.com. 
Fly from Paris to Berlin by easyJet from £129 ( easyjet.com ). Take the train from Paris to London on Eurostar from £29 one-way ( eurostar.com )
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>36</post_num>
<post_id>post-36</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/aug/22/budapest-to-berlin-stranger-on-a-train#comment-81618806</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0819</post_time>
<username>fishplate</username>
<post>
Depends if there is something happening. I need to be there in a few weeks, and during the week it is mind-bogglingly expensive, at the weekend it is just expensive (50 euros for a hostel bed levels of expensive, when I checked yesterday). If there is nothing happening, it is cheaper.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3488912bc43df6ddbed4c4a5a8add0743710d554/0_185_5558_3334/5558.jpg?w=1200&amp;amp;h=630&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;bm=normal&amp;amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxNi8wNS8yNS9vdmVybGF5LWxvZ28tMTIwMC05MF9vcHQucG5n&amp;amp;s=c79277301940941414ba8ec91e737135</main_image>
</document>
