<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Vcorp Services Named Among The 5,000 Fastest-Growing Private Companies In America By Inc Magazine For The 4th Consecutive Year</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13622719.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Vcorp Services Named Among The 5,000 Fastest-Growing Private Companies In America By Inc Magazine For The 4th Consecutive Year Share Article Vcorp Services, LLC (&quot;Vcorp&quot;), a leading corporate filing and registered agent provider, has been named by Inc. Magazine as one of the 5,000 fastest-growing private companies in America for the fourth consecutive year. Monsey, NY. (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 For 35 years, The Inc. 500 | 5000 has recognized America&apos;s fastest-growing private companies. The annual listing represents the most comprehensive look at independent minded entrepreneurs in the nation. In addition to Vcorp Services, the 2016 list includes such powerhouses as Square, Dollar Shave Club, ipsy, and Yeti Cooler. “You are in good company – which is exactly where you belong,” the President and Editor-In-Chief of Inc. Media, Eric Schurenberg, wrote in a letter to Vcorp announcing the honor. “On average, the companies on the list have grown almost five-fold over the past three years. That’s a result most businesses could only dream of.” &quot;We are humbled to receive this recognition for the fourth consecutive year. I believe this is a true testament to the hard work and dedication of the Vcorp staff. They show up for work every day with a freshness and renewed commitment to provide the best of breed in corporate services to our valued clients,&quot; says Isaac Muller, Founder &amp; CEO of Vcorp Services, LLC, “Our customers feel our eagerness to provide the highest level of outstanding personalized customer service and we are honored that our clients respond with long term patronage and loyalty.&quot; Complete results of the Inc. 500 | 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . About Vcorp Services LLC Vcorp Services assists in the creation of new businesses and helps maintain existing businesses in all 50 states. Quick, accurate and at the lowest rates, Vcorp’s knowledgeable and experienced staff has helped form thousands of new businesses including: LLCs, S-Corporations, C-Corporations, Partnerships, Non-Profits and Professional Corporations. Vcorp works with entrepreneurs, legal and tax professionals, as well as real estate experts to set up and maintain businesses across the country. Vcorp also specializes in helping small businesses to get started, grow and remain in compliance with federal and state regulations. For more information, go to http://www.vcorpservices.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.13</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13622719.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Vcorp Services Named Among The 5,000 Fastest-Growing Private Companies In America By Inc Magazine For The 4th Consecutive Year Share Article Vcorp Services, LLC (&quot;Vcorp&quot;), a leading corporate filing and registered agent provider, has been named by Inc. Magazine as one of the 5,000 fastest-growing private companies in America for the fourth consecutive year. Monsey, NY. (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 For 35 years, The Inc. 500 | 5000 has recognized America&apos;s fastest-growing private companies. The annual listing represents the most comprehensive look at independent minded entrepreneurs in the nation. In addition to Vcorp Services, the 2016 list includes such powerhouses as Square, Dollar Shave Club, ipsy, and Yeti Cooler. “You are in good company – which is exactly where you belong,” the President and Editor-In-Chief of Inc. Media, Eric Schurenberg, wrote in a letter to Vcorp announcing the honor. “On average, the companies on the list have grown almost five-fold over the past three years. That’s a result most businesses could only dream of.” &quot;We are humbled to receive this recognition for the fourth consecutive year. I believe this is a true testament to the hard work and dedication of the Vcorp staff. They show up for work every day with a freshness and renewed commitment to provide the best of breed in corporate services to our valued clients,&quot; says Isaac Muller, Founder &amp; CEO of Vcorp Services, LLC, “Our customers feel our eagerness to provide the highest level of outstanding personalized customer service and we are honored that our clients respond with long term patronage and loyalty.&quot; Complete results of the Inc. 500 | 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . About Vcorp Services LLC Vcorp Services assists in the creation of new businesses and helps maintain existing businesses in all 50 states. Quick, accurate and at the lowest rates, Vcorp’s knowledgeable and experienced staff has helped form thousands of new businesses including: LLCs, S-Corporations, C-Corporations, Partnerships, Non-Profits and Professional Corporations. Vcorp works with entrepreneurs, legal and tax professionals, as well as real estate experts to set up and maintain businesses across the country. Vcorp also specializes in helping small businesses to get started, grow and remain in compliance with federal and state regulations. For more information, go to http://www.vcorpservices.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
