<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.seattlepi.com/home/collectionRss/Home-Hcat-Nation-World-9248.php</forum>
<forum_title>Home Hcat Nation/World</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Iran chastises Russia for publicizing use of Iranian bases</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.seattlepi.com/news/world/article/Iran-chastises-Russia-for-publicizing-use-of-9176594.php</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Close Image 1 of 2 FILE -- In this on Tuesday Aug. 16, 2016 frame grab provided by Russian Defence Ministry press service, aRussian long range bomber Tu-22M3 flies during an air strike over the Aleppo region of Syria. Iran’s Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan was quoted by State TV website Monday, Aug. 22, 2016, as saying an announcement by Russia on using an Iranian airbase to attack Syrian militants was “a kind of show off and ungentlemanly.” The remarks suggest that the operation was not supposed to get public by either side. (Russian Defence Ministry Press Service photo via AP, File) less FILE -- In this on Tuesday Aug. 16, 2016 frame grab provided by Russian Defence Ministry press service, aRussian long range bomber Tu-22M3 flies during an air strike over the Aleppo region of Syria. Iran’s ... more Photo: AP Image 2 of 2 FILE -- In this Feb. 16, 2016 file photo, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu, right, and Iranian Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan shake hands during their meeting in Moscow, Russia. Dehghan was quoted by Iranian State TV website Monday, Aug. 22, 2016, as saying an announcement by Russia on using an Iranian airbase to attack Syrian militants was “a kind of show off and ungentlemanly.” The remarks suggest that the operation was not supposed to get public by either side. (Vadim Savitsky/ Russian Defense Ministry Press Service pool photo via AP, File) less FILE -- In this Feb. 16, 2016 file photo, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu, right, and Iranian Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan shake hands during their meeting in Moscow, Russia. Dehghan was quoted ... more Photo: Vadim Savitsky, AP Iran chastises Russia for publicizing use of Iranian bases 1 / 2 Back to Gallery TEHRAN, Iran (AP) — Iran&apos;s defense minister is chastising Russia, saying Moscow&apos;s announcement on using Iranian bases for attacks on Syrian militants was &quot;kind of show off and ungentlemanly.&quot; State TV&apos;s website on Monday quoted Gen. Hossein Dehghan as saying &quot;Russians seek to show that they are a superpower.&quot; Dehghan&apos;s remarks were the first sign of pushback from Tehran after Russia last week began using Iranian territory to launch airstrikes in Syria, with Moscow&apos;s bombers flying out of the Islamic Republic for three straight days to hit what Russia says are Islamic State targets and other militants in the war-ravaged country. Iran only confirmed the flights and the use of its bases a day after Russia made the announcement. Dehghan&apos;s comments suggest Iran may not have wanted the flights publicized to such an extent. Most Popular
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.seattlepi.com/news/world/article/Iran-chastises-Russia-for-publicizing-use-of-9176594.php</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0731</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Close Image 1 of 2 FILE -- In this on Tuesday Aug. 16, 2016 frame grab provided by Russian Defence Ministry press service, aRussian long range bomber Tu-22M3 flies during an air strike over the Aleppo region of Syria. Iran’s Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan was quoted by State TV website Monday, Aug. 22, 2016, as saying an announcement by Russia on using an Iranian airbase to attack Syrian militants was “a kind of show off and ungentlemanly.” The remarks suggest that the operation was not supposed to get public by either side. (Russian Defence Ministry Press Service photo via AP, File) less FILE -- In this on Tuesday Aug. 16, 2016 frame grab provided by Russian Defence Ministry press service, aRussian long range bomber Tu-22M3 flies during an air strike over the Aleppo region of Syria. Iran’s ... more Photo: AP Image 2 of 2 FILE -- In this Feb. 16, 2016 file photo, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu, right, and Iranian Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan shake hands during their meeting in Moscow, Russia. Dehghan was quoted by Iranian State TV website Monday, Aug. 22, 2016, as saying an announcement by Russia on using an Iranian airbase to attack Syrian militants was “a kind of show off and ungentlemanly.” The remarks suggest that the operation was not supposed to get public by either side. (Vadim Savitsky/ Russian Defense Ministry Press Service pool photo via AP, File) less FILE -- In this Feb. 16, 2016 file photo, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu, right, and Iranian Defense Minister Gen. Hossein Dehghan shake hands during their meeting in Moscow, Russia. Dehghan was quoted ... more Photo: Vadim Savitsky, AP Iran chastises Russia for publicizing use of Iranian bases 1 / 2 Back to Gallery TEHRAN, Iran (AP) — Iran&apos;s defense minister is chastising Russia, saying Moscow&apos;s announcement on using Iranian bases for attacks on Syrian militants was &quot;kind of show off and ungentlemanly.&quot; State TV&apos;s website on Monday quoted Gen. Hossein Dehghan as saying &quot;Russians seek to show that they are a superpower.&quot; Dehghan&apos;s remarks were the first sign of pushback from Tehran after Russia last week began using Iranian territory to launch airstrikes in Syria, with Moscow&apos;s bombers flying out of the Islamic Republic for three straight days to hit what Russia says are Islamic State targets and other militants in the war-ravaged country. Iran only confirmed the flights and the use of its bases a day after Russia made the announcement. Dehghan&apos;s comments suggest Iran may not have wanted the flights publicized to such an extent. Most Popular
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww4.hdnux.com/photos/51/17/24/10810659/3/rawImage.jpg</main_image>
</document>
