<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Local Marketing Automation Leader Surefire Social - Achieves 3rd Consecutive Listing in the Inc. 5000</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13625703.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Local Marketing Automation Leader Surefire Social - Achieves 3rd Consecutive Listing in the Inc. 5000 Share Article Inc. Magazine Unveils 35th Annual Inc. 5000 List of America’s Fastest Growing Private Companies. Continued Adoption Lands Local Marketing Automation Company - Surefire Social - on List for 3rd Straight Year. SurePulse: The First LOCAL Marketing Automation System This recognition, three years in a row, is a testament to the outstanding work performed every day by our Surefire Social team! Chris Marentis, CEO of Surefire Social McLean, VA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Surefire Social is honored to be included in the 2016 Inc. 5000 list of fastest growing companies in the U.S. A three-year growth of 204% helped land Surefire Social at #1817. Says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg, “Congratulations! For the 3 time, Surefire Social has made the Inc. 5000 list of the fastest-growing private companies in America. Only a tiny fraction of the nation&apos;s companies have demonstrated such remarkably consistent high growth. This achievement truly puts you in rarefied company.” Founded by Chris Marentis, Surefire Social has helped over 2,500 businesses in the home improvement and healthcare industries experience breakthrough results in acquiring new customers. &quot;This recognition, three years in a row, is a testament to the outstanding work performed every day by our Surefire Social team!&quot; Chris Marentis, CEO of Surefire Social Surefire Social’s listing in the 2016 Inc. 5000 was first released online at Inc.com along with other top 5000 companies featured in the September issue of Inc. The list includes many of America’s most competitive companies with the average company listed achieving a mind-boggling three-year growth of 433%. The Inc. 5000&apos;s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . &quot;The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” About Surefire Social Surefire Social offers a full marketing suite including website, mobile, social, local directory, reputation, and paid media management. SurePulse, the First Local Marketing Automation System , is built exclusively for hyper-local businesses. Local business visibility today depends on implementing a coordinated campaign across many channels. SMBs find it overwhelming and frustrating to assimilate all the changing platforms, integrate them and implement a coordinated cross-platform campaign. Brands with large franchise, dealer or contractor networks have the more complex problem of coordinating national-to-local campaigning. Surefire Social provides the technology stack and services to make it easy and cost-effective to monitor, measure and publish from one platform. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13625703.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Local Marketing Automation Leader Surefire Social - Achieves 3rd Consecutive Listing in the Inc. 5000 Share Article Inc. Magazine Unveils 35th Annual Inc. 5000 List of America’s Fastest Growing Private Companies. Continued Adoption Lands Local Marketing Automation Company - Surefire Social - on List for 3rd Straight Year. SurePulse: The First LOCAL Marketing Automation System This recognition, three years in a row, is a testament to the outstanding work performed every day by our Surefire Social team! Chris Marentis, CEO of Surefire Social McLean, VA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Surefire Social is honored to be included in the 2016 Inc. 5000 list of fastest growing companies in the U.S. A three-year growth of 204% helped land Surefire Social at #1817. Says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg, “Congratulations! For the 3 time, Surefire Social has made the Inc. 5000 list of the fastest-growing private companies in America. Only a tiny fraction of the nation&apos;s companies have demonstrated such remarkably consistent high growth. This achievement truly puts you in rarefied company.” Founded by Chris Marentis, Surefire Social has helped over 2,500 businesses in the home improvement and healthcare industries experience breakthrough results in acquiring new customers. &quot;This recognition, three years in a row, is a testament to the outstanding work performed every day by our Surefire Social team!&quot; Chris Marentis, CEO of Surefire Social Surefire Social’s listing in the 2016 Inc. 5000 was first released online at Inc.com along with other top 5000 companies featured in the September issue of Inc. The list includes many of America’s most competitive companies with the average company listed achieving a mind-boggling three-year growth of 433%. The Inc. 5000&apos;s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . &quot;The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” About Surefire Social Surefire Social offers a full marketing suite including website, mobile, social, local directory, reputation, and paid media management. SurePulse, the First Local Marketing Automation System , is built exclusively for hyper-local businesses. Local business visibility today depends on implementing a coordinated campaign across many channels. SMBs find it overwhelming and frustrating to assimilate all the changing platforms, integrate them and implement a coordinated cross-platform campaign. Brands with large franchise, dealer or contractor networks have the more complex problem of coordinating national-to-local campaigning. Surefire Social provides the technology stack and services to make it easy and cost-effective to monitor, measure and publish from one platform. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/08/19/13625703/SurePulse the First Local Marketing Automation System.jpg</main_image>
</document>
