<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.suidkaapforum.com/rss/5/Arts%20and%20Entertainment</forum>
<forum_title>Suid-Kaap Forum | Arts and Entertainment</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Exciting Working with Wood fest this weekend</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.suidkaapforum.com/news.aspx?main=Arts--Entertainment&amp;sub=Entertainment&amp;id=170747&amp;h=Exciting-Working-with-Wood-fest-this-weekend</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Disclaimers Exciting Working with Wood fest this weekend The Working with Wood shows are known for bringing top South African and international demonstrators to share their woodworking skills and crafts. Photo: Generic. SOUTERN CAPE NEWS - With a history in timber dating back as far as 1932, what better venue for this year’s Working with Wood Show in association with the Woodturning Symposium, than the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University (NMMU) George Campus. The woodworking fraternity globally are extremely excited that the Association of Woodturners of South African (AWSA) in partnership with the American Association of Woodturners (AAW), the Working with Wood Show and the School of Natural Resource Management at NMMU will take an active role in this year’s Woodturners Symposium from 26 to 28 August. This venue’s origins can be traced back to 1911 when a forestry college was established at Tokai near Cape Town. The government of the day moved the college to a new location, Saasveld, near George in the Southern Cape in 1932. From 1932 to 1985 almost 1 300 foresters were trained at this campus that is surrounded by both indigenous and commercial forests. Following on from the extremely successful 2014 Working with Wood Show in Knysna, the event quickly established itself as a leading woodworking and tool show in South Africa, and is acknowledged today as Africa’s most diverse Woodworking and Woodcraft event. The Working with Wood shows are known for bringing top South African and international demonstrators to share their woodworking skills and crafts from woodturning, carving, chair making, sharpening to furniture making with attendees. Everything timber related and eco related, from mobile milling of slabs, to fine furniture and sculptures, sustainable alternatives for the home and natural resource management displays can be found. These events showcase sustainable timber production. The Woodturning Symposium and Working with Wood Show will feature top woodworking experts. Among these are two international AWSA guests, Carmen de la Paz from the US and Chris Pouncy from the UK. The South African contingent includes John Wessels, John Speedy, Dave Stephenson, Mervin Walsh, Richard Muller, Jan Conradie and Charlie Letsoalo. Participants will be also be able to attend woodturning demonstrations and enhancements, and woodworking workshops that will highlight the global trend in woodturning and woodworking. De la Paz and Wessels will offer live demonstrations on some of the latest techniques in wood enhancements. Besides the myriad demonstrations on offer, a large exhibition of tools, equipment and the latest woodworking and woodturning equipment will also be on exhibit. These include leading brands such as Festool, Triton, Kreg, Howard Products, Pro Tech, Tork Craft, Bessey, Felo, Alpen, MPS, Spring Tools, Mag Switch, Aircraft, Drill Doctor, Armor and the latest revolutionary circular saw from Saw Stop. All equipment and supplies at the show will be on offer at special low Show prices. For further information visit www.workingwithwood.co.za and www.awsa.org.za or call Fran Kirsten on 082 416 3398 or send an e-mail to fran@out-there.co.za . The show will be open from 09:00 to 18:00 daily at a cost of R20 per adult and R10 for children under 12. &apos;We bring you the latest Garden Route, Klein Karoo, Hessequa news&apos; 08:21 (GMT+2),  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.suidkaapforum.com/news.aspx?main=Arts--Entertainment&amp;sub=Entertainment&amp;id=170747&amp;h=Exciting-Working-with-Wood-fest-this-weekend</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0821</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Disclaimers Exciting Working with Wood fest this weekend The Working with Wood shows are known for bringing top South African and international demonstrators to share their woodworking skills and crafts. Photo: Generic. SOUTERN CAPE NEWS - With a history in timber dating back as far as 1932, what better venue for this year’s Working with Wood Show in association with the Woodturning Symposium, than the Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University (NMMU) George Campus. The woodworking fraternity globally are extremely excited that the Association of Woodturners of South African (AWSA) in partnership with the American Association of Woodturners (AAW), the Working with Wood Show and the School of Natural Resource Management at NMMU will take an active role in this year’s Woodturners Symposium from 26 to 28 August. This venue’s origins can be traced back to 1911 when a forestry college was established at Tokai near Cape Town. The government of the day moved the college to a new location, Saasveld, near George in the Southern Cape in 1932. From 1932 to 1985 almost 1 300 foresters were trained at this campus that is surrounded by both indigenous and commercial forests. Following on from the extremely successful 2014 Working with Wood Show in Knysna, the event quickly established itself as a leading woodworking and tool show in South Africa, and is acknowledged today as Africa’s most diverse Woodworking and Woodcraft event. The Working with Wood shows are known for bringing top South African and international demonstrators to share their woodworking skills and crafts from woodturning, carving, chair making, sharpening to furniture making with attendees. Everything timber related and eco related, from mobile milling of slabs, to fine furniture and sculptures, sustainable alternatives for the home and natural resource management displays can be found. These events showcase sustainable timber production. The Woodturning Symposium and Working with Wood Show will feature top woodworking experts. Among these are two international AWSA guests, Carmen de la Paz from the US and Chris Pouncy from the UK. The South African contingent includes John Wessels, John Speedy, Dave Stephenson, Mervin Walsh, Richard Muller, Jan Conradie and Charlie Letsoalo. Participants will be also be able to attend woodturning demonstrations and enhancements, and woodworking workshops that will highlight the global trend in woodturning and woodworking. De la Paz and Wessels will offer live demonstrations on some of the latest techniques in wood enhancements. Besides the myriad demonstrations on offer, a large exhibition of tools, equipment and the latest woodworking and woodturning equipment will also be on exhibit. These include leading brands such as Festool, Triton, Kreg, Howard Products, Pro Tech, Tork Craft, Bessey, Felo, Alpen, MPS, Spring Tools, Mag Switch, Aircraft, Drill Doctor, Armor and the latest revolutionary circular saw from Saw Stop. All equipment and supplies at the show will be on offer at special low Show prices. For further information visit www.workingwithwood.co.za and www.awsa.org.za or call Fran Kirsten on 082 416 3398 or send an e-mail to fran@out-there.co.za . The show will be open from 09:00 to 18:00 daily at a cost of R20 per adult and R10 for children under 12. &apos;We bring you the latest Garden Route, Klein Karoo, Hessequa news&apos; 08:21 (GMT+2),  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://www.georgeherald.com/img/acltn20160822-083923-642_u0.jpg</main_image>
</document>
