<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Senator Kelly Ayotte Visits Milpower Source Facility to Discuss High-Tech Industries In Small New Hampshire Towns</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13627489.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Senator Kelly Ayotte Visits Milpower Source Facility to Discuss High-Tech Industries In Small New Hampshire Towns Share Article Senator Ayotte visits Milpower Source in Belmont, NH to discuss economic growth in small New Hampshire towns and learn more about how she can support the local workforce and new graduates with quality employment opportunities within the state. Belmont, NH (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Milpower Source, Inc. was pleased to host New Hampshire Senator Kelly Ayotte and members of her staff on Tuesday, August 16, 2016 at their facility in Belmont, NH. Senator Ayotte met with representatives from Milpower Source’s leadership team and spoke with three new employees to the company, all recent graduates from local schools and universities. Senator Ayotte was provided a facility tour by representatives from Milpower Source. Providing a comment while on the production floor, Senator Ayotte said, “I’ve been very impressed with Milpower Source in terms of its ability to produce parts for the military – V-22s, F-18s, and equipment for the Patriot Missile System.” Senator Ayotte went on to say, “As a member of the Senate Armed Services Committee, I know how important the business of supplying the military is.” Mr. Tomer Eshed, General Manager at Milpower Source added, “we’re proud to have roots in Belknap County, offering high technology jobs and stability in the area. It’s critical to establish the dialogue with our elected officials to partner in ways that can improve the economic growth in New Hampshire, and provide the local workforce and new graduates with quality employment opportunities in our state.” Milpower Source has engaged local and state technical schools, community colleges, and universities with the goal of supporting local graduates and providing an opportunity for prosperity in New Hampshire. About Milpower Source – Since 1984, Milpower Source has been a leading manufacturer of custom rugged power supplies, serving the military and aerospace markets. Milpower Source’s products are widely used in applications such as fighter aircraft, radar, and RF communications. Milpower Source is an AS9100 certified company. More at http://www.milpower.com 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.17</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13627489.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Senator Kelly Ayotte Visits Milpower Source Facility to Discuss High-Tech Industries In Small New Hampshire Towns Share Article Senator Ayotte visits Milpower Source in Belmont, NH to discuss economic growth in small New Hampshire towns and learn more about how she can support the local workforce and new graduates with quality employment opportunities within the state. Belmont, NH (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Milpower Source, Inc. was pleased to host New Hampshire Senator Kelly Ayotte and members of her staff on Tuesday, August 16, 2016 at their facility in Belmont, NH. Senator Ayotte met with representatives from Milpower Source’s leadership team and spoke with three new employees to the company, all recent graduates from local schools and universities. Senator Ayotte was provided a facility tour by representatives from Milpower Source. Providing a comment while on the production floor, Senator Ayotte said, “I’ve been very impressed with Milpower Source in terms of its ability to produce parts for the military – V-22s, F-18s, and equipment for the Patriot Missile System.” Senator Ayotte went on to say, “As a member of the Senate Armed Services Committee, I know how important the business of supplying the military is.” Mr. Tomer Eshed, General Manager at Milpower Source added, “we’re proud to have roots in Belknap County, offering high technology jobs and stability in the area. It’s critical to establish the dialogue with our elected officials to partner in ways that can improve the economic growth in New Hampshire, and provide the local workforce and new graduates with quality employment opportunities in our state.” Milpower Source has engaged local and state technical schools, community colleges, and universities with the goal of supporting local graduates and providing an opportunity for prosperity in New Hampshire. About Milpower Source – Since 1984, Milpower Source has been a leading manufacturer of custom rugged power supplies, serving the military and aerospace markets. Milpower Source’s products are widely used in applications such as fighter aircraft, radar, and RF communications. Milpower Source is an AS9100 certified company. More at http://www.milpower.com 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
