<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.tribuneindia.com/</forum>
<forum_title>The Tribune, Chandigarh, India : Latest news, India, Punjab, Chandigarh, Haryana, Himachal, Uttarakhand, J&amp;amp;K, sports, cricket </forum_title>
<discussion_title>Maya tars all with the same brush</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/maya-tars-all-with-the-same-brush/283554.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tribune News Service
Lucknow, August 21
Launching a frontal attack on the BJP, BSP chief Mayawati today alleged that the Narendra Modi-led government at the Centre was contemplating the abolition of reservation. Addressing a massive “Bahujan Hitai, Bahujan Sukhai” rally at Agra’s Kothi Meena Bazaar Maidan, Mayawati formally launched the BSP’s 2017 election campaign. Accusing the BJP of rising atrocities on Dalits and minorities, Mayawati said Modi’s words should match punitive action against the guilty if he wants to protect Dalits from mounting atrocities. (Follow The Tribune on Facebook ; and Twitter @thetribunechd ) To show how atrocities against Dalits were increasing on all fronts, she Quote: d some recent cases, including the circumstances leading to the suicide of Dalit student Rohith Vemula, thrashing of Dalits in Una and expelled BJP leader Daya Shankar Singh using abusive language against her. Accusing Modi of claiming power on the basis of false promises, Mayawati said his government had not only comprehensively failed on all fronts, but it was also now banking on communal polarisation to save its skin. Not sparing the RSS either, Mayawati said while the BJP’s policies had not been able to control prices and address poverty, the RSS was asking Hindus to produce more children. She also attacked the SP government on the law and order front, saying only the BSP could rescue the people from the prevailing “jungle raj”.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>6</post_num>
<post_id>post-6</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/maya-tars-all-with-the-same-brush/283554.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>2028</post_time>
<username>Amarinder Singh</username>
<post>
May be one good thing RSS is talking about is ,getting rid of reservation.Reservation is like a termite eating away the talent in India.we should get rid of reservation in jobs and entrance tests.Give free education to economically downtrodden irrespective of their cast but no free pass in jobs and entrance tests.
I had one IG police living close to my house .The guy is SC.His son passed entrance test exam with 1/3 rd marks compared to gen category student.Is this fair?
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://images.tribuneindia.com/cms/gall_content/2016/8/2016_8$largeimg22_Monday_2016_004554759.jpg</main_image>
</document>
