<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Hamas: Israeli &amp;apos;prisoners&amp;apos; be treated same as Palestinians in Israeli jails - Arab-Israeli Conflict - Jerusalem Post</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.jpost.com/Arab-Israeli-Conflict/Hamas-Israeli-prisoners-will-receive-the-same-treatment-as-our-prisoners-recieve-464699</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Hamas: Israeli &apos;prisoners&apos; be treated same as Palestinians in Israeli jails Arab-Israeli Conflict By YASSER OKBI/ MAARIV HASHAVUA \ 08/22/2016 10:50 Hamas: Israeli &apos;prisoners&apos; be treated same as Palestinians in Israeli jails Hamas: Israeli prisoners will receive the same treatment as our prisoners recieve Indictment reveals how Hamas pays the families of their operatives Hamas is currently thought to be holding the bodies of 2 IDF soldiers killed in 2014, along with 3 civilians who apparently suffer from mental health issues and crossed into Gaza. A student supporting Hamas holds a Palestinian flag in a rally in Ramallah, earlier this year. (photo credit:REUTERS) Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Israeli &quot;prisoners&quot; held by Hamas in Gaza will receive the same treatment that Palestinian prisoners receive in Israeli jails, warned Abu Obeida, a spokesman for Hamas&apos;s military wing, on Sunday. Hamas is currently holding the bodies of IDF Lt. Hadar Goldin and St.-Sgt. Oron Shaul, who were both killed in 2014&apos;s Operation Protective Edge. In addition to the two bodies, Hamas has three civilians, who are known to be alive. Avraham Mengistu, an Asheklon resident, who has been described as &quot;emotionally unstable,&quot; as well as Juma Ibrahim Abu Ranim, of the unrecognized Negev Beduin village of Hashim-Zina near Beersheba and Hisham al-Sayed from Hura. All three had crossed the border and according to their families suffer from mental health problems. During a military parade in Rafah, Obeida stated that the military siege over the last decade had not affected the preparations of the Izzadin Kassam, the military wing of Hamas. &quot;The enemy&apos;s policy strengthens the right of the battalions to hold weapons, until the liberation of the land and the people,&quot; Obeida said. &quot;If the enemy thinks that the quiet is a result of deterring opposition than he is mistaken. We warn the occupiers from all acts of stupidity and ventures against the Gaza strip.&quot; Obeida also addressed Hamas prisoners in Israeli jails. &quot;The treatment of the enemy towards prisoners though racist punishments prove their failure in morals, in security, politically, and militarily,&quot; he said. &quot;The enemy should know that their prisoners held here will receive the same treatment that our prisoners receive in their prisons. We caution them against continuing their policies against our prisoners&quot; Think others should know about this? Please share | Sign up for our newsletter Submit Please insert a valid email address By signing up to The Jpost mailing list, I hereby Accept the terms and conditions Tags 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.17</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.jpost.com/Arab-Israeli-Conflict/Hamas-Israeli-prisoners-will-receive-the-same-treatment-as-our-prisoners-recieve-464699</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Hamas: Israeli &apos;prisoners&apos; be treated same as Palestinians in Israeli jails Arab-Israeli Conflict By YASSER OKBI/ MAARIV HASHAVUA \ 08/22/2016 10:50 Hamas: Israeli &apos;prisoners&apos; be treated same as Palestinians in Israeli jails Hamas: Israeli prisoners will receive the same treatment as our prisoners recieve Indictment reveals how Hamas pays the families of their operatives Hamas is currently thought to be holding the bodies of 2 IDF soldiers killed in 2014, along with 3 civilians who apparently suffer from mental health issues and crossed into Gaza. A student supporting Hamas holds a Palestinian flag in a rally in Ramallah, earlier this year. (photo credit:REUTERS) Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Israeli &quot;prisoners&quot; held by Hamas in Gaza will receive the same treatment that Palestinian prisoners receive in Israeli jails, warned Abu Obeida, a spokesman for Hamas&apos;s military wing, on Sunday. Hamas is currently holding the bodies of IDF Lt. Hadar Goldin and St.-Sgt. Oron Shaul, who were both killed in 2014&apos;s Operation Protective Edge. In addition to the two bodies, Hamas has three civilians, who are known to be alive. Avraham Mengistu, an Asheklon resident, who has been described as &quot;emotionally unstable,&quot; as well as Juma Ibrahim Abu Ranim, of the unrecognized Negev Beduin village of Hashim-Zina near Beersheba and Hisham al-Sayed from Hura. All three had crossed the border and according to their families suffer from mental health problems. During a military parade in Rafah, Obeida stated that the military siege over the last decade had not affected the preparations of the Izzadin Kassam, the military wing of Hamas. &quot;The enemy&apos;s policy strengthens the right of the battalions to hold weapons, until the liberation of the land and the people,&quot; Obeida said. &quot;If the enemy thinks that the quiet is a result of deterring opposition than he is mistaken. We warn the occupiers from all acts of stupidity and ventures against the Gaza strip.&quot; Obeida also addressed Hamas prisoners in Israeli jails. &quot;The treatment of the enemy towards prisoners though racist punishments prove their failure in morals, in security, politically, and militarily,&quot; he said. &quot;The enemy should know that their prisoners held here will receive the same treatment that our prisoners receive in their prisons. We caution them against continuing their policies against our prisoners&quot; Think others should know about this? Please share | Sign up for our newsletter Submit Please insert a valid email address By signing up to The Jpost mailing list, I hereby Accept the terms and conditions Tags 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.jpost.com/HttpHandlers/ShowImage.ashx?ID=344266</main_image>
</document>
