<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.ghanaweb.com/feed/newsfeed.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Ghana News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Muslims will reward Mahama - Baba Jamal</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.ghanaweb.com/GhanaHomePage/NewsArchive/Muslims-will-reward-Mahama-Baba-Jamal-464202</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Print This President Mahama (Right) with Sheikh Dr. Osmanu Nuhu Sharubutu The non-stop flight from the Tamale Airport to Medina in Saudi Arabia on August 19 following the upgrade of the airport to international standards by President John Mahama will influence Muslims to vote for the National Democratic Congress (NDC) in this year’s presidential elections, Baba Jamal Konneh, Eastern Regional Communications Director or the NDC has said. His assertion dovetails into a similar comment Mr Mahama made when addressing supporters of the NDC at Kokompe near Takoradi last week as part of his campaign in the Western Region that the “NDC and the Zongo community have strong ties. And it starts from the days of former President Rawlings’ government. He realised there was little recognition for the Muslim religious calendar and introduced two holidays to commemorate Eid ul-Fitr and Eid ul-Adha.” He added: “…For the first time in history, the first batch of pilgrims will fly directly from Tamale to Jeddah. I will be in Tamale to commission that. It tells you about our commitment to help the Zongo community and the wellbeing of all Ghanaians.” In a short statement released on Sunday, 21 August, Mr Konneh said: “Muslims in Ghana will judge between the NDC and the NPP on 7 December as to which political party thinks about their welfare. “You don’t need to be a Muslim to love Islam. A Muslim who doesn&apos;t care about the welfare of his fellow Muslims is an enemy to the religion. “As a Muslim, I know the fears of the NPP. They are not happy Muslims are being treated nicely by the president and his government because even if 500 pilgrims decide to pray for the president every morning, afternoon, evening and night, they know Allah will obviously accept their prayers. These are their fears but they have no choice because the obvious will happen. John Mahama will win this elections one touch, Insha Allah.” Related Articles:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.ghanaweb.com/GhanaHomePage/NewsArchive/Muslims-will-reward-Mahama-Baba-Jamal-464202</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0658</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Print This President Mahama (Right) with Sheikh Dr. Osmanu Nuhu Sharubutu The non-stop flight from the Tamale Airport to Medina in Saudi Arabia on August 19 following the upgrade of the airport to international standards by President John Mahama will influence Muslims to vote for the National Democratic Congress (NDC) in this year’s presidential elections, Baba Jamal Konneh, Eastern Regional Communications Director or the NDC has said. His assertion dovetails into a similar comment Mr Mahama made when addressing supporters of the NDC at Kokompe near Takoradi last week as part of his campaign in the Western Region that the “NDC and the Zongo community have strong ties. And it starts from the days of former President Rawlings’ government. He realised there was little recognition for the Muslim religious calendar and introduced two holidays to commemorate Eid ul-Fitr and Eid ul-Adha.” He added: “…For the first time in history, the first batch of pilgrims will fly directly from Tamale to Jeddah. I will be in Tamale to commission that. It tells you about our commitment to help the Zongo community and the wellbeing of all Ghanaians.” In a short statement released on Sunday, 21 August, Mr Konneh said: “Muslims in Ghana will judge between the NDC and the NPP on 7 December as to which political party thinks about their welfare. “You don’t need to be a Muslim to love Islam. A Muslim who doesn&apos;t care about the welfare of his fellow Muslims is an enemy to the religion. “As a Muslim, I know the fears of the NPP. They are not happy Muslims are being treated nicely by the president and his government because even if 500 pilgrims decide to pray for the president every morning, afternoon, evening and night, they know Allah will obviously accept their prayers. These are their fears but they have no choice because the obvious will happen. John Mahama will win this elections one touch, Insha Allah.” Related Articles:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://cdn.ghanaweb.com/imagelib/pics/22168156.jpg</main_image>
</document>
