<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/category/commodities/commodity-news/page/657/</forum>
<forum_title>Commodity News | Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide - Part 657</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Chinese steel and iron ore futures came off session highs on</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-steel-iron-ore-futures-off-highs-after-housing-data/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Chinese steel and iron ore futures came off session highs on Wednesday after data showed Chinese new home prices fell for the first time in two years, reflecting continued pressure on the housing market that may dent demand for steel.
Prices for spot iron ore cargoes edged higher after the benchmark rate slid to a 21-month low earlier in the week, although traders said a prolonged supply glut would clip further gains.
Rebar for October delivery on the Shanghai Futures Exchange closed unchanged at 3,009 yuan ($480) a tonne after peaking at 3,027 yuan earlier.
Average new home prices in 70 major cities in China dropped 0.2 percent in May from the previous month, government data showed, underlining a downtrend taking hold in the market as the world’s No. 2 economy slows.
“The real estate market is seeing a tough period this year and so is steel. But I don’t think the government will allow a big drop in housing prices, they will not want to see a crash,” said Zhou Ting, analyst at Jinrui Futures in Shenzhen.
Shanghai rebar futures have fallen by more than 18 percent this year on slower steel demand as traders run down stocks while inventory at mills rises.
Stockpiles of steel products among Chinese traders dropped to 13.65 million tonnes last week from 13.91 million tonnes the week before, according to data from industry consultancy Mysteel, falling for a 15th week in a row.
In contrast, steel inventory among China’s mills climbed to 14.52 million tonnes as of June 10 from 13.85 million tonnes at the end of May.
Steel production in China, the world’s biggest producer, remained strong, with crude steel output at its large steel mills averaging 1.833 million tonnes in the first 10 days of June, a record pace, consultancy Custeel.com said, citing data from the China Iron and Steel Association.
Iron ore for delivery in September on the Dalian Commodity Exchange closed up 0.3 percent at 665 yuan a tonne, off the session’s high of 672 yuan.
A cargo of 62-percent grade Australian iron ore fines traded at $91 per tonne via the globalORE platform on Wednesday, up from deals of $89 and $90 on Tuesday, traders said.
The price of the benchmark 62-percent iron ore edged up to $89.30 a tonne on Tuesday, from $89 the previous day which was its weakest since September 2012, based on data compiled by Steel Index.
“Personally I’m not convinced of the price increase. Port stock prices are going down. I think there are too many bearish factors at the moment to have any real rally,” said a broker in Singapore.
Iron ore prices have fallen by more than a third this year as supply outpaced demand. Stocks of imported iron ore at Chinese ports stood at 113 million tonnes last week SH-TOT-IRONINV not far from a record-high of 113.6 million tonnes reached at the end of May, according to data from Steelhome.
China’s crackdown on commodity financing along with an ongoing probe in Qingdao port into the fraudulent use of commodities as loan collateral may curb the use of iron ore for financing and push more of the raw material into the market, Commonwealth Bank of Australia said in a note.
“Taking all of this into account, the iron ore market looks biased towards oversupply in the very near term,” the bank said.
Source: Reuters (Reporting by Manolo Serapio Jr.; Editing by Joseph Radford)
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.18</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-steel-iron-ore-futures-off-highs-after-housing-data/</post_url>
<post_date>20140619</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>hellenicshippingnews</username>
<post>
Chinese steel and iron ore futures came off session highs on Wednesday after data showed Chinese new home prices fell for the first time in two years, reflecting continued pressure on the housing market that may dent demand for steel.
Prices for spot iron ore cargoes edged higher after the benchmark rate slid to a 21-month low earlier in the week, although traders said a prolonged supply glut would clip further gains.
Rebar for October delivery on the Shanghai Futures Exchange closed unchanged at 3,009 yuan ($480) a tonne after peaking at 3,027 yuan earlier.
Average new home prices in 70 major cities in China dropped 0.2 percent in May from the previous month, government data showed, underlining a downtrend taking hold in the market as the world’s No. 2 economy slows.
“The real estate market is seeing a tough period this year and so is steel. But I don’t think the government will allow a big drop in housing prices, they will not want to see a crash,” said Zhou Ting, analyst at Jinrui Futures in Shenzhen.
Shanghai rebar futures have fallen by more than 18 percent this year on slower steel demand as traders run down stocks while inventory at mills rises.
Stockpiles of steel products among Chinese traders dropped to 13.65 million tonnes last week from 13.91 million tonnes the week before, according to data from industry consultancy Mysteel, falling for a 15th week in a row.
In contrast, steel inventory among China’s mills climbed to 14.52 million tonnes as of June 10 from 13.85 million tonnes at the end of May.
Steel production in China, the world’s biggest producer, remained strong, with crude steel output at its large steel mills averaging 1.833 million tonnes in the first 10 days of June, a record pace, consultancy Custeel.com said, citing data from the China Iron and Steel Association.
Iron ore for delivery in September on the Dalian Commodity Exchange closed up 0.3 percent at 665 yuan a tonne, off the session’s high of 672 yuan.
A cargo of 62-percent grade Australian iron ore fines traded at $91 per tonne via the globalORE platform on Wednesday, up from deals of $89 and $90 on Tuesday, traders said.
The price of the benchmark 62-percent iron ore edged up to $89.30 a tonne on Tuesday, from $89 the previous day which was its weakest since September 2012, based on data compiled by Steel Index.
“Personally I’m not convinced of the price increase. Port stock prices are going down. I think there are too many bearish factors at the moment to have any real rally,” said a broker in Singapore.
Iron ore prices have fallen by more than a third this year as supply outpaced demand. Stocks of imported iron ore at Chinese ports stood at 113 million tonnes last week SH-TOT-IRONINV not far from a record-high of 113.6 million tonnes reached at the end of May, according to data from Steelhome.
China’s crackdown on commodity financing along with an ongoing probe in Qingdao port into the fraudulent use of commodities as loan collateral may curb the use of iron ore for financing and push more of the raw material into the market, Commonwealth Bank of Australia said in a note.
“Taking all of this into account, the iron ore market looks biased towards oversupply in the very near term,” the bank said.
Source: Reuters (Reporting by Manolo Serapio Jr.; Editing by Joseph Radford)
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
