<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Cablefax Announces 2016 Program Award Winners</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13628053.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cablefax Announces 2016 Program Award Winners Share Article Congratulatory Breakfast to Celebrate Winners and Honorable Mentions in the Industry&apos;s Most Dynamic Areas Set for Sept. 22, 2016, Atop New York City Penthouse Venue The 2016 Cablefax Program Awards Rockville, MD (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Cablefax has announced the winners of the 2016 Cablefax Program Awards, which celebrate the best content on myriad screens. With thousands of scripted and non-scripted programs available across multiple platforms, Cablefax took on the tough task of judging hundreds of entries to determine the select few shows, series and people deserving of praise and recognition for excellence. View the 2016 Program Awards Hall of Fame, Winners Each year, a select group of shows and actors are hand-picked from hundreds of nominations in Cablefax’s quest to find the programming stand-outs. This is the first year Cablefax has released the winners prior to the Awards Breakfast. “It’s unprecedented for us to announce all the winners in advance, but we’re convinced it’s the best way to give our honorees the recognition they deserve at our September 22 awards breakfast in New York City,” said Cablefax Publisher Michael Grebb. The 2016 Winners Include: Best Actor: Cuba Gooding Jr., The People vs. O.J. Simpson, FX Networks Best Ensemble Cast: The Wiz Live!, NBC Entertainment Best Program: Game of Thrones, HBO Best Host - Family Friendly: Jill Wagner, Handcrafted America, INSP Best Branded Content: Dodge Real Fittest Athlete, Outside Television View all 2016 Winners “We’re encouraging those both behind and in front of the cameras to join us for a true celebration of excellence. Bring your teams. Bring your family. Bring the excitement! It will be a memorable morning featuring sweeping views of the city and even more sweeping inspiration from the best programmers in the business,” Grebb added. Cablefax is also honoring four Program Hall of Fame Inductees: Jennifer Caserta, IFC Courteney Monroe, National Geographic Global Networks Evan Shapiro, NBCUniversal Read Hall of Fame Bios Winners and Honorable Mentions will be recognized and celebrated on Thursday, September 22, 2016 at the 230 Fifth Venue in New York City from 8:00 a.m. – 10 a.m. To register for the event, please visit http://www.CablefaxProgramAwards.com . Individual tickets and tables are available for purchase. Table purchases come with priority seating and ensure attendees are seated together. For questions about Cablefax’s Program Awards or for assistance registering, contact Mary-Lou French at mfrench(at)accessintel(dot)com. For sponsorship opportunities or information about congratulatory ads in the special Program Awards magazine, contact Rich Hauptner at rhauptner(at)accessintel(dot)com. About Cablefax: Cablefax is the most trusted brand in the industry, providing cable executives with the most original, comprehensive and insightful overview of the latest industry news and strategic initiatives. Cablefax offerings include a wide range of resources for cable professionals, including Cablefax Daily, Cablefax: The Magazine, award programs, webinars, and networking events. For more information, visit http://www.Cablefax.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.21</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13628053.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Cablefax Announces 2016 Program Award Winners Share Article Congratulatory Breakfast to Celebrate Winners and Honorable Mentions in the Industry&apos;s Most Dynamic Areas Set for Sept. 22, 2016, Atop New York City Penthouse Venue The 2016 Cablefax Program Awards Rockville, MD (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Cablefax has announced the winners of the 2016 Cablefax Program Awards, which celebrate the best content on myriad screens. With thousands of scripted and non-scripted programs available across multiple platforms, Cablefax took on the tough task of judging hundreds of entries to determine the select few shows, series and people deserving of praise and recognition for excellence. View the 2016 Program Awards Hall of Fame, Winners Each year, a select group of shows and actors are hand-picked from hundreds of nominations in Cablefax’s quest to find the programming stand-outs. This is the first year Cablefax has released the winners prior to the Awards Breakfast. “It’s unprecedented for us to announce all the winners in advance, but we’re convinced it’s the best way to give our honorees the recognition they deserve at our September 22 awards breakfast in New York City,” said Cablefax Publisher Michael Grebb. The 2016 Winners Include: Best Actor: Cuba Gooding Jr., The People vs. O.J. Simpson, FX Networks Best Ensemble Cast: The Wiz Live!, NBC Entertainment Best Program: Game of Thrones, HBO Best Host - Family Friendly: Jill Wagner, Handcrafted America, INSP Best Branded Content: Dodge Real Fittest Athlete, Outside Television View all 2016 Winners “We’re encouraging those both behind and in front of the cameras to join us for a true celebration of excellence. Bring your teams. Bring your family. Bring the excitement! It will be a memorable morning featuring sweeping views of the city and even more sweeping inspiration from the best programmers in the business,” Grebb added. Cablefax is also honoring four Program Hall of Fame Inductees: Jennifer Caserta, IFC Courteney Monroe, National Geographic Global Networks Evan Shapiro, NBCUniversal Read Hall of Fame Bios Winners and Honorable Mentions will be recognized and celebrated on Thursday, September 22, 2016 at the 230 Fifth Venue in New York City from 8:00 a.m. – 10 a.m. To register for the event, please visit http://www.CablefaxProgramAwards.com . Individual tickets and tables are available for purchase. Table purchases come with priority seating and ensure attendees are seated together. For questions about Cablefax’s Program Awards or for assistance registering, contact Mary-Lou French at mfrench(at)accessintel(dot)com. For sponsorship opportunities or information about congratulatory ads in the special Program Awards magazine, contact Rich Hauptner at rhauptner(at)accessintel(dot)com. About Cablefax: Cablefax is the most trusted brand in the industry, providing cable executives with the most original, comprehensive and insightful overview of the latest industry news and strategic initiatives. Cablefax offerings include a wide range of resources for cable professionals, including Cablefax Daily, Cablefax: The Magazine, award programs, webinars, and networking events. For more information, visit http://www.Cablefax.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/08/19/13628053/Cablefax-Program-Awards-Logo-2016.png</main_image>
</document>
