<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.pr.com/rss/press-releases.xml</forum>
<forum_title>PR.com Press Releases</forum_title>
<discussion_title>The Sweet Living Group (SLG) Announces Extensive Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Patent Portfolio and Trademarks Available for Licensing in Laundry Detergent Industry</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.pr.com/press-release/684252</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Receive press releases from The Sweet Living Group: By Email RSS Feeds: The Sweet Living Group (SLG) Announces Extensive Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Patent Portfolio and Trademarks Available for Licensing in Laundry Detergent Industry The Sweet Living Group&apos;s ZnO technology is set to make an immediate impact within the Laundry Detergent [Consumer Goods] and Textile Industries. St. Louis, MO,   The Sweet Living Group (SLG) Announces Extensive Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Patent Portfolio and Trademarks Available for Licensing in Laundry Detergent IndustryThe Sweet Living Group, LLC (SLG), a leader in zinc oxide (ZnO) and nanoparticle zinc oxide (Nano-ZnO) for the textile and laundry detergent industries, announces the availability of the licensing of its innovative textile technology. The company’s patented ZnO and Nano-ZnO technology is beneficial to fabrics and textiles by: incorporating ultraviolet (UV) protection, controlling odor, enhancing anti-microbial/mold and mildew-resistance, increasing resistance to degradation, and enhancing flame retardant properties. The protections and enhancements are incorporated into existing clothing by various laundry detergents and additives. SLG has seven issued U.S. patents, two pending patent applications, and two trademarks available for licensing.The scope of coverage allows the patents to be applied in both the textile and laundry detergent industries including industrial and commercial applications. The licensing program is administered for SLG by Cerinet IP Licensing Company, which is one of the world&apos;s most experienced IP licensing companies.SLG was recently granted its seventh U.S. patent that allows for ZnO or Nano-ZnO to be incorporated into laundry detergents and laundry detergent pods. This technology adds to textile UV protection, enhances resistance to color degradation, and increases fiber strength. It also allows for anti-microbial/mold and mildew-resistance, which improves odor control.A portion of SLG’s patents focus on the use of ZnO and Nano-ZnO within the fabrics at the manufacturing phase. SLG&apos;s patents also incorporate the benefits of ZnO and Nano-ZnO in both natural and synthetic materials and fabrics.“Our Nano-ZnO technology was initially developed for application at the fiber or fabric stage of production. These manufactured textiles were enhanced to protect the skin from the sun’s ultraviolet rays, which can cause skin cancer,” said Jason Rosenberg, MD, a Dermatologist and SLG Partner/Director of Advance Technology. “Now the benefits of our patented zinc oxide technology can be used by the consumer, at home, in their laundry detergent.”“The Sweet Living Groups’s IP portfolio is extremely attractive to a wide variety of global companies directly engaged in the manufacturing of textiles and fabrics,” said John Ciannamea, Managing Director of Cerinet IP. “SLG&apos;s IP portfolio is also very significant to the laundry detergent industries. The patents wide ranging coverage allows for a large market potential in the United States for companies around the globe, as well as to the various third party companies that provide other value added products to their clients.”About SLG:The Sweet Living Group, founded in 2010, is a privately held company that specializes in the development of zinc oxide nanotechnology for increased textile performance in both the textile and laundry detergent industries.About Cerinet IP Licensing Company:Cerinet IP Licensing is a leading intellectual property licensing company. Cerinet provides intellectual property sales and licensing services to companies of all sizes in the public and private markets and across most industries. All clients benefit from senior-level attention from partners with a wide range of industry expertise. For more information, visit www.cerinet.com or contact:Inquires:John Ciannamea, Managing Director, Cerinet IP LicensingPhone: 919.345.4947
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.pr.com/press-release/684252</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0700</post_time>
<username>The Sweet Living Group</username>
<post>
Receive press releases from The Sweet Living Group: By Email RSS Feeds: The Sweet Living Group (SLG) Announces Extensive Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Patent Portfolio and Trademarks Available for Licensing in Laundry Detergent Industry The Sweet Living Group&apos;s ZnO technology is set to make an immediate impact within the Laundry Detergent [Consumer Goods] and Textile Industries. St. Louis, MO,   The Sweet Living Group (SLG) Announces Extensive Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Patent Portfolio and Trademarks Available for Licensing in Laundry Detergent IndustryThe Sweet Living Group, LLC (SLG), a leader in zinc oxide (ZnO) and nanoparticle zinc oxide (Nano-ZnO) for the textile and laundry detergent industries, announces the availability of the licensing of its innovative textile technology. The company’s patented ZnO and Nano-ZnO technology is beneficial to fabrics and textiles by: incorporating ultraviolet (UV) protection, controlling odor, enhancing anti-microbial/mold and mildew-resistance, increasing resistance to degradation, and enhancing flame retardant properties. The protections and enhancements are incorporated into existing clothing by various laundry detergents and additives. SLG has seven issued U.S. patents, two pending patent applications, and two trademarks available for licensing.The scope of coverage allows the patents to be applied in both the textile and laundry detergent industries including industrial and commercial applications. The licensing program is administered for SLG by Cerinet IP Licensing Company, which is one of the world&apos;s most experienced IP licensing companies.SLG was recently granted its seventh U.S. patent that allows for ZnO or Nano-ZnO to be incorporated into laundry detergents and laundry detergent pods. This technology adds to textile UV protection, enhances resistance to color degradation, and increases fiber strength. It also allows for anti-microbial/mold and mildew-resistance, which improves odor control.A portion of SLG’s patents focus on the use of ZnO and Nano-ZnO within the fabrics at the manufacturing phase. SLG&apos;s patents also incorporate the benefits of ZnO and Nano-ZnO in both natural and synthetic materials and fabrics.“Our Nano-ZnO technology was initially developed for application at the fiber or fabric stage of production. These manufactured textiles were enhanced to protect the skin from the sun’s ultraviolet rays, which can cause skin cancer,” said Jason Rosenberg, MD, a Dermatologist and SLG Partner/Director of Advance Technology. “Now the benefits of our patented zinc oxide technology can be used by the consumer, at home, in their laundry detergent.”“The Sweet Living Groups’s IP portfolio is extremely attractive to a wide variety of global companies directly engaged in the manufacturing of textiles and fabrics,” said John Ciannamea, Managing Director of Cerinet IP. “SLG&apos;s IP portfolio is also very significant to the laundry detergent industries. The patents wide ranging coverage allows for a large market potential in the United States for companies around the globe, as well as to the various third party companies that provide other value added products to their clients.”About SLG:The Sweet Living Group, founded in 2010, is a privately held company that specializes in the development of zinc oxide nanotechnology for increased textile performance in both the textile and laundry detergent industries.About Cerinet IP Licensing Company:Cerinet IP Licensing is a leading intellectual property licensing company. Cerinet provides intellectual property sales and licensing services to companies of all sizes in the public and private markets and across most industries. All clients benefit from senior-level attention from partners with a wide range of industry expertise. For more information, visit www.cerinet.com or contact:Inquires:John Ciannamea, Managing Director, Cerinet IP LicensingPhone: 919.345.4947
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
