<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Dialogue Key to Resolving Nigeria&apos;s Security Challenges - Abubakar</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220186.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By ? Former Head of State Gen. Abdulsalami Abubakar has called for dialogue in resolving the various security challenges currently confronting the country through various militant groups agitations in the country. Abubakar made the call while speaking with newsmen in Nnewi, Anambra on Saturday. He said there was no need for national security threats to arise from Boko Haram, Niger Delta Avengers and Biafra agitators currently threatening the peace of the country. &quot;All I can say is that there is no need for the insecurity in Nigeria. &quot;I am appealing to all Nigerians irrespective of what their grievances are to come to a roundtable and try to see how we can resolve these issues. &quot;We have amicable ways of settling these issues because there must be peace before we can progress as a country,&quot; he said. Abubakar admitted that the economy was passing through difficult time and urged Nigerians to be patient while expressing hope in the ability of the Federal Government to fix it. The former Nigerian leader urged the private sector to complement the efforts of the government to revamp the economy just as some industrialists were doing in Nnewi. &quot;Unfortunately, Nigeria is not an island; all over the world, there is economic recession and that is what is affecting us. &quot;Let us all join hands to save this economy; the private sector must come in to help us to resuscitate the economy just as Nnewi has shown,&quot; he said. (NAN) Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220186.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0746</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By ? Former Head of State Gen. Abdulsalami Abubakar has called for dialogue in resolving the various security challenges currently confronting the country through various militant groups agitations in the country. Abubakar made the call while speaking with newsmen in Nnewi, Anambra on Saturday. He said there was no need for national security threats to arise from Boko Haram, Niger Delta Avengers and Biafra agitators currently threatening the peace of the country. &quot;All I can say is that there is no need for the insecurity in Nigeria. &quot;I am appealing to all Nigerians irrespective of what their grievances are to come to a roundtable and try to see how we can resolve these issues. &quot;We have amicable ways of settling these issues because there must be peace before we can progress as a country,&quot; he said. Abubakar admitted that the economy was passing through difficult time and urged Nigerians to be patient while expressing hope in the ability of the Federal Government to fix it. The former Nigerian leader urged the private sector to complement the efforts of the government to revamp the economy just as some industrialists were doing in Nnewi. &quot;Unfortunately, Nigeria is not an island; all over the world, there is economic recession and that is what is affecting us. &quot;Let us all join hands to save this economy; the private sector must come in to help us to resuscitate the economy just as Nnewi has shown,&quot; he said. (NAN) Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
