<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Onward Behavioral Health (OBH) Opens Sixteenth Facility in Pennsylvania</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13623223.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Onward Behavioral Health (OBH) Opens Sixteenth Facility in Pennsylvania Share Article Onward Behavioral Health (OBH) has opened its sixteenth facility in Pennsylvania and is now accepting clients at its newest location in Bethlehem. Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 The office will offer a variety of outpatient and intensive outpatient services for adults, teens, and children through OBH subsidiaries Rehab After Work, The Light Program, Seeds of Hope, and Life Counseling Services. Rehab After Work will serve the Lehigh Valley with outpatient addiction counseling for adults and offer an adult DUI group. The Light Program will treat both adults and adolescents at the office. Its available mental health services include counseling, therapy, and specialty programming, such as an Addictions Awareness program. Specialized eating disorder treatment is also available at this location through Seeds of Hope, an intensive outpatient program for those struggling with anorexia, bulimia, or binge eating disorder. Life Counseling Services will offer professional counseling and psychiatric services for children, adults, and teens. Onward Behavioral Health’s Bethlehem office is located at 3400 Bath Pike, Suite 208 in Bethlehem. Referrals for all lines of service are currently being accepted. For more information, individuals can call (610) 644-6464. Rehab After Work, The Light Program, Seeds of Hope, and Life Counseling Services are part of the Pyramid Healthcare treatment partner network. This network provides expert-level addiction and mental health treatment to a wide population of people in need throughout Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and North Carolina. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.22</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13623223.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Onward Behavioral Health (OBH) Opens Sixteenth Facility in Pennsylvania Share Article Onward Behavioral Health (OBH) has opened its sixteenth facility in Pennsylvania and is now accepting clients at its newest location in Bethlehem. Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 The office will offer a variety of outpatient and intensive outpatient services for adults, teens, and children through OBH subsidiaries Rehab After Work, The Light Program, Seeds of Hope, and Life Counseling Services. Rehab After Work will serve the Lehigh Valley with outpatient addiction counseling for adults and offer an adult DUI group. The Light Program will treat both adults and adolescents at the office. Its available mental health services include counseling, therapy, and specialty programming, such as an Addictions Awareness program. Specialized eating disorder treatment is also available at this location through Seeds of Hope, an intensive outpatient program for those struggling with anorexia, bulimia, or binge eating disorder. Life Counseling Services will offer professional counseling and psychiatric services for children, adults, and teens. Onward Behavioral Health’s Bethlehem office is located at 3400 Bath Pike, Suite 208 in Bethlehem. Referrals for all lines of service are currently being accepted. For more information, individuals can call (610) 644-6464. Rehab After Work, The Light Program, Seeds of Hope, and Life Counseling Services are part of the Pyramid Healthcare treatment partner network. This network provides expert-level addiction and mental health treatment to a wide population of people in need throughout Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and North Carolina. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
