<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>First pic of mother-of-three found dead at Middlesbrough home as cops launch murder probe</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/1651352/first-pic-of-mother-of-three-found-dead-at-middlesborough-home-as-cops-launch-murder-probe/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
TRAGIC MUM PICTURED First pic of mother-of-three found dead at Middlesbrough home as cops launch murder probe 
Pensioner 73, has been arrested in connection with the death and remains in police custody Pictured by tom gillespie and emma lake 22nd August 2016, 8:16 am Shares Comments THE first pictures of a mother found dead in the home she shared with her three children have emerged. 
A murder investigation has been launched after the body of 42-year-old Deborah Wilkinson, was found on Friday evening. Facebook A 42-year-old woman, reported to be Deborah Wilkinson, was found dead in her home on Friday Facebook 7 A family member said Ms Wilkinson lived for ‘her flowers, her hair and her children’ 
The self-employed hairdresser died of a head injury and police have said an elderly man has been arrested. 
Officers were called to a home in Farthingale Way, Hemlington, Middlesbrough, at about 7pm on Friday, after they received reports that a woman was unresponsive. 
Cleveland Police said they were treating the death as “unexplained”. 
A spokesman said: “A 73-year-old man has been arrested in connection with the death and remains in custody.” RELATED STORIES DRUNKEN LIES Teary Ryan Lochte admits he was drunk when he &apos;over-exaggerated&apos; account of Rio petrol station robbery RIO&apos;S GRANDEE Team GB&apos;s Mark England hails Olympic heroes as we close in on our biggest medal haul for 108 years Quad goals Mo Farah admits he won his fourth Olympic gold medal by resting up in his room and doing NOTHING WINDSURFER DEATH Man dies after lifeboat rescue off the coast of Essex as Met Office warns of &quot;high winds&quot; KORMA WILL GET YOU Woman fooled into comical row with Wetherspoons parody Twitter account over &apos;too spicy&apos; korma 
A police cordon was put in place in the quiet cul-de-sac as forensics teams worked at the scene. 
Flowers and a card have been seen placed outside the house. 
Ms Wilkinson moved into the house at the time of the birth of her first child, a neighbour told the Mirror . 
A member of Ms Wilkinson’s family told the Mirror: “All we know is a friend of hers was arrested. He had gone to see her 24 hours before she was found unresponsive. 
“We are still in the dark about what happened. All we can say is she lived for three things – her flowers, her hair and her children. 
“The children are staying with family and are fine.” Evening Gazette Police forensic teams investigated at the property through the weekend Facebook Police have confirmed that Ms Wilkinson’s death is being treated as suspicious Evening Gazette Cards and flowers paying tribute to the victim have since been placed outside the house in a residential street Evening Gazette 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.22</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/1651352/first-pic-of-mother-of-three-found-dead-at-middlesborough-home-as-cops-launch-murder-probe/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
TRAGIC MUM PICTURED First pic of mother-of-three found dead at Middlesbrough home as cops launch murder probe 
Pensioner 73, has been arrested in connection with the death and remains in police custody Pictured by tom gillespie and emma lake 22nd August 2016, 8:16 am Shares Comments THE first pictures of a mother found dead in the home she shared with her three children have emerged. 
A murder investigation has been launched after the body of 42-year-old Deborah Wilkinson, was found on Friday evening. Facebook A 42-year-old woman, reported to be Deborah Wilkinson, was found dead in her home on Friday Facebook 7 A family member said Ms Wilkinson lived for ‘her flowers, her hair and her children’ 
The self-employed hairdresser died of a head injury and police have said an elderly man has been arrested. 
Officers were called to a home in Farthingale Way, Hemlington, Middlesbrough, at about 7pm on Friday, after they received reports that a woman was unresponsive. 
Cleveland Police said they were treating the death as “unexplained”. 
A spokesman said: “A 73-year-old man has been arrested in connection with the death and remains in custody.” RELATED STORIES DRUNKEN LIES Teary Ryan Lochte admits he was drunk when he &apos;over-exaggerated&apos; account of Rio petrol station robbery RIO&apos;S GRANDEE Team GB&apos;s Mark England hails Olympic heroes as we close in on our biggest medal haul for 108 years Quad goals Mo Farah admits he won his fourth Olympic gold medal by resting up in his room and doing NOTHING WINDSURFER DEATH Man dies after lifeboat rescue off the coast of Essex as Met Office warns of &quot;high winds&quot; KORMA WILL GET YOU Woman fooled into comical row with Wetherspoons parody Twitter account over &apos;too spicy&apos; korma 
A police cordon was put in place in the quiet cul-de-sac as forensics teams worked at the scene. 
Flowers and a card have been seen placed outside the house. 
Ms Wilkinson moved into the house at the time of the birth of her first child, a neighbour told the Mirror . 
A member of Ms Wilkinson’s family told the Mirror: “All we know is a friend of hers was arrested. He had gone to see her 24 hours before she was found unresponsive. 
“We are still in the dark about what happened. All we can say is she lived for three things – her flowers, her hair and her children. 
“The children are staying with family and are fine.” Evening Gazette Police forensic teams investigated at the property through the weekend Facebook Police have confirmed that Ms Wilkinson’s death is being treated as suspicious Evening Gazette Cards and flowers paying tribute to the victim have since been placed outside the house in a residential street Evening Gazette 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>https://www.thesun.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/nintchdbpict000261188308.jpg</main_image>
</document>
