<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Olympic Eagles Wipe Shame Off Nigerians Faces</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220182.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cameroon: Deadly Suicide Attack Hits Market The Olympic Eagles finally gave the country a little pride as they won for Nigeria her only medal at the Rio Olympics when they defeated hard-fighting Honduras 3-2 to clinch the bronze medal. Umar Sadiq opened scoring for the Samson Siasia-tutored boys when he slotted home a through pass from team captain John Mikel Obi in the 34th minute. Aminu Umar again added the second four minutes into the second half before Sadiq again took his tally in the game to two with the third goal. As is typical of Nigerian teams, the boys went to sleep, believing victory was already sealed, an action that gave the Central Americans strength to cruise unstoppably from then on.. And it almost paid off for them as Antony Lazano and Marcelo Pereira reduced the tally with their goals in the 71st and 86th minutes respectively. At this point the Nigerians who were obviously exhausted started stumbling and moving back, leaving captain Obi upfront to harass the Honduran goalkeeper. Honduras continued to make dangerous incursions but the U-23 team kept warding them off until the Brazilian referee, Sandro Ricci sounded the final whistle. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220182.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0745</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Cameroon: Deadly Suicide Attack Hits Market The Olympic Eagles finally gave the country a little pride as they won for Nigeria her only medal at the Rio Olympics when they defeated hard-fighting Honduras 3-2 to clinch the bronze medal. Umar Sadiq opened scoring for the Samson Siasia-tutored boys when he slotted home a through pass from team captain John Mikel Obi in the 34th minute. Aminu Umar again added the second four minutes into the second half before Sadiq again took his tally in the game to two with the third goal. As is typical of Nigerian teams, the boys went to sleep, believing victory was already sealed, an action that gave the Central Americans strength to cruise unstoppably from then on.. And it almost paid off for them as Antony Lazano and Marcelo Pereira reduced the tally with their goals in the 71st and 86th minutes respectively. At this point the Nigerians who were obviously exhausted started stumbling and moving back, leaving captain Obi upfront to harass the Honduran goalkeeper. Honduras continued to make dangerous incursions but the U-23 team kept warding them off until the Brazilian referee, Sandro Ricci sounded the final whistle. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
