<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.usatoday.com/olympics-rio-2016/</forum>
<forum_title>Rio 2016 Summer Olympics | USA TODAY NETWORK</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Brennan: Performances, not problems, win out in Rio</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/columnist/brennan/2016/08/21/rio-olympics-closing-ceremony/89087424/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Skip Ad Ad Loading... x Embed
x Share
USA Today Sports&apos; Martin Rogers says farewell to the Rio Games USA TODAY Sports
Lenine performs during the closing ceremony for the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Maracana. (Photo: Christopher Hanewinckel-USA TODA)
RIO DE JANEIRO — On a dark and stormy night, a surprising success story wrote its final chapter. The much-maligned 2016 Rio Olympic Games closed with color, song — and a huge sigh of relief.
It’s the sports upset we didn’t see coming. Rio pulled it off. Who thought we’d be able to say that? Never before had we seen a city with such a laundry list of problems going into an Olympics: Zika, water pollution, street crime, economic recession, political upheaval and infrastructure worries.
So, what happened? There was mysterious green water in the diving well and water polo pool and a media bus was attacked by rocks (or was it gunshots?), but Rio was anything but a sporting disaster.
Perhaps we all just “overexaggerated” the problems. Ryan Lochte’s new word turns out to be a useful catch-all. The 32-year-old American swimmer did his best to commandeer these Games in their second week with his drunken boorishness and arrogant lies, but these Games were too resilient and bounced back with a grand finale of a weekend.
USA TODAY
16 memorable moments of Rio Olympics
Five hours before the closing ceremony Sunday, in a small, leafy square 10 miles from the Olympic Park, fireworks suddenly exploded. Cheers from a few open windows filled the afternoon air. Then came shouts from a restaurant and a coffee shop. A few taxis honked their horns.
What had just happened? The Olympics would end in a few hours, but before they did, the Brazil men’s volleyball team swept Italy to win the gold medal. A day earlier, the men’s soccer team won its first Olympic gold medal, on penalty kicks, beating Germany.
Happiness on top of happiness. Who says these Games weren’t a success? Not that tiny seaside corner of Rio.
It was reminiscent of how the 2010 Vancouver Winter Olympics ended, with the Canadian men’s ice hockey team defeating the USA for the gold medal. Losing that game would have ruined those Olympics for millions of Canadians. And so it was with Brazil’s final flurry of gold as well.
But the conversation with Rio was always going to be about so much more than sports. Everywhere athletes went, they knew they would not be talking simply about what they came here to do.
“Every Olympics has its own set of issues,” said Meghan Musnicki, a member of the U.S. gold medal-winning eight rowing team, which competed in the most-discussed water on the planet.
“Everywhere you go, to every big event, they’re going to create or talk about the issues that are being presented. Very clearly, it didn’t affect what we did. So that’s kind of the moral of the story. Yeah, you’re going to deal with issues. As far as what we were focusing on and what we were thinking about, the water quality and Zika and whatever was really in the back of our mind. We were being cautious and taking precautions and here we are with our Olympic medal, so I think it worked out OK for us.”
Her teammate, Emily Regan, when asked what she thought of how things were going in Rio, shouted out a grade.
“A-plus!”
Didn’t expect to hear that from the rowers, did we?
These Games will be remembered mostly for the conversations they fostered: the ethics of allowing athletes from Russia’s doping machine to compete here, and the boos that accompanied them; the inclusion of a refugee team; the behavior of young athletes in foreign lands, on and off the field of play.
Oh, and Bolt, Phelps, Biles, Ledecky and U.S. women’s teams.
“Obviously there were a few challenges along the way,” said Larry Probst, chairman of the U.S. Olympic Committee, which oversaw the biggest medal haul yet again, “but overall I think these have been terrific Games.”
It turned out we had nothing to worry about.
PHOTOS: BEST OF CLOSING CEREMONY
Facebook Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Best of Rio Olympics closing ceremony Fullscreen Post to Facebook Posted! A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Performers dance as an introduction to the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic Games during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dancers perform during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dancers performs during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dancers perform with lace dresses during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Lenine performs during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dancers perform with umbrellas during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Julia Michaels performs during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Biles and Aly Raisman wear ponchos at the heroes of the games procession during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dancers perform in the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, Rob Schumacher-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Biles carries the American flag during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen View of the heroes of the games during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen View of the cauldron as athletes walk in at Maracana. M Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen View of the cauldron and flame during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen A singer performs as the heroes of the games enter during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen A dancer performs during the closing ceremony. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Children perform the Brazilian national anthem in the closing ceremony. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen View of the Olympic flag during the closing ceremony at Maracana. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Participants wear ponchos during the closing ceremony. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries: Replay 1 of 18 2 of 18 3 of 18 4 of 18 5 of 18 6 of 18 7 of 18 8 of 18 9 of 18 10 of 18 11 of 18 12 of 18 13 of 18 14 of 18 15 of 18 16 of 18 17 of 18 18 of 18 Autoplay Show Thumbnails Show Captions Last Slide Next Slide
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/columnist/brennan/2016/08/21/rio-olympics-closing-ceremony/89087424/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0423</post_time>
<username>Jammie Johnson</username>
<post>
When will the American media apologize for trying to spread fear about the Olympics?
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/2b4820799478d201c341f14252846f3260d28ef2/c=0-376-5082-3247&amp;amp;r=x1683&amp;amp;c=3200x1680/local/-/media/2016/08/21/USATODAY/USATODAY/636074102547366332-USP-OLYMPICS-CLOSING-CEREMONIES-84643328.JPG</main_image>
</document>
