<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.paxnigerian.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Nigeria Local News| About Nigeria | Naira news</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Guardiola warns Aguero not to &apos;disappear&apos; – Goal.com</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.paxnigerian.com/guardiola-warns-aguero-not-to-disappear-goal-com/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Sports 14 seconds ago The Manchester City boss is pleased with the Argentine’s six goals so far this season but was at pains to point out that he must keep up his work-rate off the ball 
Pep Guardiola has told Sergio Aguero to keep up his pressing of opposition defenders, warning him not to “disappear” when out of possession. 
Aguero has hit six goals in his first three games of the season, including two at Stoke City on Saturday, helping Manchester City start life with a 100 per cent record under Guardiola. 
But the City boss, speaking after the 4-1 victory in the Potteries, was at pains to point out that the Argentine needs to carry on contributing when his side do not have the ball. 
Goal understands that Guardiola’s technical staff highlighted Aguero’s relative lack of effort when not in possession before the Catalan started work in Manchester this summer. 
The Blues moved to seal the £27 million signing of Brazil youngster Gabriel Jesus after being encouraged by his willingness to close down defenders, and they hope that his eventual arrival at the Etihad Stadium will put pressure on Aguero to improve that aspect of his game further. 
Guardiola does admit his No.10 has been making strides in that department, but he was keen to ram the message home when asked to evaluate his two-goal performance at Stoke. 
“To score five goals in two games is a good statistic,” he told reporters. “From the beginning we spoke with Sergio. 
“He knows we are here to help him to play the way to create as many chances as possible and more chances to score goals. | B ravo misses Barca training ahead of City move “But he has to help us. It’s not enough to receive the ball from his team-mates. He has to help us in the first pressure and run a lot and help us a lot with movement.
“Until now he’s doing it and when that happens you are involved in defensive tasks and the offensive. 
“You cannot be brilliant when you disappear when you [don’t] have the ball. It’s impossible. Football is a connection between what you have with the ball and without the ball. 
“In the Sunderland game and the last two games he did it, and we can’t forget you need more training sessions.” 
Guardiola has also opened the door to Kelechi Iheanacho, who replaced Aguero at the newly named Bet365 Stadium on Saturday and helped create City’s third and fourth goals. 
The Nigerian youngster signed a two-year contract extention on Thursday, and Guardiola says he will have plenty of opportunities this season. 
“He is always ready,” he added. “We will need him. Sergio can’t play all season and Kelli is going to play. That’s why we saw Sergio was a little bit tired after playing four days ago and the travel. 
“He kept the ball and made some very nice assists. We can’t achieve anything with just 11 or 12 players. We need everybody and I hope they realise that. 
“Of course I have to decide and there are moments during the season where players are on top, are down and when that happens they will sit down beside me and we will play the players [that] are in better condition.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.paxnigerian.com/guardiola-warns-aguero-not-to-disappear-goal-com/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0742</post_time>
<username>saek</username>
<post>
Sports 14 seconds ago The Manchester City boss is pleased with the Argentine’s six goals so far this season but was at pains to point out that he must keep up his work-rate off the ball 
Pep Guardiola has told Sergio Aguero to keep up his pressing of opposition defenders, warning him not to “disappear” when out of possession. 
Aguero has hit six goals in his first three games of the season, including two at Stoke City on Saturday, helping Manchester City start life with a 100 per cent record under Guardiola. 
But the City boss, speaking after the 4-1 victory in the Potteries, was at pains to point out that the Argentine needs to carry on contributing when his side do not have the ball. 
Goal understands that Guardiola’s technical staff highlighted Aguero’s relative lack of effort when not in possession before the Catalan started work in Manchester this summer. 
The Blues moved to seal the £27 million signing of Brazil youngster Gabriel Jesus after being encouraged by his willingness to close down defenders, and they hope that his eventual arrival at the Etihad Stadium will put pressure on Aguero to improve that aspect of his game further. 
Guardiola does admit his No.10 has been making strides in that department, but he was keen to ram the message home when asked to evaluate his two-goal performance at Stoke. 
“To score five goals in two games is a good statistic,” he told reporters. “From the beginning we spoke with Sergio. 
“He knows we are here to help him to play the way to create as many chances as possible and more chances to score goals. | B ravo misses Barca training ahead of City move “But he has to help us. It’s not enough to receive the ball from his team-mates. He has to help us in the first pressure and run a lot and help us a lot with movement.
“Until now he’s doing it and when that happens you are involved in defensive tasks and the offensive. 
“You cannot be brilliant when you disappear when you [don’t] have the ball. It’s impossible. Football is a connection between what you have with the ball and without the ball. 
“In the Sunderland game and the last two games he did it, and we can’t forget you need more training sessions.” 
Guardiola has also opened the door to Kelechi Iheanacho, who replaced Aguero at the newly named Bet365 Stadium on Saturday and helped create City’s third and fourth goals. 
The Nigerian youngster signed a two-year contract extention on Thursday, and Guardiola says he will have plenty of opportunities this season. 
“He is always ready,” he added. “We will need him. Sergio can’t play all season and Kelli is going to play. That’s why we saw Sergio was a little bit tired after playing four days ago and the travel. 
“He kept the ball and made some very nice assists. We can’t achieve anything with just 11 or 12 players. We need everybody and I hope they realise that. 
“Of course I have to decide and there are moments during the season where players are on top, are down and when that happens they will sit down beside me and we will play the players [that] are in better condition.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SE</country>
<main_image>http://u.goal.com/288600/288646_specials.jpg</main_image>
</document>
