<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>The sky&apos;s the limit with Penthouse living</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/property/the-skys-the-limit-with-penthouse-living/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The sky&apos;s the limit with Penthouse living Maria Harris luxury Karl and Sarah Fender living it up in their 73rd floor apartment at Eureka Tower. Photo: Michael Rayner 
Penthouses are all about glamour, wealth and prestige. You are at the top of the heap and – usually – at the top of the tower. 
Odeon Tower 
Views and scarcity are among the drawcards of penthouse life. Karl and Sarah Fender’s ‘’ 
Then there are sub-penthouses, which often occupy two or three floors below the penthouse. 
When it comes to our most famous residential tower, Eureka, its architect Karl Fender of Fender Katsalidis Architects 
“It’s amazing how private living in an apartment is, but you meet people at the pool or gym. 
“ 
“We lived in apartments in London, Boston and Bangkok and when we came back to Melbourne in 1995 we continued to live the way we liked. It’s a very elegant way of living.” 
The penthou Marshall White Projects. 
“The empty-nester or downsizer sees the strength in the residential market and the increase in the value of their home over the past five years so they think it’s a good time to sell,” he says. 
“They like to buy off the plan and typically will consolidate two 70-square-metre apartments into one larger penthouse and then go to the architect to create a bespoke offering. 
“They want a lock-up-and-leave proposition, so they can travel and then come back to the place exactly as they left it. If they have an adult child or student with them, two or three car spaces are important.” 
Entry point for a penthouse in Melbourne is somewhere between $1.2 million and $2 million, and Mark says buyers often stick to buying within a kilometre of their former home. 
Penthouses are not just appearing in off-the-plan developments. In blue-chip Toorak, penthouses in older-style buildings are being renovated and given a new lease of life. 
Gabi Tomkin in the renovated penthouse at 16 Worrigoleen Road Toorak. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
John Gdanski and his wife, property developer Gaby Tomkin, have spent 18 months renovating their 1970 two-level penthouse at 16 Woorigoleen Road. 
The couple love the exclusivity of penthouse living. 
“You are literally the king or queen of the castle,” Gaby says. 
“We have 360-degree views of all of Melbourne. We have views to Port Phillip Bay and to the Dandenong Ran 
They kept the walk-in safe, which she says is like a “little metal room with 30-centimetre-wide walls”. 
“Houses in Woorigoleen Road are selling for $7 million or $8 million and they don’t have the views,” she says. 
Grant Giordano of is selling the penthouse at 16 Woorigoleen Road, Toorak. Private sale $4.5 million. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.82</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/property/the-skys-the-limit-with-penthouse-living/</post_url>
<post_date>20160810</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
The sky&apos;s the limit with Penthouse living Maria Harris luxury Karl and Sarah Fender living it up in their 73rd floor apartment at Eureka Tower. Photo: Michael Rayner 
Penthouses are all about glamour, wealth and prestige. You are at the top of the heap and – usually – at the top of the tower. 
Odeon Tower 
Views and scarcity are among the drawcards of penthouse life. Karl and Sarah Fender’s ‘’ 
Then there are sub-penthouses, which often occupy two or three floors below the penthouse. 
When it comes to our most famous residential tower, Eureka, its architect Karl Fender of Fender Katsalidis Architects 
“It’s amazing how private living in an apartment is, but you meet people at the pool or gym. 
“ 
“We lived in apartments in London, Boston and Bangkok and when we came back to Melbourne in 1995 we continued to live the way we liked. It’s a very elegant way of living.” 
The penthou Marshall White Projects. 
“The empty-nester or downsizer sees the strength in the residential market and the increase in the value of their home over the past five years so they think it’s a good time to sell,” he says. 
“They like to buy off the plan and typically will consolidate two 70-square-metre apartments into one larger penthouse and then go to the architect to create a bespoke offering. 
“They want a lock-up-and-leave proposition, so they can travel and then come back to the place exactly as they left it. If they have an adult child or student with them, two or three car spaces are important.” 
Entry point for a penthouse in Melbourne is somewhere between $1.2 million and $2 million, and Mark says buyers often stick to buying within a kilometre of their former home. 
Penthouses are not just appearing in off-the-plan developments. In blue-chip Toorak, penthouses in older-style buildings are being renovated and given a new lease of life. 
Gabi Tomkin in the renovated penthouse at 16 Worrigoleen Road Toorak. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
John Gdanski and his wife, property developer Gaby Tomkin, have spent 18 months renovating their 1970 two-level penthouse at 16 Woorigoleen Road. 
The couple love the exclusivity of penthouse living. 
“You are literally the king or queen of the castle,” Gaby says. 
“We have 360-degree views of all of Melbourne. We have views to Port Phillip Bay and to the Dandenong Ran 
They kept the walk-in safe, which she says is like a “little metal room with 30-centimetre-wide walls”. 
“Houses in Woorigoleen Road are selling for $7 million or $8 million and they don’t have the views,” she says. 
Grant Giordano of is selling the penthouse at 16 Woorigoleen Road, Toorak. Private sale $4.5 million. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/wp-content/uploads/content-watched/2016/08/1029987_Large.jpg</main_image>
</document>
