<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://feeds.feedblitz.com/lansing/news</forum>
<forum_title>Lansing - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Brent Case: The Ag-traction Strategy</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.lansingstatejournal.com/story/news/local/2016/08/21/brent-case-ag-traction-strategy/88567634/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Brent Case: The Ag-traction Strategy Brent Case, Lansing Economic Area Partnership 10:02 a.m. EDT August 21, 2016 Brent Case, Lansing Area Economic Partnership (Photo: Submitted) 
People in business know that it’s less costly to retain your existing customers versus the expense of courting and advertising to secure new business. But to grow any business, it’s critical to conduct some sort of business development, sales and attraction activity to land new customers. 
In the economic development space, it’s very similar. Successful state, regional and local agencies focus on retention and expansion, conducting retention visits with local business leaders to learn first-hand what challenges that company may be facing. Sometimes it may be necessary to bring resources to assist a company out of a negative situation, such as loss of a customer or supplier issues. However, it may also involve providing incentives for that company to stay local or expand in the area instead of locating operations in a neighboring state – or offshoring production. 
Retention and expansion are basic activities for most economic development groups. However, just as successful businesses do, economic development agencies that want to continue to grow their economy must also focus on attracting new businesses that will invest and create new jobs. 
At the Lansing Economic Area Partnership (LEAP) we have robust retention and expansion programs – but are also focused on attracting four main industries, based on our region’s strengths. Those industries include automotive suppliers, insurance and financial service companies, high-tech companies involved in particle acceleration, and agriculture and food production. LEAP’s “Ag-traction Strategy” follows similar principles of the other three industries: Identify strengths, assets and knowledge base : In Greater Lansing, we are extremely fortunate to have Michigan State University, a world-renown agricultural university that conducts research on important agricultural areas and provides an extension service to work with farmers around the state. MSU graduates thousands of people a year who are well equipped to provide leadership and innovation in businesses focused on Michigan’s 300-plus ag commodities, including fruits and vegetables, legumes, flowers, milk, soybeans, corn and potatoes. In fact, Michigan’s ag industry provides nearly 22 percent of the state’s employment. Understand the global supply chain : Work with local agriculture and food production companies to understand where they get their supplies and who their customers are. If a local company is shipping large volumes to their customer located out-of-state, there may be a chance to attract that customer to the region to be closer to them and save on logistics costs. For example, our region can compete well with other states when companies that use large quantities of milk or milk products are looking to build facilities. Our region is one of the largest dairy producers in the nation with a milk processing facility located in Ovid operated by the Michigan Milk Producers Association. Identify innovations and new opportunities that build on our existing strengths: Because of the enormous strength we have a wide variety of agricultural and food production areas, our region is poised to attract emerging opportunities, such as aquaculture. Aquaculture raises fish in a controlled environment to be used for food, but also to help repopulate species that may be endangered or close to endangered. With our region’s abundance of fresh water hundreds of feet below the surface, relatively low cost of electricity and gas, and pro-business government regulatory environment, the world envies what we have. Many global companies are exploring how they can leverage the natural resources, wealth of knowledge and experience, while investing and creating well-paying jobs here in Greater Lansing 
Just like business, LEAP is keeping our eye on the horizon and pursuing those opportunities that could have a net benefit to our region, and the world. Agriculture (and aquaculture) and food production are a top priority in our overall strategy. 
Brent Case is the Vice President of Business Attraction for the Lansing Economic Area Partnership (LEAP). Read or Share this story: http://on.lsj.com/2bM3Efr TOP VIDEOS
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.lansingstatejournal.com/story/news/local/2016/08/21/brent-case-ag-traction-strategy/88567634/</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1402</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Brent Case: The Ag-traction Strategy Brent Case, Lansing Economic Area Partnership 10:02 a.m. EDT August 21, 2016 Brent Case, Lansing Area Economic Partnership (Photo: Submitted) 
People in business know that it’s less costly to retain your existing customers versus the expense of courting and advertising to secure new business. But to grow any business, it’s critical to conduct some sort of business development, sales and attraction activity to land new customers. 
In the economic development space, it’s very similar. Successful state, regional and local agencies focus on retention and expansion, conducting retention visits with local business leaders to learn first-hand what challenges that company may be facing. Sometimes it may be necessary to bring resources to assist a company out of a negative situation, such as loss of a customer or supplier issues. However, it may also involve providing incentives for that company to stay local or expand in the area instead of locating operations in a neighboring state – or offshoring production. 
Retention and expansion are basic activities for most economic development groups. However, just as successful businesses do, economic development agencies that want to continue to grow their economy must also focus on attracting new businesses that will invest and create new jobs. 
At the Lansing Economic Area Partnership (LEAP) we have robust retention and expansion programs – but are also focused on attracting four main industries, based on our region’s strengths. Those industries include automotive suppliers, insurance and financial service companies, high-tech companies involved in particle acceleration, and agriculture and food production. LEAP’s “Ag-traction Strategy” follows similar principles of the other three industries: Identify strengths, assets and knowledge base : In Greater Lansing, we are extremely fortunate to have Michigan State University, a world-renown agricultural university that conducts research on important agricultural areas and provides an extension service to work with farmers around the state. MSU graduates thousands of people a year who are well equipped to provide leadership and innovation in businesses focused on Michigan’s 300-plus ag commodities, including fruits and vegetables, legumes, flowers, milk, soybeans, corn and potatoes. In fact, Michigan’s ag industry provides nearly 22 percent of the state’s employment. Understand the global supply chain : Work with local agriculture and food production companies to understand where they get their supplies and who their customers are. If a local company is shipping large volumes to their customer located out-of-state, there may be a chance to attract that customer to the region to be closer to them and save on logistics costs. For example, our region can compete well with other states when companies that use large quantities of milk or milk products are looking to build facilities. Our region is one of the largest dairy producers in the nation with a milk processing facility located in Ovid operated by the Michigan Milk Producers Association. Identify innovations and new opportunities that build on our existing strengths: Because of the enormous strength we have a wide variety of agricultural and food production areas, our region is poised to attract emerging opportunities, such as aquaculture. Aquaculture raises fish in a controlled environment to be used for food, but also to help repopulate species that may be endangered or close to endangered. With our region’s abundance of fresh water hundreds of feet below the surface, relatively low cost of electricity and gas, and pro-business government regulatory environment, the world envies what we have. Many global companies are exploring how they can leverage the natural resources, wealth of knowledge and experience, while investing and creating well-paying jobs here in Greater Lansing 
Just like business, LEAP is keeping our eye on the horizon and pursuing those opportunities that could have a net benefit to our region, and the world. Agriculture (and aquaculture) and food production are a top priority in our overall strategy. 
Brent Case is the Vice President of Business Attraction for the Lansing Economic Area Partnership (LEAP). Read or Share this story: http://on.lsj.com/2bM3Efr TOP VIDEOS
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/39d6e4650508bc00d7c30f3196158cc3c6010cb3/c=0-1065-3995-3322&amp;amp;r=x1683&amp;amp;c=3200x1680/local/-/media/2016/08/11/MIGroup/Lansing/636065163765293359-BrentCase.JPG</main_image>
</document>
