<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Is the Black Lives Matter movement controlled by the Muslim Brotherhood? | ACT Memphis</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://actmemphis.org/wp/?p=1028</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Posted on July 10, 2016 by BLOGadmin 
1. The co-founder of the Black Lives Matter (BLM) movement of Toronto, Yusra Khogali , is Muslim as shown in a Tweet posted 09 FEB 2016. 
While Khogali is a co-founder of the Toronto Chapter of BLM, one of the original National founders , PATRISSE CULLORS , has expressed an extreme anti-Israel and pro-Palestinian stance. She signed a letter stating, “ We know Israel’s violence toward Palestinians would be impossible without the U.S. defending Israel on the world stage and funding its violence with over $3 billion annually. We call on the U.S. government to end economic and diplomatic aid to Israel. We wholeheartedly endorse Palestinian civil society’s 2005 call for Boycott, Divestment, and Sanctions (BDS) against Israel and call on Black and U.S. institutions and organizations to do the same. We urge people of conscience to recognize the struggle for Palestinian liberation as a key matter of our time.” 
2. At the 2015 MAS / ICNA annual conference, the CAIR Executive Director, Nihad Awad , claimed the “BLM is our matter, the BLM is our campaign”. CAIR is an affiliate organization of the Muslim Brotherhood and a front group for HAMAS, a U.S. designated terrorist organization. 
Awad’s comments can be heard in the video posted HERE. Islamists from the CAIR- linked “ Muslims for Ferguson ” likened the shooting of Michael Brown to the 2009 fatal shooting of radical Islamist Luqman Abdullah during an FBI raid in Dearborn, Michigan. 
3. Daoud Abudiab is an Islamic activist in Tennessee. He is Past Co-Chair of the American Muslim Advisory Council of Tennessee (AMAC). He is the Director (President) of the Islamic Center of Columbia, TN. He is aBoard Member and founder of the Faith and Culture Center , an Islamic Interfaith group that has been active in promoting Islamic ideology among other religions. He is thecurrent President of the Tennessee Immigrant &amp; Refugee Rights Coalition (TIRRC), which supports the resettlement of Muslim refugees in Tennessee. In FEB of 2016, he attended the USCMO conference in Washington. The USCMO is a recently formed coalition of Muslim Brotherhood organizations whose stated mission is to “Streamline ‘all-way’ communication between and among our local and national organizations”. 
At the 2015 TIRRC annual convention, Abudiab led a planning effort with the BLM movement to “strategize, dream and build our movement for 2016″. (See Facebook announcement below) 
4. Drost Kokoye is a Nashville grass-roots Islamic activist who has been involved in organizing many pro-Islamic protest. She has taken part in protest at the State capital against certain bills before the General Assembly and involved in protest at her current school, University of TN, Knoxville. Kokoye has been extremely active in anti-Israel, pro-Palestinian/Hamas rallies in Tennessee and upon arriving at UTK she helped organize a pro-Ferguson rally. She was active in promoting the latest BLM protest in Nashville, Memphis and Knoxville. She attended the protest in Nashville. (See her facebook page below). 
She is active and an office holder in AMAC and the American Center for Outreach, an Islamic lobbying group in TN. 
Conclusion: 
So we have seen National, State and local activist in the Muslim Brotherhood promote and work with the Black Lives Matter movement. 
The Explanatory Memorandum was a Muslim Brotherhood (aka: Ikhwan) document that was seized in a raid of the home of a major Brotherhood operative. The document was entered into evidence in the Federal trial of the Holy Land Foundation, the largest terrorism financing trial in U.S. history. The following selection is from that document (as translated from the original Arabic by a court appoint ed translator) : 
4- Understanding the role of the Muslim Brother in North America: 
The process of settlement is a “Civilization-Jihadist Process” with all the word means. The Ikhwan must understand that their work in America is a kind of grand Jihad in eliminating and destroying the Western civilization from within and “sabotaging” its miserable house by their hands and the hands of the believers so that it is eliminated and Allah’s religion is made victorious over all other religions. Without this level of understanding, we are not up to this challenge and have not prepared ourselves for Jihad yet. It is a Muslim’s destiny to perform Jihad and work wherever he is and wherever he lands until the final hour comes, and there is no escape from that destiny except for those who chose to slack. But, would the slackers and the Mujahedeen be equal. 

5- Understanding that we cannot perform the settlement mission by ourselves or away from people: 
A mission as significant and as huge as the settlement mission needs magnificent and exhausting efforts. With their capabilities, human, financial and scientific resources, the Ikhwan will not be able to carry out this mission alone or away from people and he who believes that is wrong, and Allah knows best. As for the role of the Ikhwan, it is the initiative, pioneering, leadership, raising the banner and pushing people in that direction. They are then to work to employ, direct and unify Muslims’ efforts and powers for this process. In order to do that, we must possess a mastery of the art of “coalitions”, the art of “absorption” and the principles of “cooperation”. 
[Highlighting added for emphasis. 
Another document was recovered in a raid by Swiss authorities in November 2001. This document, known as The Project , reveals a top-secret plan developed by the oldest Islamist organization with one of the most extensive terror networks in the world to launch a program of &quot;cultural invasion&quot; and eventual conquest of the West. In part, it states: 
Point of Departure 7: To accept the principle of temporary cooperation between Islamic movements and nationalist movements in the broad sphere and on common ground such as the struggle against colonialism, preaching and the Jewish state, without however having to form alliances. This will require, on the other hand, limited contacts between certain leaders, on a case by case basis, as long as these contacts do not violate the [shari&apos;a] law. Nevertheless, one must not give them allegiance or take them into confidence, bearing in mind that the Islamic movement must be the origin of the initiatives and orientations taken. This entry was posted in Uncategorized . Bookmark the permalink . 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.69</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://actmemphis.org/wp/?p=1028</post_url>
<post_date>20160710</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Posted on July 10, 2016 by BLOGadmin 
1. The co-founder of the Black Lives Matter (BLM) movement of Toronto, Yusra Khogali , is Muslim as shown in a Tweet posted 09 FEB 2016. 
While Khogali is a co-founder of the Toronto Chapter of BLM, one of the original National founders , PATRISSE CULLORS , has expressed an extreme anti-Israel and pro-Palestinian stance. She signed a letter stating, “ We know Israel’s violence toward Palestinians would be impossible without the U.S. defending Israel on the world stage and funding its violence with over $3 billion annually. We call on the U.S. government to end economic and diplomatic aid to Israel. We wholeheartedly endorse Palestinian civil society’s 2005 call for Boycott, Divestment, and Sanctions (BDS) against Israel and call on Black and U.S. institutions and organizations to do the same. We urge people of conscience to recognize the struggle for Palestinian liberation as a key matter of our time.” 
2. At the 2015 MAS / ICNA annual conference, the CAIR Executive Director, Nihad Awad , claimed the “BLM is our matter, the BLM is our campaign”. CAIR is an affiliate organization of the Muslim Brotherhood and a front group for HAMAS, a U.S. designated terrorist organization. 
Awad’s comments can be heard in the video posted HERE. Islamists from the CAIR- linked “ Muslims for Ferguson ” likened the shooting of Michael Brown to the 2009 fatal shooting of radical Islamist Luqman Abdullah during an FBI raid in Dearborn, Michigan. 
3. Daoud Abudiab is an Islamic activist in Tennessee. He is Past Co-Chair of the American Muslim Advisory Council of Tennessee (AMAC). He is the Director (President) of the Islamic Center of Columbia, TN. He is aBoard Member and founder of the Faith and Culture Center , an Islamic Interfaith group that has been active in promoting Islamic ideology among other religions. He is thecurrent President of the Tennessee Immigrant &amp; Refugee Rights Coalition (TIRRC), which supports the resettlement of Muslim refugees in Tennessee. In FEB of 2016, he attended the USCMO conference in Washington. The USCMO is a recently formed coalition of Muslim Brotherhood organizations whose stated mission is to “Streamline ‘all-way’ communication between and among our local and national organizations”. 
At the 2015 TIRRC annual convention, Abudiab led a planning effort with the BLM movement to “strategize, dream and build our movement for 2016″. (See Facebook announcement below) 
4. Drost Kokoye is a Nashville grass-roots Islamic activist who has been involved in organizing many pro-Islamic protest. She has taken part in protest at the State capital against certain bills before the General Assembly and involved in protest at her current school, University of TN, Knoxville. Kokoye has been extremely active in anti-Israel, pro-Palestinian/Hamas rallies in Tennessee and upon arriving at UTK she helped organize a pro-Ferguson rally. She was active in promoting the latest BLM protest in Nashville, Memphis and Knoxville. She attended the protest in Nashville. (See her facebook page below). 
She is active and an office holder in AMAC and the American Center for Outreach, an Islamic lobbying group in TN. 
Conclusion: 
So we have seen National, State and local activist in the Muslim Brotherhood promote and work with the Black Lives Matter movement. 
The Explanatory Memorandum was a Muslim Brotherhood (aka: Ikhwan) document that was seized in a raid of the home of a major Brotherhood operative. The document was entered into evidence in the Federal trial of the Holy Land Foundation, the largest terrorism financing trial in U.S. history. The following selection is from that document (as translated from the original Arabic by a court appoint ed translator) : 
4- Understanding the role of the Muslim Brother in North America: 
The process of settlement is a “Civilization-Jihadist Process” with all the word means. The Ikhwan must understand that their work in America is a kind of grand Jihad in eliminating and destroying the Western civilization from within and “sabotaging” its miserable house by their hands and the hands of the believers so that it is eliminated and Allah’s religion is made victorious over all other religions. Without this level of understanding, we are not up to this challenge and have not prepared ourselves for Jihad yet. It is a Muslim’s destiny to perform Jihad and work wherever he is and wherever he lands until the final hour comes, and there is no escape from that destiny except for those who chose to slack. But, would the slackers and the Mujahedeen be equal. 

5- Understanding that we cannot perform the settlement mission by ourselves or away from people: 
A mission as significant and as huge as the settlement mission needs magnificent and exhausting efforts. With their capabilities, human, financial and scientific resources, the Ikhwan will not be able to carry out this mission alone or away from people and he who believes that is wrong, and Allah knows best. As for the role of the Ikhwan, it is the initiative, pioneering, leadership, raising the banner and pushing people in that direction. They are then to work to employ, direct and unify Muslims’ efforts and powers for this process. In order to do that, we must possess a mastery of the art of “coalitions”, the art of “absorption” and the principles of “cooperation”. 
[Highlighting added for emphasis. 
Another document was recovered in a raid by Swiss authorities in November 2001. This document, known as The Project , reveals a top-secret plan developed by the oldest Islamist organization with one of the most extensive terror networks in the world to launch a program of &quot;cultural invasion&quot; and eventual conquest of the West. In part, it states: 
Point of Departure 7: To accept the principle of temporary cooperation between Islamic movements and nationalist movements in the broad sphere and on common ground such as the struggle against colonialism, preaching and the Jewish state, without however having to form alliances. This will require, on the other hand, limited contacts between certain leaders, on a case by case basis, as long as these contacts do not violate the [shari&apos;a] law. Nevertheless, one must not give them allegiance or take them into confidence, bearing in mind that the Islamic movement must be the origin of the initiatives and orientations taken. This entry was posted in Uncategorized . Bookmark the permalink . 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
