<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.aspentimes.com/csp/mediapool/sites/SwiftShared/assets/csp/rssCategoryFeed.csp?pub=AspenTimes&amp;sectionId=745&amp;sectionLabel=News</forum>
<forum_title>The Aspen Times Section RSS Feed: News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Poschman leads commissioner Pitkin County race fundraising</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.aspentimes.com/news/23519494-113/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Smaller Larger Related Media The filmmaker and longtime local who received the most votes in the June primary for the only contested seat on the Pitkin County Board of Commissioners also is leading the way in campaign fundraising — by far. Greg Poschman, 56, has raised $11,165 since Nov. 29 for the June 28 primary and Nov. 8 general election, according to campaign-finance reports filed with Pitkin County Clerk and Recorder Janice Vos Caudill. By contrast, businessman Scott Writer — who came in second in the primary with 32 percent of the vote — raised a grand total of nothing, according to the campaign-finance reports. Writer, 58, raised zero dollars and spent the same on his campaign between Dec. 1 and May 29. He spent $1,354 between May 30 and June 15 on voter-registration lists, advertising and graphic design but again received no donations, according to his report. Writer reported spending $1,190 between June 20 and July 23 with no contributions. On Wednesday, Writer said he didn’t want to solicit campaign contributions before he made it through the primary. After July 23, he began accepting donations for his general-election campaign, he said. The next reporting period for campaign-finance reports is not until October. Poschman reported raising $7,945 between Nov. 29 and June 2 and spending $3,194, mainly on advertising. One of the largest donations during that period came from John McBride, a skiing coach and majority owner of the Aspen Business Center, who contributed $500, according to the report. St. Moritz Lodge owner Michael Behrendt contributed $250 during the same period, while former Aspen Mayor Bill Stirling chipped in $200 and Boomerang Lodge developer Steve Stunda contributed $100, according to the finance report. Poschman began the reporting period between June 3 and June 19 with $4,750 and raised $1,570 more while spending $4,670. Notable contributors during that period included Stirling again, who donated another $100, and former Pitkin County Commissioner Jack Hatfield, who contributed $50, according to the report. Between June 20 and July 23, Poschman raised another $1,650, including a $500 donation from former Hotel Jerome owner Dick Butera. Poschman ended the period with $2,900 left in his campaign fund, according to the report he filed. Longtime Open Space and Trails Board member Hawk Greenway, who finished third in the June primary voting and did not advance to the general-election ballot, reported raising $1,595 between Dec. 1 and May 29, according to the only campaign-finance report he filed. Greenway reported spending $1,447 and finished the reporting period with $148 left in his campaign fund, the report states. He loaned his campaign $600, according to the report. Greenway did not file a final campaign-finance report covering the period between May 30 and the June 28 primary, Vos Caudill said. Poschman and Writer will vie for the District 3 seat being vacated by Michael Owsley, who has served the limit of three four-year terms on the board. District 3 essentially wraps around Aspen’s city limits and includes Independence Pass, Brush Creek and Woody Creek, though county board representatives are elected on an at-large basis, meaning county residents vote for candidates in all districts. The District 4 and District 5 seats also are open in November, though the current occupants of those chairs — Steve Child, 68, and George Newman, 64 — ran unopposed in the primary and face no competition in the general election.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.aspentimes.com/news/23519494-113/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0132</post_time>
<username>Jason Auslander</username>
<post>
Smaller Larger Related Media The filmmaker and longtime local who received the most votes in the June primary for the only contested seat on the Pitkin County Board of Commissioners also is leading the way in campaign fundraising — by far. Greg Poschman, 56, has raised $11,165 since Nov. 29 for the June 28 primary and Nov. 8 general election, according to campaign-finance reports filed with Pitkin County Clerk and Recorder Janice Vos Caudill. By contrast, businessman Scott Writer — who came in second in the primary with 32 percent of the vote — raised a grand total of nothing, according to the campaign-finance reports. Writer, 58, raised zero dollars and spent the same on his campaign between Dec. 1 and May 29. He spent $1,354 between May 30 and June 15 on voter-registration lists, advertising and graphic design but again received no donations, according to his report. Writer reported spending $1,190 between June 20 and July 23 with no contributions. On Wednesday, Writer said he didn’t want to solicit campaign contributions before he made it through the primary. After July 23, he began accepting donations for his general-election campaign, he said. The next reporting period for campaign-finance reports is not until October. Poschman reported raising $7,945 between Nov. 29 and June 2 and spending $3,194, mainly on advertising. One of the largest donations during that period came from John McBride, a skiing coach and majority owner of the Aspen Business Center, who contributed $500, according to the report. St. Moritz Lodge owner Michael Behrendt contributed $250 during the same period, while former Aspen Mayor Bill Stirling chipped in $200 and Boomerang Lodge developer Steve Stunda contributed $100, according to the finance report. Poschman began the reporting period between June 3 and June 19 with $4,750 and raised $1,570 more while spending $4,670. Notable contributors during that period included Stirling again, who donated another $100, and former Pitkin County Commissioner Jack Hatfield, who contributed $50, according to the report. Between June 20 and July 23, Poschman raised another $1,650, including a $500 donation from former Hotel Jerome owner Dick Butera. Poschman ended the period with $2,900 left in his campaign fund, according to the report he filed. Longtime Open Space and Trails Board member Hawk Greenway, who finished third in the June primary voting and did not advance to the general-election ballot, reported raising $1,595 between Dec. 1 and May 29, according to the only campaign-finance report he filed. Greenway reported spending $1,447 and finished the reporting period with $148 left in his campaign fund, the report states. He loaned his campaign $600, according to the report. Greenway did not file a final campaign-finance report covering the period between May 30 and the June 28 primary, Vos Caudill said. Poschman and Writer will vie for the District 3 seat being vacated by Michael Owsley, who has served the limit of three four-year terms on the board. District 3 essentially wraps around Aspen’s city limits and includes Independence Pass, Brush Creek and Woody Creek, though county board representatives are elected on an at-large basis, meaning county residents vote for candidates in all districts. The District 4 and District 5 seats also are open in November, though the current occupants of those chairs — Steve Child, 68, and George Newman, 64 — ran unopposed in the primary and face no competition in the general election.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.aspentimes.com/csp/mediapool/sites/AspenTimes/assets/img/facebook-thumbnail-1200.jpg</main_image>
</document>
