<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.newsweek.com/rss</forum>
<forum_title>Newsweek</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Rio 2016: Three More Irish Officials Held As Police Investigate Illegal Ticket Sales</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://europe.newsweek.com/rio-2016-olympics-olympic-council-ireland-ticket-touting-patrick-hickey-492254</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Rio 2016: Three More Irish Officials Held As Police Investigate Illegal Ticket Sales Members of Ireland&apos;s Olympic council allegedly sold tickets allocated for athletes&apos; families. Close Olympics Ticket Scalping Arrest Of IOC Executive Patrick Hickey 
Brazilian police have confiscated the passports, phones and laptops of three officials from the Olympic Council of Ireland (OCI). 
The seizures follow the arrest of the council’s president, Patrick Hickey, on August 17. Police are investigating all four council members over alleged illegal ticket sales.   
Brazilian security officials have named the three men, who were arrested shortly after the Olympics ended Sunday, as Stephen Martin, the OCI’s chief executive, Dermot Henihan, the secretary-general, and Kevin Kitty, Ireland’s team leader, the BBC reported . Martin is also a former Olympic hockey gold medallist. 
Under the leadership of Hickey, the OCI in Brazil is alleged to have sold Olympic tickets that Rio officials allocated for athletes and their families. Though police have not formally arrested Martin, Henihan and Kitty, they will question the three men Tuesday, The Guardian reported . As well as confiscating their passports and electronic devices, investigators also took unused tickets belonging to the OCI. 
Brazilian police have said that they’re hoping to seize the passports of three other people with links to the OCI. Back in Ireland, the council has set up a crisis management committee to deal with the investigation. In addition, it will hire an accountancy company to review its ticketing procedures in Rio. 
Hickey, who is currently detained in Rio’s Bangu 10 jail has stood down as OCI president. Police have accused him of ticket touting and running a cartel, though they have not yet charged him. 
He is sharing his jail cell with his fellow Irishman Kevin Mallon, a director at THG Sports, a corporate hospitality company that specializes in sporting events. Mallon, along with three other THG members, stands similarly accused of illegally selling tickets. He was arrested on August 5, after police seized a stash of tickets in a Rio hotel.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://europe.newsweek.com/rio-2016-olympics-olympic-council-ireland-ticket-touting-patrick-hickey-492254</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0752</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Rio 2016: Three More Irish Officials Held As Police Investigate Illegal Ticket Sales Members of Ireland&apos;s Olympic council allegedly sold tickets allocated for athletes&apos; families. Close Olympics Ticket Scalping Arrest Of IOC Executive Patrick Hickey 
Brazilian police have confiscated the passports, phones and laptops of three officials from the Olympic Council of Ireland (OCI). 
The seizures follow the arrest of the council’s president, Patrick Hickey, on August 17. Police are investigating all four council members over alleged illegal ticket sales.   
Brazilian security officials have named the three men, who were arrested shortly after the Olympics ended Sunday, as Stephen Martin, the OCI’s chief executive, Dermot Henihan, the secretary-general, and Kevin Kitty, Ireland’s team leader, the BBC reported . Martin is also a former Olympic hockey gold medallist. 
Under the leadership of Hickey, the OCI in Brazil is alleged to have sold Olympic tickets that Rio officials allocated for athletes and their families. Though police have not formally arrested Martin, Henihan and Kitty, they will question the three men Tuesday, The Guardian reported . As well as confiscating their passports and electronic devices, investigators also took unused tickets belonging to the OCI. 
Brazilian police have said that they’re hoping to seize the passports of three other people with links to the OCI. Back in Ireland, the council has set up a crisis management committee to deal with the investigation. In addition, it will hire an accountancy company to review its ticketing procedures in Rio. 
Hickey, who is currently detained in Rio’s Bangu 10 jail has stood down as OCI president. Police have accused him of ticket touting and running a cartel, though they have not yet charged him. 
He is sharing his jail cell with his fellow Irishman Kevin Mallon, a director at THG Sports, a corporate hospitality company that specializes in sporting events. Mallon, along with three other THG members, stands similarly accused of illegally selling tickets. He was arrested on August 5, after police seized a stash of tickets in a Rio hotel.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://d.europe.newsweek.com/en/full/62707/olympic-tickets.jpg?w=1800</main_image>
</document>
