<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.tribuneindia.com/</forum>
<forum_title>The Tribune, Chandigarh, India : Latest news, India, Punjab, Chandigarh, Haryana, Himachal, Uttarakhand, J&amp;amp;K, sports, cricket </forum_title>
<discussion_title>PM may skip NAM Summit in Venezuela</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/pm-may-skip-nam-summit-in-venezuela/283569.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Simran Sodhi
Tribune News Service
New Delhi, August 21
Prime Minister Narendra Modi is likely to skip the Non-Aligned Movement (NAM) Summit in Venezuela next month. This is despite the fact that Venezuela has twice extended invitations to India for the summit and out of consideration for the PM’s busy schedule, Venezuela even moved the summit from July last year to this year. Sources in the Venezuelan diplomatic circles said Venezuela was yet to receive a communication as to who would be representing India at the summit. They said they remained “hopeful” that Modi would attend the summit as NAM inspires a multi-polar world as opposed to big forces dominating the world unilaterally. The US is the only country which doesn’t want NAM to succeed because “the success of NAM is a defeat for the US”. However, indications seem to be that Modi is still not going to attend the summit; and that will indicate a policy shift for India. All PMs to date, except Charan Singh in 1979, have made it a point to attend NAM summits. India was one of the founding members of NAM and hence, the attendance of the PM is something Venezuela was keen on. However, it is now more likely that External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj would represent India at the summit. This week, she met her Venezulean counterpart who extended an invitation to her to attend the summit. While officially India has maintained a silence on the question of whether the PM will be attending the summit, Foreign Secretary S Jaishankar on Wednesday offered an insight into the government’s thinking on blocs and multilateral forums. He said, “Blocs and alliances are less relevant today and the world is moving towards a loosely arranged order.” Another reason that is doing the buzz in the corridors of South Block is that NAM is today regarded as an almost defunct alliance and the government wants to be seen making efforts in multi-lateral forums such as BRICS and the G20 which give India a global role. Another reason is the perceptible change in India’s foreign policy which has seen the Modi government embracing the US eagerly. NAM has traditionally been regarded as being anti-US and that is one sentiment the government wants to shed. The foreign policy, under the Modi government, is focusing on pushing its Africa relationship as seen in the grand India-Africa Summit India hosted last year along with the visits by the President, PM and Vice-President to the continent. There has been a great outreach by the Modi government to the countries of the Gulf and also in its ‘Look East’ policy. The PM has made it a point to travel to many countries and has given his personal touch to many of the bilateral relationships India has today. Skipping the NAM Summit is a quiet message that India has outgrown an alliance whose roots go back to the colonial era and India now sees itself as an emerging global and not a regional player.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>1.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tribuneindia.com/news/nation/pm-may-skip-nam-summit-in-venezuela/283569.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>2231</post_time>
<username>El Comandante</username>
<post>
Before you go, have Venezuela finally settle its debt.
1) Get the money up front.
2) Get it in gold, euros, or dollars.
3) Check the silverware drawer AND do a towel, soap, shampoo, shower cap, toilet paper, and Kleenex, count at whatever hotel the Venezuelan delegation is staying in BEFORE they leave.
They are worse than that lazy, unemployed, no good, worthless cousin everyone has that is always stealing stuff from Grandma. ...and that is just the government leadership.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://images.tribuneindia.com/cms/gall_content/2016/8/2016_8$largeimg22_Monday_2016_005650272.jpg</main_image>
</document>
