<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Secrets of my success: Lisa Messenger</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/secrets-of-my-success-lisa-messenger/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Peter Wilmoth THE SECRETS OF LISA When did you first realise you were successful? Collective a lot of stuff. When you’re not completely fulfilled in your life – this was true for me – you go out and buy clothes or shoes or whatever and it’s instant gratification. The funny thing is now, every single day as an editor, I get sent probably 10 to 20 free things – clothes, shoes, all the stuff I used to buy – and now I pretty much give it all away to my team. I don’t need stuff any more. I used to think I was going to work to be successful to buy more stuff, and now as I’m getting a level of success I actually don’t want stuff. I’m living more and more simply now that I’m more fulfilled in my work. Has success changed you? I hope not. I don’t feel any different. I feel this is the start of a very big vision and I don’t want to get complacent or egotistical. It’s not why I started. The moment we forget why we started something, then it can all fall apart. Top tip? Have an unwavering self-belief. You might knock on 80 doors and all but one will get slammed in your face. You’ve got to have that tenacity to keep going. Have a really clear vision and understand your “why”: why are you doing this? That’s the one question I ask myself every day. And hustle. You’ve got to get out there and work your butt off. How do you measure success in other people? My biggest measure of success is seeing others use their talents and step into their own purpose. Once they do that, I view them as successful because they’re living their best life and following their passion. That is true success in my eyes. 
Take her “entrepreneurial and lifestyle” magazine, Collective Hub, 
“I had no idea what I was doing,” she says. 
collectivehub.com 
“I had no idea about online or digital,” she says. “I learnt the mechanics and put a team in place.” 
Daring and Disruptive 
We meet at The Weekly Review 
The day before our interview, she says, John Cleese rang her. On another occasion American Vogue’s 
“People asked me what I was going to wear. I said, ‘I don’t care what I’m going to wear, I’m worried about what’s going to come out of my brain!’ ” 
Collective Hub 
Under its banner she runs 18 business arms including a multi-media business comprising the monthly print magazine, online news site, an event company, a custom publishing unit, an online store offering products such as candles, towels and diaries as well as links to Lisa’s speaking engagements and conferences or festivals. 
Marriage and Motherhood 
The book outlines the break-up with “the man of my absolute dreams” who walked out “six days after we had just moved into our dream apartment together”. The book’s title needed to change, and it did, to Break-ups and Breakthroughs: turn an endi . 
Geared towards the positive but not afraid to confront the negative, it says a lot about Lisa’s outlook on the world and goes a long way to explaining her crash-or-crash-through multi-platform success. 
Life Love had just gone to number one on Booktopia, the magazine was doing really well, “things were starting to move, then this break-up came out of the blue and dropped me to my knees. I couldn’t brush it under the carpet. It’s really inauthentic if I didn’t say, ‘Actually, I went through tough stuff too’.” 
She says writing about the break-up was “kind of hideous and kind of extraordinarily cathartic”. 
Collective Hub 
Central to her philosophy is non-conformism, doing things differently, testing an idea without fear of its failure. JOHN BERTRAND John Bertrand. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
SECRETS OF MY SUCCESS: 
SECRETS OF MY SUCCESS: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.87</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/secrets-of-my-success-lisa-messenger/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Peter Wilmoth THE SECRETS OF LISA When did you first realise you were successful? Collective a lot of stuff. When you’re not completely fulfilled in your life – this was true for me – you go out and buy clothes or shoes or whatever and it’s instant gratification. The funny thing is now, every single day as an editor, I get sent probably 10 to 20 free things – clothes, shoes, all the stuff I used to buy – and now I pretty much give it all away to my team. I don’t need stuff any more. I used to think I was going to work to be successful to buy more stuff, and now as I’m getting a level of success I actually don’t want stuff. I’m living more and more simply now that I’m more fulfilled in my work. Has success changed you? I hope not. I don’t feel any different. I feel this is the start of a very big vision and I don’t want to get complacent or egotistical. It’s not why I started. The moment we forget why we started something, then it can all fall apart. Top tip? Have an unwavering self-belief. You might knock on 80 doors and all but one will get slammed in your face. You’ve got to have that tenacity to keep going. Have a really clear vision and understand your “why”: why are you doing this? That’s the one question I ask myself every day. And hustle. You’ve got to get out there and work your butt off. How do you measure success in other people? My biggest measure of success is seeing others use their talents and step into their own purpose. Once they do that, I view them as successful because they’re living their best life and following their passion. That is true success in my eyes. 
Take her “entrepreneurial and lifestyle” magazine, Collective Hub, 
“I had no idea what I was doing,” she says. 
collectivehub.com 
“I had no idea about online or digital,” she says. “I learnt the mechanics and put a team in place.” 
Daring and Disruptive 
We meet at The Weekly Review 
The day before our interview, she says, John Cleese rang her. On another occasion American Vogue’s 
“People asked me what I was going to wear. I said, ‘I don’t care what I’m going to wear, I’m worried about what’s going to come out of my brain!’ ” 
Collective Hub 
Under its banner she runs 18 business arms including a multi-media business comprising the monthly print magazine, online news site, an event company, a custom publishing unit, an online store offering products such as candles, towels and diaries as well as links to Lisa’s speaking engagements and conferences or festivals. 
Marriage and Motherhood 
The book outlines the break-up with “the man of my absolute dreams” who walked out “six days after we had just moved into our dream apartment together”. The book’s title needed to change, and it did, to Break-ups and Breakthroughs: turn an endi . 
Geared towards the positive but not afraid to confront the negative, it says a lot about Lisa’s outlook on the world and goes a long way to explaining her crash-or-crash-through multi-platform success. 
Life Love had just gone to number one on Booktopia, the magazine was doing really well, “things were starting to move, then this break-up came out of the blue and dropped me to my knees. I couldn’t brush it under the carpet. It’s really inauthentic if I didn’t say, ‘Actually, I went through tough stuff too’.” 
She says writing about the break-up was “kind of hideous and kind of extraordinarily cathartic”. 
Collective Hub 
Central to her philosophy is non-conformism, doing things differently, testing an idea without fear of its failure. JOHN BERTRAND John Bertrand. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
SECRETS OF MY SUCCESS: 
SECRETS OF MY SUCCESS: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Lisa-Messenger-14.jpg</main_image>
</document>
