<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://news.yahoo.com/sitemap/stories/7.xml</forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>USA rout Spain for sixth women&apos;s basketball gold in a row</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://news.yahoo.com/us-women-rout-spain-win-sixth-straight-basketball-202210189--nba.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Rio de Janeiro (AFP) - Staking its claim to rank among the greatest women&apos;s basketball teams ever assembled, the United States captured a sixth consecutive Olympic gold medal and eighth in nine tries on Sunday.
An overwhelming 101-72 victory over Spain in the final stretched the US Olympic win streak to 49 games since a 1992 semi-final loss.
The Americans improved to 89-1 over the past 20 years in global tournaments.
&quot;I&apos;m pretty sure we demonstrated we are one of the best teams ever,&quot; US guard Sue Bird said.
Diana Taurasi and Lindsay Whalen led the US squad with 17 points each in the final while Maya Moore added 14.
&quot;It&apos;s pretty incredible,&quot; Taurasi said. &quot;We had a goal to win the gold medal but there&apos;s something more to it than that.
&quot;It&apos;s not about one person, one coach -- it&apos;s about, &apos;How can we make this the best basketball team ever?&apos;&quot;
US stars Taurasi, Bird and Tamika Catchings matched an Olympic basketball record with their fourth gold medals each, tying ex-US standouts Lisa Leslie and Teresa Edwards for most golds by a player, man or woman.
&quot;Super special,&quot; Moore said. &quot;I feel so privileged to have those leaders ahead of me, to watch them, play alongside them, to just learn so that in the future when I&apos;m in moments where leadership is needed, I can call on memories I&apos;ve had with them.&quot;
The only longer team Olympic gold-medal run than the US women&apos;s six is that of the US men&apos;s basketball team, which took the first seven Olympic titles.
&quot;That&apos;s unreal,&quot; said US forward Angel McCoughtry.
Spain&apos;s silver is the first Olympic women&apos;s basketball medal secured by the Spaniards, whose best prior showing was fifth in 1992 and 2008.
&quot;It&apos;s historic for our country. For me, it&apos;s a dream come true,&quot; said Alba Torrens , who led Spain with 18 points.
&quot;This medal pays off so much work these past years.&quot;
Serbia beat France 70-63 in the bronze medal game.
The championship game was a rematch of the 2014 Women&apos;s Basketball World Cup final won by the Americans 77-64, but it more resembled the US women&apos;s 103-63 rout of Spain in a Rio group stage encounter as the US women improved to 10-0 all-time against their European rivals.
&quot;It&apos;s a Dream Team, best team in the world,&quot; Spain guard Silvia Dominguez said.
&quot;In a few years maybe we can beat them,&quot; said Spanish forward Laura Quevedo. &quot;Right now it&apos;s a Dream Team.&quot;
Torrens scored 10 points in the first eight minutes to give her team its largest lead at 17-14.
The Americans answered with a 10-0 run for a 24-17 edge on a 3-pointer from Bird, back from a right knee injury.
Astou Ndour&apos;s 3-pointer pulled Spain within 27-24 but the US responded with a 14-2 run for a 41-26 edge. Taurasi made two 3-pointers in the spurt and Moore and Breanna Stewart each added four points.
Whalen sank a fast break layup at the half-time buzzer to give the Americans their largest lead yet at 49-32 and Spain never trailed by less again.
Dominguez sank a half-court 3-pointer at the third-period buzzer, but it only pulled Spain within 81-49 as the Americans would not be denied.
&quot;My first gold medal -- it means everything to me,&quot; said US center Brittney Griner. &quot;I can&apos;t believe it&apos;s on my neck.&quot;
- &apos;A storybook tournament&apos; -
As the US anthem finished, Taurasi smiled and screamed.
&quot;We&apos;ve sacrificed a lot for this moment and I&apos;m so happy,&quot; said Taurasi, who averaged a team-high 15.6 points a game.
&quot;She had just a storybook tournament people will be talking about for a long time,&quot; US coach Geno Auriemma said.
At 34, Taurasi was expected to call it quits, but said, &quot;We&apos;ll see. I&apos;ll leave the door open.&quot;
</topic_text>
<spam_score>1.00</spam_score>
<post_num>3</post_num>
<post_id>post-3</post_id>
<post_url>https://news.yahoo.com/us-women-rout-spain-win-sixth-straight-basketball-202210189--nba.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1856</post_time>
<username>Anonymous</username>
<post>
Nice. USA Baby!
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://s.yimg.com/uu/api/res/1.2/11KqXBwgWtPmmrlwM24uEw--/aD02ODI7dz0xMDI0O3NtPTE7YXBwaWQ9eXRhY2h5b24-/http://media.zenfs.com/en_us/News/afp.com/40fe50054182fc5768d197d66eb6aaa53ffd02a6.jpg</main_image>
</document>
