<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.careerbuilder.com/RTQ/rss20.aspx?rssid=RSS_PD&amp;num=25&amp;geoip=false&amp;ddcompany=false&amp;ddtitle=false&amp;cat=JN070</forum>
<forum_title>Latest CareerBuilder Jobs</forum_title>
<discussion_title>SPX Technical Director</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3K1LG6BHD395LZ3P2J</topic_url>
<topic_text>
How Do You Compare to the Competition? Get facts about other applicants with a CareerBuilder Account Sign Up Job Description The Sensor Processing and Exploitation Technical Group is seeking a Technical Director to lead our predictive analytics efforts with a preliminary focus on the space domain. The Director of the Special Activity Exploitation (SAX) Directorate will report directly to the Director of the Sensor Processing and Exploitation (SPX) Technology Group (TGD). This position includes profit and loss responsibility for the SAX Directorate. Responsibilities include:Define and execute the annual strategy for the SAX Directorate. Develop annual business plan and manage the business to meet or exceed the plan. Track progress to towards that plan on a regular basis. Key elements of the business plan include funding, sales, profit, new business funds, directorate expense and staff utilization planning and management. Provide advice and counsel to SPX Director and Sr. Leadership. Provide leadership oversight and active engagement in the development and pursuit of business opportunities for the SAX Directorate. Develop relationships with Defense and Intelligence customers in the SAX R&amp;D market segment to create and shape new business opportunities. Provide leadership oversight and active engagement in the preparation of technical, management and cost proposals. Manage new business funds allocated to the directorate. Maintain cognizance of corporate capabilities and identify new business leads for other Directorates, Technology Groups and Business Areas. Ensure the successful execution of all programs led by the SAX Directorate. Ensure all programs are executed in accordance with Technology Solutions Program Management Policies. Coordinate efforts across multiple projects, within and outside of the Directorate. Lead the pursuit of follow-on business opportunities. Support cross Directorate, Tech Group and Business Area programs.Proactively engage with BAE Systems Business Areas to facilitate transition of SAX technology to BAE Systems products. Build relationships with Business Area technical and management staff to facilitate technology transition and collaboration. This includes early engagement on major R&amp;D pursuits, coordinating blended teams for execution of R&amp;D projects and coordinating roadmaps and investments to facilitate transition of technology for Business Area leverage.Work with the SPX leadership team to actively manage and develop talent within the SAX Directorate. Work with HR and the SPX Director to prepare salary and compensation review recommendations. Develop performance goals for the staff and conduct annual performance appraisals.   Strong technical expertise in predictive analytics, Indications and Warnings, and Space Situational Awareness. Domain expertise in Intelligence Surveillance and Reconnaissance for Defense and Intelligence applications Active TS/SCI Familiarity with equipment and processes; ability to provide technical inputs, logical thinking, forethought of action, analytical ability, demonstrated ability to work in team, initiative, versatility, moderate troubleshooting skills, strong communication skills, process improvement mindset, ability to understand and follow procedures Preferred Skills and Education Proven experience in sponsored R&amp;D for the Intelligence and DoD Communities. Demonstrated experience in developing customer relationships and winning new business with IC and DoD Customers About BAE Systems Electronic Systems BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services.The Electronic Systems (ES) sector spans the commercial and defense electronics markets with a broad portfolio of mission-critical electronic systems, including flight and engine controls; electronic warfare and night vision systems; surveillance and reconnaissance sensors; secure networked communications equipment; geospatial imagery intelligence products and systems; mission management; and power-and energy-management systems. Headquartered in Nashua, New Hampshire, ES employs approximately 13,000 people globally, with engineering and manufacturing functions primarily in the United States, United Kingdom, and Israel. Equal Opportunity Employer/Females/Minorities/Veterans/Disabled/Sexual Orientation/Gender Identity/Gender Expression EEO Career Site Equal Opportunity Employer. Minorities . females . veterans . individuals with disabilities . sexual orientation . gender identity . gender expression Department
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3K1LG6BHD395LZ3P2J</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0712</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
How Do You Compare to the Competition? Get facts about other applicants with a CareerBuilder Account Sign Up Job Description The Sensor Processing and Exploitation Technical Group is seeking a Technical Director to lead our predictive analytics efforts with a preliminary focus on the space domain. The Director of the Special Activity Exploitation (SAX) Directorate will report directly to the Director of the Sensor Processing and Exploitation (SPX) Technology Group (TGD). This position includes profit and loss responsibility for the SAX Directorate. Responsibilities include:Define and execute the annual strategy for the SAX Directorate. Develop annual business plan and manage the business to meet or exceed the plan. Track progress to towards that plan on a regular basis. Key elements of the business plan include funding, sales, profit, new business funds, directorate expense and staff utilization planning and management. Provide advice and counsel to SPX Director and Sr. Leadership. Provide leadership oversight and active engagement in the development and pursuit of business opportunities for the SAX Directorate. Develop relationships with Defense and Intelligence customers in the SAX R&amp;D market segment to create and shape new business opportunities. Provide leadership oversight and active engagement in the preparation of technical, management and cost proposals. Manage new business funds allocated to the directorate. Maintain cognizance of corporate capabilities and identify new business leads for other Directorates, Technology Groups and Business Areas. Ensure the successful execution of all programs led by the SAX Directorate. Ensure all programs are executed in accordance with Technology Solutions Program Management Policies. Coordinate efforts across multiple projects, within and outside of the Directorate. Lead the pursuit of follow-on business opportunities. Support cross Directorate, Tech Group and Business Area programs.Proactively engage with BAE Systems Business Areas to facilitate transition of SAX technology to BAE Systems products. Build relationships with Business Area technical and management staff to facilitate technology transition and collaboration. This includes early engagement on major R&amp;D pursuits, coordinating blended teams for execution of R&amp;D projects and coordinating roadmaps and investments to facilitate transition of technology for Business Area leverage.Work with the SPX leadership team to actively manage and develop talent within the SAX Directorate. Work with HR and the SPX Director to prepare salary and compensation review recommendations. Develop performance goals for the staff and conduct annual performance appraisals.   Strong technical expertise in predictive analytics, Indications and Warnings, and Space Situational Awareness. Domain expertise in Intelligence Surveillance and Reconnaissance for Defense and Intelligence applications Active TS/SCI Familiarity with equipment and processes; ability to provide technical inputs, logical thinking, forethought of action, analytical ability, demonstrated ability to work in team, initiative, versatility, moderate troubleshooting skills, strong communication skills, process improvement mindset, ability to understand and follow procedures Preferred Skills and Education Proven experience in sponsored R&amp;D for the Intelligence and DoD Communities. Demonstrated experience in developing customer relationships and winning new business with IC and DoD Customers About BAE Systems Electronic Systems BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services.The Electronic Systems (ES) sector spans the commercial and defense electronics markets with a broad portfolio of mission-critical electronic systems, including flight and engine controls; electronic warfare and night vision systems; surveillance and reconnaissance sensors; secure networked communications equipment; geospatial imagery intelligence products and systems; mission management; and power-and energy-management systems. Headquartered in Nashua, New Hampshire, ES employs approximately 13,000 people globally, with engineering and manufacturing functions primarily in the United States, United Kingdom, and Israel. Equal Opportunity Employer/Females/Minorities/Veterans/Disabled/Sexual Orientation/Gender Identity/Gender Expression EEO Career Site Equal Opportunity Employer. Minorities . females . veterans . individuals with disabilities . sexual orientation . gender identity . gender expression Department
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
