<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.careerbuilder.com/RTQ/rss20.aspx?rssid=RSS_PD&amp;num=25&amp;geoip=false&amp;ddcompany=false&amp;ddtitle=false&amp;cat=JN070</forum>
<forum_title>Latest CareerBuilder Jobs</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Program Controls Analyst</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3G7SH6JW7BQBYP5YPC</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Government - Federal Job Description Responsible for preparing the Minneapolis Paladin PIM IWO deliverables (Cost Performance Report &amp; Contract Funds Status Report), conducting and coordinating Earned Value Management Responsibilities(EVMS) responsibilities for Control Account Managers (CAM&apos;s) and Work Package (WP) Managers assigned. Responsibilities include: Detail planning to set the baseline, development of performance metrics to objectively claim performance , understands the actual costs charged and overhead rates applied, and facilitates development and analysis of estimates to complete. Responsible for coordinating and consolidating monthly Format 5 Variance analysis (IWO). Coordinates rolling wave planning activities and bottoms up Comprehensive Estimate at Complete (CEAC) development with CAM&apos;s and WP Managers. Leads the development and processing of Baseline Change Notices (BCN&apos;s) and insures processing through internal systems. These positions also supports subcontract EVMS management and assists with other financial duties as assigned. This position will charge direct 72% of the time and supports the Paladin PIM Program and Indirect financial forecast duties. Minimum Education and Experience Bachelor&apos;s Degree and 2 years work experience or equivalent experience   Knowledge - Frequent use and general knowledge of industry practices, techniques and standards. General application of concepts and principles Problem Solving - Develops solutions to a variety of problems of moderate scope and complexity. Refers to policies and practices for guidance. Discretion/Latitude- Works under only very general supervision. Work is reviewed for soundness of judgment and overall adequacy and accuracy. Impact - Contributes to the completion of organizational projects and goals. Errors in judgment or failure to achieve results would normally require moderate expenditure of resources to rectify. Liason - Frequent internal company and external contacts. Represents organization on specific projects. Preferred Skills and Education Business Administration degree in Accounting or Finance. Previous defense experience a plus. Strong computer skills and ability to work with teams to produce high quality reports in accordance with program deadlines. About BAE Systems Platforms &amp; Services Posting BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. With headquarters in Arlington, Virginia, this Platform and Services Group of BAE Systems employs nearly 11,000 professionals at more than 30 locations worldwide. Platform and Services is a global leader in the design, development, production, and service support of armored combat vehicles, major and minor caliber naval guns and missile launchers, canisters, artillery systems, and intelligent munitions. People are the greatest asset in any Company. Equal Opportunity Employer/Females/Minorities/Veterans/Disabled/Sexual Orientation/Gender Identity/Gender Expression EEO Career Site Equal Opportunity Employer. Minorities . females . veterans . individuals with disabilities . sexual orientation . gender identity . gender expression Department
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3G7SH6JW7BQBYP5YPC</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0712</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Government - Federal Job Description Responsible for preparing the Minneapolis Paladin PIM IWO deliverables (Cost Performance Report &amp; Contract Funds Status Report), conducting and coordinating Earned Value Management Responsibilities(EVMS) responsibilities for Control Account Managers (CAM&apos;s) and Work Package (WP) Managers assigned. Responsibilities include: Detail planning to set the baseline, development of performance metrics to objectively claim performance , understands the actual costs charged and overhead rates applied, and facilitates development and analysis of estimates to complete. Responsible for coordinating and consolidating monthly Format 5 Variance analysis (IWO). Coordinates rolling wave planning activities and bottoms up Comprehensive Estimate at Complete (CEAC) development with CAM&apos;s and WP Managers. Leads the development and processing of Baseline Change Notices (BCN&apos;s) and insures processing through internal systems. These positions also supports subcontract EVMS management and assists with other financial duties as assigned. This position will charge direct 72% of the time and supports the Paladin PIM Program and Indirect financial forecast duties. Minimum Education and Experience Bachelor&apos;s Degree and 2 years work experience or equivalent experience   Knowledge - Frequent use and general knowledge of industry practices, techniques and standards. General application of concepts and principles Problem Solving - Develops solutions to a variety of problems of moderate scope and complexity. Refers to policies and practices for guidance. Discretion/Latitude- Works under only very general supervision. Work is reviewed for soundness of judgment and overall adequacy and accuracy. Impact - Contributes to the completion of organizational projects and goals. Errors in judgment or failure to achieve results would normally require moderate expenditure of resources to rectify. Liason - Frequent internal company and external contacts. Represents organization on specific projects. Preferred Skills and Education Business Administration degree in Accounting or Finance. Previous defense experience a plus. Strong computer skills and ability to work with teams to produce high quality reports in accordance with program deadlines. About BAE Systems Platforms &amp; Services Posting BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. With headquarters in Arlington, Virginia, this Platform and Services Group of BAE Systems employs nearly 11,000 professionals at more than 30 locations worldwide. Platform and Services is a global leader in the design, development, production, and service support of armored combat vehicles, major and minor caliber naval guns and missile launchers, canisters, artillery systems, and intelligent munitions. People are the greatest asset in any Company. Equal Opportunity Employer/Females/Minorities/Veterans/Disabled/Sexual Orientation/Gender Identity/Gender Expression EEO Career Site Equal Opportunity Employer. Minorities . females . veterans . individuals with disabilities . sexual orientation . gender identity . gender expression Department
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
