<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.briefreport.co.uk/feed.rss</forum>
<forum_title>BriefReport.co.uk</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Lancashire police to recruit more armed officers</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.briefreport.co.uk/news/lancashire-police-to-recruit-more-armed-officers-4354979.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Search Lancashire police to recruit more armed officers 
Police chiefs in Lancashire have launched a drive to recruit more trained armed officers to respond to serious incidents. The constabulary has advertised vacancies for a number of Armed Response Vehicle officers. Trained officers from other forces throughout England and Wales have been invited to apply. Last month, it was reported that 1,500 more armed officers are to be deployed on Britain’s streets, following the extremist attacks in France earlier this year. Eighty-four people died when a lorry was driven into a crowd celebrating Bastille Day in Nice in July. Already, 600 new armed... read more County has enough armed officers to deal with attack 
The number of armed police officers in Cumbria is not going up – despite a rise nationally. Cumbria police says it has enough armed officers to cope if a response is needed after a terror attack. A force spokesman said: “We maintain a sufficient... News &amp; Star , 5 August 2016 in Regional North West County has enough armed officers to deal with attack 
The number of armed police officers in Cumbria is not going up – despite a rise nationally. Cumbria police says it has enough armed officers to cope if a response is needed after a terror attack. A force spokesman said: “We maintain a sufficient... Cumberland News , 5 August 2016 in Regional North West Lancashire police officer faces sack in booze shame 
A Lancashire police officer has been convicted of drink driving while on duty after a court heard he was sinking a bottle of vodka a day. Iain Norton, 41, is now facing the sack from Lancashire Police after being caught drink driving behind the wheel...
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.briefreport.co.uk/news/lancashire-police-to-recruit-more-armed-officers-4354979.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0756</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Search Lancashire police to recruit more armed officers 
Police chiefs in Lancashire have launched a drive to recruit more trained armed officers to respond to serious incidents. The constabulary has advertised vacancies for a number of Armed Response Vehicle officers. Trained officers from other forces throughout England and Wales have been invited to apply. Last month, it was reported that 1,500 more armed officers are to be deployed on Britain’s streets, following the extremist attacks in France earlier this year. Eighty-four people died when a lorry was driven into a crowd celebrating Bastille Day in Nice in July. Already, 600 new armed... read more County has enough armed officers to deal with attack 
The number of armed police officers in Cumbria is not going up – despite a rise nationally. Cumbria police says it has enough armed officers to cope if a response is needed after a terror attack. A force spokesman said: “We maintain a sufficient... News &amp; Star , 5 August 2016 in Regional North West County has enough armed officers to deal with attack 
The number of armed police officers in Cumbria is not going up – despite a rise nationally. Cumbria police says it has enough armed officers to cope if a response is needed after a terror attack. A force spokesman said: “We maintain a sufficient... Cumberland News , 5 August 2016 in Regional North West Lancashire police officer faces sack in booze shame 
A Lancashire police officer has been convicted of drink driving while on duty after a court heard he was sinking a bottle of vodka a day. Iain Norton, 41, is now facing the sack from Lancashire Police after being caught drink driving behind the wheel...
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
