<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mowgli expands: Five more restaurants that should open in Liverpool business district - Liverpool Echo</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.liverpoolecho.co.uk/news/liverpool-news/mowgli-expands-five-more-restaurants-11133943</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Mowgli expands: Five more restaurants that should open in Liverpool business district 12:00, 4 Apr 2016 What would office workers like to see in their end of town? Shares Get daily news by email Nisha Katona has opened a new restaurant on Bold Street called Mowgli. 
Mowgli is set to open a second Liverpool restaurant in the business district , sparing the city’s legal eagles and office walkers the 15-20 minute trek up to Bold Street for their fix of Indian street food. 
And that got us thinking - which other restaurants should look at opening in this part of town? 
Castle Street is hugely popular with restaurateurs and bars at the moment, with recent openings from Cau, Pinch and Veeno, as well as a planned pizza and cocktail place from the team behind Salt Dog Slims and a new Neighbourhood in the vacant 62 Castle Street unit. 
So here are a few others we think would do well in the business district. Admittedly, if they opened here they’d be just a stone’s throw from the ECHO offices on Old Hall Street, and as we love our food, that’s never a bad thing. 
Any more suggestions? Let us know by tweeting @livechonews 1. Maray 
Maray restaurant on Bold Street, Liverpool. 
Jay Rayner loves it, and its name comes from the historic Marais district in Paris full of buildings of architectural importance. Liverpool’s business district might not have the same bohemian roots, but we have our fair share of historic buildings and we love to eat. And falafel and small plates are perfect for a quick lunchtime bite to eat. 2. Bakchich 
Amine Elgueddar and Otto Mellouki at Bakchich 
Street food again - this time Lebanese. It’s perfect for a quick bite to eat at lunchtime or after work, and we think Bakchich would be popular in the business end of town. 3. Nolita Cantina 
Nolita Cantina Restaurant &amp; Bar on Bold Street 
Liverpool loves burgers, and Nolita Cantina serves up some of the best in the city. Wall of Fame on Victoria Street is an easy walk, but we’d like to see more bunfights over burger lovers in this part of town. 4. Wahaca 
Mexican bar and restaurant Wahaca opens in Liverpool. Pictured: Gavin Smith, Operations. Photo by Ian Cooper 
If Mowgli can bring Indian street food to the business district, why not Mexican street food? Wahaca’s mouthwatering menu of tacos, burritos, salads is now being served on College Lane in Liverpool One, but they would be welcome to spice up our lives on the other side of town. 5. Lucha Libre 
Taco Day at Lucha Libre Wood Street Liverpool. Sous Chef Phil Schofield with Taco Platter. 
Lucha Libre could make a whole load of new amigos by coming to the business district. The Mexican street food specialists - who also serve up a pretty awesome frozen margharita - are on Wood Street but that 25 minute walk isn’t an option for Liverpool’s hungry office workers. And those beers and cocktails would go down very well on a Friday after work. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.05</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.liverpoolecho.co.uk/news/liverpool-news/mowgli-expands-five-more-restaurants-11133943</post_url>
<post_date>20160404</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Lorna Hughes</username>
<post>
Mowgli expands: Five more restaurants that should open in Liverpool business district 12:00, 4 Apr 2016 What would office workers like to see in their end of town? Shares Get daily news by email Nisha Katona has opened a new restaurant on Bold Street called Mowgli. 
Mowgli is set to open a second Liverpool restaurant in the business district , sparing the city’s legal eagles and office walkers the 15-20 minute trek up to Bold Street for their fix of Indian street food. 
And that got us thinking - which other restaurants should look at opening in this part of town? 
Castle Street is hugely popular with restaurateurs and bars at the moment, with recent openings from Cau, Pinch and Veeno, as well as a planned pizza and cocktail place from the team behind Salt Dog Slims and a new Neighbourhood in the vacant 62 Castle Street unit. 
So here are a few others we think would do well in the business district. Admittedly, if they opened here they’d be just a stone’s throw from the ECHO offices on Old Hall Street, and as we love our food, that’s never a bad thing. 
Any more suggestions? Let us know by tweeting @livechonews 1. Maray 
Maray restaurant on Bold Street, Liverpool. 
Jay Rayner loves it, and its name comes from the historic Marais district in Paris full of buildings of architectural importance. Liverpool’s business district might not have the same bohemian roots, but we have our fair share of historic buildings and we love to eat. And falafel and small plates are perfect for a quick lunchtime bite to eat. 2. Bakchich 
Amine Elgueddar and Otto Mellouki at Bakchich 
Street food again - this time Lebanese. It’s perfect for a quick bite to eat at lunchtime or after work, and we think Bakchich would be popular in the business end of town. 3. Nolita Cantina 
Nolita Cantina Restaurant &amp; Bar on Bold Street 
Liverpool loves burgers, and Nolita Cantina serves up some of the best in the city. Wall of Fame on Victoria Street is an easy walk, but we’d like to see more bunfights over burger lovers in this part of town. 4. Wahaca 
Mexican bar and restaurant Wahaca opens in Liverpool. Pictured: Gavin Smith, Operations. Photo by Ian Cooper 
If Mowgli can bring Indian street food to the business district, why not Mexican street food? Wahaca’s mouthwatering menu of tacos, burritos, salads is now being served on College Lane in Liverpool One, but they would be welcome to spice up our lives on the other side of town. 5. Lucha Libre 
Taco Day at Lucha Libre Wood Street Liverpool. Sous Chef Phil Schofield with Taco Platter. 
Lucha Libre could make a whole load of new amigos by coming to the business district. The Mexican street food specialists - who also serve up a pretty awesome frozen margharita - are on Wood Street but that 25 minute walk isn’t an option for Liverpool’s hungry office workers. And those beers and cocktails would go down very well on a Friday after work. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://i4.liverpoolecho.co.uk/incoming/article11134010.ece/ALTERNATES/s1200/JS49113694.jpg</main_image>
</document>
