<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.cisionwire.com/rss/all-information/</forum>
<forum_title>Cision News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Welsh travel experts extend sponsorship of rugby giants</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://news.cision.com/dakota-digitalltd/r/welsh-travel-experts-extend-sponsorship-of-rugby-giants,c2062114</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Welsh travel experts extend sponsorship of rugby giants Mon, Aug 22, 2016 04:00 EST 
After Wales’ success in the European Football Tournament, the country is set to be gripped by their first sport as the Welsh Rugby season kicks off in September. And one company who can’t wait for the new season is holiday experts, Leisuretime. 
The leading provider of premier coach trips to the UK, Europe beyond, has extended its sponsorship of Merthyr RFC, one of the biggest clubs in Wales, and will be the title sponsor for the upcoming season, after previously partnering with the club over the last two years. Further cementing their long-standing relationship with the sporting team, the company is set to adorn the team’s shirts and work with them throughout the coming year. 
George Johnson, Director, said, “We are ecstatic to be extending our partnership with the team for the second year running. Rugby really is part of daily life for many here in Wales, and as one of the most successful businesses in south Wales, we are committed to giving back and supporting the community in South Wales and beyond.” 
Owned by Welsh businessman and property developer, Sir Stanley Thomas, Merthyr RFC had an incredible season last year. Finishing top of the WRU Championship, the team is now set to play in the Principality Premiership for the coming season. In order to get ready for their premier challenge, the team has lead the way and had a 4g pitch installed at their home, The Wern Sports Park. One of the first Welsh Rugby clubs to take the leap towards an artificial field, the players are ready and raring to go and tackle some of the finest teams in the world, including Newport, Cardiff and Ebbw Vale, and set to be thrust onto one of the biggest stages in rugby. 
Chanelle Murphy, Holiday Sales Consultant said “Our Coach Holiday Shop is located close to the Merthyr RFC ground in Merthyr town centre, so we can’t wait for the new season to kick off and hear the thousands of fans cheering on their local heroes.” 
To find out more about Leisuretime and the fantastic destinations they run holidays to, visit the website: www.leisuretime.co.uk . 
Keep up to date on social media:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://news.cision.com/dakota-digitalltd/r/welsh-travel-experts-extend-sponsorship-of-rugby-giants,c2062114</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0800</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Welsh travel experts extend sponsorship of rugby giants Mon, Aug 22, 2016 04:00 EST 
After Wales’ success in the European Football Tournament, the country is set to be gripped by their first sport as the Welsh Rugby season kicks off in September. And one company who can’t wait for the new season is holiday experts, Leisuretime. 
The leading provider of premier coach trips to the UK, Europe beyond, has extended its sponsorship of Merthyr RFC, one of the biggest clubs in Wales, and will be the title sponsor for the upcoming season, after previously partnering with the club over the last two years. Further cementing their long-standing relationship with the sporting team, the company is set to adorn the team’s shirts and work with them throughout the coming year. 
George Johnson, Director, said, “We are ecstatic to be extending our partnership with the team for the second year running. Rugby really is part of daily life for many here in Wales, and as one of the most successful businesses in south Wales, we are committed to giving back and supporting the community in South Wales and beyond.” 
Owned by Welsh businessman and property developer, Sir Stanley Thomas, Merthyr RFC had an incredible season last year. Finishing top of the WRU Championship, the team is now set to play in the Principality Premiership for the coming season. In order to get ready for their premier challenge, the team has lead the way and had a 4g pitch installed at their home, The Wern Sports Park. One of the first Welsh Rugby clubs to take the leap towards an artificial field, the players are ready and raring to go and tackle some of the finest teams in the world, including Newport, Cardiff and Ebbw Vale, and set to be thrust onto one of the biggest stages in rugby. 
Chanelle Murphy, Holiday Sales Consultant said “Our Coach Holiday Shop is located close to the Merthyr RFC ground in Merthyr town centre, so we can’t wait for the new season to kick off and hear the thousands of fans cheering on their local heroes.” 
To find out more about Leisuretime and the fantastic destinations they run holidays to, visit the website: www.leisuretime.co.uk . 
Keep up to date on social media:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SE</country>
<main_image>http://mb.cision.com/Public/20/2062114/ba495948a2d9be54_400x400ar.jpg</main_image>
</document>
