<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Three ridiculously easy ways to multiply your Twitter followers – WELCOME TO PR BRAIN BUSTERS – 2800+ VIEWERS &amp; GROWING</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prbrainbusters.com/three-ridiculously-easy-ways-to-explode-your-number-of-twitter-followers/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Disclaimer Three ridiculously easy ways to multiply your Twitter followers 
Of all the social media platforms at play across the digital universe today, Twitter is one of the most popular and compelling. 
An estimated 310 million people use this social media channel each month, a number which is expected to continue growing. 
The most influential figures in the world – celebrities, politicians, journalists and business leaders – are using Twitter regularly to speak directly with their publics. Many of these figures have literally millions of Twitter followers. 
But most of us are not world famous and therefore need to take specific and consistent steps to grow our followers. 
Consistently growing your follower base is crucial in order for Twitter to be an effective tool for engagement and influence. This is not as challenging as it may seem. 
Here are three simple techniques to continuously grow your Twitter follower base: 
1, Tweet a lot, every day if possible 
The key to building your follower base on Twitter is getting noticed on a regular basis. The equation is simple: the more you tweet, the more you will appear across the Twitter feeds of other people. 
Explore the hashtags you are interested in, and add those hashtags to your tweets to inject yourself into specific conversations 
As people notice your tweets, they will see you as someone with something to say on a variety of topics. 
Also, the more you tweet the more your Twitter profile will emerge regularly in the “who to follow” suggestion list that appears at the top of the Twitter feeds of other users, making it easy for them to follow you. 
2, Follow back the people who follow you 
Twitter is a two-way street. When someone follows you, make sure you follow them back quickly, preferably within 24 hours. 
Many Twitter users, as a rule, will automatically unfollow those who fail to follow them back. 
3, Like and retweet other tweets 
When you see compelling content flowing across your Twitter feed, like and retweet the tweets you find interesting. 
This will easily and consistently raise your profile across Twitter and encourage people to follow you. 
PLEASE SHARE THIS POST WITH YOUR FRIENDS &amp; COLLEAGUES Share this: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.03</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prbrainbusters.com/three-ridiculously-easy-ways-to-explode-your-number-of-twitter-followers/</post_url>
<post_date>20160621</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>View All Posts Andrew Pelletier</username>
<post>
Disclaimer Three ridiculously easy ways to multiply your Twitter followers 
Of all the social media platforms at play across the digital universe today, Twitter is one of the most popular and compelling. 
An estimated 310 million people use this social media channel each month, a number which is expected to continue growing. 
The most influential figures in the world – celebrities, politicians, journalists and business leaders – are using Twitter regularly to speak directly with their publics. Many of these figures have literally millions of Twitter followers. 
But most of us are not world famous and therefore need to take specific and consistent steps to grow our followers. 
Consistently growing your follower base is crucial in order for Twitter to be an effective tool for engagement and influence. This is not as challenging as it may seem. 
Here are three simple techniques to continuously grow your Twitter follower base: 
1, Tweet a lot, every day if possible 
The key to building your follower base on Twitter is getting noticed on a regular basis. The equation is simple: the more you tweet, the more you will appear across the Twitter feeds of other people. 
Explore the hashtags you are interested in, and add those hashtags to your tweets to inject yourself into specific conversations 
As people notice your tweets, they will see you as someone with something to say on a variety of topics. 
Also, the more you tweet the more your Twitter profile will emerge regularly in the “who to follow” suggestion list that appears at the top of the Twitter feeds of other users, making it easy for them to follow you. 
2, Follow back the people who follow you 
Twitter is a two-way street. When someone follows you, make sure you follow them back quickly, preferably within 24 hours. 
Many Twitter users, as a rule, will automatically unfollow those who fail to follow them back. 
3, Like and retweet other tweets 
When you see compelling content flowing across your Twitter feed, like and retweet the tweets you find interesting. 
This will easily and consistently raise your profile across Twitter and encourage people to follow you. 
PLEASE SHARE THIS POST WITH YOUR FRIENDS &amp; COLLEAGUES Share this: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.prbrainbusters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/QYQWBJP85R-300x225.jpg</main_image>
</document>
