<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://sport.stv.tv/football/champions-league/?format=rss</forum>
<forum_title>Scottish football and SPFL news | STV Sport</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Transfer Talk: Celtic resist chase for big names, Dons deal for McGinn</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://stv.tv/sport/football/1364754-transfer-talk-celtic-resist-chase-for-big-names-dons-deal-for-mcginn/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Transfer Talk: Celtic resist chase for big names, Dons deal for McGinn Laura Brannan Your daily round up of the latest movement around Scotland and beyond. Future: Niall McGinn is ready to commit to Aberdeen. SNS Group 
The countdown to deadline day has now entered single digits but that&apos;s not getting Celtic boss Brendan Rodgers in a sweat. 
He says even if Celtic qualify for the Champions League group stages on Tuesday evening he is not under any pressure to shop for big name signings. 
Former Celtic winger Niall McGinn looks set to commit his future to Aberdeen after expressing his desire to stay at Pittodrie. The club will enter talks with the Northern Ireland international who is out of contract at the end of the season. 
Meanwhile, former Hibernian midfielder Kevin Thomson has left Tranent Juniors just weeks after signing for the club due to media commitments. 
Down south there are reports that Chelsea are submitting a £60m offer for Real Madrid midfielder James Rodriguez, which would be a club record after Fernando Torres signed for £50m in 2013. 
It comes after their preferred target, Everton striker Roemlu Lukaku, pledged his future to the Toffees for another season. They are also said to be interested in Juventus striker Mario Mandzukic. Today&apos;s top stories Copyright © 20072016 STV. All rights reserved. Cookie Info: To find out how to manage cookies, see our cookie policy . One account. All of STV. Close Please enter your email address to sign in or join. This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. Welcome back! This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. Password This field is required. At least 6 characters please. Did you enter your details correctly?If you&apos;ve forgotten your details then use the &apos;Forgot password?&apos; link. Need to reset your password? We&apos;ll send a link to reset your password to Back We&apos;ve sent you details on how to reset your password Please check your email and follow the instructions. Forgotten your email address? Have you forgotten the email address that you previously joined with? Don&apos;t worry, by emailing we can help. Back One account. All of STV. Close This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. First name This field is required. Please enter at least 2 characters Last name This field is required. Please enter at least 2 characters Password At least 6 characters please Show Hide This field is required. At least 6 characters please. Date of Birth You have to be 16 or over to join This field is required. This doesn&apos;t appear to be a valid date Address Why do we need this? Type your full postcode and select your address This field is required. It doesn&apos;t look like you&apos;ve entered a valid postcode. Can&apos;t find your address? Confirm the details you&apos;ve given us are correct by clicking here Now that you&apos;ve joined STV, we&apos;ll be able to send you email updates about STV&apos;s programmes and services. If you don&apos;t want them, please tick this box. By continuing you agree to our Terms of Use , including our Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy . Any issues . Upload Profile Picture Close Please make sure your image is under 2mb in size and a valid JPG, PNG or GIF. Select file Are you sure? Close Unfortunately, you&apos;ll be unable to access our premium content. We’ll be sorry to see you go, but if you change your mind you can rejoin us at any time. Cancel Please verify your STV account Close Please verify your STV account using the email we sent you. If you have lost the email, we can send you another one, just click the button below. Thanks We&apos;ve sent you a new verification email.Please check your email and follow the instructions to verify your account. Close
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://stv.tv/sport/football/1364754-transfer-talk-celtic-resist-chase-for-big-names-dons-deal-for-mcginn/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0710</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Transfer Talk: Celtic resist chase for big names, Dons deal for McGinn Laura Brannan Your daily round up of the latest movement around Scotland and beyond. Future: Niall McGinn is ready to commit to Aberdeen. SNS Group 
The countdown to deadline day has now entered single digits but that&apos;s not getting Celtic boss Brendan Rodgers in a sweat. 
He says even if Celtic qualify for the Champions League group stages on Tuesday evening he is not under any pressure to shop for big name signings. 
Former Celtic winger Niall McGinn looks set to commit his future to Aberdeen after expressing his desire to stay at Pittodrie. The club will enter talks with the Northern Ireland international who is out of contract at the end of the season. 
Meanwhile, former Hibernian midfielder Kevin Thomson has left Tranent Juniors just weeks after signing for the club due to media commitments. 
Down south there are reports that Chelsea are submitting a £60m offer for Real Madrid midfielder James Rodriguez, which would be a club record after Fernando Torres signed for £50m in 2013. 
It comes after their preferred target, Everton striker Roemlu Lukaku, pledged his future to the Toffees for another season. They are also said to be interested in Juventus striker Mario Mandzukic. Today&apos;s top stories Copyright © 20072016 STV. All rights reserved. Cookie Info: To find out how to manage cookies, see our cookie policy . One account. All of STV. Close Please enter your email address to sign in or join. This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. Welcome back! This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. Password This field is required. At least 6 characters please. Did you enter your details correctly?If you&apos;ve forgotten your details then use the &apos;Forgot password?&apos; link. Need to reset your password? We&apos;ll send a link to reset your password to Back We&apos;ve sent you details on how to reset your password Please check your email and follow the instructions. Forgotten your email address? Have you forgotten the email address that you previously joined with? Don&apos;t worry, by emailing we can help. Back One account. All of STV. Close This field is required. That doesn&apos;t look like a valid e-mail format, please check. That e-mail&apos;s already in our system. Please try again. First name This field is required. Please enter at least 2 characters Last name This field is required. Please enter at least 2 characters Password At least 6 characters please Show Hide This field is required. At least 6 characters please. Date of Birth You have to be 16 or over to join This field is required. This doesn&apos;t appear to be a valid date Address Why do we need this? Type your full postcode and select your address This field is required. It doesn&apos;t look like you&apos;ve entered a valid postcode. Can&apos;t find your address? Confirm the details you&apos;ve given us are correct by clicking here Now that you&apos;ve joined STV, we&apos;ll be able to send you email updates about STV&apos;s programmes and services. If you don&apos;t want them, please tick this box. By continuing you agree to our Terms of Use , including our Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy . Any issues . Upload Profile Picture Close Please make sure your image is under 2mb in size and a valid JPG, PNG or GIF. Select file Are you sure? Close Unfortunately, you&apos;ll be unable to access our premium content. We’ll be sorry to see you go, but if you change your mind you can rejoin us at any time. Cancel Please verify your STV account Close Please verify your STV account using the email we sent you. If you have lost the email, we can send you another one, just click the button below. Thanks We&apos;ve sent you a new verification email.Please check your email and follow the instructions to verify your account. Close
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>TV</country>
<main_image>http://files.stv.tv/imagebase/364/w1280xh720xmFit/364391-niall-mcginn-aberdeen.jpg</main_image>
</document>
