<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Thyroid Storm: What You Need to Know - Medical News Today</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/312442.php</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Shaking Sweating 
A high fever is often one of the most common signs of thyroid storm. It may reach as high as 105-106°F. Diagnosis of thyroid storm 
There are no specific lab tests that can diagnose thyroid storm. The diagnosis is primarily up to the doctor. To diagnose thyroid storm, the doctor will look to see if the patient has any common symptoms of hyperthyroidism, high temperature, fast heart rate, or confusion. 
Blood tests can help signal high levels of thyroid hormones in the blood. The thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) test is also used. 
Thyroid storm is a very dangerous condition. In many cases, there is no time for blood tests. Instead, medical treatment is started immediately. Even with medical care, The University of California, San Diego Health Center state that the mortality rate of thyroid storm is between 20-30 percent . The disorder is particularly dangerous in older adults. Treatment for thyroid storm 
Treatment for thyroid storm depends on age, the cause, the severity of the illness, and any other medical conditions the patient may have. 
In many cases, the right treatment regime produces improvement within 24 hours. With continued treatment, thyroid storm is generally resolved within a week. Treatment options include: Beta-blockers to control symptoms like altered heart rate Iodine Glucocorticoids Propylthiouracil or methimazole 
According to The American Thyroid Association, more than 12 percent of the United States population will develop a thyroid condition during their lifetimes. Undiagnosed thyroid disease can increase the risk of osteoporosis , infertility , and heart disease . 
People with an overactive thyroid can help control their disorder by eating well, exercising, and keeping their stress levels down. 
Anyone that experiences any of the symptoms discussed should see a health professional immediately. Other disorders can mimic hyperthyroidism, so testing is often needed for a correct diagnosis. 
Quick treatment is vital to making sure that the body functions normally, but also prevents the onset of thyroid storm. Thyroid storm can be prevented by treating an overactive thyroid and following doctor&apos;s orders. What is Graves&apos; disease? 
Graves&apos; disease is the leading cause of hyperthyroidism. According to the Graves&apos; Disease and Thyroid Foundation, about 2-3 percent of the population - about 10 million people - have this disorder. 
The Virginia Mason Institute state that as many as 70-80 percent of patients with hyperthyroidism have Graves&apos; disease. It is an autoimmune condition where the immune system attacks the thyroid gland. In response, the thyroid makes too much thyroid hormone. 
The pituitary gland releases the hormone that helps control thyroid function. The thyrotropin receptor antibody (TRAb) is linked with Graves&apos; disease, and it works like the regulatory pituitary hormone. As a result, the TRAb overrides the normal regulation of the thyroid and causes hyperthyroidism. 
Anyone can develop Graves&apos; disease, but there are a number of factors that increase the risk, including: Women are more likely than men to develop Graves&apos; disease. A family history of Graves&apos; disease or other thyroid or autoimmune disorders Other autoimmune disorders: People inflicted with other immune disorders such as type 1 diabetes or rheumatoid arthritis have an increased risk Emotional or physical stress: Stressful life events or illnesses can trigger an onset of Graves&apos; disease Pregnancy: Pregnancy or a recent childbirth can increase the risk of the disorder in some women Smoking: Cigarette smoking can affect the immune system and increase the risk of Graves&apos; disease 
Women are also more likely to develop the disorder than men. According to the Office on Women&apos;s Health, it affects 10 times more women than men, and often strikes while they are in their 20s and 30s. Graves&apos; disease treatment 
Most people who have Graves&apos; disease have some symptoms of hyperthyroidism. A doctor will likely perform a physical exam as well as additional tests to help make a final diagnosis. These can include: Thyroid function tests Radioactive iodine uptake (RAIU) Antibody tests 
There are three main treatment options. Beta-blockers, which block the action of the thyroid hormone, are given. 
Two antithyroid medicine drugs are used in the U.S: methimazole and propylthiouracil. They help to keep the thyroid from making too much thyroid hormone. 
Radioactive iodine (RAI) treatment requires patients to swallow a pill that contains a form of iodine that damages the thyroid with radiation. By damaging thyroid cells, less thyroid hormones are made. 
In some cases, surgery is recommended where most of the thyroid is removed. Written by Brian Wu Click the stars to rate this article Thyroid Storm: What You Need to Know Public / Patient 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.03</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/312442.php</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Shaking Sweating 
A high fever is often one of the most common signs of thyroid storm. It may reach as high as 105-106°F. Diagnosis of thyroid storm 
There are no specific lab tests that can diagnose thyroid storm. The diagnosis is primarily up to the doctor. To diagnose thyroid storm, the doctor will look to see if the patient has any common symptoms of hyperthyroidism, high temperature, fast heart rate, or confusion. 
Blood tests can help signal high levels of thyroid hormones in the blood. The thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) test is also used. 
Thyroid storm is a very dangerous condition. In many cases, there is no time for blood tests. Instead, medical treatment is started immediately. Even with medical care, The University of California, San Diego Health Center state that the mortality rate of thyroid storm is between 20-30 percent . The disorder is particularly dangerous in older adults. Treatment for thyroid storm 
Treatment for thyroid storm depends on age, the cause, the severity of the illness, and any other medical conditions the patient may have. 
In many cases, the right treatment regime produces improvement within 24 hours. With continued treatment, thyroid storm is generally resolved within a week. Treatment options include: Beta-blockers to control symptoms like altered heart rate Iodine Glucocorticoids Propylthiouracil or methimazole 
According to The American Thyroid Association, more than 12 percent of the United States population will develop a thyroid condition during their lifetimes. Undiagnosed thyroid disease can increase the risk of osteoporosis , infertility , and heart disease . 
People with an overactive thyroid can help control their disorder by eating well, exercising, and keeping their stress levels down. 
Anyone that experiences any of the symptoms discussed should see a health professional immediately. Other disorders can mimic hyperthyroidism, so testing is often needed for a correct diagnosis. 
Quick treatment is vital to making sure that the body functions normally, but also prevents the onset of thyroid storm. Thyroid storm can be prevented by treating an overactive thyroid and following doctor&apos;s orders. What is Graves&apos; disease? 
Graves&apos; disease is the leading cause of hyperthyroidism. According to the Graves&apos; Disease and Thyroid Foundation, about 2-3 percent of the population - about 10 million people - have this disorder. 
The Virginia Mason Institute state that as many as 70-80 percent of patients with hyperthyroidism have Graves&apos; disease. It is an autoimmune condition where the immune system attacks the thyroid gland. In response, the thyroid makes too much thyroid hormone. 
The pituitary gland releases the hormone that helps control thyroid function. The thyrotropin receptor antibody (TRAb) is linked with Graves&apos; disease, and it works like the regulatory pituitary hormone. As a result, the TRAb overrides the normal regulation of the thyroid and causes hyperthyroidism. 
Anyone can develop Graves&apos; disease, but there are a number of factors that increase the risk, including: Women are more likely than men to develop Graves&apos; disease. A family history of Graves&apos; disease or other thyroid or autoimmune disorders Other autoimmune disorders: People inflicted with other immune disorders such as type 1 diabetes or rheumatoid arthritis have an increased risk Emotional or physical stress: Stressful life events or illnesses can trigger an onset of Graves&apos; disease Pregnancy: Pregnancy or a recent childbirth can increase the risk of the disorder in some women Smoking: Cigarette smoking can affect the immune system and increase the risk of Graves&apos; disease 
Women are also more likely to develop the disorder than men. According to the Office on Women&apos;s Health, it affects 10 times more women than men, and often strikes while they are in their 20s and 30s. Graves&apos; disease treatment 
Most people who have Graves&apos; disease have some symptoms of hyperthyroidism. A doctor will likely perform a physical exam as well as additional tests to help make a final diagnosis. These can include: Thyroid function tests Radioactive iodine uptake (RAIU) Antibody tests 
There are three main treatment options. Beta-blockers, which block the action of the thyroid hormone, are given. 
Two antithyroid medicine drugs are used in the U.S: methimazole and propylthiouracil. They help to keep the thyroid from making too much thyroid hormone. 
Radioactive iodine (RAI) treatment requires patients to swallow a pill that contains a form of iodine that damages the thyroid with radiation. By damaging thyroid cells, less thyroid hormones are made. 
In some cases, surgery is recommended where most of the thyroid is removed. Written by Brian Wu Click the stars to rate this article Thyroid Storm: What You Need to Know Public / Patient 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/content/images/articles/312/312442/image-of-the-thyroid-gland-in-the-body.jpg</main_image>
</document>
