<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Boundaries with Archangel Michael Angel EFT cord cutting</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://angeleft.com/index.php/2016/08/18/boundaries-archangel-michael/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Angel EFT Talk angelEFT Boundaries with Archangel Michael 
Archangel Michael is the protective archangel, sometimes known as the spiritual bouncer. He is the patron saint of police officers and security guards, and he does his job very effectively. Within seconds if you will allow. Simply by calling his name ‘Archangel Michael, please help with…’ invokes this superpower to be by your side instantly and on the case. 
I was inspired to write this blog as one day I was having a boundary issue with someone, and picked a card from the Archangel Michael cards app on my phone. The card read ‘draw a line in the sand’ and funnily enough was about boundaries. I immediately felt stronger and more sure of myself. There was no need to fear or compromise. 
It’s okay to be clear about what is okay for you and what is not. Not everyone might like it, but why should you compromise yourself? The message we give to others when we compromise ourselves by allowing bad behaviour is that ‘it’s fine to treat me this way.’ Really?? Archangel Michael can help you if you have a habit of doing this. 
Boundaries are useful and necessary for everyone. Take the example of a young child who wants to run around even though there is a busy road nearby. The boundary needs to be clear that you can’t run in or near the busy road, because it’s dangerous. If you have got into the habit of allowing others’ put on you, treat you in a disrespectful way or similar, you can change your mind about it whenever you like. 
Here is a prayer to Archangel Michael for healthy boundaries: 
Dear Beloved Archangel Michael, 
Please help me to be assertive and clear to others’ as to how I want to be treated. Please assist in dissolving any patterns I have adopted, through my soul’s journey, modelling from parents or society, genetic or otherwise, so that I may have healthy boundaries in my life and in all of my relationships. 
Please help me to communicate my wants and needs in a courageous and appropriate way. Help me to see any behaviours I may have that have not been serving me, especially related to having healthy boundaries in my life. I choose to love and respect myself, and to model to others that it is a great way to be. 
Thank you for your courage and strength. 
It is done. 
I have imagined Archangel Michael walking alongside me, rather like a bouncer at times when I have felt I needed extra strength and courage. You can also ask him to cut cords for you. Did you get my free cord cutting visualisation yet? Click here to get it, you also get the free inspirational newsletter, so you never miss a blog or video again or the events I’m running. 
Wishing you an abundance of angel blessings and the strength of Archangel Michael in your day, 
Susan. 
About the author: Susan Browne helps people to feel great in their energy and achieve their goals through Angel EFT and Energy EFT . She is a Guild of Energists Energy EFT Trainer , teaching in Co. Kerry &amp; Galway, Ireland and she internationally provides 1:1 Angel EFT, Energy EFT sessions , and Success Mentoring via Skype. Susan trained with the Diana Cooper Foundation in Angels, Ascension and Lemurian Planetary Healing. Get in touch for more info. Post navigation Receive the Angel EFT NewsletterFree guided Angel Visualisation on Signup JOIN OUR COMMUNITY 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.45</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://angeleft.com/index.php/2016/08/18/boundaries-archangel-michael/</post_url>
<post_date>20160818</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Angel EFT Talk angelEFT Boundaries with Archangel Michael 
Archangel Michael is the protective archangel, sometimes known as the spiritual bouncer. He is the patron saint of police officers and security guards, and he does his job very effectively. Within seconds if you will allow. Simply by calling his name ‘Archangel Michael, please help with…’ invokes this superpower to be by your side instantly and on the case. 
I was inspired to write this blog as one day I was having a boundary issue with someone, and picked a card from the Archangel Michael cards app on my phone. The card read ‘draw a line in the sand’ and funnily enough was about boundaries. I immediately felt stronger and more sure of myself. There was no need to fear or compromise. 
It’s okay to be clear about what is okay for you and what is not. Not everyone might like it, but why should you compromise yourself? The message we give to others when we compromise ourselves by allowing bad behaviour is that ‘it’s fine to treat me this way.’ Really?? Archangel Michael can help you if you have a habit of doing this. 
Boundaries are useful and necessary for everyone. Take the example of a young child who wants to run around even though there is a busy road nearby. The boundary needs to be clear that you can’t run in or near the busy road, because it’s dangerous. If you have got into the habit of allowing others’ put on you, treat you in a disrespectful way or similar, you can change your mind about it whenever you like. 
Here is a prayer to Archangel Michael for healthy boundaries: 
Dear Beloved Archangel Michael, 
Please help me to be assertive and clear to others’ as to how I want to be treated. Please assist in dissolving any patterns I have adopted, through my soul’s journey, modelling from parents or society, genetic or otherwise, so that I may have healthy boundaries in my life and in all of my relationships. 
Please help me to communicate my wants and needs in a courageous and appropriate way. Help me to see any behaviours I may have that have not been serving me, especially related to having healthy boundaries in my life. I choose to love and respect myself, and to model to others that it is a great way to be. 
Thank you for your courage and strength. 
It is done. 
I have imagined Archangel Michael walking alongside me, rather like a bouncer at times when I have felt I needed extra strength and courage. You can also ask him to cut cords for you. Did you get my free cord cutting visualisation yet? Click here to get it, you also get the free inspirational newsletter, so you never miss a blog or video again or the events I’m running. 
Wishing you an abundance of angel blessings and the strength of Archangel Michael in your day, 
Susan. 
About the author: Susan Browne helps people to feel great in their energy and achieve their goals through Angel EFT and Energy EFT . She is a Guild of Energists Energy EFT Trainer , teaching in Co. Kerry &amp; Galway, Ireland and she internationally provides 1:1 Angel EFT, Energy EFT sessions , and Success Mentoring via Skype. Susan trained with the Diana Cooper Foundation in Angels, Ascension and Lemurian Planetary Healing. Get in touch for more info. Post navigation Receive the Angel EFT NewsletterFree guided Angel Visualisation on Signup JOIN OUR COMMUNITY 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IE</country>
<main_image>http://angeleft.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/boundaries_archangel_michael-300x169.jpg</main_image>
</document>
