<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Free Malaysia Today</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Penang opens tender for low-cost housing project</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2016/08/22/penang-opens-tender-for-low-cost-housing-project/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Predeep Nambiar | August 22, 2016 Project in Butterworth will provide better homes on site currently filled with squatter houses, says Lim Guan Eng. VIDEO INSIDE 
GEORGE TOWN: Developers are invited to build a state government low-cost housing project in Butterworth via a competitive open tender, Chief Minister Lim Guan Eng announced today. 
He said 600 low-cost housing units will be built on a 13.3 acre-site leasehold land by the state government in Ujung Batu, in Bagan Dalam. 
Lim said the project was to alleviate the present-day squatter problem, and that land there will be developed into homes and mixed development, with related infrastructure and facilities. 
“The state government will continue to give emphasis to upgrade and provide better housing facilities for the squatters. 
“Presently there are around 400 squatter houses in the area. 
“This development will transform Ujong Batu into a modern enclave, offering a conducive environment and a sustainable vibrant community,” he said in a press conference in Komtar here, today. 
Lim said state-investment arm Penang Development Corporation (PDC) has appointed project managers, and will invite companies to participate in the “Proposed Development Agreement” (PDA). 
He said the winning bidder will undertake the design, building and completion of the whole development area in accordance with specific criteria and guidelines of the Request for Proposal (RFP). 
“Residents and squatters affected by the development will be offered compensation in accordance with state Land Guidelines,” Lim said. 
The development components formulated for the project are : 600 units low cost housing with a total area of 650 sq ft,and with maximum density of 150 units/acre (subject to the exact requirement), and mixed development with maximum density of 120 units/acre; Public facilities, namely two futsal courts and a hall that can accommodate four badminton courts which will be handed over to the Seberang Perai Municipal Council (MPSP); Common areas to be equipped with safety features, such as CCTV; Access card for both the gate entrance and lift; and Facade treatment reflecting high-end finishing for windows and doors 
The low-cost housing project is expected to be completed in phases and will be developed simultaneously with the mixed-development project. 
However, the whole development project will take about 10 years to be completed. 
Interested companies who wish to participate in the PDA can purchase the tender document for RM1,060 from PDC. The RFP closes on Oct 24.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2016/08/22/penang-opens-tender-for-low-cost-housing-project/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0735</post_time>
<username>Predeep Nambiar</username>
<post>
Predeep Nambiar | August 22, 2016 Project in Butterworth will provide better homes on site currently filled with squatter houses, says Lim Guan Eng. VIDEO INSIDE 
GEORGE TOWN: Developers are invited to build a state government low-cost housing project in Butterworth via a competitive open tender, Chief Minister Lim Guan Eng announced today. 
He said 600 low-cost housing units will be built on a 13.3 acre-site leasehold land by the state government in Ujung Batu, in Bagan Dalam. 
Lim said the project was to alleviate the present-day squatter problem, and that land there will be developed into homes and mixed development, with related infrastructure and facilities. 
“The state government will continue to give emphasis to upgrade and provide better housing facilities for the squatters. 
“Presently there are around 400 squatter houses in the area. 
“This development will transform Ujong Batu into a modern enclave, offering a conducive environment and a sustainable vibrant community,” he said in a press conference in Komtar here, today. 
Lim said state-investment arm Penang Development Corporation (PDC) has appointed project managers, and will invite companies to participate in the “Proposed Development Agreement” (PDA). 
He said the winning bidder will undertake the design, building and completion of the whole development area in accordance with specific criteria and guidelines of the Request for Proposal (RFP). 
“Residents and squatters affected by the development will be offered compensation in accordance with state Land Guidelines,” Lim said. 
The development components formulated for the project are : 600 units low cost housing with a total area of 650 sq ft,and with maximum density of 150 units/acre (subject to the exact requirement), and mixed development with maximum density of 120 units/acre; Public facilities, namely two futsal courts and a hall that can accommodate four badminton courts which will be handed over to the Seberang Perai Municipal Council (MPSP); Common areas to be equipped with safety features, such as CCTV; Access card for both the gate entrance and lift; and Facade treatment reflecting high-end finishing for windows and doors 
The low-cost housing project is expected to be completed in phases and will be developed simultaneously with the mixed-development project. 
However, the whole development project will take about 10 years to be completed. 
Interested companies who wish to participate in the PDA can purchase the tender document for RM1,060 from PDC. The RFP closes on Oct 24.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://s3media.freemalaysiatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Lim-Guan-Eng5.jpg</main_image>
</document>
