<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Young guns: Meet Melbourne’s successful young entrepreneurs</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/young-guns-meet-successful-young-melbourne-entrepreneurs/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
BY Property developer Tim Gurner and Effie Kats, owner of the fashion Label Zachary. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
EFFIE KATS, 26 \ ZACHARY 
Who: Fashion designer and founder of womenswear label Zachary , Effie Kats’ designs have been worn by celebrities from the Kardashians to Kate Hudson, generating annual turnover of around $3 million. 
How: “When I started Zachary [in 2013] I’d dropped out of uni courses in photography and public relations. I had a wedding coming up and couldn’t find a dress that was classic, good quality and affordable. 
“So I went to my father, a tailor, and said I thought there was a gap in the market. I designed five dresses and began selling them through my Instagram account, and I had one rack of clothes in Dad’s factory in Coburg. 
“I had no fashion background – just a belief in my vision. I had to teach myself the business.” 
“My first cheeky purchase late last year was a black Louis Vuitton bag with my initials engraved into it. It’s my first designer handbag and the love of my life!” 
“Follow your instincts and your passion.” 
R, 34 \ GURNER TM Property developer Tim Gurner. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
Founder of Gurner TM , a luxury property business with more than $2.5 billion in projects under development. 
“I studied commerce, got fed up and started my first business, a gym, when I was 19. It was my biggest risk to date – I borrowed $150,000 – and I sold it after two-and-a-half years because I wanted to get into property. 
“Every project teaches us something. There have been projects where we didn’t make much money, but I enjoyed the problem solving.” 
“Last year we bought a farm at Flinders. I have two girls and bought the farm so they can turn off the TV and run around.” 
“Be obsessed about what you do.” Co-founder of Brosa , an online designer furniture store with an annual turnover of $10 million. How: bourne 13 years ago I did a media and communications degree at the University of Melbourne and thought I’d end up in PR. But I graduated during the GFC and my first job was telephone sales in a computer equipment company. I helped other friends grow their businesses and launched my first business when I was 24 – an online custom-tailored clothing business. “In the early stages you have to move quickly but you realise you need to build strong processes, invest, train people and scale the business rather than getting stuff done frantically.” “We are not swimming in cash but we spend money and time on family and friends. Earlier this year we went to Hong Kong to see mum’s side of the family – my aunts and uncles were together for the first time in 20 years.” “A business idea can take off quickly and you suddenly have customers, emails, phone calls … If this takes off are you ready to give it your all?” 
STUART STOYAN, 38 \ MONEYPLACE Stuart Stoyan. Photo: supplied Who: der and chief executive of MoneyPlace , a peer-to-peer lender and online marketplace that connects borrowers and investors. Auswide Bank has partnered with MoneyPlace in a $60 million funding program. “I studied commerce at Monash University and was a management consultant for 11 years, before joining NAB Business as head of strategy for three years. “It took 18 months to get regulatory approval from ASIC (Australian Securities and Investments Commission). We expected to launch our business sooner. But investors take confidence in knowing it was a robust approval process.” “I’d love to say I bought myself a Maserati! The best thing I did was take a couple of weeks off after we launched and I went to Malaysia with my wife and son. That was my reward to myself.” “If you are just about to work on a start-up, don’t do it in isolation. Isolation is your worst enemy and you can get filled with self doubt. We moved early on into a co-working space with other startups around us and we could bounce ideas off each other.” an Le. Photo: supplied Who: Founder of Emotiv , a tech startup based in San Francisco specialising in Brainwear Wireless EEG Technology, with an annual turnover of about $2 million. How : “I arrived in Melbourne from Vietnam with my family when I was four. I went to a Catholic primary school and then to Mac.Robertson Girls’ High School. It was there I became involved in community service and that led to me becoming the Young Australian of the Year in 1998 when I was 20. “I was in my final year of law at Monash then and ready to take the world by the reins and see what I could do. I started a career as a lawyer but left after starting a mobile e-commerce company that I sold when I was 26. “Making sure the product we built was fit for purpose and people were excited enough to buy it.” “The most valuable thing I have now is the ability to help the people I love when they need me.” “Surround yourself with advisors and mentors but find your own voice, too.” 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/young-guns-meet-successful-young-melbourne-entrepreneurs/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
BY Property developer Tim Gurner and Effie Kats, owner of the fashion Label Zachary. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
EFFIE KATS, 26 \ ZACHARY 
Who: Fashion designer and founder of womenswear label Zachary , Effie Kats’ designs have been worn by celebrities from the Kardashians to Kate Hudson, generating annual turnover of around $3 million. 
How: “When I started Zachary [in 2013] I’d dropped out of uni courses in photography and public relations. I had a wedding coming up and couldn’t find a dress that was classic, good quality and affordable. 
“So I went to my father, a tailor, and said I thought there was a gap in the market. I designed five dresses and began selling them through my Instagram account, and I had one rack of clothes in Dad’s factory in Coburg. 
“I had no fashion background – just a belief in my vision. I had to teach myself the business.” 
“My first cheeky purchase late last year was a black Louis Vuitton bag with my initials engraved into it. It’s my first designer handbag and the love of my life!” 
“Follow your instincts and your passion.” 
R, 34 \ GURNER TM Property developer Tim Gurner. Photo: Scott McNaughton 
Founder of Gurner TM , a luxury property business with more than $2.5 billion in projects under development. 
“I studied commerce, got fed up and started my first business, a gym, when I was 19. It was my biggest risk to date – I borrowed $150,000 – and I sold it after two-and-a-half years because I wanted to get into property. 
“Every project teaches us something. There have been projects where we didn’t make much money, but I enjoyed the problem solving.” 
“Last year we bought a farm at Flinders. I have two girls and bought the farm so they can turn off the TV and run around.” 
“Be obsessed about what you do.” Co-founder of Brosa , an online designer furniture store with an annual turnover of $10 million. How: bourne 13 years ago I did a media and communications degree at the University of Melbourne and thought I’d end up in PR. But I graduated during the GFC and my first job was telephone sales in a computer equipment company. I helped other friends grow their businesses and launched my first business when I was 24 – an online custom-tailored clothing business. “In the early stages you have to move quickly but you realise you need to build strong processes, invest, train people and scale the business rather than getting stuff done frantically.” “We are not swimming in cash but we spend money and time on family and friends. Earlier this year we went to Hong Kong to see mum’s side of the family – my aunts and uncles were together for the first time in 20 years.” “A business idea can take off quickly and you suddenly have customers, emails, phone calls … If this takes off are you ready to give it your all?” 
STUART STOYAN, 38 \ MONEYPLACE Stuart Stoyan. Photo: supplied Who: der and chief executive of MoneyPlace , a peer-to-peer lender and online marketplace that connects borrowers and investors. Auswide Bank has partnered with MoneyPlace in a $60 million funding program. “I studied commerce at Monash University and was a management consultant for 11 years, before joining NAB Business as head of strategy for three years. “It took 18 months to get regulatory approval from ASIC (Australian Securities and Investments Commission). We expected to launch our business sooner. But investors take confidence in knowing it was a robust approval process.” “I’d love to say I bought myself a Maserati! The best thing I did was take a couple of weeks off after we launched and I went to Malaysia with my wife and son. That was my reward to myself.” “If you are just about to work on a start-up, don’t do it in isolation. Isolation is your worst enemy and you can get filled with self doubt. We moved early on into a co-working space with other startups around us and we could bounce ideas off each other.” an Le. Photo: supplied Who: Founder of Emotiv , a tech startup based in San Francisco specialising in Brainwear Wireless EEG Technology, with an annual turnover of about $2 million. How : “I arrived in Melbourne from Vietnam with my family when I was four. I went to a Catholic primary school and then to Mac.Robertson Girls’ High School. It was there I became involved in community service and that led to me becoming the Young Australian of the Year in 1998 when I was 20. “I was in my final year of law at Monash then and ready to take the world by the reins and see what I could do. I started a career as a lawyer but left after starting a mobile e-commerce company that I sold when I was 26. “Making sure the product we built was fit for purpose and people were excited enough to buy it.” “The most valuable thing I have now is the ability to help the people I love when they need me.” “Surround yourself with advisors and mentors but find your own voice, too.” 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/TWR-Success-Effie-and-Tim-10.jpg</main_image>
</document>
