<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Patterson Cos. (PDCO) Downgraded to Sell at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/patterson-cos-pdco-downgraded-to-sell-at-zacks-investment-research/1212610/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research lowered shares of Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) from a hold rating to a sell rating in a report released on Tuesday morning. 
According to Zacks, “Patterson is expected to benefit from improving end markets (except livestock), which will drive top-line growth. We remain upbeat about the growth prospects of the company’s Animal Health segment. The partnerships with Abaxis and Sirona are expected to help the company gain significant market traction in the near term. The divestiture of Patterson Medical is expected to help the company focus on its core business segments and propel better growth in the long run. Meanwhile, estimates have been stable lately ahead of the company’s first-quarter earnings release. However, unfavorable foreign exchange rate, higher operating expenses and accelerating debt are major concerns at present.” 
Shares of Patterson Cos. ( NASDAQ:PDCO ) opened at 46.57 on Tuesday. The stock has a market capitalization of $4.45 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 24.32. The company has a 50 day moving average of $48.22 and a 200 day moving average of $46.07. Patterson Cos. has a 52-week low of $38.51 and a 52-week high of $50.40. 
Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) last announced its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, May 26th. The company reported $0.77 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.75 by $0.02. During the same quarter last year, the business earned $0.88 earnings per share. The firm had revenue of $1.45 billion for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $1.46 billion. The business’s revenue for the quarter was up 40.5% compared to the same quarter last year. Analysts predict that Patterson Cos. will post $2.65 EPS for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Friday, July 29th. Stockholders of record on Friday, July 15th were issued a dividend of $0.24 per share. This represents a $0.96 dividend on an annualized basis and a dividend yield of 2.06%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Wednesday, July 13th. 
In other news, CFO Ann B. Gugino sold 750 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $48.86, for a total transaction of $36,645.00. Following the transaction, the chief financial officer now directly owns 36,187 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,768,096.82. The sale was disclosed in a filing with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available through the SEC website . 
Other hedge funds and institutional investors have modified their holdings of the company. Benjamin F. Edwards &amp; Company Inc. raised its position in shares of Patterson Cos. by 0.5% in the second quarter. Benjamin F. Edwards &amp; Company Inc. now owns 2,358 shares of the company’s stock worth $113,000 after buying an additional 12 shares during the period. Friess Associates LLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $151,000. QUANTRES ASSET MANAGEMENT Ltd acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the second quarter worth approximately $220,000. Magnetar Financial LLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $270,000. Finally, Prudential PLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $279,000. 
Several other brokerages have also recently issued reports on PDCO. Jefferies Group restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Thursday, August 4th. Stifel Nicolaus reiterated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Tuesday, May 31st. Evercore ISI upgraded Patterson Cos. from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research note on Wednesday, June 1st. Credit Suisse Group AG reiterated a buy rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Tuesday, May 31st. Finally, Off Wall Street started coverage on Patterson Cos. in a research note on Monday, August 8th. They issued a sell rating on the stock. Two investment analysts have rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and four have issued a buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock has a consensus rating of Hold and a consensus target price of $50.88. 
Patterson Companies, Inc is a distributor serving the dental, veterinary and rehabilitation supply markets. The Company operates through three segments: dental supply, veterinary supply and rehabilitation supply. The dental supply segment provides a range of consumable dental products, clinical and laboratory equipment, and value-added services to dentists, dental laboratories, institutions and other dental healthcare providers across North America. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Patterson Cos. (PDCO) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Patterson Cos.   Patterson Cos.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/patterson-cos-pdco-downgraded-to-sell-at-zacks-investment-research/1212610/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0747</post_time>
<username>Karim Khaledi</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research lowered shares of Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) from a hold rating to a sell rating in a report released on Tuesday morning. 
According to Zacks, “Patterson is expected to benefit from improving end markets (except livestock), which will drive top-line growth. We remain upbeat about the growth prospects of the company’s Animal Health segment. The partnerships with Abaxis and Sirona are expected to help the company gain significant market traction in the near term. The divestiture of Patterson Medical is expected to help the company focus on its core business segments and propel better growth in the long run. Meanwhile, estimates have been stable lately ahead of the company’s first-quarter earnings release. However, unfavorable foreign exchange rate, higher operating expenses and accelerating debt are major concerns at present.” 
Shares of Patterson Cos. ( NASDAQ:PDCO ) opened at 46.57 on Tuesday. The stock has a market capitalization of $4.45 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 24.32. The company has a 50 day moving average of $48.22 and a 200 day moving average of $46.07. Patterson Cos. has a 52-week low of $38.51 and a 52-week high of $50.40. 
Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) last announced its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, May 26th. The company reported $0.77 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.75 by $0.02. During the same quarter last year, the business earned $0.88 earnings per share. The firm had revenue of $1.45 billion for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $1.46 billion. The business’s revenue for the quarter was up 40.5% compared to the same quarter last year. Analysts predict that Patterson Cos. will post $2.65 EPS for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Friday, July 29th. Stockholders of record on Friday, July 15th were issued a dividend of $0.24 per share. This represents a $0.96 dividend on an annualized basis and a dividend yield of 2.06%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Wednesday, July 13th. 
In other news, CFO Ann B. Gugino sold 750 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $48.86, for a total transaction of $36,645.00. Following the transaction, the chief financial officer now directly owns 36,187 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,768,096.82. The sale was disclosed in a filing with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available through the SEC website . 
Other hedge funds and institutional investors have modified their holdings of the company. Benjamin F. Edwards &amp; Company Inc. raised its position in shares of Patterson Cos. by 0.5% in the second quarter. Benjamin F. Edwards &amp; Company Inc. now owns 2,358 shares of the company’s stock worth $113,000 after buying an additional 12 shares during the period. Friess Associates LLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $151,000. QUANTRES ASSET MANAGEMENT Ltd acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the second quarter worth approximately $220,000. Magnetar Financial LLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $270,000. Finally, Prudential PLC acquired a new position in shares of Patterson Cos. during the first quarter worth approximately $279,000. 
Several other brokerages have also recently issued reports on PDCO. Jefferies Group restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Thursday, August 4th. Stifel Nicolaus reiterated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Tuesday, May 31st. Evercore ISI upgraded Patterson Cos. from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research note on Wednesday, June 1st. Credit Suisse Group AG reiterated a buy rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research note on Tuesday, May 31st. Finally, Off Wall Street started coverage on Patterson Cos. in a research note on Monday, August 8th. They issued a sell rating on the stock. Two investment analysts have rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and four have issued a buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock has a consensus rating of Hold and a consensus target price of $50.88. 
Patterson Companies, Inc is a distributor serving the dental, veterinary and rehabilitation supply markets. The Company operates through three segments: dental supply, veterinary supply and rehabilitation supply. The dental supply segment provides a range of consumable dental products, clinical and laboratory equipment, and value-added services to dentists, dental laboratories, institutions and other dental healthcare providers across North America. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Patterson Cos. (PDCO) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Patterson Cos.   Patterson Cos.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/patterson-companies-inc-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
