<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/articles.rss</forum>
<forum_title>Articles | Mail Online</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Miley Cyrus and Alicia Keys make their debut as coaches on NBC&apos;s The Voice in sneak peek preview</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-3752483/Miley-Cyrus-Alicia-Keys-make-debut-coaches-NBC-s-Voice-sneak-peek-preview.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
e-mail 
View 
comments
Miley Cyrus and Alicia Keys made their debut as new coaches on The Voice in a special sneak preview episode on Sunday night. 
The stars joined veteran coaches Adam Levine and Blake Shelton on the hit singing competition show and will battle it out to secure the most talented performers for their own teams. 
And they did not waste time in taking on the guys as they jumped on stage to each perform duets with one of the talented hopefuls. 
Sneak peek: Miley Cyrus was joined by new judge Alicia Keys on Sunday in a sneak peek of the upcoming season of The Voice
The show also silently displayed a memorial card &apos;In loving memory of our friend&apos; the late Christina Grimmie, the former show contestant murdered in June after a concert in Orlando, Florida. 
The first blind audition was done by We McDonald, 17, from Harlem, New York, who performed Feeling Good. 
RELATED ARTICLES Previous 1 Next Gwen Stefani and Blake Shelton pack on the PDA at Hamptons... Closer than ever! Miley Cyrus looks every inch in love as... &apos;She&apos;s the youthful spirit that we&apos;ve been missing&apos;: Adam... Natural beauty! Alicia Keys goes makeup free in striped... Share this article Share Miley, 23, was the first coach to turn followed quickly by the other three. 
&apos;That is not the voice I was expecting after that voice. Your voice is so strong. From what I heard you are a total star,&apos; Miley told the high-pitched teenager who was bullied at school. 
Singing star: Alicia brings 15 Grammy Awards to The Voice
Loving memory: The Voice remembered former contstant Christina Grimmie who was shot to death in June in Florida
&apos;You&apos;ve got a friend in all of us and hopefully a coach in me,&apos; added Miley, who was decked head to toe in denim and flowers and danced throughout the performance. 
Blake, 40, told her he would do anything to be her coach and Adam, 37, called her performance &apos;remarkable&apos; and promised to throw her a party if she picked him. 
&apos;You came to this show to meet me. I&apos;m not playing or joking, I am serious. I don&apos;t want to be like anyone else, I don&apos;t want you to be like anyone else, you were born to show people what love sounds like,&apos; Alicia told her. 
First up: We McDonald was the first singer to perform
Teenage talent: The singer from Harlem, New York City, got all four judges to press their buttons
After bringing her family out We decided to go with Alicia as &apos;everything about it felt honest and real.&apos; 
Alicia, 35, celebrated her victory by handing out tissues to Miley, Blake and Adam to wipe away their tears. 
In between performances Blake picked up some fashion tips from Miley and got a matching flowery jacket. 
Strong pairing: Alicia assured We that she had her back after the girl picked her as a coach
Good move: The Fallin&apos; signer handed out tissues after landing the teenage singer
Next up was Darby Walker, 17, from Atlanta, Georgia, who performed Stand By Me. 
Darby moved from Georgia to Los Angeles at the age of nine to pursue her career and her talent got all four coaches to turn their chairs around. 
Miley recognized the shaky vibrato quality of Darby&apos;s voice and because she sings the same way jumped up on stage to perform a duet together of Jolene. 
Georgia native: Darby Walker was up next and performed Stand By Me
Impromptu duet: Miley jumped on the stage to sing a duet of Jolene with Darby
Quick pitch: The Wrecking Ball singer told Darby after their duet to pick her
&apos;I want you on my team so bad,&apos; she told the youngster. 
Blake drew some laughs when he deployed a set of headphones to block out Miley&apos;s voice. 
Not to be outdone Alicia said she loved the power in her voice and got up on stage to perform her hit No One together. 
Her turn: Alicia also left her chair to sing a duet of No One with Darby
The veterans: Adam Levine and Blake Shelton could only watch as Miley and Alicia went to work
When it came time to chose Darby sided with Miley and joined her team after agreeing they have similar voices. 
The show ended with all four of the coaches taking to the stage to perform their own version of Aerosmith&apos;s &apos;Dream On&apos; with Alicia on keyboard and Adam playing guitar. 
The Voice returns on September 19. 
Her choice: Darby picked Miley as her coach
She&apos;s good: Alicia kicked off the group performance of Dream On at the piano
All-star group: Adam hit incredibly high notes while performing with Alicia, Miley and Blake
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-3752483/Miley-Cyrus-Alicia-Keys-make-debut-coaches-NBC-s-Voice-sneak-peek-preview.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0849</post_time>
<username>Dailymail.com Reporter</username>
<post>
e-mail 
View 
comments
Miley Cyrus and Alicia Keys made their debut as new coaches on The Voice in a special sneak preview episode on Sunday night. 
The stars joined veteran coaches Adam Levine and Blake Shelton on the hit singing competition show and will battle it out to secure the most talented performers for their own teams. 
And they did not waste time in taking on the guys as they jumped on stage to each perform duets with one of the talented hopefuls. 
Sneak peek: Miley Cyrus was joined by new judge Alicia Keys on Sunday in a sneak peek of the upcoming season of The Voice
The show also silently displayed a memorial card &apos;In loving memory of our friend&apos; the late Christina Grimmie, the former show contestant murdered in June after a concert in Orlando, Florida. 
The first blind audition was done by We McDonald, 17, from Harlem, New York, who performed Feeling Good. 
RELATED ARTICLES Previous 1 Next Gwen Stefani and Blake Shelton pack on the PDA at Hamptons... Closer than ever! Miley Cyrus looks every inch in love as... &apos;She&apos;s the youthful spirit that we&apos;ve been missing&apos;: Adam... Natural beauty! Alicia Keys goes makeup free in striped... Share this article Share Miley, 23, was the first coach to turn followed quickly by the other three. 
&apos;That is not the voice I was expecting after that voice. Your voice is so strong. From what I heard you are a total star,&apos; Miley told the high-pitched teenager who was bullied at school. 
Singing star: Alicia brings 15 Grammy Awards to The Voice
Loving memory: The Voice remembered former contstant Christina Grimmie who was shot to death in June in Florida
&apos;You&apos;ve got a friend in all of us and hopefully a coach in me,&apos; added Miley, who was decked head to toe in denim and flowers and danced throughout the performance. 
Blake, 40, told her he would do anything to be her coach and Adam, 37, called her performance &apos;remarkable&apos; and promised to throw her a party if she picked him. 
&apos;You came to this show to meet me. I&apos;m not playing or joking, I am serious. I don&apos;t want to be like anyone else, I don&apos;t want you to be like anyone else, you were born to show people what love sounds like,&apos; Alicia told her. 
First up: We McDonald was the first singer to perform
Teenage talent: The singer from Harlem, New York City, got all four judges to press their buttons
After bringing her family out We decided to go with Alicia as &apos;everything about it felt honest and real.&apos; 
Alicia, 35, celebrated her victory by handing out tissues to Miley, Blake and Adam to wipe away their tears. 
In between performances Blake picked up some fashion tips from Miley and got a matching flowery jacket. 
Strong pairing: Alicia assured We that she had her back after the girl picked her as a coach
Good move: The Fallin&apos; signer handed out tissues after landing the teenage singer
Next up was Darby Walker, 17, from Atlanta, Georgia, who performed Stand By Me. 
Darby moved from Georgia to Los Angeles at the age of nine to pursue her career and her talent got all four coaches to turn their chairs around. 
Miley recognized the shaky vibrato quality of Darby&apos;s voice and because she sings the same way jumped up on stage to perform a duet together of Jolene. 
Georgia native: Darby Walker was up next and performed Stand By Me
Impromptu duet: Miley jumped on the stage to sing a duet of Jolene with Darby
Quick pitch: The Wrecking Ball singer told Darby after their duet to pick her
&apos;I want you on my team so bad,&apos; she told the youngster. 
Blake drew some laughs when he deployed a set of headphones to block out Miley&apos;s voice. 
Not to be outdone Alicia said she loved the power in her voice and got up on stage to perform her hit No One together. 
Her turn: Alicia also left her chair to sing a duet of No One with Darby
The veterans: Adam Levine and Blake Shelton could only watch as Miley and Alicia went to work
When it came time to chose Darby sided with Miley and joined her team after agreeing they have similar voices. 
The show ended with all four of the coaches taking to the stage to perform their own version of Aerosmith&apos;s &apos;Dream On&apos; with Alicia on keyboard and Adam playing guitar. 
The Voice returns on September 19. 
Her choice: Darby picked Miley as her coach
She&apos;s good: Alicia kicked off the group performance of Dream On at the piano
All-star group: Adam hit incredibly high notes while performing with Alicia, Miley and Blake
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2016/08/22/08/377B6A2800000578-0-image-a-18_1471851125648.jpg</main_image>
</document>
