<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/109173786/kusa-broncos</forum>
<forum_title>KUSA - Denver-Broncos</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Broncos QB battle: Siemian and Lynch?</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/109173786/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;9news&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;nfl&amp;#x2f;denver-broncos&amp;#x2f;mike-klis&amp;#x2f;broncos-qb-battle-siemian-may-still-have-lead-but-here-comes-paxton-lynch&amp;#x2f;303982167</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Broncos QB battle: Siemian may still lead but here comes Paxton Lynch Mike Klis, KUSA 1:34   Quarterback Trevor Siemian of the Denver Broncos walks off the field after a preseason NFL game against the San Francisco 49ers. (Photo: Dustin Bradford / Getty Images)   - To better understand the Denver Broncos’ quarterback situation, liken it to our country’s economy. 
Hold on to your Trevor Siemian stock. Buy a few more Paxton Lynch shares. Sell a share or two of Mark Sanchez. 
Siemian played well in the first quarter of the Broncos’ 31-24 loss to the San Francisco 49ers on Saturday night, leading the No. 1 offense to a touchdown on its opening drive and completing 10 of 11 passes. 
It may be telling that on the pick-six Siemian threw on the first official play of the second quarter, Broncos head coach Gary Kubiak took blame. Rookie running back Devontae Booker had just moved before the snap to bring about second-and-16 at the Broncos’ 35 when Siemian threw a pass in the right flat intended for Demaryius Thomas. Instead, San Francisco safety Eric Reid squatted on the route and took it the other way. 
(Note: Although Kubiak was asked about Lynch in his postgame press conference, the coach thought the question was about Siemian). 
“I thought he did great,” Kubiak said of Siemian. “I wish I called a better play, that’s the way I look at it as a coach. Second-and-15, I put him in a situation and gave him a play, obviously not a very good football play. I look at myself. You try to keep your quarterback in the best position possible. That’s the way I look at things first. We had a chance to come out of this game as well as he could, except for that one play when you think about it. We all take responsibility for it. We have to get better.” 
Kubiak seemed more perturbed at Sanchez fumbling the ball away twice as he was getting sacked in the red zone. 
Sanchez was considered the heavy favorite to become the Broncos’ starting quarterback for their regular-season opener Sept. 8 against the Carolina Panthers. He is a terrific leader and he has played well at times. But his penchant for turnovers has made this a competition. 
“I just let one go tonight,’’ Sanchez said. “It’s really too bad.’’ 
I wouldn’t be surprised if Kubiak starts to give Lynch, the team’s first-round rookie, some regular first-team reps this week. Lynch was the most exciting of the three quarterbacks against the 49ers – although we should maintain the perspective that less was expected of him. 
After looking like a lost rookie in his first two possessions – two incompletes and two sacks – Lynch’s ability to scramble out of a sack was the key moment in a 13-play, 80-yard touchdown drive on his next series. 
During that drive, Lynch hit DeVier Posey for 11 yards, Henry Krieger-Coble for 11, Jordan Taylor for 15 yards and tight end John Phillips for an 8-yard touchdown pass. 
Lynch later directed a 14-play touchdown drive in which he completed passes of 9 yards to Bralon Addison, 13 to Krieger-Coble, 12 yards to Durron Neal and finally a 4-yard touchdown flip to Neal. 
Give the kid a week with Thomas and Emmanuel Sanders and see what he can do. 
“He did some really good stuff tonight,’’ Kubiak said of Lynch. “He made some mistakes, too. I think I’ve continued to tell you guys that he is behind the others from a knowledge standpoint as far as running the group. Obviously, we need to keep coming, keep bringing him along. We’re going to keep working here, find the guy that we think is best for our football team and go from there.” 
Kubiak had hoped to name his starting quarterback heading into the Broncos’ final preseason game for the starters on Saturday against the Los Angeles Rams at soon-to-be-renamed Sports Authority Field at Mile High. 
He also let it be known he couldn’t promise. 
Me? I start Siemian against the Rams and have Lynch play much of the second half. Maybe, give Sanchez a couple series in between. Maybe, not. 
I still think Siemian has the slight lead in the competition, but not by enough to declare him The Guy on, say, Monday afternoon, when Kubiak meets the press. I’d wait one more week. 
But I’m not Kubiak. We’ll see. 
We do know this is hardly ideal. A Super Bowl champion should know who its quarterback is heading into its third preseason game. But over the past five-and-a-half years, hasn’t it always seemed to work out for John Elway, the general manager who builds the Broncos’ roster? 
Remember, too, Kubiak went through a week-to-week quarterback mystery last season with Peyton Manning and Brock Osweiler.That worked out perfectly, despite the imperfections at the position. 
So what will Kubiak do about his quarterback dilemma this week? 
“I foresee myself trying to find a way to fix some mistakes,” Kubiak said. “I’m going to take it a day at a time. That’s where I’m going right now.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/109173786/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;9news&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;nfl&amp;#x2f;denver-broncos&amp;#x2f;mike-klis&amp;#x2f;broncos-qb-battle-siemian-may-still-have-lead-but-here-comes-paxton-lynch&amp;#x2f;303982167</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0734</post_time>
<username>Mike Klis</username>
<post>
Broncos QB battle: Siemian may still lead but here comes Paxton Lynch Mike Klis, KUSA 1:34   Quarterback Trevor Siemian of the Denver Broncos walks off the field after a preseason NFL game against the San Francisco 49ers. (Photo: Dustin Bradford / Getty Images)   - To better understand the Denver Broncos’ quarterback situation, liken it to our country’s economy. 
Hold on to your Trevor Siemian stock. Buy a few more Paxton Lynch shares. Sell a share or two of Mark Sanchez. 
Siemian played well in the first quarter of the Broncos’ 31-24 loss to the San Francisco 49ers on Saturday night, leading the No. 1 offense to a touchdown on its opening drive and completing 10 of 11 passes. 
It may be telling that on the pick-six Siemian threw on the first official play of the second quarter, Broncos head coach Gary Kubiak took blame. Rookie running back Devontae Booker had just moved before the snap to bring about second-and-16 at the Broncos’ 35 when Siemian threw a pass in the right flat intended for Demaryius Thomas. Instead, San Francisco safety Eric Reid squatted on the route and took it the other way. 
(Note: Although Kubiak was asked about Lynch in his postgame press conference, the coach thought the question was about Siemian). 
“I thought he did great,” Kubiak said of Siemian. “I wish I called a better play, that’s the way I look at it as a coach. Second-and-15, I put him in a situation and gave him a play, obviously not a very good football play. I look at myself. You try to keep your quarterback in the best position possible. That’s the way I look at things first. We had a chance to come out of this game as well as he could, except for that one play when you think about it. We all take responsibility for it. We have to get better.” 
Kubiak seemed more perturbed at Sanchez fumbling the ball away twice as he was getting sacked in the red zone. 
Sanchez was considered the heavy favorite to become the Broncos’ starting quarterback for their regular-season opener Sept. 8 against the Carolina Panthers. He is a terrific leader and he has played well at times. But his penchant for turnovers has made this a competition. 
“I just let one go tonight,’’ Sanchez said. “It’s really too bad.’’ 
I wouldn’t be surprised if Kubiak starts to give Lynch, the team’s first-round rookie, some regular first-team reps this week. Lynch was the most exciting of the three quarterbacks against the 49ers – although we should maintain the perspective that less was expected of him. 
After looking like a lost rookie in his first two possessions – two incompletes and two sacks – Lynch’s ability to scramble out of a sack was the key moment in a 13-play, 80-yard touchdown drive on his next series. 
During that drive, Lynch hit DeVier Posey for 11 yards, Henry Krieger-Coble for 11, Jordan Taylor for 15 yards and tight end John Phillips for an 8-yard touchdown pass. 
Lynch later directed a 14-play touchdown drive in which he completed passes of 9 yards to Bralon Addison, 13 to Krieger-Coble, 12 yards to Durron Neal and finally a 4-yard touchdown flip to Neal. 
Give the kid a week with Thomas and Emmanuel Sanders and see what he can do. 
“He did some really good stuff tonight,’’ Kubiak said of Lynch. “He made some mistakes, too. I think I’ve continued to tell you guys that he is behind the others from a knowledge standpoint as far as running the group. Obviously, we need to keep coming, keep bringing him along. We’re going to keep working here, find the guy that we think is best for our football team and go from there.” 
Kubiak had hoped to name his starting quarterback heading into the Broncos’ final preseason game for the starters on Saturday against the Los Angeles Rams at soon-to-be-renamed Sports Authority Field at Mile High. 
He also let it be known he couldn’t promise. 
Me? I start Siemian against the Rams and have Lynch play much of the second half. Maybe, give Sanchez a couple series in between. Maybe, not. 
I still think Siemian has the slight lead in the competition, but not by enough to declare him The Guy on, say, Monday afternoon, when Kubiak meets the press. I’d wait one more week. 
But I’m not Kubiak. We’ll see. 
We do know this is hardly ideal. A Super Bowl champion should know who its quarterback is heading into its third preseason game. But over the past five-and-a-half years, hasn’t it always seemed to work out for John Elway, the general manager who builds the Broncos’ roster? 
Remember, too, Kubiak went through a week-to-week quarterback mystery last season with Peyton Manning and Brock Osweiler.That worked out perfectly, despite the imperfections at the position. 
So what will Kubiak do about his quarterback dilemma this week? 
“I foresee myself trying to find a way to fix some mistakes,” Kubiak said. “I’m going to take it a day at a time. That’s where I’m going right now.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.9news.com/photo/2016/08/21/trevor_1471813606986_5671729_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
