<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.careerbuilder.com/RTQ/rss20.aspx?rssid=RSS_PD&amp;num=25&amp;geoip=false&amp;ddcompany=false&amp;ddtitle=false&amp;cat=JN070</forum>
<forum_title>Latest CareerBuilder Jobs</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Multimedia Specialist-Flash, Dreamweaver</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3H7NS61FQ57VYJ1YS5</topic_url>
<topic_text>
How Do You Compare to the Competition? Get facts about other applicants with a CareerBuilder Account Sign Up Job Description Demonstrate skills using Adobe Master Collection CS6 with a strong emphasis in both web and graphic design. Proficient in writing and manipulating HTML 5, CSS3 and familiarity using JavaScript. Strong developing and authoring skills in CSS3, excellent user interface design (UI) along with a strong understanding of the user experience (UX), strong concept of visual communication techniques, and programming techniques. Demonstrate customer service excellence by clearly and concisely communicating work status, methods, instructions, problems, requirements, options, and concerns, with team members, managers and customer . Bachelor&apos;s Degree and 2 years work experience or equivalent experience   Knowledge and proficiency in development of rich interactive multimedia products and electronic publishing tradecraft. Experience with commercial electronic publishing applications - Adobe Master Collection CS6, Microsoft Office Suite, structured authoring software. Experience with Adobe-InDesign, Dreamweaver, Premiere, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Adobe Flash. Experience in system applications, database designs, programming and networking. Ability to incorporate audio, video, graphics and textual data to create advanced presentations Preferred Skills and Education dl{margin:0 0 .8em}dt{font-weight:bold}dd{margin:.4em 0 0 2em} Preferred Skills: About BAE Systems Intelligence &amp; Security BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. Information Solutions, based in Reston, Virginia, is among the 10 largest IT providers to the U.S. government, serving most of the federal defense and civilian marketplace. It provides network-centric command, control, computing, and intelligence (C3I) solutions; wideband networking radio systems; information systems for the U.S. intelligence community; geospatial information services; and information technology services. Leveraging its knowledge of signals and data derived from signals, Information Solutions has attained a market-leading position in advanced information technology research, intelligence analysis and production, and geospatial exploitation software. People are the greatest asset in any Company ... BAE Systems is committed to a high performance culture and provides an environment that challenges our employees to be remarkable and obtain their full potential. Equal Opportunity Employer. Females. Minorities. Veterans. Disabled Department
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.careerbuilder.com/job/J3H7NS61FQ57VYJ1YS5</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0712</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
How Do You Compare to the Competition? Get facts about other applicants with a CareerBuilder Account Sign Up Job Description Demonstrate skills using Adobe Master Collection CS6 with a strong emphasis in both web and graphic design. Proficient in writing and manipulating HTML 5, CSS3 and familiarity using JavaScript. Strong developing and authoring skills in CSS3, excellent user interface design (UI) along with a strong understanding of the user experience (UX), strong concept of visual communication techniques, and programming techniques. Demonstrate customer service excellence by clearly and concisely communicating work status, methods, instructions, problems, requirements, options, and concerns, with team members, managers and customer . Bachelor&apos;s Degree and 2 years work experience or equivalent experience   Knowledge and proficiency in development of rich interactive multimedia products and electronic publishing tradecraft. Experience with commercial electronic publishing applications - Adobe Master Collection CS6, Microsoft Office Suite, structured authoring software. Experience with Adobe-InDesign, Dreamweaver, Premiere, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Adobe Flash. Experience in system applications, database designs, programming and networking. Ability to incorporate audio, video, graphics and textual data to create advanced presentations Preferred Skills and Education dl{margin:0 0 .8em}dt{font-weight:bold}dd{margin:.4em 0 0 2em} Preferred Skills: About BAE Systems Intelligence &amp; Security BAE Systems is a premier global defense and security company with approximately 90,000 employees delivering a full range of products and services for air, land and naval forces, as well as advanced electronics, security, information technology solutions and customer support and services. Information Solutions, based in Reston, Virginia, is among the 10 largest IT providers to the U.S. government, serving most of the federal defense and civilian marketplace. It provides network-centric command, control, computing, and intelligence (C3I) solutions; wideband networking radio systems; information systems for the U.S. intelligence community; geospatial information services; and information technology services. Leveraging its knowledge of signals and data derived from signals, Information Solutions has attained a market-leading position in advanced information technology research, intelligence analysis and production, and geospatial exploitation software. People are the greatest asset in any Company ... BAE Systems is committed to a high performance culture and provides an environment that challenges our employees to be remarkable and obtain their full potential. Equal Opportunity Employer. Females. Minorities. Veterans. Disabled Department
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
