<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Zacks Investment Research Downgrades Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (ZYNE) to Hold</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-downgrades-zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-zyne-to-hold/1212650/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (NASDAQ:ZYNE) from a buy rating to a hold rating in a research note published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is a specialty pharmaceutical company which focuses on developing and commercializing proprietary synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. Its product candidates which are in clinical trial stage include ZYN002 and ZYN001 synthetic transdermal cannabinoid therapeutics for indications including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome, osteoarthritis, fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is headquartered in Devon, Pennsylvania. “ 
Shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals ( NASDAQ:ZYNE ) opened at 9.87 on Tuesday. The stock’s market cap is $90.79 million. The stock has a 50 day moving average of $8.48 and a 200-day moving average of $8.27. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals has a 52 week low of $4.64 and a 52 week high of $33.06. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (NASDAQ:ZYNE) last issued its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported ($0.70) earnings per share for the quarter, missing the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of ($0.53) by $0.18. Equities research analysts predict that Zynerba Pharmaceuticals will post ($2.54) earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
In other Zynerba Pharmaceuticals news, insider Suzanne M. Hanlon sold 3,000 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of $10.53, for a total transaction of $31,590.00. Following the sale, the insider now owns 39,893 shares in the company, valued at approximately $420,073.29. The transaction was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this hyperlink . 
Other large investors have recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. State Street Corp boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 1.5% in the first quarter. State Street Corp now owns 37,629 shares of the company’s stock worth $356,000 after buying an additional 562 shares during the last quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 5.6% in the second quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA now owns 176,514 shares of the company’s stock valued at $1,209,000 after buying an additional 9,329 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Cormorant Asset Management LLC boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 33.2% in the first quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC now owns 475,035 shares of the company’s stock valued at $4,489,000 after buying an additional 118,435 shares during the last quarter. 
ZYNE has been the topic of several other research reports. Oppenheimer Holdings Inc. reiterated a buy rating and issued a $29.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Monday, May 16th. Canaccord Genuity reiterated a buy rating on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Monday, April 18th. Finally, Piper Jaffray Cos. reiterated an overweight rating and issued a $42.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Tuesday, July 26th. One research analyst has rated the stock with a hold rating and five have assigned a buy rating to the company’s stock. The company presently has a consensus rating of Buy and an average target price of $28.58. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc is a specialty pharmaceutical company focused on developing and commercializing synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. The Company is evaluating approximately two product candidates, ZYN002 and ZYN001, in over five indications, including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome (FXS), osteoarthritis (OA), fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (ZYNE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-downgrades-zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-zyne-to-hold/1212650/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0754</post_time>
<username>Masoud Bidgoli</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (NASDAQ:ZYNE) from a buy rating to a hold rating in a research note published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is a specialty pharmaceutical company which focuses on developing and commercializing proprietary synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. Its product candidates which are in clinical trial stage include ZYN002 and ZYN001 synthetic transdermal cannabinoid therapeutics for indications including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome, osteoarthritis, fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is headquartered in Devon, Pennsylvania. “ 
Shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals ( NASDAQ:ZYNE ) opened at 9.87 on Tuesday. The stock’s market cap is $90.79 million. The stock has a 50 day moving average of $8.48 and a 200-day moving average of $8.27. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals has a 52 week low of $4.64 and a 52 week high of $33.06. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (NASDAQ:ZYNE) last issued its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported ($0.70) earnings per share for the quarter, missing the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of ($0.53) by $0.18. Equities research analysts predict that Zynerba Pharmaceuticals will post ($2.54) earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
In other Zynerba Pharmaceuticals news, insider Suzanne M. Hanlon sold 3,000 shares of the firm’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of $10.53, for a total transaction of $31,590.00. Following the sale, the insider now owns 39,893 shares in the company, valued at approximately $420,073.29. The transaction was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this hyperlink . 
Other large investors have recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. State Street Corp boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 1.5% in the first quarter. State Street Corp now owns 37,629 shares of the company’s stock worth $356,000 after buying an additional 562 shares during the last quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 5.6% in the second quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA now owns 176,514 shares of the company’s stock valued at $1,209,000 after buying an additional 9,329 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Cormorant Asset Management LLC boosted its stake in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 33.2% in the first quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC now owns 475,035 shares of the company’s stock valued at $4,489,000 after buying an additional 118,435 shares during the last quarter. 
ZYNE has been the topic of several other research reports. Oppenheimer Holdings Inc. reiterated a buy rating and issued a $29.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Monday, May 16th. Canaccord Genuity reiterated a buy rating on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Monday, April 18th. Finally, Piper Jaffray Cos. reiterated an overweight rating and issued a $42.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Tuesday, July 26th. One research analyst has rated the stock with a hold rating and five have assigned a buy rating to the company’s stock. The company presently has a consensus rating of Buy and an average target price of $28.58. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc is a specialty pharmaceutical company focused on developing and commercializing synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. The Company is evaluating approximately two product candidates, ZYN002 and ZYN001, in over five indications, including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome (FXS), osteoarthritis (OA), fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (ZYNE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-logo.png</main_image>
</document>
