<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.indiainfoline.com/rss/sectormetal.xml</forum>
<forum_title>India Infoline News Service</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Rahul Majumdar, Founder, Knowlens</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.indiainfoline.com/article/editorial-interviews-leader-speak/rahul-majumdar-founder-knowlens-116082200168_1.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Enter characters of the above image Submit Rahul Majumdar, Founder, Knowlens Yash Ved, IIFL | Mumbai | August 22, 2016 13:05 IST “We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. “ Article saved successfully to my page. You must be Logged in to save article. A + a - 0 Knowlens believes that career skills for working professionals and final year students is one of the most important and often neglected spaces in online learning. With the recent developments in technology and the unprecedented dominance of films as the most powerful medium of communication in the current century, the avenues for multi-dimensional learning have expanded manifold. Knowlens is the pioneer in leveraging this ability to engage in multiple and simultaneous learning styles of diverse audiences including visual, auditory, read-write and kinesthetic. Rahul Majumdar, Founder, Knowlens, an IIT Bombay IIM Lucknow alumnus, has worked in diverse organizations at HCL/NIIT, ICICI Bank, DCB, Artha and Times group. Involved in several pioneering internet based businesses including the earliest e-Learning venture NIIT Netvarsity in India (1996), the first bill payment and remittance portal in the country. He brings a wide understanding of internet based businesses and is highly interested in films. Replying to Yash Ved of IIFL , Rahul Majumdar says, “ We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. “ Brief us about your business model? Our business model is built around our ability to understand the soft skill needs of the corporate and college segments and build powerful visual and interactive online experiences based on a mix of film impact, case study approach and interactive internet functionality. We invest in deeply researched content, a creative concept behind every module. Supported by a well-designed learning interface the course thus created is then offered as an annuity product to enterprises and as priced products to individuals through knowlens.com . Brief us about the launch of new product on the Fundamentals of Interviews called “The Final Countdown”? The launch of this product is being done through our website knowlens.com and tie ups with recruitment sites like naukri.com and Timesjobs.com. We are also seeding the product in colleges across the country. The product for the first time introduces a 360 degree view of interviews based on feedback from all the corporate that we deal with. While structured around the core film story, it looks at interviews from a multidimensional perspective including the organization, the candidate, frequently questions as well as from a competency perspective. It provides for the first time a self development framework to help candidates work on their competencies and comes with useful tools like video search and video notes and ready reckoner etc. Finally it offers a chance to practice interviews through video recording. Any new launch products for the coming months? We are looking at new products coming up in the next few months. These will be focused on the IT segment and BFSI. We will be sharing the details closer to the launch dates. Brief us about your strategic tie-ups with Naukri, HT Shine and Times Jobs. All three tie ups leverage and position us as the provider of film learning solutions to typical job seekers. It provides us access to a large user base of over 50 mn users across the 3 portals and significantly enhances the e learning programs available at these portals. The interview module will be relevant for all job seekers and the sales module will be targeted at sales professionals as well as individuals keen on developing sales skills. What are your fund raising plans? We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. What is your revenue model? The revenue model works on two revenue streams; the enterprise business works on a annuity license for the corporate based on number of users. The consumer business works on individual purchasers purchasing online through the knowlens.com site, alliances with organizations like Naukri.com, Timesjobs.com and HTshine.com and other offline alliance partners. The individual space has just been launched with two modules on the fundamentals of sales and on the fundamentals of Interviews.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.indiainfoline.com/article/editorial-interviews-leader-speak/rahul-majumdar-founder-knowlens-116082200168_1.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0735</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Enter characters of the above image Submit Rahul Majumdar, Founder, Knowlens Yash Ved, IIFL | Mumbai | August 22, 2016 13:05 IST “We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. “ Article saved successfully to my page. You must be Logged in to save article. A + a - 0 Knowlens believes that career skills for working professionals and final year students is one of the most important and often neglected spaces in online learning. With the recent developments in technology and the unprecedented dominance of films as the most powerful medium of communication in the current century, the avenues for multi-dimensional learning have expanded manifold. Knowlens is the pioneer in leveraging this ability to engage in multiple and simultaneous learning styles of diverse audiences including visual, auditory, read-write and kinesthetic. Rahul Majumdar, Founder, Knowlens, an IIT Bombay IIM Lucknow alumnus, has worked in diverse organizations at HCL/NIIT, ICICI Bank, DCB, Artha and Times group. Involved in several pioneering internet based businesses including the earliest e-Learning venture NIIT Netvarsity in India (1996), the first bill payment and remittance portal in the country. He brings a wide understanding of internet based businesses and is highly interested in films. Replying to Yash Ved of IIFL , Rahul Majumdar says, “ We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. “ Brief us about your business model? Our business model is built around our ability to understand the soft skill needs of the corporate and college segments and build powerful visual and interactive online experiences based on a mix of film impact, case study approach and interactive internet functionality. We invest in deeply researched content, a creative concept behind every module. Supported by a well-designed learning interface the course thus created is then offered as an annuity product to enterprises and as priced products to individuals through knowlens.com . Brief us about the launch of new product on the Fundamentals of Interviews called “The Final Countdown”? The launch of this product is being done through our website knowlens.com and tie ups with recruitment sites like naukri.com and Timesjobs.com. We are also seeding the product in colleges across the country. The product for the first time introduces a 360 degree view of interviews based on feedback from all the corporate that we deal with. While structured around the core film story, it looks at interviews from a multidimensional perspective including the organization, the candidate, frequently questions as well as from a competency perspective. It provides for the first time a self development framework to help candidates work on their competencies and comes with useful tools like video search and video notes and ready reckoner etc. Finally it offers a chance to practice interviews through video recording. Any new launch products for the coming months? We are looking at new products coming up in the next few months. These will be focused on the IT segment and BFSI. We will be sharing the details closer to the launch dates. Brief us about your strategic tie-ups with Naukri, HT Shine and Times Jobs. All three tie ups leverage and position us as the provider of film learning solutions to typical job seekers. It provides us access to a large user base of over 50 mn users across the 3 portals and significantly enhances the e learning programs available at these portals. The interview module will be relevant for all job seekers and the sales module will be targeted at sales professionals as well as individuals keen on developing sales skills. What are your fund raising plans? We have already raised more than US$200,000. We are in conversation with funds to explore a larger fund raise. This will help accelerate our growth trajectory. What is your revenue model? The revenue model works on two revenue streams; the enterprise business works on a annuity license for the corporate based on number of users. The consumer business works on individual purchasers purchasing online through the knowlens.com site, alliances with organizations like Naukri.com, Timesjobs.com and HTshine.com and other offline alliance partners. The individual space has just been launched with two modules on the fundamentals of sales and on the fundamentals of Interviews.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://content.indiainfoline.com/_media/iifl/img/article/2016-08/22/full/1471851577-3707.jpg</main_image>
</document>
