<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.zawya.com/rss/pr.cfm?section=1</forum>
<forum_title>Zawya.com - Press Releases - Latest News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Ericsson and Etisalat Misr win GTB 2016 innovation award for the second year in a row</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.zawya.com/story/Ericsson_and_Etisalat_Misr_win_GTB_2016_innovation_award_for_the_second_year_in_a_row-ZAWYA20160822074942/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Ericsson and Etisalat Misr win GTB 2016 innovation award for the second year in a row 22 August, 2016 · For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award 
· The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry 
· Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr 22 August 2016 · For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award
· The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry 
· Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award 2016 as part of the Global Telecom Business (GTP) Telecoms Innovation &amp; Technology Summit that was held in London this year. 
The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry, led by service providers and their technology suppliers. Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr.
On this occasion, Khalid Al Mansouri, Chief Information Technology Officer of Etisalat Misr declared: &quot;There is no doubt that today&apos;s data explosion creates higher demands from subscribers to receive a bigger variety of tailor-made offerings. Our Customer Value Management project with Ericsson is one of the key innovative projects that can help us in improving our customer services via real time analytics.&quot; 
Khalid AL Kaf, IT Infrastructure and Operations Director at Etisalat Misr stated: &quot;We are once again proud to receive such a prestigious award together with our trusted partners from Ericsson. Faster provisioning of infrastructure and storage are helping to Advertisement speed innovation and time to market, From IT&apos;s perspective, self-serve means we spend less time on user service and support and more time on innovation.&quot; 
Helene Henriksson, Head of Ericsson Egypt, said, &quot; Our target is to continue in our strategic partnership with Etisalat Misr to always deliver innovative solutions to the market. Therefore, we are pleased to have been recognized for this innovative project with Etisalat Misr, and we hope we can continue to offer the market with unique and valuable solutions. With industries and even whole societies being disrupted by mobility, broadband and cloud, we are accelerating our transformation into the Networked Society.&quot; 
Last year Ericsson and Etisalat Misr were awarded together the 2015 innovation award for accelerating mobile broadband monetization and service agility and the ceremony also took place in London. 
For media kits, backgrounders and high-resolution photos, please visit www.ericsson.com/press 
About Ericsson is the driving force behind the Networked Society - a world leader in communications technology and services. Our long-term relationships with every major telecom operator in the world allow people, business and society to fulfill their potential and create a more sustainable future. 
Our services, software and infrastructure - especially in mobility, broadband and the cloud- are enabling the telecom industry and other sectors to do better business, increase efficiency, improve the user experience and capture new opportunities. 
With approximately 115,000 professionals and customers in 180 countries,we combine global scale with technology and services leadership. We support networks that connect more than 2.5 billion subscribers. Forty percent of the world&apos;s mobile traffic is carried over Ericsson networks. And our investments in research and development ensure that our solutions - and our customers - stay in front. 
Founded in 1876, Ericsson has its headquarters in Stockholm, Sweden. Net sales in2015 were SEK 246.9 billion (USD 29.4 billion). Ericsson is listed on NASDAQ OMX stock exchange in Stockholm and the NASDAQ in New York.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.zawya.com/story/Ericsson_and_Etisalat_Misr_win_GTB_2016_innovation_award_for_the_second_year_in_a_row-ZAWYA20160822074942/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0749</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Ericsson and Etisalat Misr win GTB 2016 innovation award for the second year in a row 22 August, 2016 · For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award 
· The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry 
· Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr 22 August 2016 · For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award
· The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry 
· Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr For the second year in a row, Ericsson and Etisalat Misr won the Global Telecom Business (GTB) innovation award 2016 as part of the Global Telecom Business (GTP) Telecoms Innovation &amp; Technology Summit that was held in London this year. 
The Global Telecoms Business Innovation Awards highlights innovative projects in the global telecommunications industry, led by service providers and their technology suppliers. Both companies received an award for their joint efforts in launching the Customer Value Management solution for Etisalat Misr.
On this occasion, Khalid Al Mansouri, Chief Information Technology Officer of Etisalat Misr declared: &quot;There is no doubt that today&apos;s data explosion creates higher demands from subscribers to receive a bigger variety of tailor-made offerings. Our Customer Value Management project with Ericsson is one of the key innovative projects that can help us in improving our customer services via real time analytics.&quot; 
Khalid AL Kaf, IT Infrastructure and Operations Director at Etisalat Misr stated: &quot;We are once again proud to receive such a prestigious award together with our trusted partners from Ericsson. Faster provisioning of infrastructure and storage are helping to Advertisement speed innovation and time to market, From IT&apos;s perspective, self-serve means we spend less time on user service and support and more time on innovation.&quot; 
Helene Henriksson, Head of Ericsson Egypt, said, &quot; Our target is to continue in our strategic partnership with Etisalat Misr to always deliver innovative solutions to the market. Therefore, we are pleased to have been recognized for this innovative project with Etisalat Misr, and we hope we can continue to offer the market with unique and valuable solutions. With industries and even whole societies being disrupted by mobility, broadband and cloud, we are accelerating our transformation into the Networked Society.&quot; 
Last year Ericsson and Etisalat Misr were awarded together the 2015 innovation award for accelerating mobile broadband monetization and service agility and the ceremony also took place in London. 
For media kits, backgrounders and high-resolution photos, please visit www.ericsson.com/press 
About Ericsson is the driving force behind the Networked Society - a world leader in communications technology and services. Our long-term relationships with every major telecom operator in the world allow people, business and society to fulfill their potential and create a more sustainable future. 
Our services, software and infrastructure - especially in mobility, broadband and the cloud- are enabling the telecom industry and other sectors to do better business, increase efficiency, improve the user experience and capture new opportunities. 
With approximately 115,000 professionals and customers in 180 countries,we combine global scale with technology and services leadership. We support networks that connect more than 2.5 billion subscribers. Forty percent of the world&apos;s mobile traffic is carried over Ericsson networks. And our investments in research and development ensure that our solutions - and our customers - stay in front. 
Founded in 1876, Ericsson has its headquarters in Stockholm, Sweden. Net sales in2015 were SEK 246.9 billion (USD 29.4 billion). Ericsson is listed on NASDAQ OMX stock exchange in Stockholm and the NASDAQ in New York.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>AE</country>
<main_image>http://images.zawya.com/pr/images/2016/ak_2016_08_22.jpg</main_image>
</document>
