<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Sydney Opera House reveals 2017 MADE winners | ArchitectureAU</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://architectureau.com/articles/sydney-opera-house-reveals-2017-made-winners/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
News Words Louisa Wright Click to enlarge 
Australian winners of the 2017 MADE student exchange: James Hansen, Jacob Levy, Eleanor Gibson, Nicola Shear and Awkar Ruel. Image: Prudence Upton 
Sydney Opera House CEO Louise Herron AM has announced the five Australian students selected for the 2017 MADE by the Opera House program, an Australian-Danish exchange now in its third year. 
The program supports five Australian and fiveDanish students each year and will create an alumnus group of 100 students by the time of the Opera House’s 50 th anniversary in 2023. 
In January 2017 the five engineering, architecture and design students will travel to Denmark where they will spend six weeks working together on a crossdisciplinary project while being mentored by a range of prestigious Danish firms and organizations. 
The Australian students selected for the 2017 MADE program are Eleanor Gibson (Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney), James Hansen (Bachelor of Civil Engineering, University of New South Wales), Jacob Levy (Bachelor of Engineering (Civil)/Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney), Awkar Ruel (Bachelor of Design in Architecture/Bachelor of Creative Intelligence and Innovation, University of Technology Sydney) and Nicola Shear (Bachelor of Engineering (Civil)/Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney). 
The winners were revealed at an Opera House MADE celebration attended by Opera House Eminent Architect Panel member Jan Utzon, son of Opera House architect Jørn Utzon. 
The 2016 MADE Danish students presented their response to the brief they worked on as part of their exchange at the event. The brief challenged students to create a “Kit of Parts,” or temporary outdoor event structures, that would adapt to the wide range of events held on the Opera House Forecourt, while also respecting the building’s heritage and Jørn Utzon’s legacy. 
MADE was launched by Crown Prince Frederik of Denmark at the Sydney Opera House’s 40 th anniversary in October 2013, with the support of The Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts, Arup, Steensen Varming, The NSW Architects Registration Board, and the Bikuben, Dreyer and Obel Family foundations. 
“Last week we unveiled designs for the Opera House’s renewal, funded by the NSW government to prepare the building for future generations of artists, audiences and visitors. It’s so fitting that simultaneously the MADE program is fostering and encouraging the next generation of architects, designers and engineers, who will together design the cultural spaces of our future,” said Herron. 
“Thanks to MADE, our renewal is not just for the next generation, it’s also with them. Through MADE, outstanding students have an opportunity to work together, learn from experts, inspire us and influence thinking, both here and in Denmark.” Words 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.10</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://architectureau.com/articles/sydney-opera-house-reveals-2017-made-winners/</post_url>
<post_date>20160831</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
News Words Louisa Wright Click to enlarge 
Australian winners of the 2017 MADE student exchange: James Hansen, Jacob Levy, Eleanor Gibson, Nicola Shear and Awkar Ruel. Image: Prudence Upton 
Sydney Opera House CEO Louise Herron AM has announced the five Australian students selected for the 2017 MADE by the Opera House program, an Australian-Danish exchange now in its third year. 
The program supports five Australian and fiveDanish students each year and will create an alumnus group of 100 students by the time of the Opera House’s 50 th anniversary in 2023. 
In January 2017 the five engineering, architecture and design students will travel to Denmark where they will spend six weeks working together on a crossdisciplinary project while being mentored by a range of prestigious Danish firms and organizations. 
The Australian students selected for the 2017 MADE program are Eleanor Gibson (Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney), James Hansen (Bachelor of Civil Engineering, University of New South Wales), Jacob Levy (Bachelor of Engineering (Civil)/Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney), Awkar Ruel (Bachelor of Design in Architecture/Bachelor of Creative Intelligence and Innovation, University of Technology Sydney) and Nicola Shear (Bachelor of Engineering (Civil)/Bachelor of Design in Architecture, University of Sydney). 
The winners were revealed at an Opera House MADE celebration attended by Opera House Eminent Architect Panel member Jan Utzon, son of Opera House architect Jørn Utzon. 
The 2016 MADE Danish students presented their response to the brief they worked on as part of their exchange at the event. The brief challenged students to create a “Kit of Parts,” or temporary outdoor event structures, that would adapt to the wide range of events held on the Opera House Forecourt, while also respecting the building’s heritage and Jørn Utzon’s legacy. 
MADE was launched by Crown Prince Frederik of Denmark at the Sydney Opera House’s 40 th anniversary in October 2013, with the support of The Royal Danish Academy of Fine Arts, Arup, Steensen Varming, The NSW Architects Registration Board, and the Bikuben, Dreyer and Obel Family foundations. 
“Last week we unveiled designs for the Opera House’s renewal, funded by the NSW government to prepare the building for future generations of artists, audiences and visitors. It’s so fitting that simultaneously the MADE program is fostering and encouraging the next generation of architects, designers and engineers, who will together design the cultural spaces of our future,” said Herron. 
“Thanks to MADE, our renewal is not just for the next generation, it’s also with them. Through MADE, outstanding students have an opportunity to work together, learn from experts, inspire us and influence thinking, both here and in Denmark.” Words 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://media4.architecturemedia.net/site_media/media/cache/ca/b9/cab91e8cbf5af9b3ee63d18baa9695a4.jpg</main_image>
</document>
