<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.jckonline.com/rss.xml</forum>
<forum_title>JCK</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Philadelphia’s Jewelers Row Threatened, Reports Say</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.jckonline.com/philadelphias-jewelers-row-threatened-reports-say-903</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Philadelphia’s Jewelers Row Threatened, Reports Say   
Well here is the thing Terry. We keep displacing small businesses in this country for hedge fund investment interest that are funding these properties (and most of the retail world) only to see 1/2 empty structures that provide actually less ROI to the community because of large tax incentives and the loss of real earnings for stock valuations. This is happening all over NYC too and it is why the economy is still very weak for more and more people. If you are for corporate feudalism then great. But even benign companies will become more and more aggressive with less and less competition. Eventually a true feudal state will exist where people are working literally for food and shelter. And these once new grand hollow structures will represent the hollowness of a once great country. There is a fine line here between; new construction to meet a demand of a successful country/economy, the sprucing up of old neighborhoods with the hope of a great return, and the gutting of industries using our hedge fund retirement money along with out right gambling by banks knowing they are doing it for the implied new real estate value that they can sell off to investors and not the actual return of liquid cash to the economy. The feeding frenzy that represents these deals have nothing/zero to do with need or even risk aversion but quite the opposite. We are in a new era of to large to fail so leveraging to the hilt by conglomerates with CEO ’s baring no downside risk could be catastrophic if at some point we will not bale out this next level of mortgage bundle greed. I understand “you” as the owner of the property want to sell and run with your bag of loot. But we live inside a carpet bagger age where the carpet baggers are these large funds absorbing the countries pristine real estate to make it mostly useful to fewer people and it is all based on a few people’s (the mega rich and politicians) brilliant insightful thoughts. We have become a country that no longer believes in real competition and that the strength of a country is held in the majority of its people, not in the hands of a few “successful” ones. Last point; I get that this looks like every other time in history when small businesses were displaced for progress but hopefully you can appreciate the difference this time. The last 30 years have been very different times and although stock market gains seemed great until 2008 hit, I believe we are in the post era economy of 2008 which means there is a huge break between the real economy and the stock market economy and that gap is now extremely dangerous. Link:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.jckonline.com/philadelphias-jewelers-row-threatened-reports-say-903</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0737</post_time>
<username>Admin User</username>
<post>
Philadelphia’s Jewelers Row Threatened, Reports Say   
Well here is the thing Terry. We keep displacing small businesses in this country for hedge fund investment interest that are funding these properties (and most of the retail world) only to see 1/2 empty structures that provide actually less ROI to the community because of large tax incentives and the loss of real earnings for stock valuations. This is happening all over NYC too and it is why the economy is still very weak for more and more people. If you are for corporate feudalism then great. But even benign companies will become more and more aggressive with less and less competition. Eventually a true feudal state will exist where people are working literally for food and shelter. And these once new grand hollow structures will represent the hollowness of a once great country. There is a fine line here between; new construction to meet a demand of a successful country/economy, the sprucing up of old neighborhoods with the hope of a great return, and the gutting of industries using our hedge fund retirement money along with out right gambling by banks knowing they are doing it for the implied new real estate value that they can sell off to investors and not the actual return of liquid cash to the economy. The feeding frenzy that represents these deals have nothing/zero to do with need or even risk aversion but quite the opposite. We are in a new era of to large to fail so leveraging to the hilt by conglomerates with CEO ’s baring no downside risk could be catastrophic if at some point we will not bale out this next level of mortgage bundle greed. I understand “you” as the owner of the property want to sell and run with your bag of loot. But we live inside a carpet bagger age where the carpet baggers are these large funds absorbing the countries pristine real estate to make it mostly useful to fewer people and it is all based on a few people’s (the mega rich and politicians) brilliant insightful thoughts. We have become a country that no longer believes in real competition and that the strength of a country is held in the majority of its people, not in the hands of a few “successful” ones. Last point; I get that this looks like every other time in history when small businesses were displaced for progress but hopefully you can appreciate the difference this time. The last 30 years have been very different times and although stock market gains seemed great until 2008 hit, I believe we are in the post era economy of 2008 which means there is a huge break between the real economy and the stock market economy and that gap is now extremely dangerous. Link:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.jckonline.com/sites/all/themes/jck/images/share-image.jpg</main_image>
</document>
