<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>RestorationMaster Recently Developed Micro-Sites for the Newest Addition to RestorationMasterFinder.com, ServiceMaster Recovery Services of New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/servicemaster-milwaukee/restorationmaster/prweb13628265.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
RestorationMaster Recently Developed Micro-Sites for the Newest Addition to RestorationMasterFinder.com, ServiceMaster Recovery Services of New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI Share Article RestorationMaster just added new micro-sites for ServiceMaster Recovery Services on RestorationMasterFinder.com to boost their online marketing campaign in the New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI area. ServiceMaster Recovery Services Love RMF and our site. Most of our non program work is from RMF and our site... Past News Releases RestorationMaster Expands Online... Milwaukee, WI (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 ServiceMaster Recovery Services has been serving the New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI area with trusted disaster restoration and cleaning services for over 40 years. Recently, RestorationMaster added ServiceMaster Recovery Services as the newest business on RestorationMasterFinder.com to help expand their online marketing outreach in Milwaukee as well as New Berlin, WI. RestorationMaster built a new micro-site for New Berlin, WI and Milwaukee, WI to maximize the local search traffic to these pages and increase their number of sales leads. Each of the new micro-sites for ServiceMaster Recovery Services is highly optimized and includes several service pages such as water damage restoration , fire damage restoration, mold removal, and reconstruction to boost local search traffic looking for these services. The increase in relevant search traffic to these service pages will result in a higher volume of calls to improve their conversion rate. About RestorationMasterFinder.com RestorationMasterFinder.com, or RMF, is a website built by Proceed Innovative to help generate cost effective leads with micro-sites optimized to attract local search traffic. The businesses included on RMF are of the disaster restoration, furniture restoration, and cleaning industries and the micro-sites for each business help attract relevant search traffic from their service areas to generate quality leads. “Love RMF and our site. Most of our non program work is from RMF and our site,” says Steve VanDenBerg, ServiceMaster DRR . RMF has a strong presence on major search engines including Google, Yahoo, and Bing as well as many local, vertical, and social media web portals. About ServiceMaster Recovery Services ServiceMaster Recovery Services is located in New Berlin, WI and provides disaster restoration and cleaning services for homes and businesses in New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI. They were founded in 1976 and a decade later, they had a full crew and moved into a larger facility. Their technicians are highly trained to provide effective disaster restoration and cleaning services with the best cleaning products and equipment available. You can learn more by calling ServiceMaster Recovery Services at (262) 923-3888. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.40</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/servicemaster-milwaukee/restorationmaster/prweb13628265.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
RestorationMaster Recently Developed Micro-Sites for the Newest Addition to RestorationMasterFinder.com, ServiceMaster Recovery Services of New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI Share Article RestorationMaster just added new micro-sites for ServiceMaster Recovery Services on RestorationMasterFinder.com to boost their online marketing campaign in the New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI area. ServiceMaster Recovery Services Love RMF and our site. Most of our non program work is from RMF and our site... Past News Releases RestorationMaster Expands Online... Milwaukee, WI (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 ServiceMaster Recovery Services has been serving the New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI area with trusted disaster restoration and cleaning services for over 40 years. Recently, RestorationMaster added ServiceMaster Recovery Services as the newest business on RestorationMasterFinder.com to help expand their online marketing outreach in Milwaukee as well as New Berlin, WI. RestorationMaster built a new micro-site for New Berlin, WI and Milwaukee, WI to maximize the local search traffic to these pages and increase their number of sales leads. Each of the new micro-sites for ServiceMaster Recovery Services is highly optimized and includes several service pages such as water damage restoration , fire damage restoration, mold removal, and reconstruction to boost local search traffic looking for these services. The increase in relevant search traffic to these service pages will result in a higher volume of calls to improve their conversion rate. About RestorationMasterFinder.com RestorationMasterFinder.com, or RMF, is a website built by Proceed Innovative to help generate cost effective leads with micro-sites optimized to attract local search traffic. The businesses included on RMF are of the disaster restoration, furniture restoration, and cleaning industries and the micro-sites for each business help attract relevant search traffic from their service areas to generate quality leads. “Love RMF and our site. Most of our non program work is from RMF and our site,” says Steve VanDenBerg, ServiceMaster DRR . RMF has a strong presence on major search engines including Google, Yahoo, and Bing as well as many local, vertical, and social media web portals. About ServiceMaster Recovery Services ServiceMaster Recovery Services is located in New Berlin, WI and provides disaster restoration and cleaning services for homes and businesses in New Berlin and Milwaukee, WI. They were founded in 1976 and a decade later, they had a full crew and moved into a larger facility. Their technicians are highly trained to provide effective disaster restoration and cleaning services with the best cleaning products and equipment available. You can learn more by calling ServiceMaster Recovery Services at (262) 923-3888. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/08/19/13628265/ServiceMaster-Recovery-Services-Disaster-Restoration-and-Cleaning-in-Milwaukee-WI.gif</main_image>
</document>
