<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Sindhu and Gopichand receive grand welcome at Hyderabad | Business Standard News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/sindhu-and-gopichand-receive-grand-welcome-at-hyderabad-116082200359_1.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Business Standard Sindhu and Gopichand receive grand welcome at Hyderabad Hundreds sports enthusiasts &amp; people waved the badminton star &amp; her coach as they travelled standing on an open top bus August 22, 2016 Last Updated at 12:55 IST email this article Type address separated by commas Your Email: Enter the characters shown in the image. Send me a copy: Copy tiny URL to save and share articles. P V Sindhu and P Gopichand Photo: ANI Twitter Handle ALSO READ Telangana, AP shower cash rewards on Sindhu, Gopichand P V Sindhu&apos;s run to the Olympic semi-final hasn&apos;t happened overnight Where the Saina, Sindhu legends were born KCR increases his son&apos;s role in government Chinese company offers to build irrigation projects in Telangana For once the VVIPs of Telangana and Andhra Pradesh (AP) governments jostled with each other like ordinary sports fans to receive Olympic silver medalist P V Sindhu and her coach Pullela Gopichand and present them with flower bouquets and shawls as the shuttler-coach duo arrived at Rajiv Gandhi International Airport from Rio this morning for a grand welcome organised by the state government. A large contingent of Telangana ministers and public representatives led by minister K T Rama Rao and a team of A P ministers led by Deputy Chief Minister Nimmakayala Chinarajappa among other officials and sports personalities in the city received the badminton star as she stepped out of the airport, with a kind of fan fare that only top film stars or leaders enjoyed on such special moments. Hundreds of students, sports enthusiasts and people waved the badminton star and her coach as they travelled standing on an open top bus in a rally filled with dozens of red and blue VIP beacon cars from the airport to Gachibowli Stadium covering more than 30 km distance. The state government hosted a colorful reception for Sindhu at the stadium amidst song and dance programmes by teams of artists. Police bands played inspirational themes on this occasion. The shuttler received a rousing reception at the stadium as flowers were showered on Sindhu from atop the stadium as she went around to greet the crowds. Thousands of students, parents and sports fans, who were waiting since morning, raised slogans and chanted Sindhu&apos;s name in unison. On Saturday, Telangana Chief Minister K Chandrasekhara Rao announced a cash reward of Rs 5 crore for Olympic silver medalist and Rs 1 crore for her coach Gopichand for winning the country&apos; first Olympic silver medal in women&apos;s category. Earlier AP Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu announced a Rs 3 crore cash reward besides offering a 1,000 square yard residential plot in the upcoming capital Amaravati and a Group-1 government job to Sindhu. As Haryana Chief Minister Manohar Lal Khattar too announced a cash reward of Rs 50 lakh for Hyderabadi girl, Telangana Chief Minister quickly reciprocated the gesture of his counterpart by offering a similar cash reward to Haryana&apos;s Sakshi Malik, the only other person who won the medal in Rio Olympics. Sibling rivalry was also played out in announcing the rewards for Sindhu as AP chief minister sought to take credit for the latest achievement of the Hyderabad athlete as Gopichand&apos;s badminton academy was set up in a plot given for this purpose during his tenure as chief minister in the undivided state. Sindhu was the second Olympic medalist produced by Gopichand academy. Saina Nehwal, who was trained in the academy, had won bronze medal in London Olympics in 2012. AP government is also hosting a similar reception to Sindhu at Vijayawada on Tuesday. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.17</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/sindhu-and-gopichand-receive-grand-welcome-at-hyderabad-116082200359_1.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>B Dasarath Reddy</username>
<post>
Business Standard Sindhu and Gopichand receive grand welcome at Hyderabad Hundreds sports enthusiasts &amp; people waved the badminton star &amp; her coach as they travelled standing on an open top bus August 22, 2016 Last Updated at 12:55 IST email this article Type address separated by commas Your Email: Enter the characters shown in the image. Send me a copy: Copy tiny URL to save and share articles. P V Sindhu and P Gopichand Photo: ANI Twitter Handle ALSO READ Telangana, AP shower cash rewards on Sindhu, Gopichand P V Sindhu&apos;s run to the Olympic semi-final hasn&apos;t happened overnight Where the Saina, Sindhu legends were born KCR increases his son&apos;s role in government Chinese company offers to build irrigation projects in Telangana For once the VVIPs of Telangana and Andhra Pradesh (AP) governments jostled with each other like ordinary sports fans to receive Olympic silver medalist P V Sindhu and her coach Pullela Gopichand and present them with flower bouquets and shawls as the shuttler-coach duo arrived at Rajiv Gandhi International Airport from Rio this morning for a grand welcome organised by the state government. A large contingent of Telangana ministers and public representatives led by minister K T Rama Rao and a team of A P ministers led by Deputy Chief Minister Nimmakayala Chinarajappa among other officials and sports personalities in the city received the badminton star as she stepped out of the airport, with a kind of fan fare that only top film stars or leaders enjoyed on such special moments. Hundreds of students, sports enthusiasts and people waved the badminton star and her coach as they travelled standing on an open top bus in a rally filled with dozens of red and blue VIP beacon cars from the airport to Gachibowli Stadium covering more than 30 km distance. The state government hosted a colorful reception for Sindhu at the stadium amidst song and dance programmes by teams of artists. Police bands played inspirational themes on this occasion. The shuttler received a rousing reception at the stadium as flowers were showered on Sindhu from atop the stadium as she went around to greet the crowds. Thousands of students, parents and sports fans, who were waiting since morning, raised slogans and chanted Sindhu&apos;s name in unison. On Saturday, Telangana Chief Minister K Chandrasekhara Rao announced a cash reward of Rs 5 crore for Olympic silver medalist and Rs 1 crore for her coach Gopichand for winning the country&apos; first Olympic silver medal in women&apos;s category. Earlier AP Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu announced a Rs 3 crore cash reward besides offering a 1,000 square yard residential plot in the upcoming capital Amaravati and a Group-1 government job to Sindhu. As Haryana Chief Minister Manohar Lal Khattar too announced a cash reward of Rs 50 lakh for Hyderabadi girl, Telangana Chief Minister quickly reciprocated the gesture of his counterpart by offering a similar cash reward to Haryana&apos;s Sakshi Malik, the only other person who won the medal in Rio Olympics. Sibling rivalry was also played out in announcing the rewards for Sindhu as AP chief minister sought to take credit for the latest achievement of the Hyderabad athlete as Gopichand&apos;s badminton academy was set up in a plot given for this purpose during his tenure as chief minister in the undivided state. Sindhu was the second Olympic medalist produced by Gopichand academy. Saina Nehwal, who was trained in the academy, had won bronze medal in London Olympics in 2012. AP government is also hosting a similar reception to Sindhu at Vijayawada on Tuesday. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://bsmedia.business-standard.com/_media/bs/img/article/2016-08/22/full/1471844823-9885.jpg</main_image>
</document>
