<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>As Kerry Visits Nigeria Tambuwal</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220174.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 Ahead of the visit of US Secretary of State, John Kerry to Nigeria this week, the Sokoto State Government has said it will collaborate with United States of America to expand access to education with a view to tackling terrorism and promoting small and medium scale industries in the state. Governor Aminu Waziri Tambuwal said this after a meeting with Ambassador Johnnie Carson, an expert on African affairs and also a Senior Advisor with the United States Institute for Peace (USIP). A statement issued on Saturday in Sokoto by Tambuwal&apos;s spokesman, Malam Imam Imam, said the meeting centered on efforts by the state government to increase enrolment in schools, enhance quality output, and develop a framework that will inspire the citizens to develop critical thinking and problem solving skills at a young age. &quot;Governor Tambuwal briefed Carson and his team of efforts to increase literacy and numeracy among vast majority of children left out of school. He also spoke extensively on creating opportunities for youth, women and children, and, importantly, improving other social sectors like health and provision of water in the state. &quot;Issues of gender equality and how to enhance the integration of women into decision-making organs were also discussed,&quot; the statement added. It said government will continue to explore avenues of empowering small and medium scale businesses in order to enhance their potential and increase employment generation in Sokoto state. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220174.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0742</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 Ahead of the visit of US Secretary of State, John Kerry to Nigeria this week, the Sokoto State Government has said it will collaborate with United States of America to expand access to education with a view to tackling terrorism and promoting small and medium scale industries in the state. Governor Aminu Waziri Tambuwal said this after a meeting with Ambassador Johnnie Carson, an expert on African affairs and also a Senior Advisor with the United States Institute for Peace (USIP). A statement issued on Saturday in Sokoto by Tambuwal&apos;s spokesman, Malam Imam Imam, said the meeting centered on efforts by the state government to increase enrolment in schools, enhance quality output, and develop a framework that will inspire the citizens to develop critical thinking and problem solving skills at a young age. &quot;Governor Tambuwal briefed Carson and his team of efforts to increase literacy and numeracy among vast majority of children left out of school. He also spoke extensively on creating opportunities for youth, women and children, and, importantly, improving other social sectors like health and provision of water in the state. &quot;Issues of gender equality and how to enhance the integration of women into decision-making organs were also discussed,&quot; the statement added. It said government will continue to explore avenues of empowering small and medium scale businesses in order to enhance their potential and increase employment generation in Sokoto state. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
