<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>BREAKING! Disquiet As Serious Financial Crunch Hits National Assembly. – Igberetv News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.igberetvnews.com/49313</topic_url>
<topic_text>
22nd August 2016 News No comments Prev 1 of 2 Next Use your ← → (arrow) keys to browse 
These are hard times for Nigeria’s federal legislature as the dwindling economy has affected the finances of the National Assembly. 
According to a report by Daily Trust, contractors and suppliers are grumbling over the inability of the management of the National Assembly to liquidate the accumulated debts. 
These are not smiling times for the leadership of the National Asssembly The report stated that the situation has forced the management to take cost cutting measures including slashing of salaries of legislative aides by about 70 percent. 
A source who within the National Assembly squealed that the management is now taking inventory of the debt stock, while adding that some of the debts incurred through contracts might not have been executed. 
The source said: “It is a yearly occurrence. There are huge debts, no doubt. They’re still in the process of compiling.” Another source said the new clerk to the National Assembly, Alhaji Mohammed Sani-Omolori has demanded for the comprehensive details of the debts profile in order to address the situation. 
“You’ll be shocked if you know the monumental corruption taking place in the management of the National Assembly. They change office equipment every year on paper, but you don’t get to see anything. 
“You can imagine even the maintenance being carried out by Julius Berger at the time was done on credit. It was because of the way they were going about the whole thing that Berger backed out from the contract of maintaining the NASS complex. 
“There are a lot of things my brother. Some of them would raise fake vouchers just to divert the money. Somebody would say he has travelled to somewhere, whereas he was in his house. 
“They also have ghost workers among the NASS staff, but because nobody probes them, people don’t get to know. With this kind of things, how do you expect the country to change?” said the source. 
A management staff of the National Assembly blamed the situation on what he described as, “irregular release of funds by the executive arm of government.” 
According to the staff who spoke under the condition of anonymity, unlike before when the funds were released quarterly, the funds are now being released by the executive arm monthly. 
“Until this administration, the National Assembly funds were released quarterly but now the present administration has adopted a new style. We are now getting our money monthly. 
“This is negatively affecting us because after paying salaries of lawmakers, their aides and National Assembly staff, the remaining money is Prev 1 of 2 Next Use your ← → (arrow) keys to browse About the author 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.03</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.igberetvnews.com/49313</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
22nd August 2016 News No comments Prev 1 of 2 Next Use your ← → (arrow) keys to browse 
These are hard times for Nigeria’s federal legislature as the dwindling economy has affected the finances of the National Assembly. 
According to a report by Daily Trust, contractors and suppliers are grumbling over the inability of the management of the National Assembly to liquidate the accumulated debts. 
These are not smiling times for the leadership of the National Asssembly The report stated that the situation has forced the management to take cost cutting measures including slashing of salaries of legislative aides by about 70 percent. 
A source who within the National Assembly squealed that the management is now taking inventory of the debt stock, while adding that some of the debts incurred through contracts might not have been executed. 
The source said: “It is a yearly occurrence. There are huge debts, no doubt. They’re still in the process of compiling.” Another source said the new clerk to the National Assembly, Alhaji Mohammed Sani-Omolori has demanded for the comprehensive details of the debts profile in order to address the situation. 
“You’ll be shocked if you know the monumental corruption taking place in the management of the National Assembly. They change office equipment every year on paper, but you don’t get to see anything. 
“You can imagine even the maintenance being carried out by Julius Berger at the time was done on credit. It was because of the way they were going about the whole thing that Berger backed out from the contract of maintaining the NASS complex. 
“There are a lot of things my brother. Some of them would raise fake vouchers just to divert the money. Somebody would say he has travelled to somewhere, whereas he was in his house. 
“They also have ghost workers among the NASS staff, but because nobody probes them, people don’t get to know. With this kind of things, how do you expect the country to change?” said the source. 
A management staff of the National Assembly blamed the situation on what he described as, “irregular release of funds by the executive arm of government.” 
According to the staff who spoke under the condition of anonymity, unlike before when the funds were released quarterly, the funds are now being released by the executive arm monthly. 
“Until this administration, the National Assembly funds were released quarterly but now the present administration has adopted a new style. We are now getting our money monthly. 
“This is negatively affecting us because after paying salaries of lawmakers, their aides and National Assembly staff, the remaining money is Prev 1 of 2 Next Use your ← → (arrow) keys to browse About the author 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>medium</main_image>
</document>
