<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.capitalbay.news/feed/news/index.1.rss</forum>
<forum_title>CapitalBay</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Help! My step-daughter’s moved in: At 64, Linda Kelsey was enjoying having the house to herself - until her partner dropped a bombshell</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.capitalbay.news/news/1068983-help-my-step-daughter%E2%80%99s-moved-in-at-64%2C-linda-kelsey-was-enjoying-having-the-house-to-herself-until-her-partner-dropped-a-bombshell.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Linda&apos;s stepdaughter Lora, 31, a psychiatric nurse, became unemployed Her birth mother lives in the countryside while Lora&apos;s life is in London Lora and Linda get on well living together and Lora even told her step-mother she loves her 
By Linda Kelsey for the Daily Mail 
Published: 16:57 EST, 21 August 2016 | Updated: 02:32 EST, 22 August 2016 e-mail 
View comments 
When I first got together with my partner eight years ago at the age of 56, one of the things that clinched the deal was the fact his two girls were already in their 20s and out of the nest. 
The last thing I would have wanted at the time was to become a sudden stepmum to tantrummy toddlers or to find myself in the eye of the hormonal storm of teenage girls. 
My own son, back from university and set up with a good job, was just a few months shy of moving out of the new home I’d bought after my divorce and into a shared house with friends. 
Linda (right) with stepdaughter Lora, who became unemployed and moved in with her 
It had meant that Ron, who planned to move in with me, and I had plenty of ‘us time’ to get to know one another and to adjust to sharing a life without the added responsibilities of parenting one another’s kids. 
So back in February, when Ron tentatively asked how I’d feel if Lora, his younger daughter - albeit now a fully-fledged woman of 31 - came to live with us for an unspecified period, my first instinct was to pour myself a stiff gin and tonic. 
Despite having lived independently for a decade, Lora, a psychiatric nurse working with troubled children and adolescents, had found herself without work through no fault of her own, uncertain of her career direction, and broke. 
Her own mum wasn’t a viable option to move in with because she was now living deep in the countryside, while Lora’s life was in London. 
I didn’t doubt for a moment that I would say of course, let’s invite her to come and stay, because just as I would expect Ron not to object if my son Thomas had a reason for moving back in, I could hardly turn a blind eye to his daughter at a time of crisis. 
Moving in with Lora&apos;s own mother wasn’t a viable option as she had moved to the countryside, while Lora’s life was in London 
Lora needed an anchor and we could try to provide it. One of the things that Ron and I never disagree on is family ties and family loyalty. 
Like so many of her generation of so-called millennials, born in the Eighties, Lora has come to maturity still saddled with student debt, still working out what to do with her life, and resigned for now to a life of renting. 
A total of 3.3 million 20 to 34-year-olds lived with their parents in 2015, according to the Office for National Statistics, just a few thousand less than the previous year, which recorded the highest number since it started keeping records in 1996. 
I was about to experience at first-hand the boomerang phenomenon, whereby cash-strapped adult kids move back in. To say I was apprehensive is something of an understatement. RETURNING TO THE NEST 
More than 3.3 million British adults aged 20-34 are still living, or have moved back in, with their parents 
I sat down with Ron, who had apprehensions of his own, to talk it through. Two rules, I said, must be adhered to. The common quarters, specifically the kitchen and living areas, would have to be kept pristine. 
I make no apology for being a cushion-plumper and someone who cannot sleep peacefully until greasy pans have been scrubbed and put away, and all surfaces wiped clean. 
This needed saying because I’d noticed, on the few occasions Lora has stayed over or when we have shared our holiday apartment in Spain, what I regard as a fling- it-anywhere approach to housekeeping. 
The second rule I realised could prove trickier. Over the years I’d always taken a back seat when things exploded between Lora and her dad, with him inadvertently (but inevitably) pressing the wrong buttons about her approach to life, work and the universe and her laying into him without inhibition. 
‘I won’t have the harmony of this household disrupted by arguments between the two of you,’ I said. ‘Not on my patch.’ 
The truth is I both like and admire Lora. Feisty, chatty and smart, and with a strong sense of right and wrong, she has chosen to take on work that exacts a large emotional toll for a lot less money than she could have earned in other occupations. 
Like so many of her generation, Lora has come to maturity still saddled with student debt and resigned for now to a life of renting 
She is neither materialistic nor acquisitive, but nevertheless has a wonderful sense of personal style, always dressing in riotously colourful clothes culled exclusively from charity shops. 
But there was one other thing that troubled me. Although I knew Lora was pleased her dad had finally found happiness a good few years after he and her mum split up, I wasn’t sure if she actually liked me. 
I couldn’t put my finger on it, but I sometimes sensed a degree of disapproval of my prissy ways, my comparatively well-heeled and somewhat conventional lifestyle. 
It was only a feeling and one I needed perhaps to work out for myself. I also needed to work out how I felt about Lora’s way of being, too. 
It’s only natural, I suppose, that I would find myself comparing Lora’s lifestyle with my own at her age. 
By the time I was 31, I had already been married and divorced, had a home and mortgage of my own, and was about to be appointed editor of Cosmopolitan. For me adulthood, ambition and success had all come early. 
What I’ve come to recognise, though, through living with Lora, is how much easier it was for my generation, with free university education, jobs landing on our laps and tax relief on our youthful mortgages. 
I don’t envy the uncertainty of the millennial generation, the financial insecurity of short-term and zero hours contracts, the transient world of dating apps and the business of reaching your 30s with no clear path ahead. 
The day Lora came to stay, I thought I might have to be the one to move out. As the hallway downstairs filled with more and more of her stuff, I felt resentful of the idea that her dad and I were perhaps little more than a convenient storage container. 
Linda says: &apos;Life with Lora these past few months has worked out so much better than expected&apos; 
What couldn’t fit into her small bedroom would have to be piled up in the outbuilding in our garden that doubles up as an office. Rather than hover and let my disquiet show, I left the house to visit my sister and moan. 
By the time I got home, order was more or less restored, and I suddenly saw it all quite differently. 
After all, I had a lovely house full of my possessions, whereas everything Lora owned fitted into one narrow corridor. How could I possibly begrudge Lora her dressing table, her chest of drawers and a few bits of furniture? 
Life with Lora these past few months has worked out so much better than expected. She moved into my son Thomas’s sober boy bedroom, which had more cables for various items of audio equipment than clothing or personal knick-knacks, and filled it with colour. 
Her clothes hang on rails and as I puff away on the cross trainer, which is in her bedroom, my eyes range over the rainbow colours of Lora’s wacky wardrobe, her technicolour embroidered bedspread, and Thomas’s bookshelves now draped with jewellery, and I smile at this sense of a daughterly presence I’ve never before experienced as the mother to one male child. 
Even ignoring the mess has become easier, which I now recognise is probably Lora’s version of deep-cleaned and tidied. 
At first, when Lora moved in, I felt more polite than relaxed. The same must have gone for her. I noticed that rather than fill in job applications from here as I worked from my study, she would take herself and her laptop off to a cafe to get out of my way. 
Slowly Linda (pictured with husband Ron) and Lora learned to be themselves with one another, and on the day Lora told her she loved her, Linda let out a small sob 
Slowly we have both learned to be ourselves with one another, and on the day she gave me a spontaneous hug and told me she loved me, I let out a small sob. To my relief, Lora did like me after all. 
The expected rows with her dad haven’t materialised. It makes me realise that Lora, who has house-shared for a decade, understands very well the compromises required on all sides. 
It can’t always be easy for her, and my respect for her has grown even stronger. 
Lora’s life is beginning to fall into place again. She has decided to do a masters degree so she can become a qualified child and adolescent psychotherapist, which will mean yet more student debt, but better long-term prospects. She has sorted herself out with two part-time jobs to help with her finances while she studies. Her love life appears to be looking up as well. 
Meanwhile, she lives here rent-free because her dad and I would far rather she saved for when she does move out than hand over what little she earns from shift work to us. 
With her mane of sleek dark hair, olive skin and multi-hued wardrobe, Lora puts me in mind of an exotic bird of paradise that has temporarily veered off course and landed in my own backyard. 
We’re good friends now. After she returns from her temp work in the evening, we sit at the kitchen table and chat. 
When her dad arrives home, he often finds us engaged in conversation while I chop the veg for dinner, and it helps him know it has all turned out OK. 
The expected rows with Lora&apos;s father Ron (pictured) haven’t materialised. It made Linda realise that Lora, who has house-shared for a decade, understands very well the compromises required on all sides 
We take it for granted today that our kids will move out as soon as they can afford it. But in other countries, such as Spain, it’s quite normal for children of both sexes to stay put until they marry or move in with partners. 
Compared with the attitude gulf between us and our parents’ generation, we children of the Sixties - at least in terms of social and sexual mores — are closer to the millennials, and more likely to get on. 
So perhaps it’s time to ditch the stigma and the embarrassment on both sides, and to simply enjoy the boomerang moment for as long as it lasts. 
I do want Lora to move out as soon as she is able, because now she’s passed 30 it has to be better for her in the long-term. 
But while a couple of months ago she gave us August as her deadline, I can’t see anything changing until next year at the earliest. And I find I don’t mind at all. Right now I’m thinking that when she does go, I’ll miss her a lot. 
And that’s the most surprising thing of all. 
LORA SAYS: 
No line can douse the fires of first-date passion faster than ‘I live with my parents’, even when whispered seductively into the ear of your intended. 
Based on this alone, I have even found myself saying no to a second date with someone who had moved back to his parents. The surprise is that this added complication, or Linda as I should call her, has been the saving grace of the situation 
I became acutely aware of the irony of this when I joined the hordes of returnees. 
I hadn’t realised how much independent living defined me until I had to give it up. In fact, until recently, I avoided discussing the topic with old and new friends. 
The news would always be delivered as a fleeting statement or omitted completely. Like my online dating profile, my living status remained without update. 
I have the added complication of the fact I am actually living with my father and his partner, in a house that she owns. 
The surprise is that this added complication, or Linda as I should call her, has been the saving grace of the situation. She has provided the buffer between me and my very loving, but worrywart, dad. 
It is incredible how quickly I revert back to my teenage self when cornered over certain lifestyle choices. 
Linda has proved to be a surprising buffer for arguments between Lora and her father (file photo) 
Last summer, following the loss of my job due to government funding cuts, I found myself at a crossroads. I had lost confidence in my chosen career path and didn’t know what to do next. I started making ambitious, if somewhat outlandish, plans to run away and join a foreign aid agency. 
While both my parents were pretty horrified by the idea, my father, guided by Linda, offered me a place to stay while I figured things out. It was under this proviso that they tricked me into moving back, hoping I’d change my mind about moving continents. 
Linda’s house is a far cry from the suburban semi I grew up in. As children, my sister and I used to covet the one piece of antiquity our house had to offer, a reproduction carriage clock that we were convinced would be worth a fortune at the Antiques Roadshow. 
In my current surroundings, Linda has lovingly filled the space with beautiful artwork and mid-century furniture. Linda letting me into her home has allowed me to address the fact I’ve never told her I loved her, something I found myself rectifying recently while helping to put the groceries away 
Despite having lived here for more than seven years, my father still feels the need to run everything domestic past Linda, as though he still feels more of a guest than a co-habitee. 
This used to irk me somewhat, but in time I’ve realised it says more about my father’s anxieties than Linda’s. Yes, she likes things a certain way, no shoes on the carpet upstairs and for some reason she keeps her potatoes in the fridge. But she owns these quirks of hers completely. 
Yes, I may feel under scrutiny while washing up and putting things away in the kitchen. And, yes, the fact I share my room with Linda’s gym equipment means I have to remember to pick up my knickers more diligently than before. 
But Linda letting me into her home has allowed me to address the fact I’ve never told her I loved her, something I found myself rectifying recently while helping to put the groceries away. 
At the beginning I would find any opportunity to stay out during the week. 
And, you know what, it’s kind of nice when my father checks in by text in the morning following one of my after-work drinks that has turned into an all-nighter. 
I haven’t lived with my dad for 13 years. Since the age of 18 I’ve moved 12 times. I’m hoping to make my 13th at the start of next year - if Linda can put up with my unruly dishwasher loading techniques until then. Most watched News videos Share Or Comment On This Article Disclaimer : Opinions expressed here are those of the writers and do not reflect those of Capitalbay. Capitalbay accepts no responsibility legal or otherwise for their accuracy of content. Please report any inappropriate content to us, and we will evaluate it as a matter of priority. What&apos;s next
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.capitalbay.news/news/1068983-help-my-step-daughter%E2%80%99s-moved-in-at-64%2C-linda-kelsey-was-enjoying-having-the-house-to-herself-until-her-partner-dropped-a-bombshell.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0732</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Linda&apos;s stepdaughter Lora, 31, a psychiatric nurse, became unemployed Her birth mother lives in the countryside while Lora&apos;s life is in London Lora and Linda get on well living together and Lora even told her step-mother she loves her 
By Linda Kelsey for the Daily Mail 
Published: 16:57 EST, 21 August 2016 | Updated: 02:32 EST, 22 August 2016 e-mail 
View comments 
When I first got together with my partner eight years ago at the age of 56, one of the things that clinched the deal was the fact his two girls were already in their 20s and out of the nest. 
The last thing I would have wanted at the time was to become a sudden stepmum to tantrummy toddlers or to find myself in the eye of the hormonal storm of teenage girls. 
My own son, back from university and set up with a good job, was just a few months shy of moving out of the new home I’d bought after my divorce and into a shared house with friends. 
Linda (right) with stepdaughter Lora, who became unemployed and moved in with her 
It had meant that Ron, who planned to move in with me, and I had plenty of ‘us time’ to get to know one another and to adjust to sharing a life without the added responsibilities of parenting one another’s kids. 
So back in February, when Ron tentatively asked how I’d feel if Lora, his younger daughter - albeit now a fully-fledged woman of 31 - came to live with us for an unspecified period, my first instinct was to pour myself a stiff gin and tonic. 
Despite having lived independently for a decade, Lora, a psychiatric nurse working with troubled children and adolescents, had found herself without work through no fault of her own, uncertain of her career direction, and broke. 
Her own mum wasn’t a viable option to move in with because she was now living deep in the countryside, while Lora’s life was in London. 
I didn’t doubt for a moment that I would say of course, let’s invite her to come and stay, because just as I would expect Ron not to object if my son Thomas had a reason for moving back in, I could hardly turn a blind eye to his daughter at a time of crisis. 
Moving in with Lora&apos;s own mother wasn’t a viable option as she had moved to the countryside, while Lora’s life was in London 
Lora needed an anchor and we could try to provide it. One of the things that Ron and I never disagree on is family ties and family loyalty. 
Like so many of her generation of so-called millennials, born in the Eighties, Lora has come to maturity still saddled with student debt, still working out what to do with her life, and resigned for now to a life of renting. 
A total of 3.3 million 20 to 34-year-olds lived with their parents in 2015, according to the Office for National Statistics, just a few thousand less than the previous year, which recorded the highest number since it started keeping records in 1996. 
I was about to experience at first-hand the boomerang phenomenon, whereby cash-strapped adult kids move back in. To say I was apprehensive is something of an understatement. RETURNING TO THE NEST 
More than 3.3 million British adults aged 20-34 are still living, or have moved back in, with their parents 
I sat down with Ron, who had apprehensions of his own, to talk it through. Two rules, I said, must be adhered to. The common quarters, specifically the kitchen and living areas, would have to be kept pristine. 
I make no apology for being a cushion-plumper and someone who cannot sleep peacefully until greasy pans have been scrubbed and put away, and all surfaces wiped clean. 
This needed saying because I’d noticed, on the few occasions Lora has stayed over or when we have shared our holiday apartment in Spain, what I regard as a fling- it-anywhere approach to housekeeping. 
The second rule I realised could prove trickier. Over the years I’d always taken a back seat when things exploded between Lora and her dad, with him inadvertently (but inevitably) pressing the wrong buttons about her approach to life, work and the universe and her laying into him without inhibition. 
‘I won’t have the harmony of this household disrupted by arguments between the two of you,’ I said. ‘Not on my patch.’ 
The truth is I both like and admire Lora. Feisty, chatty and smart, and with a strong sense of right and wrong, she has chosen to take on work that exacts a large emotional toll for a lot less money than she could have earned in other occupations. 
Like so many of her generation, Lora has come to maturity still saddled with student debt and resigned for now to a life of renting 
She is neither materialistic nor acquisitive, but nevertheless has a wonderful sense of personal style, always dressing in riotously colourful clothes culled exclusively from charity shops. 
But there was one other thing that troubled me. Although I knew Lora was pleased her dad had finally found happiness a good few years after he and her mum split up, I wasn’t sure if she actually liked me. 
I couldn’t put my finger on it, but I sometimes sensed a degree of disapproval of my prissy ways, my comparatively well-heeled and somewhat conventional lifestyle. 
It was only a feeling and one I needed perhaps to work out for myself. I also needed to work out how I felt about Lora’s way of being, too. 
It’s only natural, I suppose, that I would find myself comparing Lora’s lifestyle with my own at her age. 
By the time I was 31, I had already been married and divorced, had a home and mortgage of my own, and was about to be appointed editor of Cosmopolitan. For me adulthood, ambition and success had all come early. 
What I’ve come to recognise, though, through living with Lora, is how much easier it was for my generation, with free university education, jobs landing on our laps and tax relief on our youthful mortgages. 
I don’t envy the uncertainty of the millennial generation, the financial insecurity of short-term and zero hours contracts, the transient world of dating apps and the business of reaching your 30s with no clear path ahead. 
The day Lora came to stay, I thought I might have to be the one to move out. As the hallway downstairs filled with more and more of her stuff, I felt resentful of the idea that her dad and I were perhaps little more than a convenient storage container. 
Linda says: &apos;Life with Lora these past few months has worked out so much better than expected&apos; 
What couldn’t fit into her small bedroom would have to be piled up in the outbuilding in our garden that doubles up as an office. Rather than hover and let my disquiet show, I left the house to visit my sister and moan. 
By the time I got home, order was more or less restored, and I suddenly saw it all quite differently. 
After all, I had a lovely house full of my possessions, whereas everything Lora owned fitted into one narrow corridor. How could I possibly begrudge Lora her dressing table, her chest of drawers and a few bits of furniture? 
Life with Lora these past few months has worked out so much better than expected. She moved into my son Thomas’s sober boy bedroom, which had more cables for various items of audio equipment than clothing or personal knick-knacks, and filled it with colour. 
Her clothes hang on rails and as I puff away on the cross trainer, which is in her bedroom, my eyes range over the rainbow colours of Lora’s wacky wardrobe, her technicolour embroidered bedspread, and Thomas’s bookshelves now draped with jewellery, and I smile at this sense of a daughterly presence I’ve never before experienced as the mother to one male child. 
Even ignoring the mess has become easier, which I now recognise is probably Lora’s version of deep-cleaned and tidied. 
At first, when Lora moved in, I felt more polite than relaxed. The same must have gone for her. I noticed that rather than fill in job applications from here as I worked from my study, she would take herself and her laptop off to a cafe to get out of my way. 
Slowly Linda (pictured with husband Ron) and Lora learned to be themselves with one another, and on the day Lora told her she loved her, Linda let out a small sob 
Slowly we have both learned to be ourselves with one another, and on the day she gave me a spontaneous hug and told me she loved me, I let out a small sob. To my relief, Lora did like me after all. 
The expected rows with her dad haven’t materialised. It makes me realise that Lora, who has house-shared for a decade, understands very well the compromises required on all sides. 
It can’t always be easy for her, and my respect for her has grown even stronger. 
Lora’s life is beginning to fall into place again. She has decided to do a masters degree so she can become a qualified child and adolescent psychotherapist, which will mean yet more student debt, but better long-term prospects. She has sorted herself out with two part-time jobs to help with her finances while she studies. Her love life appears to be looking up as well. 
Meanwhile, she lives here rent-free because her dad and I would far rather she saved for when she does move out than hand over what little she earns from shift work to us. 
With her mane of sleek dark hair, olive skin and multi-hued wardrobe, Lora puts me in mind of an exotic bird of paradise that has temporarily veered off course and landed in my own backyard. 
We’re good friends now. After she returns from her temp work in the evening, we sit at the kitchen table and chat. 
When her dad arrives home, he often finds us engaged in conversation while I chop the veg for dinner, and it helps him know it has all turned out OK. 
The expected rows with Lora&apos;s father Ron (pictured) haven’t materialised. It made Linda realise that Lora, who has house-shared for a decade, understands very well the compromises required on all sides 
We take it for granted today that our kids will move out as soon as they can afford it. But in other countries, such as Spain, it’s quite normal for children of both sexes to stay put until they marry or move in with partners. 
Compared with the attitude gulf between us and our parents’ generation, we children of the Sixties - at least in terms of social and sexual mores — are closer to the millennials, and more likely to get on. 
So perhaps it’s time to ditch the stigma and the embarrassment on both sides, and to simply enjoy the boomerang moment for as long as it lasts. 
I do want Lora to move out as soon as she is able, because now she’s passed 30 it has to be better for her in the long-term. 
But while a couple of months ago she gave us August as her deadline, I can’t see anything changing until next year at the earliest. And I find I don’t mind at all. Right now I’m thinking that when she does go, I’ll miss her a lot. 
And that’s the most surprising thing of all. 
LORA SAYS: 
No line can douse the fires of first-date passion faster than ‘I live with my parents’, even when whispered seductively into the ear of your intended. 
Based on this alone, I have even found myself saying no to a second date with someone who had moved back to his parents. The surprise is that this added complication, or Linda as I should call her, has been the saving grace of the situation 
I became acutely aware of the irony of this when I joined the hordes of returnees. 
I hadn’t realised how much independent living defined me until I had to give it up. In fact, until recently, I avoided discussing the topic with old and new friends. 
The news would always be delivered as a fleeting statement or omitted completely. Like my online dating profile, my living status remained without update. 
I have the added complication of the fact I am actually living with my father and his partner, in a house that she owns. 
The surprise is that this added complication, or Linda as I should call her, has been the saving grace of the situation. She has provided the buffer between me and my very loving, but worrywart, dad. 
It is incredible how quickly I revert back to my teenage self when cornered over certain lifestyle choices. 
Linda has proved to be a surprising buffer for arguments between Lora and her father (file photo) 
Last summer, following the loss of my job due to government funding cuts, I found myself at a crossroads. I had lost confidence in my chosen career path and didn’t know what to do next. I started making ambitious, if somewhat outlandish, plans to run away and join a foreign aid agency. 
While both my parents were pretty horrified by the idea, my father, guided by Linda, offered me a place to stay while I figured things out. It was under this proviso that they tricked me into moving back, hoping I’d change my mind about moving continents. 
Linda’s house is a far cry from the suburban semi I grew up in. As children, my sister and I used to covet the one piece of antiquity our house had to offer, a reproduction carriage clock that we were convinced would be worth a fortune at the Antiques Roadshow. 
In my current surroundings, Linda has lovingly filled the space with beautiful artwork and mid-century furniture. Linda letting me into her home has allowed me to address the fact I’ve never told her I loved her, something I found myself rectifying recently while helping to put the groceries away 
Despite having lived here for more than seven years, my father still feels the need to run everything domestic past Linda, as though he still feels more of a guest than a co-habitee. 
This used to irk me somewhat, but in time I’ve realised it says more about my father’s anxieties than Linda’s. Yes, she likes things a certain way, no shoes on the carpet upstairs and for some reason she keeps her potatoes in the fridge. But she owns these quirks of hers completely. 
Yes, I may feel under scrutiny while washing up and putting things away in the kitchen. And, yes, the fact I share my room with Linda’s gym equipment means I have to remember to pick up my knickers more diligently than before. 
But Linda letting me into her home has allowed me to address the fact I’ve never told her I loved her, something I found myself rectifying recently while helping to put the groceries away. 
At the beginning I would find any opportunity to stay out during the week. 
And, you know what, it’s kind of nice when my father checks in by text in the morning following one of my after-work drinks that has turned into an all-nighter. 
I haven’t lived with my dad for 13 years. Since the age of 18 I’ve moved 12 times. I’m hoping to make my 13th at the start of next year - if Linda can put up with my unruly dishwasher loading techniques until then. Most watched News videos Share Or Comment On This Article Disclaimer : Opinions expressed here are those of the writers and do not reflect those of Capitalbay. Capitalbay accepts no responsibility legal or otherwise for their accuracy of content. Please report any inappropriate content to us, and we will evaluate it as a matter of priority. What&apos;s next
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.capitalbay.com/thumbnail.php?file=&amp;size=article_large</main_image>
</document>
