<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://mice-contact.com/rss.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Recent News Releases from MICE-Contact.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Thailand hikes visa-on-arrival fee</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://mice-contact.com/news/detail/article/thailand-hik.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Thailand hikes visa-on-arrival fee 
Aug 22, 2016 Thailand will double its visa-on-arrival fee, 27 September, and China and India, two of the most promising tourism markets for Thailand, are on the list of 19 nationalities. Thailand’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs Consular Department released details of the VOA fee increase 11 August. The Consular Department confirmed it would double the cost of a visa-on-arrival from THB1,000 to THB2,000 for 19 nationalities. The visa, valid for 15 days, is available at 42 immigration checkpoints, mainly land borders, but also all designated international airports and sea ports in the country. There are no surprises on the list of nationalities with the exception of China, India and Taiwan, all three important inbound travel markets for Thailand. China generated 7,954,791 visits in 2015, up by an astounding 71%. This year, it is likely the tally will reach 10 million. There have been calls to allow visa-free travel for Chinese visitors as it is now the largest single tourism market for the country exceeding Malaysia 1(5 days visa-free travel) that supplied 3,423,397 visits up 30.99% in 2015. Thailand gained 1,069,149 visitors from India, last year, up 14.64%. Tourism Authority of Thailand identifies India as a priority, emerging market along side Brazil, Russia and China (BRIC). Already, India generates more tourists for Thailand than the UK market where citizens enjoy visa-free travel to Thailand for up to 60 days. Taiwan supplied 552,624 visitors in 2015 up 40.21% on 2014. It is one of the oldest travel markets for Thailand alongside Hong Kong. The 19 nationalities that will have to pay double for a visa-on-arrival are: Andorra; Bulgaria; Bhutan; China; Cyprus; Ethiopia; India; Kazakhstan; Latvia; Lithuania; Maldives; Malta; Mauritius; Romania; San Marino; Saudi Arabia; Taiwan; Ukraine and Uzbekistan.With the exception of China, India, Taiwan and Saudi Arabia none of the nationalities muster enough tourists to be identified individually on the Ministry of Tourism and Sport annual tourist arrivals charts. But local media, last week, claimed the Ministry of Foreign Affairs hopes the higher visa-on-arrival fee will reduce queues at immigration checkpoints at Bangkok’s Suvarnabhumi and Don Mueang airports. However, the move may encourage more Chinese to apply for a visa in advance at the nearest Thai consulate or embassy using online applications and postal delivery for their passport. Critics say a simplified visa-on-arrival form, with a pre-processed online option, including pre-payment, would cut the workload at the airport to just stamping the visa in the passport. It would reduce queues more effectively than raising the visa-fee. Security concerns could be addressed by checking the Interpol blacklist. That would require the immigration authorities to invest in a subscription of around USD25,000 to assess security data. Critics quote the highly successful online visa process offered by Myanmar, which is pre-processed and approved and paid for by credit cards. However, immigration officials still have the final say at the checkpoint to validate the visa in the passport or not. Visa-on-arrival immigration checkpoints
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://mice-contact.com/news/detail/article/thailand-hik.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0652</post_time>
<username>info@mice-contact.com</username>
<post>
Thailand hikes visa-on-arrival fee 
Aug 22, 2016 Thailand will double its visa-on-arrival fee, 27 September, and China and India, two of the most promising tourism markets for Thailand, are on the list of 19 nationalities. Thailand’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs Consular Department released details of the VOA fee increase 11 August. The Consular Department confirmed it would double the cost of a visa-on-arrival from THB1,000 to THB2,000 for 19 nationalities. The visa, valid for 15 days, is available at 42 immigration checkpoints, mainly land borders, but also all designated international airports and sea ports in the country. There are no surprises on the list of nationalities with the exception of China, India and Taiwan, all three important inbound travel markets for Thailand. China generated 7,954,791 visits in 2015, up by an astounding 71%. This year, it is likely the tally will reach 10 million. There have been calls to allow visa-free travel for Chinese visitors as it is now the largest single tourism market for the country exceeding Malaysia 1(5 days visa-free travel) that supplied 3,423,397 visits up 30.99% in 2015. Thailand gained 1,069,149 visitors from India, last year, up 14.64%. Tourism Authority of Thailand identifies India as a priority, emerging market along side Brazil, Russia and China (BRIC). Already, India generates more tourists for Thailand than the UK market where citizens enjoy visa-free travel to Thailand for up to 60 days. Taiwan supplied 552,624 visitors in 2015 up 40.21% on 2014. It is one of the oldest travel markets for Thailand alongside Hong Kong. The 19 nationalities that will have to pay double for a visa-on-arrival are: Andorra; Bulgaria; Bhutan; China; Cyprus; Ethiopia; India; Kazakhstan; Latvia; Lithuania; Maldives; Malta; Mauritius; Romania; San Marino; Saudi Arabia; Taiwan; Ukraine and Uzbekistan.With the exception of China, India, Taiwan and Saudi Arabia none of the nationalities muster enough tourists to be identified individually on the Ministry of Tourism and Sport annual tourist arrivals charts. But local media, last week, claimed the Ministry of Foreign Affairs hopes the higher visa-on-arrival fee will reduce queues at immigration checkpoints at Bangkok’s Suvarnabhumi and Don Mueang airports. However, the move may encourage more Chinese to apply for a visa in advance at the nearest Thai consulate or embassy using online applications and postal delivery for their passport. Critics say a simplified visa-on-arrival form, with a pre-processed online option, including pre-payment, would cut the workload at the airport to just stamping the visa in the passport. It would reduce queues more effectively than raising the visa-fee. Security concerns could be addressed by checking the Interpol blacklist. That would require the immigration authorities to invest in a subscription of around USD25,000 to assess security data. Critics quote the highly successful online visa process offered by Myanmar, which is pre-processed and approved and paid for by credit cards. However, immigration officials still have the final say at the checkpoint to validate the visa in the passport or not. Visa-on-arrival immigration checkpoints
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>DE</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
