<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Gallup</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.emergencegrowth.com/gallup.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
How Does it Work? Our definition of a strengths team is an imperfect but talented group of contributors, who are valued for their strengths and who need one another to realise individual and team excellence. We use the following simple, but proven 5-step approach to building team strengths that empowers individuals and managers: Create awareness of the principles of strength based development; Increase awareness of and appreciation for the team’s individual and collective talents and strengths; Enable the team’s application of the principles of strength based development; Increase the team members application of their individual and collective talents and strengths; and Conclude with a team strategy and action plan. Strengths Development Process The role of the manager is critical in the success of the process. We help managers gain awareness and appreciation of their talents within the context of their role as people leaders. We will also help managers gain an understanding of and appreciation for each team member’s unique and powerful talents. When team members are aware of each other’s talent filters, they understand how each person is inclined to think, act and feel. This awareness helps the team navigate the issues all teams encounter. They understand how the team can best work together to accomplish its goals and performance objectives. During the team building workshop we use a team strengths grid to create awareness and help team members understand how best the team can work together. The Team Strengths Grid By the end of the team building workshop, the following outputs are achieved: Identification of individual strengths (name); The development of a team strengths grid (claim); and The development of a team strategy and plan (aim). In order for the team building workshop to be effective, it is suggested that each member of the team complete the Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment. All people have unique combination of talents, knowledge, and skills -- strengths -- that they use in their daily lives to do their work, achieve their goals, and interact with others. Gallup has found that when people understand and apply their strengths, the effect on their lives and work is transformational. People who use their strengths every day are six times more likely to be engaged in their work and three times more likely to say they have an excellent quality of life. Yet, many people do not know what their strengths are or have the opportunity to use them to their advantage. In fact, many people tend to focus on fixing their weaknesses. By exploring the ways in which you naturally think, feel, and behave, the Clifton StrengthsFinder can identify and build on the areas where you have infinite potential to grow and succeed. “What will happen when we think about what is right with people rather than fixating on what is wrong with them ?” - Donald O. Clifton, Ph.D The Clifton StrengthsFinder contains 34 strengths spread across the four domains of: influencing, relationship building, executing and strategic thinking. The Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment is an easy to use on-line assessment that takes about 20 minutes to complete. Once completed, participants receive a full report of either their top 5 or all 34 strengths, dependent on the option selected. Once a participant has their report, they can use this to agree a further development plan with their managers or coach. In order to keep the momentum of a strengths based development approach, be that strengths or a team based strengths approach; we advocate that individuals are identified to become certified coaches within organisations. Should you not want to train up your own certified coaches, we would be happy to provide further coaching support where required. Achieve an elite level of coaching by completing Gallup’s strengths coaching certification process. People seek a coach when they need a navigator for their journey or when they believe an alternative perspective or broadening of their outlook will make them more effective or even better than they are today. Based on more than four decades of the study of talents, strengths, and success, Gallup’s Accelerated Strengths Coaching course is an invaluable opportunity to help you understand and apply the principles of strengths-based development to advance you’re coaching and help your organisation learn, grow, develop, and achieve personal and professional success. What you can expect This advanced four-and-a-half-day course will accelerate your coaching. You will gain tools, techniques, and invaluable experience to help you help others understand how they filter their world. You will receive sophisticated insights to help your clients respond to situations, work with others, get work done, and understand their biases and vulnerabilities. Two groundbreaking coaching kits are included in the price of the programme: Strengths Coaching Starter Kit; and Coaching Managers and Teams Kit. The tools in these kits, coupled with the educational experiences in the course, will assist you in helping your clients harness their strengths to achieve success. This course also includes an individual coaching session with a Gallup strengths coach. During this program, you will learn how to integrate the principles of strengths-based development into your coaching and improve your coaching by: Applying your greatest talents in your role as a coach and integrating your strengths to become a more effective coach; Helping your clients understand their talents and how to use them to produce results and reach their goals; Helping your clients overcome obstacles, weaknesses, and vulnerabilities; Educating clients about how to use strengths to transform their relationships; Helping individuals understand their unique strengths within the context of others; Providing managers with techniques for using strengths-based development to address specific team-related issues and challenges; and Teaching teams to discover, develop, and use their unique talents for greater team engagement and productivity. If there are 6 or more people in your organisation that wish to attend, we are able to deliver the programme at your location. 
The Clifton StrengthsFinder measures the presence of talents in 34 general areas referred to as “Signature themes.” These Signature themes represent what how you naturally think, feel, and behave as unique individuals. 
Over a secure connection, the Clifton StrengthsFinder presents 178 items to the respondent. Each item consists of a pair of potential self-descriptors, such as “I read instructions carefully” versus “I like to jump right into things.” The descriptors are placed as if anchoring polar ends of a continuum. The respondent is then asked to choose from that pair the statement that best describes him or her, and to what extent that chosen option is descriptive. The respondent gets 20 seconds to respond to a given pair of descriptors before the system moves on to the next pair. (Clifton StrengthsFinder developmental research showed that the 20-second limit resulted in a negligible item non-completion rate.) 
Upon completing the Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment, respondents receive a report displaying their top five (most dominant) themes. The respondent then has the opportunity to delve into those themes to discover his or her greatest talents. Visualize Your Goals &amp; Make Your Dreams Come True! Employee Turnover Among employees recieving some strengths feedback, Turnover rates were 14.9% lower than those employees recieving nothing Productivity Those whos managers recieved strengths feedback showed 12.5% greater productivity post-intervention. Profitability Those units whose managers recieved strengths feedback showed 8.9% greater profitability post intervention relative to units where managers recieved nothing. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.20</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.emergencegrowth.com/gallup.html</post_url>
<post_date>20161226</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
How Does it Work? Our definition of a strengths team is an imperfect but talented group of contributors, who are valued for their strengths and who need one another to realise individual and team excellence. We use the following simple, but proven 5-step approach to building team strengths that empowers individuals and managers: Create awareness of the principles of strength based development; Increase awareness of and appreciation for the team’s individual and collective talents and strengths; Enable the team’s application of the principles of strength based development; Increase the team members application of their individual and collective talents and strengths; and Conclude with a team strategy and action plan. Strengths Development Process The role of the manager is critical in the success of the process. We help managers gain awareness and appreciation of their talents within the context of their role as people leaders. We will also help managers gain an understanding of and appreciation for each team member’s unique and powerful talents. When team members are aware of each other’s talent filters, they understand how each person is inclined to think, act and feel. This awareness helps the team navigate the issues all teams encounter. They understand how the team can best work together to accomplish its goals and performance objectives. During the team building workshop we use a team strengths grid to create awareness and help team members understand how best the team can work together. The Team Strengths Grid By the end of the team building workshop, the following outputs are achieved: Identification of individual strengths (name); The development of a team strengths grid (claim); and The development of a team strategy and plan (aim). In order for the team building workshop to be effective, it is suggested that each member of the team complete the Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment. All people have unique combination of talents, knowledge, and skills -- strengths -- that they use in their daily lives to do their work, achieve their goals, and interact with others. Gallup has found that when people understand and apply their strengths, the effect on their lives and work is transformational. People who use their strengths every day are six times more likely to be engaged in their work and three times more likely to say they have an excellent quality of life. Yet, many people do not know what their strengths are or have the opportunity to use them to their advantage. In fact, many people tend to focus on fixing their weaknesses. By exploring the ways in which you naturally think, feel, and behave, the Clifton StrengthsFinder can identify and build on the areas where you have infinite potential to grow and succeed. “What will happen when we think about what is right with people rather than fixating on what is wrong with them ?” - Donald O. Clifton, Ph.D The Clifton StrengthsFinder contains 34 strengths spread across the four domains of: influencing, relationship building, executing and strategic thinking. The Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment is an easy to use on-line assessment that takes about 20 minutes to complete. Once completed, participants receive a full report of either their top 5 or all 34 strengths, dependent on the option selected. Once a participant has their report, they can use this to agree a further development plan with their managers or coach. In order to keep the momentum of a strengths based development approach, be that strengths or a team based strengths approach; we advocate that individuals are identified to become certified coaches within organisations. Should you not want to train up your own certified coaches, we would be happy to provide further coaching support where required. Achieve an elite level of coaching by completing Gallup’s strengths coaching certification process. People seek a coach when they need a navigator for their journey or when they believe an alternative perspective or broadening of their outlook will make them more effective or even better than they are today. Based on more than four decades of the study of talents, strengths, and success, Gallup’s Accelerated Strengths Coaching course is an invaluable opportunity to help you understand and apply the principles of strengths-based development to advance you’re coaching and help your organisation learn, grow, develop, and achieve personal and professional success. What you can expect This advanced four-and-a-half-day course will accelerate your coaching. You will gain tools, techniques, and invaluable experience to help you help others understand how they filter their world. You will receive sophisticated insights to help your clients respond to situations, work with others, get work done, and understand their biases and vulnerabilities. Two groundbreaking coaching kits are included in the price of the programme: Strengths Coaching Starter Kit; and Coaching Managers and Teams Kit. The tools in these kits, coupled with the educational experiences in the course, will assist you in helping your clients harness their strengths to achieve success. This course also includes an individual coaching session with a Gallup strengths coach. During this program, you will learn how to integrate the principles of strengths-based development into your coaching and improve your coaching by: Applying your greatest talents in your role as a coach and integrating your strengths to become a more effective coach; Helping your clients understand their talents and how to use them to produce results and reach their goals; Helping your clients overcome obstacles, weaknesses, and vulnerabilities; Educating clients about how to use strengths to transform their relationships; Helping individuals understand their unique strengths within the context of others; Providing managers with techniques for using strengths-based development to address specific team-related issues and challenges; and Teaching teams to discover, develop, and use their unique talents for greater team engagement and productivity. If there are 6 or more people in your organisation that wish to attend, we are able to deliver the programme at your location. 
The Clifton StrengthsFinder measures the presence of talents in 34 general areas referred to as “Signature themes.” These Signature themes represent what how you naturally think, feel, and behave as unique individuals. 
Over a secure connection, the Clifton StrengthsFinder presents 178 items to the respondent. Each item consists of a pair of potential self-descriptors, such as “I read instructions carefully” versus “I like to jump right into things.” The descriptors are placed as if anchoring polar ends of a continuum. The respondent is then asked to choose from that pair the statement that best describes him or her, and to what extent that chosen option is descriptive. The respondent gets 20 seconds to respond to a given pair of descriptors before the system moves on to the next pair. (Clifton StrengthsFinder developmental research showed that the 20-second limit resulted in a negligible item non-completion rate.) 
Upon completing the Clifton StrengthsFinder assessment, respondents receive a report displaying their top five (most dominant) themes. The respondent then has the opportunity to delve into those themes to discover his or her greatest talents. Visualize Your Goals &amp; Make Your Dreams Come True! Employee Turnover Among employees recieving some strengths feedback, Turnover rates were 14.9% lower than those employees recieving nothing Productivity Those whos managers recieved strengths feedback showed 12.5% greater productivity post-intervention. Profitability Those units whose managers recieved strengths feedback showed 8.9% greater profitability post intervention relative to units where managers recieved nothing. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
