<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.walesonline.co.uk/sport/?service=rss</forum>
<forum_title>walesonline - Sport</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Swansea City legend Leon Britton signs one-year contract extension</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.walesonline.co.uk/sport/football/football-news/swansea-city-legend-leon-britton-11780783</topic_url>
<topic_text>
By the time his new deal runs out, Britton will have been at the Swans for 16 years Shares Get rugby news by email Getty Images Leon Britton captained the Swans at Burnley Leon Britton will be at Swansea City until at least 2018 after penning a one-year contract extension. The midfielder earned his 500th appearance for the Swans last season and will have spent 16 years at the South Wales club by the time his new contract expires. Sorting a new deal can sometimes be a lengthy process but Britton suggested this might be the easiest negotiations the club have ever been involved in. 
“Signing the extension was a very easy decision, like most of my contracts at Swansea have been,” Britton said. 
“I spoke to the chairman and said if you are happy to have me, let’s just keep the same terms. I think it’s one of the easiest contracts the club have ever drawn up. 
“If you include the loan deals when I first came, I have now signed 13 contracts at Swansea. Huw Evans Picture Agency Leon Britton has a shot on goal Read More Swansea City begin talks on stadium expansion 
“You never know, there might be a 14th - it’s down to me to try to prove I can still do a job. 
“Getting up to 600 appearances for the club might be a big ask, but you have always got to have targets.&quot; 
The longest serving player at the club accepts that days of playing week in, week out may be behind him but is intent on playing as much as possible before he hangs up his boots. 
Britton, who turns 34 next month, understands that his role is different now and is happy to help out in whatever way he can. 
“Looking forward, I know my role will change a little bit in terms of not playing as regularly as I have done over the years,” he added. Leon Britton training in Washington Read More Swansea City linked with move for Udinese defender as club searches for Ashley Williams replacement 
“I have spoken to the manager about that and I understand it. I have said to him that I am ready to start, to come on or just to be involved in the squad and trying to help the other players. 
“I will just train well, keep fit and be ready for the manager however he wants to use me. 
“At my age, maybe that sharpness you have when you are 24 or 25 is not there. You have to adjust your game a bit. You try to read the game better and use your experience. 
&quot;I think there is life in me yet.&quot;
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.walesonline.co.uk/sport/football/football-news/swansea-city-legend-leon-britton-11780783</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0723</post_time>
<username>Matthew Southcombe</username>
<post>
By the time his new deal runs out, Britton will have been at the Swans for 16 years Shares Get rugby news by email Getty Images Leon Britton captained the Swans at Burnley Leon Britton will be at Swansea City until at least 2018 after penning a one-year contract extension. The midfielder earned his 500th appearance for the Swans last season and will have spent 16 years at the South Wales club by the time his new contract expires. Sorting a new deal can sometimes be a lengthy process but Britton suggested this might be the easiest negotiations the club have ever been involved in. 
“Signing the extension was a very easy decision, like most of my contracts at Swansea have been,” Britton said. 
“I spoke to the chairman and said if you are happy to have me, let’s just keep the same terms. I think it’s one of the easiest contracts the club have ever drawn up. 
“If you include the loan deals when I first came, I have now signed 13 contracts at Swansea. Huw Evans Picture Agency Leon Britton has a shot on goal Read More Swansea City begin talks on stadium expansion 
“You never know, there might be a 14th - it’s down to me to try to prove I can still do a job. 
“Getting up to 600 appearances for the club might be a big ask, but you have always got to have targets.&quot; 
The longest serving player at the club accepts that days of playing week in, week out may be behind him but is intent on playing as much as possible before he hangs up his boots. 
Britton, who turns 34 next month, understands that his role is different now and is happy to help out in whatever way he can. 
“Looking forward, I know my role will change a little bit in terms of not playing as regularly as I have done over the years,” he added. Leon Britton training in Washington Read More Swansea City linked with move for Udinese defender as club searches for Ashley Williams replacement 
“I have spoken to the manager about that and I understand it. I have said to him that I am ready to start, to come on or just to be involved in the squad and trying to help the other players. 
“I will just train well, keep fit and be ready for the manager however he wants to use me. 
“At my age, maybe that sharpness you have when you are 24 or 25 is not there. You have to adjust your game a bit. You try to read the game better and use your experience. 
&quot;I think there is life in me yet.&quot;
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://i4.walesonline.co.uk/incoming/article11780786.ece/ALTERNATES/s1200/JS97073008.jpg</main_image>
</document>
