<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.expressandstar.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Midlands News – West Midlands Local News - UK News « Express &amp; Star</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Memorable moments from the 2016 Rio Olympics</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.expressandstar.com/sport/uk-sport/2016/08/22/memorable-moments-from-the-2016-rio-olympics/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
PUBLISHED: August 22, 2016 8:10 am Memorable moments from the 2016 Rio Olympics Rio has staged an Olympic Games full of memorable moments for the world&apos;s top athletes. Adam Peaty smashed the world record he had set in the heats to win Great Britain&apos;s first gold in the 100m breaststroke 
Here, Press Association Sport picks out some of the highlights. 
August 6 
Refugee swimmer Yusra Mardini won her heat of the 100 metres butterfly. A year ago, the 18-year-old Syrian saved other migrants by pushing their boat when it got into difficultly in the Aegean Sea. 
Swimmer Adam Peaty smashed the world record he had set in the heats to win Great Britain&apos;s first gold in the 100m breaststroke. 
Tennis world number one Novak Djokovic was beaten in the opening round of the men&apos;s singles by Juan Martin Del Potro, with both men finishing the match in tears. 
American teenager Lilly King beat Yulia Efimova to 100m breaststroke gold after calling out the controversial Russian, who has served a doping ban. 
Michael Phelps claimed the gold that had tempted him back to swimming, gaining revenge on Chad Le Clos in the 200m butterfly. 
Rafaela Silva, from the infamous City of God favela, won Brazil&apos;s first gold of the Games in judo. 
Staffordshire&apos;s Joe Clarke claimed a shock gold for Britain in the K1 canoe slalom. 
Jack Laugher and Chris Mears won Britain&apos;s first ever Olympic diving gold in the men&apos;s synchronised three metres springboard. 
:: Forty-year-old Katherine Grainger became the joint most decorated female British Olympian of all-time by winning women&apos;s double sculls silver with Vicky Thornley. 
:: Fiji claimed their first ever Olympic medal with gold in the inaugural rugby sevens tournament, beating Great Britain in the final. 
:: Extraordinary American gymnast Simone Biles won the women&apos;s all-around title by more than two points. Her final tally was four golds and one bronze. 
August 12 
:: Sir Bradley Wiggins became the first British athlete to win eight Olympic medals with gold alongside Ed Clancy, Owain Doull and Steven Burke in the team pursuit. 
:: Helen Glover and Heather Stanning retained the women&apos;s pairs rowing title and extended their unbeaten run to a remarkable 39 races. 
:: On a golden morning at the Lagoa, Britain&apos;s men&apos;s four won gold for a fifth straight Olympics. 
:: Katie Ledecky claimed her fourth gold medal in the pool, the American teenager winning the 800m freestyle by more then 11 seconds in a new world record. Britain&apos;s Jazz Carlin won her second silver medal. 
August 13 
Mo Farah became the first British track and field athlete to win three Olympic gold medals as he retained his 10,000 metres title despite a mid-race fall. 
:: Unheralded Monica Puig defeated Angelique Kerber in the women&apos;s tennis final to win Puerto Rico&apos;s first ever Olympic gold medal. 
:: Phelps won a 23rd and final Olympic gold medal in the medley relay. 
August 14 
:: Max Whitlock won a stunning gold on the floor, Britain&apos;s first ever in gymnastics, ahead of Brazilian duo Diego Hypolito and Arthur Mariano. 
:: Andy Murray became the first tennis player to win successive singles golds by beating Del Potro in a four-hour marathon. 
:: Having become the first golfer to hit a hole in one, Justin Rose went on to become the sport&apos;s first Olympic champion for more than a century. 
:: Wayde van Niekerk stunned the crowd, which included Michael Johnson, by breaking the American&apos;s 400m world record. 
:: Usain Bolt defeated Justin Gatlin, who was booed, to win a third straight 100m title. 
August 15 
:: Mark Cavendish won his first Olympic medal with silver in the omnium despite causing a crash in the final event, the points race. 
:: Shaunae Miller of the Bahamas beat Allyson Felix to gold in the 400m after diving across the finish line. 
August 16 
:: Jason Kenny won his third gold of the Games and sixth overall in a dramatic Keirin. 
:: Kenny&apos;s fiancee Laura Trott became the first British woman to win four Olympic gold medals with a dominant victory in the omnium. 
:: American Abbey D&apos;Agostino tripped over Nikki Hamblin in the 5,000m heats and stopped to urge the New Zealand runner to get up and carry on. 
August 17 
:: Jamaica&apos;s Elaine Thompson completed the sprint double by beating Dafne Schippers in the 200m. 
August 18 
:: Alistair and Jonny Brownlee won gold and silver in the triathlon, the first British brothers ever to finish one and two in an individual event. 
:: Marcus Ellis and Chris Langridge won Great Britain&apos;s first Olympic badminton medal since 2004 with bronze in the men&apos;s doubles. 
:: Bolt&apos;s final individual race at the Olympics brought the great Jamaican gold in the 200m. 
August 19 
:: Great Britain&apos;s women beat Holland in a penalty shoot-out to win a first hockey gold medal. 
:: Nick Skelton, 58, won a jump-off to claim individual show jumping gold. 
:: Bolt anchored Jamaica&apos;s relay team to 4x100m gold to complete the treble treble of sprint titles. 
:: Lutalo Muhammad lost out on gold in the last second of his taekwondo final when Cheick Sallah Cisse landed a head kick. 
August 20 
:: Brazil got the golden ending it hoped for when Neymar slotted the winning penalty against Germany in the men&apos;s football final, sparking wild scenes in the Maracana and across Rio. 
:: Farah completed his second Olympic double with his ninth consecutive global title in the 5,000m 
:: Nicola Adams became the first British boxer to retain an Olympic title in 92 years with victory in the flyweight category. Commercial Links
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.expressandstar.com/sport/uk-sport/2016/08/22/memorable-moments-from-the-2016-rio-olympics/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0710</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
PUBLISHED: August 22, 2016 8:10 am Memorable moments from the 2016 Rio Olympics Rio has staged an Olympic Games full of memorable moments for the world&apos;s top athletes. Adam Peaty smashed the world record he had set in the heats to win Great Britain&apos;s first gold in the 100m breaststroke 
Here, Press Association Sport picks out some of the highlights. 
August 6 
Refugee swimmer Yusra Mardini won her heat of the 100 metres butterfly. A year ago, the 18-year-old Syrian saved other migrants by pushing their boat when it got into difficultly in the Aegean Sea. 
Swimmer Adam Peaty smashed the world record he had set in the heats to win Great Britain&apos;s first gold in the 100m breaststroke. 
Tennis world number one Novak Djokovic was beaten in the opening round of the men&apos;s singles by Juan Martin Del Potro, with both men finishing the match in tears. 
American teenager Lilly King beat Yulia Efimova to 100m breaststroke gold after calling out the controversial Russian, who has served a doping ban. 
Michael Phelps claimed the gold that had tempted him back to swimming, gaining revenge on Chad Le Clos in the 200m butterfly. 
Rafaela Silva, from the infamous City of God favela, won Brazil&apos;s first gold of the Games in judo. 
Staffordshire&apos;s Joe Clarke claimed a shock gold for Britain in the K1 canoe slalom. 
Jack Laugher and Chris Mears won Britain&apos;s first ever Olympic diving gold in the men&apos;s synchronised three metres springboard. 
:: Forty-year-old Katherine Grainger became the joint most decorated female British Olympian of all-time by winning women&apos;s double sculls silver with Vicky Thornley. 
:: Fiji claimed their first ever Olympic medal with gold in the inaugural rugby sevens tournament, beating Great Britain in the final. 
:: Extraordinary American gymnast Simone Biles won the women&apos;s all-around title by more than two points. Her final tally was four golds and one bronze. 
August 12 
:: Sir Bradley Wiggins became the first British athlete to win eight Olympic medals with gold alongside Ed Clancy, Owain Doull and Steven Burke in the team pursuit. 
:: Helen Glover and Heather Stanning retained the women&apos;s pairs rowing title and extended their unbeaten run to a remarkable 39 races. 
:: On a golden morning at the Lagoa, Britain&apos;s men&apos;s four won gold for a fifth straight Olympics. 
:: Katie Ledecky claimed her fourth gold medal in the pool, the American teenager winning the 800m freestyle by more then 11 seconds in a new world record. Britain&apos;s Jazz Carlin won her second silver medal. 
August 13 
Mo Farah became the first British track and field athlete to win three Olympic gold medals as he retained his 10,000 metres title despite a mid-race fall. 
:: Unheralded Monica Puig defeated Angelique Kerber in the women&apos;s tennis final to win Puerto Rico&apos;s first ever Olympic gold medal. 
:: Phelps won a 23rd and final Olympic gold medal in the medley relay. 
August 14 
:: Max Whitlock won a stunning gold on the floor, Britain&apos;s first ever in gymnastics, ahead of Brazilian duo Diego Hypolito and Arthur Mariano. 
:: Andy Murray became the first tennis player to win successive singles golds by beating Del Potro in a four-hour marathon. 
:: Having become the first golfer to hit a hole in one, Justin Rose went on to become the sport&apos;s first Olympic champion for more than a century. 
:: Wayde van Niekerk stunned the crowd, which included Michael Johnson, by breaking the American&apos;s 400m world record. 
:: Usain Bolt defeated Justin Gatlin, who was booed, to win a third straight 100m title. 
August 15 
:: Mark Cavendish won his first Olympic medal with silver in the omnium despite causing a crash in the final event, the points race. 
:: Shaunae Miller of the Bahamas beat Allyson Felix to gold in the 400m after diving across the finish line. 
August 16 
:: Jason Kenny won his third gold of the Games and sixth overall in a dramatic Keirin. 
:: Kenny&apos;s fiancee Laura Trott became the first British woman to win four Olympic gold medals with a dominant victory in the omnium. 
:: American Abbey D&apos;Agostino tripped over Nikki Hamblin in the 5,000m heats and stopped to urge the New Zealand runner to get up and carry on. 
August 17 
:: Jamaica&apos;s Elaine Thompson completed the sprint double by beating Dafne Schippers in the 200m. 
August 18 
:: Alistair and Jonny Brownlee won gold and silver in the triathlon, the first British brothers ever to finish one and two in an individual event. 
:: Marcus Ellis and Chris Langridge won Great Britain&apos;s first Olympic badminton medal since 2004 with bronze in the men&apos;s doubles. 
:: Bolt&apos;s final individual race at the Olympics brought the great Jamaican gold in the 200m. 
August 19 
:: Great Britain&apos;s women beat Holland in a penalty shoot-out to win a first hockey gold medal. 
:: Nick Skelton, 58, won a jump-off to claim individual show jumping gold. 
:: Bolt anchored Jamaica&apos;s relay team to 4x100m gold to complete the treble treble of sprint titles. 
:: Lutalo Muhammad lost out on gold in the last second of his taekwondo final when Cheick Sallah Cisse landed a head kick. 
August 20 
:: Brazil got the golden ending it hoped for when Neymar slotted the winning penalty against Germany in the men&apos;s football final, sparking wild scenes in the Maracana and across Rio. 
:: Farah completed his second Olympic double with his ninth consecutive global title in the 5,000m 
:: Nicola Adams became the first British boxer to retain an Olympic title in 92 years with victory in the flyweight category. Commercial Links
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
