<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.capitalbay.news/feed/news/index.1.rss</forum>
<forum_title>CapitalBay</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Liverpool bride is left stunned by groom&apos;s dance routine</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.capitalbay.news/news/1068980-liverpool-bride-is-left-stunned-by-groom-s-dance-routine.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tim Wright, 30, planned a big surprise for his wife Sally at their wedding He told Sally, 29, he was playing football in months running up to the day Instead, he and his friends were secretly learning a dance routine 
By Esra Gurkan For Mailonline 
Published: 04:36 EST, 21 August 2016 | Updated: 02:27 EST, 22 August 2016 e-mail 
View comments 
Any bride worth her salt will have their wedding day planned down to the tiniest detail. 
So imagine pharmacist Sally Wright&apos;s surprise when her groom Tim Wright, 30, busted out a choreographed routine without any warning. 
The newlywed, from Liverpool, thought her teacher fiance had been at football practice every week but in fact he had been having dance lessons with his childhood friends in the hopes of turning his &apos;shambolic&apos; moves into a routine good enough to wow his bride. 
Scroll down for video 
Tim and Sally, pictured above, on their honeymoon in the Maldives after their wedding 
Groom Tim, who admits he &apos;can&apos;t dance&apos;, spent spent months rehearsing with instructor Clare Williams, who runs Dance Passion in north Liverpool. 
And he managed to keep the choreographed routine a secret from his 29-year-old wife-to-be, leaving her stunned when he hit the dance floor with his friends. 
Sally gasped and put her face in her hands as she watched her husband performing ballet-inspired moves to the Verve&apos;s Bittersweet Symphony, before Let&apos;s Dance by David Bowie kicked in. 
Bruno Mars&apos; and Mark Ronson&apos;s Uptown Funk followed and by the time Bootylicious by Destiny&apos;s Child was playing, the guests were equally delighted, singing along with every word as they whooped and clapped. 
Tim, a primary school teacher, told the Liverpool Echo that they&apos;d perfected the dance routine in 10 lessons after he gave Clare a list of songs. 
He said: &apos;We were an absolute shambles at first and our first session was very similar to the scene in The Full Monty when all the blokes are auditioning and falling into each other.&apos; 
Tim Wright, 30, (pictured above middle) had spent the final three months before his wedding taking dance lessons with his friends 
The groom says he came up with the idea after seeing how much effort Sally was putting into organising the wedding. &apos;I wanted to surprise her with something which would take some effort on my part,&apos; he said. 
&apos;I have a very close group of friends - most of us have been mates since primary school - and, even though we&apos;re all 30 now, we still all go on holidays together with our wives and girlfriends. 
&apos;They are always up for a laugh so I knew they wouldn&apos;t need much persuading when I first came up with the idea of surprising Sally with a dance. 
Sally, 29, had thought Tim was at football practice every week but instead he was enlisting the help of north Liverpool-based dance teacher Clare Williams 
&apos;The main stumbling block was that none of us can actually dance!&apos; 
Fortunately, the men managed to keep their routine a complete secret from Sally right up until the moment they began. 
Tim says: &apos;They didn&apos;t suspect a thing so when I got up on the microphone during the evening, there was a look of horror on Sally&apos;s face, wondering what I was going to do.&apos; 
He said that their final performance outdid their rehearsals and - thanks to some Dutch courage - they all &apos;loved it&apos;. 
At the beginning, Tim said, &apos;We were an absolute shambles&apos; but the men managed to pull it off on the night 
The men even managed to keep the whole routine a secret and Sally had absolutely no idea 
The video was filmed by Videographers Papertwin Weddings and the dance can be viewed in its entirety online 
&apos;Seeing the look on the faces of Sally and our guests made it all worthwhile.&apos; 
Tim and Sally spent their honeymoon in the Maldives once the wedding was over and Sally, who is studying for a PhD, says: &apos;You can see the fear in my eyes when I didn&apos;t know what Tim was going to do. 
&apos;I thought the whole thing was hilarious. I can&apos;t believe the effort all the lads put into the dance. It was the best surprise and something I won&apos;t forget.&apos; 
The video was filmed by Liverpool-based wedding videographers Papertwin Weddings who captured the dance in its entirety. Read more:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.capitalbay.news/news/1068980-liverpool-bride-is-left-stunned-by-groom-s-dance-routine.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0727</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Tim Wright, 30, planned a big surprise for his wife Sally at their wedding He told Sally, 29, he was playing football in months running up to the day Instead, he and his friends were secretly learning a dance routine 
By Esra Gurkan For Mailonline 
Published: 04:36 EST, 21 August 2016 | Updated: 02:27 EST, 22 August 2016 e-mail 
View comments 
Any bride worth her salt will have their wedding day planned down to the tiniest detail. 
So imagine pharmacist Sally Wright&apos;s surprise when her groom Tim Wright, 30, busted out a choreographed routine without any warning. 
The newlywed, from Liverpool, thought her teacher fiance had been at football practice every week but in fact he had been having dance lessons with his childhood friends in the hopes of turning his &apos;shambolic&apos; moves into a routine good enough to wow his bride. 
Scroll down for video 
Tim and Sally, pictured above, on their honeymoon in the Maldives after their wedding 
Groom Tim, who admits he &apos;can&apos;t dance&apos;, spent spent months rehearsing with instructor Clare Williams, who runs Dance Passion in north Liverpool. 
And he managed to keep the choreographed routine a secret from his 29-year-old wife-to-be, leaving her stunned when he hit the dance floor with his friends. 
Sally gasped and put her face in her hands as she watched her husband performing ballet-inspired moves to the Verve&apos;s Bittersweet Symphony, before Let&apos;s Dance by David Bowie kicked in. 
Bruno Mars&apos; and Mark Ronson&apos;s Uptown Funk followed and by the time Bootylicious by Destiny&apos;s Child was playing, the guests were equally delighted, singing along with every word as they whooped and clapped. 
Tim, a primary school teacher, told the Liverpool Echo that they&apos;d perfected the dance routine in 10 lessons after he gave Clare a list of songs. 
He said: &apos;We were an absolute shambles at first and our first session was very similar to the scene in The Full Monty when all the blokes are auditioning and falling into each other.&apos; 
Tim Wright, 30, (pictured above middle) had spent the final three months before his wedding taking dance lessons with his friends 
The groom says he came up with the idea after seeing how much effort Sally was putting into organising the wedding. &apos;I wanted to surprise her with something which would take some effort on my part,&apos; he said. 
&apos;I have a very close group of friends - most of us have been mates since primary school - and, even though we&apos;re all 30 now, we still all go on holidays together with our wives and girlfriends. 
&apos;They are always up for a laugh so I knew they wouldn&apos;t need much persuading when I first came up with the idea of surprising Sally with a dance. 
Sally, 29, had thought Tim was at football practice every week but instead he was enlisting the help of north Liverpool-based dance teacher Clare Williams 
&apos;The main stumbling block was that none of us can actually dance!&apos; 
Fortunately, the men managed to keep their routine a complete secret from Sally right up until the moment they began. 
Tim says: &apos;They didn&apos;t suspect a thing so when I got up on the microphone during the evening, there was a look of horror on Sally&apos;s face, wondering what I was going to do.&apos; 
He said that their final performance outdid their rehearsals and - thanks to some Dutch courage - they all &apos;loved it&apos;. 
At the beginning, Tim said, &apos;We were an absolute shambles&apos; but the men managed to pull it off on the night 
The men even managed to keep the whole routine a secret and Sally had absolutely no idea 
The video was filmed by Videographers Papertwin Weddings and the dance can be viewed in its entirety online 
&apos;Seeing the look on the faces of Sally and our guests made it all worthwhile.&apos; 
Tim and Sally spent their honeymoon in the Maldives once the wedding was over and Sally, who is studying for a PhD, says: &apos;You can see the fear in my eyes when I didn&apos;t know what Tim was going to do. 
&apos;I thought the whole thing was hilarious. I can&apos;t believe the effort all the lads put into the dance. It was the best surprise and something I won&apos;t forget.&apos; 
The video was filmed by Liverpool-based wedding videographers Papertwin Weddings who captured the dance in its entirety. Read more:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.capitalbay.com/thumbnail.php?file=&amp;size=article_large</main_image>
</document>
