<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rapidtvnews.com//feed/rss.html</forum>
<forum_title>Rapid TV News - Broadcast Technology Daily</forum_title>
<discussion_title>BBC Three’s demise boosts increase in UK commercial TV viewing in first half of 2016</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.rapidtvnews.com/2016082244050/bbc-three-s-demise-boosts-increase-in-uk-commercial-tv-viewing-in-first-half-of-2016.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Editor | 22 August 2016 Even though total TV viewing was found to have dipped slightly, the first half of 2016 witnessed an expansion in the commercial TV sector, according to data from the latter’s marketing body Thinkbox. The data found that in the period January to June 2016 commercial TV viewing on TV sets increased to 67.4%, or two hours 24 minutes a day. This represented a rise of one minute on the same period in 2015, and seven minutes more a day than a decade ago.Total UK TV viewing —including BBC channels — decreased slightly year on year to three hours, 34 minutes a day - a decrease of two minutes a day. TV’s weekly reach remained stable, at 93.8% of the UK. On average 86% of TV viewing in the six-month period was live.Thinkbox’s figures were based on the UK industry standard measurement for TV viewing – that is, consumption in home on a TV set within seven days of the original broadcast, as measured by the Broadcasters’ Audience Research Board (BARB). It noted that the BARB’s standard measurement did not include TV watched on other devices, such as tablets and smartphones, nor the increasing amount of viewing on a TV set that now happens after a week or out of home. By including the latter, overall TV viewing during the first half of 2016 – any time, any place, any screen – would have increased by eight minutes a day to total three hours, 42 minutes a day.Attempting to identify drivers UK commercial TV channels’ strong beginning to 2016, Thinkbox proposed that the closure of BBC Three’s broadcast TV channel in February could be partly responsible for a dip in BBC TV viewing, in particular the viewing of 16-34s. The marketing body found that in the first half of the year, overall TV viewing of 16-34 year olds dropped by an average of three minutes a day compared with 2015 to two hours, 20 minutes a day. This decline, Thinkbox stressed, was entirely borne by BBC channels. Commercial TV viewing saw an increase of one minute a day to an average of one hour, 49 minutes a day.Commenting on the research, Matt Hill, research and planning director at Thinkbox said: “TV is thriving on all screens, but the importance of TV channels on TV sets cannot be overlooked. They remain the first port of call for the majority of people of all ages. The apparent boost that commercial TV has received from BBC Three’s disappearance from the schedules underlines this fact – a strategy that is in stark contrast to the imminent arrival of Viceland on commercial TV.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.rapidtvnews.com/2016082244050/bbc-three-s-demise-boosts-increase-in-uk-commercial-tv-viewing-in-first-half-of-2016.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0750</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Editor | 22 August 2016 Even though total TV viewing was found to have dipped slightly, the first half of 2016 witnessed an expansion in the commercial TV sector, according to data from the latter’s marketing body Thinkbox. The data found that in the period January to June 2016 commercial TV viewing on TV sets increased to 67.4%, or two hours 24 minutes a day. This represented a rise of one minute on the same period in 2015, and seven minutes more a day than a decade ago.Total UK TV viewing —including BBC channels — decreased slightly year on year to three hours, 34 minutes a day - a decrease of two minutes a day. TV’s weekly reach remained stable, at 93.8% of the UK. On average 86% of TV viewing in the six-month period was live.Thinkbox’s figures were based on the UK industry standard measurement for TV viewing – that is, consumption in home on a TV set within seven days of the original broadcast, as measured by the Broadcasters’ Audience Research Board (BARB). It noted that the BARB’s standard measurement did not include TV watched on other devices, such as tablets and smartphones, nor the increasing amount of viewing on a TV set that now happens after a week or out of home. By including the latter, overall TV viewing during the first half of 2016 – any time, any place, any screen – would have increased by eight minutes a day to total three hours, 42 minutes a day.Attempting to identify drivers UK commercial TV channels’ strong beginning to 2016, Thinkbox proposed that the closure of BBC Three’s broadcast TV channel in February could be partly responsible for a dip in BBC TV viewing, in particular the viewing of 16-34s. The marketing body found that in the first half of the year, overall TV viewing of 16-34 year olds dropped by an average of three minutes a day compared with 2015 to two hours, 20 minutes a day. This decline, Thinkbox stressed, was entirely borne by BBC channels. Commercial TV viewing saw an increase of one minute a day to an average of one hour, 49 minutes a day.Commenting on the research, Matt Hill, research and planning director at Thinkbox said: “TV is thriving on all screens, but the importance of TV channels on TV sets cannot be overlooked. They remain the first port of call for the majority of people of all ages. The apparent boost that commercial TV has received from BBC Three’s disappearance from the schedules underlines this fact – a strategy that is in stark contrast to the imminent arrival of Viceland on commercial TV.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>FR</country>
<main_image>http://www.rapidtvnews.com/images/BBC.png</main_image>
</document>
