<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.usatoday.com/olympics-rio-2016/</forum>
<forum_title>Rio 2016 Summer Olympics | USA TODAY NETWORK</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mongolian wrestling coaches go nuts, strip down after unfavorable decision</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/olympics/rio-2016/2016/08/21/mongolian-wrestling-coaches-go-nuts-strip-down-after-unfavorable-decision/89076210/</topic_url>
<topic_text>

Coaches from Mongolia thought their wrestler, Mandakhnaran Ganzorig, had won his match. When a ruling went against him they protested. Vociferously. p (Photo: Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports)
RIO DE JANEIRO — Two Mongolian wrestling coaches, head coach Tserenbaatar Tsogtbayar and assistant coach Byambarenchin Bayaraa, stripped their clothes off in protest after their athlete, Ganzorigiin Mandakhnaran, lost the bronze medal match to Uzbekistan’s Ikhtiyor Navruzov. Mandakhnaran lost when the judges awarded a penalty point after the finish of the match.
As the match ended, it appeared Mandakhnaran had won. His two coaches sprinted onto the mat in celebration, one carrying the flag of Mongolia.
Seconds later, it was Navruzov and his coach who were celebrating after the judges awarded the penalty point.
The two Mongolian coaches then tossed a challenge flag, and when the judges explained to them the call couldn’t be challenged, they ran out onto the mat while Mandakhnaran dropped to his knees. As the judges attempted to wave them off, the two coaches stripped down in protest — one removing his shirt, and the other removing both his shirt and pants, leaving on only his underwear.
“The referees are no good,” said a visibly emotional Bayaraa through a translator, when asked why he had taken his clothes off. “There are 3 million Mongolian people, all waiting for a bronze medal. And now? No medal. Only (a few) Mongolian athletes come here.”
Security was brought in as the crowd started cheering “MONGOLIA! MONGOLIA!”
“All of the stadium was behind us,” Bayaraa said. “One hundred percent for Mongolia.”
Eventually security was able to escort the two coaches off the mat.
AGONY OF DEFEAT IN RIO
Facebook Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Olympic sadness: Agony of defeat in Rio Fullscreen Post to Facebook Posted! A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
The Serbia bench reacts against USA in the men&apos;s basketball gold medal match Carioca Arena 1. David E. Klutho-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Issoufou Alfaga Adboulrazak (NIG) reacts after losing to Radik Isaev (AZE) in the men&apos;s +80kg taekwondo gold medal match. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Inika McPherson (USA) reacts during the women&apos;s high jump. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Chaunte Lowe (USA) reacts during the women&apos;s high jump. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Shakur Stevenson (USA) wins silver in men&apos;s bantam 56kg boxing Riocentro - Pavilion 6. Robert Hanashiro-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Spain forward Marta Xargay (10) reacts after losing to USA in the women&apos;s basketball gold medal match Carioca Arena 1. Bob Rosato, RVR Photos-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Britain&apos;s Holly Bradshaw reacts after failing to clear the bar in the pole vault finals. Morry Gash, AP Fullscreen Lutalo Muhammad of Great Britain reacts against Cheick Sallah Cissé during the men&apos;s 80kg gold medal contest. Muhammad finished with a silver. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Madeline Heiner Hills of Australia reacts after finishing 10th the women&apos;s 5,000-meter final. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Russia&apos;s Aniuar GeduevIran&apos;s Hassan reacts after losing to Iran&apos;s Hassan Aliazam Yazdanicharati for the gold in the men&apos;s wrestling freestyle 74-kg competition. Charlie Riedel, AP Fullscreen Andrew Bogut of Australia, middle, reacts with teammates on the bench during a loss to Serbia in the men&apos;s basketball semifinals. Jamie Squire, Getty Images Fullscreen Norway&apos;s Camilla Herrem, left, and Ida Alstad react after losing a women&apos;s semifinal handball match to Russia. EPA Fullscreen Adam Gemili reacts after coming up just short of bronze in the men&apos;s 200-meter final. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Nikita Glasnovic of Sweden reacts to her loss to Jade Jones of Great Britain in a women&apos;s taekwondo 57kg semifinal match. Daniel Powers, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kimia Alizadeh Zenoorin of Iran reacts on losing to Eva Calvo Gomez of Spain during a women&apos;s -57kg quarterfinal taekwondo bout. EPA Fullscreen Three-time defending Olympic champion Saori Yoshida (JPN) reacts after losing the gold medal wrestling match to the USA&apos;s Helen Maroulis. Jeff Swinger-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The Serbia bench reacts in the game against Spain during the women&apos;s basketball semifinals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1. Mandatory Credit: RVR Photos-USA TODAY Sports Bob Rosato, RVR Photos-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen United States libero Kayla Banwarth (2) reacts after losing to Serbia during the semifinal round of the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Matt Kryger-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Nozomi Okuhara (JPN) reacts after losing to V. Sindhu Pusarla (IND) in a badminton women&apos;s singles semifinal match. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Javier Culson (PUR) reacts after being disqualified from the men&apos;s 400m hurdles final. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Argentina opposite spiker Cristian Poglajen (6) reacts after losing to Brazil in a men&apos;s quarterfinal volleyball match. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Argentina middle blocker Martin Ramos (4) and setter Demian Gonzalez (8) react after losing to Brazil in a men&apos;s quarterfinal volleyball match. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Russia left defender Viacheslav Krasilnikov reacts after losing to Itlay in a men&apos;s team semifinal beach volleyball game. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Argentina shooting guard Manu Ginobili (5) reacts on the bench after the game against USA during the men&apos;s basketball quarterfinals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1. Jason Getz-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Jeff Porter of the USA reacts after failing to advance in the men&apos;s 110-meter hurdle semifinals. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Brazil&apos;s Fabiana Moraes reacts after failing to advance in the women&apos;s 100-meter hurdles. AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Brazil midfield Marta (10) is consoled after losing to Sweden in a shootout during the women&apos;s semifinal soccer match at Maracana during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic games. Sweden won the game. Christopher Hanewinckel-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Australia shooting guard Penny Taylor (7) reacts as Serbia players celebrate after defeating Australia in a women&apos;s quarterfinal basketball game at Carioca Arena 1 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Geoff Burke-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Wilhem Belocian (FRA) reacts during the first round of men&apos;s 110 hurdles in track and field competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Mima Ito (JPN), left and Ai Fukuhara (JPN) react to a point as they play against Xiaona Shan (GER) and Petrissa Solja (GER) in a women&apos;s team table tennis semifinal match at Riocentro - Pavilion 3 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Christopher Hanewinckel-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Reinder Nummerdor (NED) reacts as he and partner Christiaan Varenhorst (NED) take on Alexander Brouwer (NED) and Robert Meeuwsen (NED) in a men&apos;s beach volleyball match at Beach Volleyball Arena during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Nummerdor and his partner were ousted on Monday. Kevin Jairaj-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Nadine Zumkehr consoles Switzerland teammate Joana Heidrich after losing to Brazil in the beach volleyball quarterfinal. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Iran&apos;s Saeid Morad Abdvali reacts after losing to Denmark&apos;s Mark Overgaard Madsen during the men&apos;s wrestling Greco-Roman 75-kg competition. Markus Schreiber, AP Fullscreen Hsien Hsiang of Taiwan reacts after he failed to clear the bar at 2.22 meter in the men&apos;s high jump qualifying round. EPA Fullscreen Romania&apos;s Gabriela Perianu reacts after losing a women&apos;s handball preliminary round game to Norway. EPA Fullscreen France&apos;s Christophe Lemaitre reacts after failing to advance in the men&apos;s 100-meter semifinals. AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Arturo Chavez of Perus reacts after failing to clear the bar in the men&apos;s high jump qualification. EPA Fullscreen Germany&apos;s Eike Onnen reacts after failing to qualify in the men&apos;s high jump. AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Mark Overgaard Madsen of Denmark reacts after being defeated by Roman Vlasov of Russia in the men&apos;s Greco-Roman 75kg gold medal match. David Ramos, Getty Images Fullscreen Rafael Nadal of Spain leaves the court after being defeated by Juan Martin del Potro of Argentina during the men&apos;s singles semifinal match. Michael Reynolds, EPA Fullscreen Patrick Reed of the U.S. reacts to a missed birdie on the 14th hole during the third round of golf at the games. Scott Halleran, Getty Images Fullscreen Brazil&apos;s Evandro Goncalves Oliveira Junior reacts after losing the men&apos;s beach volleyball round of 16 match against Russia at the Beach Volley Arena. Leon Neal, AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Thailand&apos;s Saylom Ardee reacts after losing against France&apos;s Souleymane Diop Cissokho during the men&apos;s welter (69kg) quarterfinal 3. YURI CORTEZ, AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Players of Denmark react after losing the men&apos;s quarterfinal match against Nigeria. Cristiane Mattos, EPA Fullscreen Brazil&apos;s bench reacts to the double overtime loss to Argentina during the men&apos;s preliminary round Group B match on Day 8 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1. Elsa, Getty Images Fullscreen Dagmara Wozniak (USA) reacts during the match between Mariel Zagunis (USA) and Yana Egorian (RUS). The U.S. lost to Russia in the women&apos;s team sabre semifinal. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Madison Keys (USA) reacts during her bronze medal match against Petra Kvitova (CZE). Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Alanna Kennedy of the Australian women&apos;s soccer team is embraced after a quarterfinal loss to Brazil. Pedro Vilela, Getty Images Fullscreen Iran&apos;s Mohammad Arzandeh reacts after failing to advance in the long jump. AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Megan Rapinoe after the U.S. women&apos;s soccer team suffered a stunning upset loss to Sweden. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen U.S. captain Carli Lloyd during the women&apos;s soccer team&apos;s quarterfinal loss to Sweden. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Jonas Kaspar and Marek Sindler of Czech Republic react after competing in the men&apos;s canoe double finals in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Whitewater Stadium. They finished last. Guy Rhodes, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Marhinde Verkerk of the Netherlands reacts after losing during her women&apos;s 78kg elimination round judo contest with Yalennis Castillo of Cuba at Carioca Arena 2 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Karl-Richard Frey of Germany, left, reacts after losing his bout against Cyrille Maret of France compete in a men&apos;s 100kg bronze medal judo contest at Carioca Arena 2 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Joost van der Burg of the Netherlands crashes during the men&apos;s team pursuit qualifying in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Velodrome. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Karl-Richard Frey (GER, white) reacts after his bout against Cyrille Maret (FRA, blue) in a men&apos;s 100kg bronze medal judo contest at Carioca Arena 2 during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kyle Terada-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen United States back Madison Hughes reacts after losing to Fiji in a rugby sevens match. Daniel Powers, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Sweden&apos;s Marcus Nyman reacts after losing to China&apos;s Cheng Xunzhao during their men&apos;s -90kg judo contest quarterfinal match. AFP/Getty Images Fullscreen Carlos Eduardo Quipo Pilataxi of Ecuador reacts after losing in the men&apos;s boxing light flyweight quarterfinals. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Mohamed Mahmoud of Egypt reacts after missing his attempt in the men&apos;s 77kg weightlifting category. Larry W Smith, EPA Fullscreen Germany&apos;s Lars Flueggen reacts to a missed chance against Russia during a men&apos;s beach volleyball match. Marcio Jose Sanchez, AP Fullscreen United States wing spiker Aaron Russell (2) reacts after a loss to Itay in a men&apos;s preliminary round Group A volleyball match at Maracanazinho during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kirby Lee-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Travis Stevens of the U.S. reacts after losing to Khasan Khalmurzaev of Russia in the men&apos;s judo 81kg gold medal match. John David Mercer, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen South Africa&apos;s Chad Le Clos after placing fourth in the final of the men&apos;s 200-meter butterfly during the swimming competitions at the 2016 Summer Olympics, Tuesday, Aug. 9, 2016, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Matt Slocum, AP Fullscreen Serena Williams reacts during her loss to Elina Svitolina of Ukraine. Cameron Spencer, Getty Images Fullscreen Benjamin Savsek of Slovenia reacts during the men&apos;s canoe single final. Savsek came within two seconds of a medal, but finished sixth. Mark Kolbe, Getty Images Fullscreen Benjamin Steffen of Switzerland reacts after losing to Gauthier Grumier of France in the men&apos;s epee individual bronze medal match. EPA Fullscreen Charles Albert Shone Conwell of the U.S. reacts after losing to Krishan Vikas of India in the men&apos;s middleweight boxing preliminaries. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Magwede of the Zimbabwe women&apos;s soccer team reacts during a loss to Australia. Felipe Oliveira, Getty Images Fullscreen Mariana Silva of Brazil reacts in front of a joyous Anicka van Emden of the Netherlands after the women&apos;s -63kg bronze medal. EPA Fullscreen Namika Matsumoto of Japan reacts to an unsuccessful attempt in the women&apos;s 63kg weightlifting competition. Mike Groll, AP Fullscreen Ibtihaj Muhammad (USA) reacts after being eliminated in women&apos;s sabre individual competition against Cecilia Berder (FRA). Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen USA center forward John Mann reacts after losing the match against Spain during the men&apos;s water polo group b preliminaries. Jeffrey Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Venus Williams (USA) reacts after she and Serena Williams (USA, not pictured) lose during the women&apos;s doubles in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Jeffrey Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Alexander Massialas (USA) reacts after taking silver in the final match with Daniele Garozzo (ITA, not pictured) during men&apos;s fencing competition in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Dan Powers, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Novak Djokovic (SRB) reacts during his match against Juan Martin Del Potro (ARG, not pictured) during the men&apos;s singles in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Olympic Tennis Centre. Jeff Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Megan Guarnier (USA) and Mara Abbott react after competing in the women&apos;s cycling road race at Fort Copacabana during the 2016 Rio Summer Olympic Games. Kyle Terada-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dewi Safitri (INA) reacts after the bar and weights land on her legs during the 53kg weightlifting event at Riocentro in the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Kevin Jairaj-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Brazil guard Leandro Barbosa looks on against Lithuania, a loss in the preliminary round. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Angelica Delgado (United States) reacts after a loss against Tsolmon Adiyasambuu (Mongolia) during the women&apos;s judo 52kg Round of 32. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Andreea Chitu (Romania) reacts after a loss to Odette Giuffrida (Italy) during the women&apos;s judo 52kg quarterfinals. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Melania Costa Schmid (Spain) after the women&apos;s 400m freestyle heats. She finished 17th. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries: Replay 1 of 82 2 of 82 3 of 82 4 of 82 5 of 82 6 of 82 7 of 82 8 of 82 9 of 82 10 of 82 11 of 82 12 of 82 13 of 82 14 of 82 15 of 82 16 of 82 17 of 82 18 of 82 19 of 82 20 of 82 21 of 82 22 of 82 23 of 82 24 of 82 25 of 82 26 of 82 27 of 82 28 of 82 29 of 82 30 of 82 31 of 82 32 of 82 33 of 82 34 of 82 35 of 82 36 of 82 37 of 82 38 of 82 39 of 82 40 of 82 41 of 82 42 of 82 43 of 82 44 of 82 45 of 82 46 of 82 47 of 82 48 of 82 49 of 82 50 of 82 51 of 82 52 of 82 53 of 82 54 of 82 55 of 82 56 of 82 57 of 82 58 of 82 59 of 82 60 of 82 61 of 82 62 of 82 63 of 82 64 of 82 65 of 82 66 of 82 67 of 82 68 of 82 69 of 82 70 of 82 71 of 82 72 of 82 73 of 82 74 of 82 75 of 82 76 of 82 77 of 82 78 of 82 79 of 82 80 of 82 81 of 82 82 of 82 Autoplay Show Thumbnails Show Captions Last Slide Next Slide
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.91</spam_score>
<post_num>26</post_num>
<post_id>post-26</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/olympics/rio-2016/2016/08/21/mongolian-wrestling-coaches-go-nuts-strip-down-after-unfavorable-decision/89076210/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0526</post_time>
<username>Цэцэгмаа Цэнддорж</username>
<post>
I wonder why Ryan Lochte made up a robbery story? He is lier and he is from CLASS=U.S.A team right? I wonder how he made it to Olimpics.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/7655e78aacfe2c6a6a2b29f74092037ecc3f5c85/c=0-97-2817-1689&amp;amp;r=x633&amp;amp;c=1200x630/local/-/media/2016/08/21/USATODAY/USATODAY/636073836424170818-USP-OLYMPICS-WRESTLING-84626128.JPG</main_image>
</document>
