<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>SIA Women in Leadership Forum - Safety Institute of Australia</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://sia.org.au/events/calendar/sia-women-in-leadership-forum.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
SIA Women in Leadership Forum Thursday 8 September, 2016 
The Safety Institute of Australia invites you to join us for the inaugural Women in Leadership Forum which will be held on Thursday 8 September 2016 at the Sydney Showground. 
The forum will focus on the theme: Leaning In: Leading and influencing health, safety and business performance. 
Throughout the day local and interstate speakers will explore the issues surrounding women transitioning into senior roles in HSE, and discuss the challenges involved with enough with needing to influence the direction of the company and its business leaders, particularly when there is only one female in the room. 
The SIA Women in Leadership Forum forms part of the broader National Safety Convention and events program for the Safety Institute of Australia. It provides an excellent opportunity for men and women to gain insight into gender diversity issues associated with the OHS profession. The forum is also an excellent opportunity for men and women to hear the latest in thought leadership and network with peers, colleagues and industry professionals. 
The 2016 program will bring together interstate and local OHS professionals in a dynamic and interactive setting to examine a range of pertinent industry topics, challenges and opportunities surrounding leadership.The 2016 Women in Leadership Forum promises to ignite important discussion around the future of women in leadership within the Australian OHS sector. SIA invites you to take part in the conversation. 
Follow the hashtag #SIAsafetyconvention16 for updates and announcements about this highly anticipated event. Event Details 
Date: Thursday 8 September 2016 
Time: 9:00am - 5:00pm Register your attendance now Who should attend? This event is open to all men and women working in the field of OHS / WHS professionals. The content of this session will be suitable for delegates with a range of experience and seniority. Sponsors &amp; Supporters 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.05</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://sia.org.au/events/calendar/sia-women-in-leadership-forum.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160908</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
SIA Women in Leadership Forum Thursday 8 September, 2016 
The Safety Institute of Australia invites you to join us for the inaugural Women in Leadership Forum which will be held on Thursday 8 September 2016 at the Sydney Showground. 
The forum will focus on the theme: Leaning In: Leading and influencing health, safety and business performance. 
Throughout the day local and interstate speakers will explore the issues surrounding women transitioning into senior roles in HSE, and discuss the challenges involved with enough with needing to influence the direction of the company and its business leaders, particularly when there is only one female in the room. 
The SIA Women in Leadership Forum forms part of the broader National Safety Convention and events program for the Safety Institute of Australia. It provides an excellent opportunity for men and women to gain insight into gender diversity issues associated with the OHS profession. The forum is also an excellent opportunity for men and women to hear the latest in thought leadership and network with peers, colleagues and industry professionals. 
The 2016 program will bring together interstate and local OHS professionals in a dynamic and interactive setting to examine a range of pertinent industry topics, challenges and opportunities surrounding leadership.The 2016 Women in Leadership Forum promises to ignite important discussion around the future of women in leadership within the Australian OHS sector. SIA invites you to take part in the conversation. 
Follow the hashtag #SIAsafetyconvention16 for updates and announcements about this highly anticipated event. Event Details 
Date: Thursday 8 September 2016 
Time: 9:00am - 5:00pm Register your attendance now Who should attend? This event is open to all men and women working in the field of OHS / WHS professionals. The content of this session will be suitable for delegates with a range of experience and seniority. Sponsors &amp; Supporters 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>AU</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
