<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>The Transformational Gift -</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://clarisconsulting.net/the-transformational-gift/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
August 21, 2016 
This week I want to talk to you about the transformational gift. 
Sometimes when we give gifts, we think that we should go out and buy a nice bottle of wine, some flowers or chocolates, maybe even a new watch. We try and think of the person we’re giving the gift to and what they’d like, but the transformational gift is not a thing. 
The transformational gift is our presence. 
Yes, the transformational gift we give to others is not a thing, but rather an experience we share with someone. I realized this first hand recently when my wife, Alyson, who has become enamored with stand up paddle boarding ask me to give her the gift of my presence. 
Alyson has purchased two stand-up paddle boards within the last two months. One is a flat-water board and the other is a board that can be ridden in rougher waters. She came in from paddle boarding and in preparation of her fiftieth birthday said, “Do you know what the greatest gift would be for my fiftieth birthday?” I said, “No, what’s that?” 
She said, “the greatest gift would be for you to be out on the water with me on a stand-up paddle board.” “Hugh, it’s gorgeous! I see fish swimming underneath my board, I see herons and eagles flying overhead in the gorgeous blue skies…and I’m getting great exercise. It’s just gorgeous! And the one thing I want more than anything is for you to be out there with me. I know you’re never going to get into stand-up paddle boarding in the same way I have, but I love it so much that I want the love of my life to experience it with me. That would be the greatest gift.” 
What Alyson didn’t know at the time was that she transformed my thinking substantially about gift giving. She gave me the gift of saying, “I love you and I don’t need or want more things. What I want is to spend time with you and I want you to enjoy this with me.” 
I am in turn going down to Hood River, Oregon next week for the third time in three month to buy a stand-up paddle board from Eddie at Big Winds . Eddy has helped us so much that he is now one of our new best friends and I’m sure he’ll be on our Christmas card distribution list. 
I want to remind you that it takes a shift in mindset to say that the gift I’m going to give someone is to simply to be present with them, and that by doing so I’ll cultivate a memorable experience. 
Sometime our presence needs to be transactional. For example, I’m in your presence because I have to communicate something to you about an expectation or a task that needs completing. Yes, that’s necessary. 
But the greatest gift is when I don’t “have to” spend time and communicate with you, but rather I choose to spend time with you. Imagine hearing, “I want to spend time with you.” That is a transformational gift. 
Ladies and gentlemen, this week if you want to shift someone’s mindset, either in your personal life or your professional life, spend time with them. Don’t go in with an agenda, just be fully present with them. If you do that, it will be transformational. Get a complimentary copy of my special report Mastering Your Mindset: 9 Negative Habits that Hold Executives Back &amp; How To Break Them for Accelerated Performance Speak Your Mind 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.07</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://clarisconsulting.net/the-transformational-gift/</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
August 21, 2016 
This week I want to talk to you about the transformational gift. 
Sometimes when we give gifts, we think that we should go out and buy a nice bottle of wine, some flowers or chocolates, maybe even a new watch. We try and think of the person we’re giving the gift to and what they’d like, but the transformational gift is not a thing. 
The transformational gift is our presence. 
Yes, the transformational gift we give to others is not a thing, but rather an experience we share with someone. I realized this first hand recently when my wife, Alyson, who has become enamored with stand up paddle boarding ask me to give her the gift of my presence. 
Alyson has purchased two stand-up paddle boards within the last two months. One is a flat-water board and the other is a board that can be ridden in rougher waters. She came in from paddle boarding and in preparation of her fiftieth birthday said, “Do you know what the greatest gift would be for my fiftieth birthday?” I said, “No, what’s that?” 
She said, “the greatest gift would be for you to be out on the water with me on a stand-up paddle board.” “Hugh, it’s gorgeous! I see fish swimming underneath my board, I see herons and eagles flying overhead in the gorgeous blue skies…and I’m getting great exercise. It’s just gorgeous! And the one thing I want more than anything is for you to be out there with me. I know you’re never going to get into stand-up paddle boarding in the same way I have, but I love it so much that I want the love of my life to experience it with me. That would be the greatest gift.” 
What Alyson didn’t know at the time was that she transformed my thinking substantially about gift giving. She gave me the gift of saying, “I love you and I don’t need or want more things. What I want is to spend time with you and I want you to enjoy this with me.” 
I am in turn going down to Hood River, Oregon next week for the third time in three month to buy a stand-up paddle board from Eddie at Big Winds . Eddy has helped us so much that he is now one of our new best friends and I’m sure he’ll be on our Christmas card distribution list. 
I want to remind you that it takes a shift in mindset to say that the gift I’m going to give someone is to simply to be present with them, and that by doing so I’ll cultivate a memorable experience. 
Sometime our presence needs to be transactional. For example, I’m in your presence because I have to communicate something to you about an expectation or a task that needs completing. Yes, that’s necessary. 
But the greatest gift is when I don’t “have to” spend time and communicate with you, but rather I choose to spend time with you. Imagine hearing, “I want to spend time with you.” That is a transformational gift. 
Ladies and gentlemen, this week if you want to shift someone’s mindset, either in your personal life or your professional life, spend time with them. Don’t go in with an agenda, just be fully present with them. If you do that, it will be transformational. Get a complimentary copy of my special report Mastering Your Mindset: 9 Negative Habits that Hold Executives Back &amp; How To Break Them for Accelerated Performance Speak Your Mind 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
