<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.guardian.co.uk/rssfeed/0,,8,00.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Education | The Guardian</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Will the Teaching Excellence Framework be a licence for universities to raise fees?</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/aug/22/teaching-excellence-framework-universities-tuition-fees-tef</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Patrick McGhee 
If properly implemented the TEF could improve university teaching, but its link with tuition fees must be cut once and for all ‘Many people are concerned that the Teaching Excellence Framework will be too heavily driven by blunt metrics.’ Photograph: Chris Ison/PA Monday 22 August 2016 09.00 BST Last modified on Monday 22 August 2016 09.01 BST Share on Messenger 
T he Teaching Excellence Framework (TEF) will be among the features of the higher education and research bill, which will go to committee stage next month. The government wants the scheme to “incentivise excellent teaching” and give students better information on where the best provision is found. But it still intends to use good scores on the TEF as licence for individual universities to raise fees in line with inflation. 
This should be one of the most important points for scrutiny in parliament – especially in the light of news that at least one university is raising fees already on the back of the TEF not just for new students but for existing ones too. 
Related: The Teaching Excellence Framework: can higher education up its game? 
With the relocation of responsibility for universities into the Department for Education some worry that the TEF is uncomfortably close to Ofsted grades, and we know what those can do to a school’s reputation and fortunes. Universities UK, the vice-chancellors’ body, has called for implementation to be delayed until universities’ post-Brexit links with the EU are clarified. Many are concerned that the TEF will be too heavily driven by blunt metrics. However, the idea is too good an opportunity to miss for universities to promote teaching excellence. 
We now know what the key criteria will be: the headings are “teaching quality”, “learning environment” (eg facilities) and “student outcomes &amp; learning gain” (eg the employment outcomes of graduates and the gains made by students from a range of different backgrounds). Universities will be judged on each of the three areas on the basis of performance indicators (or “metrics”) alongside, crucially, universities’ own additional evidence. These will be combined to yield a grade: “meets expectations”, “excellent” or “outstanding”. 
“Teaching Quality” is defined as “teaching practices which provide an appropriate level of contact, stimulation and challenge, encourage student effort and engagement”. This will be measured by National Student Survey (NSS) questions. Institutions will add their own statements on issues such as effectiveness of innovative approaches, new technology or educational research and “recognition and reward schemes, including progression and promotion opportunities for staff”. 
Here the TEF, if implemented well – and it’s a big “if” – can be a force for good by providing parity of recognition for committed and effective teaching alongside research. Let’s hope this dimension also encourages a reduction in the casualisation of the academic workforce. 
The “learning environment” may include use of technology, work experience, extraurricular activities and opportunities for peer-to-peer interaction. This is a broader, richer conceptualisation than many had anticipated. Alongside NSS scores, judgments here will also reflect dropout rates. Universities will be able to contextualise the data by outlining what they are doing to improve retention. This seeks to address the spectre of some universities rejecting non-traditional students for fear of their potential impact on dropout rates. 
Related: Outstanding higher education teaching should not increase students’ debt | Patrick McGhee 
The metric for the student outcomes category is not only the unloved first Destinations of Leavers from Higher Education (DLHE) survey, which measures employment and training a mere six months after graduation, but also potentially a new index on “highly skilled employment”. No mention of graduate earnings. 
These factors will be judged alongside the provider’s own account of what it is doing to help disadvantaged students to progress and achieve. 
The government appears keen to send the message that final assessments will be by peer assessors and panellists rather than by civil servants, or spreadsheets. More changes and improvements will come. 
However, more important than the detail of these measurements and statements is the link between how universities perform and tuition fees: this should be cut once and for all. The TEF, rather than a licence to raise fees should be a method to locate the best public investment opportunities in the interests of students – be that bursaries, infrastructure, or better staffing and staff recognition. The process could be good for students and for universities. 
But we can surely do better than finding the best teaching, and then increasing the prospective debt of the young people who might benefit most from that teaching.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/aug/22/teaching-excellence-framework-universities-tuition-fees-tef</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0800</post_time>
<username>Patrick McGhee</username>
<post>
Patrick McGhee 
If properly implemented the TEF could improve university teaching, but its link with tuition fees must be cut once and for all ‘Many people are concerned that the Teaching Excellence Framework will be too heavily driven by blunt metrics.’ Photograph: Chris Ison/PA Monday 22 August 2016 09.00 BST Last modified on Monday 22 August 2016 09.01 BST Share on Messenger 
T he Teaching Excellence Framework (TEF) will be among the features of the higher education and research bill, which will go to committee stage next month. The government wants the scheme to “incentivise excellent teaching” and give students better information on where the best provision is found. But it still intends to use good scores on the TEF as licence for individual universities to raise fees in line with inflation. 
This should be one of the most important points for scrutiny in parliament – especially in the light of news that at least one university is raising fees already on the back of the TEF not just for new students but for existing ones too. 
Related: The Teaching Excellence Framework: can higher education up its game? 
With the relocation of responsibility for universities into the Department for Education some worry that the TEF is uncomfortably close to Ofsted grades, and we know what those can do to a school’s reputation and fortunes. Universities UK, the vice-chancellors’ body, has called for implementation to be delayed until universities’ post-Brexit links with the EU are clarified. Many are concerned that the TEF will be too heavily driven by blunt metrics. However, the idea is too good an opportunity to miss for universities to promote teaching excellence. 
We now know what the key criteria will be: the headings are “teaching quality”, “learning environment” (eg facilities) and “student outcomes &amp; learning gain” (eg the employment outcomes of graduates and the gains made by students from a range of different backgrounds). Universities will be judged on each of the three areas on the basis of performance indicators (or “metrics”) alongside, crucially, universities’ own additional evidence. These will be combined to yield a grade: “meets expectations”, “excellent” or “outstanding”. 
“Teaching Quality” is defined as “teaching practices which provide an appropriate level of contact, stimulation and challenge, encourage student effort and engagement”. This will be measured by National Student Survey (NSS) questions. Institutions will add their own statements on issues such as effectiveness of innovative approaches, new technology or educational research and “recognition and reward schemes, including progression and promotion opportunities for staff”. 
Here the TEF, if implemented well – and it’s a big “if” – can be a force for good by providing parity of recognition for committed and effective teaching alongside research. Let’s hope this dimension also encourages a reduction in the casualisation of the academic workforce. 
The “learning environment” may include use of technology, work experience, extraurricular activities and opportunities for peer-to-peer interaction. This is a broader, richer conceptualisation than many had anticipated. Alongside NSS scores, judgments here will also reflect dropout rates. Universities will be able to contextualise the data by outlining what they are doing to improve retention. This seeks to address the spectre of some universities rejecting non-traditional students for fear of their potential impact on dropout rates. 
Related: Outstanding higher education teaching should not increase students’ debt | Patrick McGhee 
The metric for the student outcomes category is not only the unloved first Destinations of Leavers from Higher Education (DLHE) survey, which measures employment and training a mere six months after graduation, but also potentially a new index on “highly skilled employment”. No mention of graduate earnings. 
These factors will be judged alongside the provider’s own account of what it is doing to help disadvantaged students to progress and achieve. 
The government appears keen to send the message that final assessments will be by peer assessors and panellists rather than by civil servants, or spreadsheets. More changes and improvements will come. 
However, more important than the detail of these measurements and statements is the link between how universities perform and tuition fees: this should be cut once and for all. The TEF, rather than a licence to raise fees should be a method to locate the best public investment opportunities in the interests of students – be that bursaries, infrastructure, or better staffing and staff recognition. The process could be good for students and for universities. 
But we can surely do better than finding the best teaching, and then increasing the prospective debt of the young people who might benefit most from that teaching.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ed63161e86bbf900b8f9833b97b26bbfff23da91/0_111_2592_1556/2592.jpg?w=1200&amp;amp;h=630&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;bm=normal&amp;amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxNi8wNS8yNS9vdmVybGF5LWxvZ28tMTIwMC05MF9vcHQucG5n&amp;amp;s=d6060de9bf31dbd59d5d46f50e69e899</main_image>
</document>
