<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Cyber Security Conference to Host a Privacy vs. Security Debate</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/privacy_vs_security/HackerHalted/prweb13628890.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Cyber Security Conference to Host a Privacy vs. Security Debate Share Article The Privacy vs. Security debate at EC-Council Foundation’s Hacker Halted conference will feature perspectives from the US government, information security executives, hackers, and privacy advocates discussing where the line should be drawn between privacy and security. The question of privacy versus safety has never been as important or as topical as it is today. EC-Council Foundation will be encouraging debate on the controversies surrounding this complex issue by With the recent tug of war between the US government and Apple, as well as the fact that so much of the advancing technology in the industry seems to be based on what some could argue is an invasion of privacy, we knew this topic would be a big draw Atlanta, GA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 EC-Council Foundation is hosting a presidential style debate to argue where the line should be drawn between protecting the public’s safety versus protecting the public’s privacy. This debate applies to governments, corporations, families, and the information security industry at large. The debate will be held during a joint session of EC-Council Foundation’s premier annual conference, Hacker Halted . Slated to contribute their points of view are Kurt Opshaul from the EFF to represent Privacy, Amar Singh, former CISO of News International, to represent executive cybersecurity; Jack Daniel, security researcher at Tenable Network Security to represent Hackers; and retired FBI Special Agent Steve Bongart, representing the interests of the government. A member of the media specializing in information security will moderate the debate. Hacker Halted attracts a broad group of industry professionals, from researchers to managers. The Global CISO Forum , EC-Council Foundation’s other security event coinciding with Hacker Halted, is an event tailored for the executives of information security. The two conferences cover very different topics, as the CISOs are less interested in the technical details of their roles and more in the policy, governance, strategic, and financial implications of security decisions. However, for the Privacy vs. Security Debate , both Hacker Halted attendees and Global CISO Forum attendees will be present for the debate – a rare time one topic has been of such importance to both groups. “The fact that this debate is of interest to both groups really speaks to the broad applicability of the topic and why EC-Council Foundation knew it needed to be brought to the stage,” said Eric Lopez, Executive Director of EC-Council Foundation . He added “With the recent tug of war between the US government and Apple, as well as the fact that so much of the advancing technology in the industry seems to be based on what some could argue is an invasion of privacy, we knew this topic would be a big draw for both crowds. We hope good discussion and real collaboration can take place.” Companies have to grapple with the decision of where to draw the line when it comes to monitoring their employees in order to keep their data secure. This used to just mean warning employees that their browser history, emails, chats, and other modes of communication were not private, but with recent technology breakthroughs, the debate now includes things like location tracking and other more detailed metrics. While those kinds of questions can feel trivial, other aspects of the debate deal with life or death, national security questions. When should the government be able to access the data of a private citizen? When should companies comply with government requests and demands for such information? If one branch of a government is given access to a citizen’s information for one situation, should that set a precedent for future, similar situations? Is there anything to stop governments from expanding their access once some level of access is granted? These are the kinds of questions the participants will discuss, each from their own perspective. The Privacy vs. Security debate will not only be available to attendees of both events but will also be live streamed as well. Anyone interested in watching remotely should check the Hacker Halted website for details. To attend the debate in person, register for either Hacker Halted or the Global CISO Forum (open only to director-level or above information security professionals). About EC-Council Foundation: EC-Council Foundation is a charitable and educational organization dedicated to educating and training individuals in cyber security. Established in 2012 by EC-Council, the foundation seeks to raise awareness, build capacity across nations and ultimately unify global cyber defense. EC-Council Foundation is the creator and organizer of Global CyberLympics, Hacker Halted, TakeDownCon, The Global CISO Forum, and Live.Learn.Secure. an education and training program. For more information regarding EC-Council Foundation or any of its programs visit foundation.eccouncil.org. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.45</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/privacy_vs_security/HackerHalted/prweb13628890.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Cyber Security Conference to Host a Privacy vs. Security Debate Share Article The Privacy vs. Security debate at EC-Council Foundation’s Hacker Halted conference will feature perspectives from the US government, information security executives, hackers, and privacy advocates discussing where the line should be drawn between privacy and security. The question of privacy versus safety has never been as important or as topical as it is today. EC-Council Foundation will be encouraging debate on the controversies surrounding this complex issue by With the recent tug of war between the US government and Apple, as well as the fact that so much of the advancing technology in the industry seems to be based on what some could argue is an invasion of privacy, we knew this topic would be a big draw Atlanta, GA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 EC-Council Foundation is hosting a presidential style debate to argue where the line should be drawn between protecting the public’s safety versus protecting the public’s privacy. This debate applies to governments, corporations, families, and the information security industry at large. The debate will be held during a joint session of EC-Council Foundation’s premier annual conference, Hacker Halted . Slated to contribute their points of view are Kurt Opshaul from the EFF to represent Privacy, Amar Singh, former CISO of News International, to represent executive cybersecurity; Jack Daniel, security researcher at Tenable Network Security to represent Hackers; and retired FBI Special Agent Steve Bongart, representing the interests of the government. A member of the media specializing in information security will moderate the debate. Hacker Halted attracts a broad group of industry professionals, from researchers to managers. The Global CISO Forum , EC-Council Foundation’s other security event coinciding with Hacker Halted, is an event tailored for the executives of information security. The two conferences cover very different topics, as the CISOs are less interested in the technical details of their roles and more in the policy, governance, strategic, and financial implications of security decisions. However, for the Privacy vs. Security Debate , both Hacker Halted attendees and Global CISO Forum attendees will be present for the debate – a rare time one topic has been of such importance to both groups. “The fact that this debate is of interest to both groups really speaks to the broad applicability of the topic and why EC-Council Foundation knew it needed to be brought to the stage,” said Eric Lopez, Executive Director of EC-Council Foundation . He added “With the recent tug of war between the US government and Apple, as well as the fact that so much of the advancing technology in the industry seems to be based on what some could argue is an invasion of privacy, we knew this topic would be a big draw for both crowds. We hope good discussion and real collaboration can take place.” Companies have to grapple with the decision of where to draw the line when it comes to monitoring their employees in order to keep their data secure. This used to just mean warning employees that their browser history, emails, chats, and other modes of communication were not private, but with recent technology breakthroughs, the debate now includes things like location tracking and other more detailed metrics. While those kinds of questions can feel trivial, other aspects of the debate deal with life or death, national security questions. When should the government be able to access the data of a private citizen? When should companies comply with government requests and demands for such information? If one branch of a government is given access to a citizen’s information for one situation, should that set a precedent for future, similar situations? Is there anything to stop governments from expanding their access once some level of access is granted? These are the kinds of questions the participants will discuss, each from their own perspective. The Privacy vs. Security debate will not only be available to attendees of both events but will also be live streamed as well. Anyone interested in watching remotely should check the Hacker Halted website for details. To attend the debate in person, register for either Hacker Halted or the Global CISO Forum (open only to director-level or above information security professionals). About EC-Council Foundation: EC-Council Foundation is a charitable and educational organization dedicated to educating and training individuals in cyber security. Established in 2012 by EC-Council, the foundation seeks to raise awareness, build capacity across nations and ultimately unify global cyber defense. EC-Council Foundation is the creator and organizer of Global CyberLympics, Hacker Halted, TakeDownCon, The Global CISO Forum, and Live.Learn.Secure. an education and training program. For more information regarding EC-Council Foundation or any of its programs visit foundation.eccouncil.org. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/08/19/13628890/privacy-security-header-2.png</main_image>
</document>
