<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>PlateSmart Joins Forces with VIVOTEK in International Integration Partnership</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13627627.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
PlateSmart Joins Forces with VIVOTEK in International Integration Partnership Share Article Award-winning security software provider and leading global IP surveillance provider team up to make ALPR-based analytics available and affordable worldwide Oldsmar, Florida (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 PlateSmart® Technologies, creator of the award-winning ARES® video analytics software, is pleased to announce its new integration partnership with leading IP surveillance provider VIVOTEK. Through their association, the two companies will introduce PlateSmart’s disruptive Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR)-based video analytics technology to VIVOTEK’s vast and growing global client base. With this new relationship, PlateSmart affirms ARES’ reputation as among the security industry’s most versatile and affordable solutions. The software is compatible with a wide range of off-the-shelf surveillance cameras, which enables users to add ALPR-based video analytics to their security systems affordably and without having to “rip and replace” their existing cameras. Having certified VIVOTEK cameras for use with ARES, PlateSmart takes its place in VIVOTEK’s Solution Integration Alliance (SIA) program, an initiative to create security solutions that meet the needs of a diverse user base all over the world. For PlateSmart CEO John Chigos, the new partnership with VIVOTEK is a significant step forward in advancing his vision of a safer world. “The law enforcement and security officers that protect us have hard jobs, and those jobs get harder every day,” Chigos said. “PlateSmart is committed to providing them with the best intelligence-gathering tools available. The more widely technologies like ARES are deployed, the easier those officials’ jobs become and the safer we all are. Working with great companies like VIVOTEK makes that goal possible.” “VIVOTEK is continuing to expand cooperation with the world’s leading License Plate Recognition (LPR) software partners to offer customized solutions and enhance customer efficiencies and capabilities” said William Ku, Spokesman and Vice president, Brand Business Division, VIVOTEK Inc. “Through the strategic alliance, VIVOTEK will provide highly secure, efficient, and professional IP surveillance solutions that can seamlessly integrate with PlateSmart’s Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR) technology. Combining the expertise of two companies also drives the growth and development of the Smart City in the United States.” About PlateSmart PlateSmart Technologies has developed the world’s first software-only Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR) and video analytic solutions, which are compatible with both state-of-the-art and legacy cameras. PlateSmart offers both mobile and fixed ALPR and analytic solutions, which are designed either to function as stand-alone tools or to integrate with third-party software and hardware. ARES, PlateSmart’s enterprise ALPR-based analytics solution, provides real-time actionable intelligence with industry-leading accuracies and state jurisdiction recognition for complete situational awareness. PlateSmart’s solutions have been recognized as the most innovative and forward-thinking LPR technology by Frost and Sullivan. http://www.platesmart.com About VIVOTEK VIVOTEK, established in 2000, has quickly taken its place as a leading brand in the security industry. Known for delivering world-class IP surveillance solutions, VIVOTEK specializes in system applications and integration. With innovative R&amp;D teams adopting ground-breaking codec technologies, VIVOTEK provides a wide range of products, including network cameras, video servers, video receivers, network video recorders, central management software, and PoE solutions. VIVOTEK (TAIEX: 3454) was listed on the Taiwan Stock Exchange in 2011. In 2008, a branch office was set up in California, USA. VIVOTEK established a Europe branch office in Almere, the Netherlands in 2013, India office in Delhi in 2014, and Middle East office in Dubai in 2015, Mexico office in 2016. VIVOTEK is currently working with more than 183 authorized distributors in over 116 countries. For more information, please visit http://www.vivotek.com . DISCLAIMER: This press release may contain forward-looking statements and/or predictions. These statements are based on history, current knowledge, and current market conditions. They are subject to change without notice as conditions and knowledge change; therefore, undue reliance should not be placed on such statements. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.02</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13627627.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
PlateSmart Joins Forces with VIVOTEK in International Integration Partnership Share Article Award-winning security software provider and leading global IP surveillance provider team up to make ALPR-based analytics available and affordable worldwide Oldsmar, Florida (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 PlateSmart® Technologies, creator of the award-winning ARES® video analytics software, is pleased to announce its new integration partnership with leading IP surveillance provider VIVOTEK. Through their association, the two companies will introduce PlateSmart’s disruptive Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR)-based video analytics technology to VIVOTEK’s vast and growing global client base. With this new relationship, PlateSmart affirms ARES’ reputation as among the security industry’s most versatile and affordable solutions. The software is compatible with a wide range of off-the-shelf surveillance cameras, which enables users to add ALPR-based video analytics to their security systems affordably and without having to “rip and replace” their existing cameras. Having certified VIVOTEK cameras for use with ARES, PlateSmart takes its place in VIVOTEK’s Solution Integration Alliance (SIA) program, an initiative to create security solutions that meet the needs of a diverse user base all over the world. For PlateSmart CEO John Chigos, the new partnership with VIVOTEK is a significant step forward in advancing his vision of a safer world. “The law enforcement and security officers that protect us have hard jobs, and those jobs get harder every day,” Chigos said. “PlateSmart is committed to providing them with the best intelligence-gathering tools available. The more widely technologies like ARES are deployed, the easier those officials’ jobs become and the safer we all are. Working with great companies like VIVOTEK makes that goal possible.” “VIVOTEK is continuing to expand cooperation with the world’s leading License Plate Recognition (LPR) software partners to offer customized solutions and enhance customer efficiencies and capabilities” said William Ku, Spokesman and Vice president, Brand Business Division, VIVOTEK Inc. “Through the strategic alliance, VIVOTEK will provide highly secure, efficient, and professional IP surveillance solutions that can seamlessly integrate with PlateSmart’s Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR) technology. Combining the expertise of two companies also drives the growth and development of the Smart City in the United States.” About PlateSmart PlateSmart Technologies has developed the world’s first software-only Automatic License Plate Recognition (ALPR) and video analytic solutions, which are compatible with both state-of-the-art and legacy cameras. PlateSmart offers both mobile and fixed ALPR and analytic solutions, which are designed either to function as stand-alone tools or to integrate with third-party software and hardware. ARES, PlateSmart’s enterprise ALPR-based analytics solution, provides real-time actionable intelligence with industry-leading accuracies and state jurisdiction recognition for complete situational awareness. PlateSmart’s solutions have been recognized as the most innovative and forward-thinking LPR technology by Frost and Sullivan. http://www.platesmart.com About VIVOTEK VIVOTEK, established in 2000, has quickly taken its place as a leading brand in the security industry. Known for delivering world-class IP surveillance solutions, VIVOTEK specializes in system applications and integration. With innovative R&amp;D teams adopting ground-breaking codec technologies, VIVOTEK provides a wide range of products, including network cameras, video servers, video receivers, network video recorders, central management software, and PoE solutions. VIVOTEK (TAIEX: 3454) was listed on the Taiwan Stock Exchange in 2011. In 2008, a branch office was set up in California, USA. VIVOTEK established a Europe branch office in Almere, the Netherlands in 2013, India office in Delhi in 2014, and Middle East office in Dubai in 2015, Mexico office in 2016. VIVOTEK is currently working with more than 183 authorized distributors in over 116 countries. For more information, please visit http://www.vivotek.com . DISCLAIMER: This press release may contain forward-looking statements and/or predictions. These statements are based on history, current knowledge, and current market conditions. They are subject to change without notice as conditions and knowledge change; therefore, undue reliance should not be placed on such statements. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
