<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Independent - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>The government thinks Team GB&apos;s Rio performance shows how Brexit can be a success | Olympic News | Sport</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/sport/olympics/news/the-government-thinks-team-gbs-rio-performance-shows-brexit-can-be-a-success-a7203051.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The government has claimed Team GB’s success at the Rio Olympics can be used as a “template” for making Brexit a success. 
Business Secretary Greg Clark said the country would harness the spirit of the team’s “world beaters” and use the same approach to back “excellence” – though provided little detail as to how it would work in practice.
It comes as the team became one of the most successful in British history after finishing second in the league, ahead of China, for the first time in more than a century. 
Read more Rio 2016: Could this be Team GB’s last great Olympics after Brexit? Brexiteers- stop claiming responsibility for Team GB’s success, you’re the reason we’ll fall short in Tokyo 2020 Brexit latest: Are we heading for another recession now Britain is leaving the EU? Team GB exceeded its medal haul from the London 2012 Games and the UK was dubbed the world’s new “sporting superpower” .
Mr Clark said: “By making the most of our strengths, improving our facilities, developing the skills of athletes and coaches alike, we have become a world-beating sporting nation.
“We have a real opportunity to apply many of the same insights as we bring together a long-term strategy for our industrial and commercial future . 
“Recognising our strengths — from science to the creative industries — and making sure they are nurtured and encouraged.”
Rio 2016 Olympics - in pictures 74 show all Rio 2016 Olympics - in pictures 1/74 Day Eight Andy Murray celebrates his victory over Kai Nishikori to reach the men&apos;s Olympic final.
Getty
2/74 Day Eight Jessica Ennis-Hill continues her bid for gold in heptathlon.
Getty
3/74 Day Eight Usain Bolt breezed through his 100m heat.
Getty
4/74 Day Eight Team GB took silver in the women&apos;s eight.
Getty
5/74 Day Eight The men&apos;s eight gold took Great Britain top of the rowing medal table.
Getty
6/74 Day Seven Britain&apos;s Jazz Carlin secured her second silver of the Games in the women&apos;s 800m freestyle, as American Katie Ledecky surged to her fourth Rio gold.
Getty
7/74 Day Seven Singapore&apos;s Joseph Schooling won his nation&apos;s first gold medal with victory in the 100m butterfly as Michael Phelps was denied a 23rd Olympic title. 
Getty
8/74 Day Seven Sir Bradley Wiggins becomes Britain&apos;s greatest Olympian ever as Team GB win gold in the men&apos;s Team Pursuit at the Velodrome.
AFP
9/74 Day Seven Bryony Page on her way to a silver in gymnastics trampoline.
EPA
10/74 Day Seven Heather Stanning and Helen Glover win gold in the women&apos;s rowing pairs.
Getty
11/74 Day Seven Alex Gregory, Mohamed Sbihi, George Nash and Constantine Louloudis celebrate their success in the men’s coxless four.
Getty
12/74 Day Seven Defending champions Great Britain won silver in the Olympic team dressage, as world champions Germany claimed gold. The British quartet - Spencer Wilton, Fiona Bigwood, Carl Hester and Charlotte Dujardin - were beaten into second by 3.334 points.
Getty
13/74 Day Six American Simone Manuel became the first black female swimmer to win an Olympic title as she shared the women&apos;s 100m freestyle gold with Canada&apos;s Penny Oleksiak, 16, after a dead heat.
Getty Images
14/74 Day Six Swimming legend Michael Phelps demolished the field in the 200m individual medley to claim his 22nd Olympic gold.
Getty
15/74 Day Six Simone Biles takes gold in the Women’s individual all-around artistic gymnastics.
Getty
16/74 Day Six Fiji&apos;s Vatemo Ravouvou breaks through to score during the Men&apos;s Rugby Sevens Gold medal final match against Great Britain. Team GB settled for silver as Fiji romped to gold.
David Rogers/Getty Images
17/74 Day Six Callum Skinner, Jason Kenny and Philip Hindes of Great Britain celebrate after winning gold in the men&apos;s team sprint.
AFP
18/74 Day Six Double act David Florence and Richard Hounslow won their second joint Olympic silver in the canoeing slalom.
Getty
19/74 Day Six Victoria Thornley and Katherine Grainger show off their silver medals after the women&apos;s double sculls final
Getty
20/74 Day Five Max Whitlock poses with his bronze medal
Getty
21/74 Day Five Joe Clarke reacts to winning Britain&apos;s second gold of thee Games
Reuters
22/74 Day Five Jack Laugher and Chris Mears celebrate with their gold medals
Getty
23/74 Day Four David Florence suffered heartbreak in the canoe single C1 men&apos;s semi-final 
Getty
24/74 Day Four Andy Murray celebrates his straight sets victory against Juan Monaco
Getty
25/74 Day Three Lilly King shows off her gold medal as Yulia Efimova parades her silver
AFP
26/74 Day Three Russia&apos;s Yulia Efimova (left) looks on as the US&apos;s Lilly King (right) celebrates winning the Women&apos;s 100m Breaststroke Final earlier this morning
Getty
27/74 Day Three Lilly King celebrates after beating her Russian rival Yulia Efimova
Getty
28/74 Day Three Michael Phelps takes on Chad Le Clos in the men&apos;s 200m butterfly final
Getty
29/74 Day Three Michael Phelps says it &apos;breaks my heart&apos; to see drug cheats at the Olympics
Getty
30/74 Day Three James Guy missed out on bronze on Monday night
Getty
31/74 Day Three Louis Smith reacts to his pommel stumble which may have cost Team GB a medal
Getty
32/74 Day Three Dan Goodfellow (right) and Tom Daley celebrate with their bronze medals
Getty
33/74 Day Three Tom Daley and Dan Goodfellow dive into the pool in delight after winning bronze
Getty
34/74 Day Three Tom Daley (left) and Daniel Goodfellow performing in the men&apos;s synchronised 10m platform final
PA
35/74 Day Three Canada celebrate their victory against Team GB on day three
Getty
36/74 Day Three Heather Watson leaves the court yesterday after losing her second round match against Elina Svitolina of Ukraine
Reuters
37/74 Day Two Carlin proudly shows off her silver medal
Getty
38/74 Day Two Carlin reacts after learning that she has won the silver medal
Getty
39/74 Day Two Peaty shows off his gold medal with pride
Getty
40/74 Day Two Adam Peaty celebrates his gold
Getty
41/74 Day Two Andy Murray and Jamie Murray were knocked out of the men&apos;s doubles by Thomaz Bellucci and Andre Sa
AFP
42/74 Day Two Venus and Serena Williams suffered their first ever Olympic defeat playing together
Getty
43/74 Day Two Richard Kruse battling the Russian Timur Safin
GETTY
44/74 Day Two Lizzie Armitstead finished fifth in the women&apos;s road race
PA
45/74 Day Two Anna van der Breggen celebrates winning gold in the women&apos;s road race
Reuters
46/74 Day Two Annemiek van Vleuten suffered a horrific accident in the women&apos;s road race
Reuters
47/74 Day Two The women&apos;s road race passes along the beach in Rio de Janeiro
Getty
48/74 Day Two Andy Murray beat Viktor Troicki 6-3, 6-2 to win his men&apos;s singles first round match
Getty
49/74 Day Two Serena Williams is through to the second round of the women&apos;s singles after defeating Daria Gavrilova
Getty
50/74 Day Two Gold medal winner, Hoang Xuan Vinh of Vietnam, center, silver medal winner, Felipe Almeida Wu of Brazil, left, and bronze medalist Pang Wei of China, at the victory ceremony for the men&apos;s 10-meter air pistol event 
AP
51/74 Day Two Rowing was cancelled on day two over fears of sinking and capsizing due to strong winds
Getty
52/74 Day One Yusra Mardini has won her heat of the Women&apos;s 100m Butterfly but she will not be able to go forward to the semi-final
Getty Images
53/74 Day One Britain&apos;s James Guy chops through the water
Getty
54/74 Day One Kantinka Hosszu of Hungary set a new world record in winning gold in the Women&apos;s 100m Individual Medley final
Getty
55/74 Day One Samir Ait Said receiving medical help after suffering a badly broken leg
Getty
56/74 Day One Yusra Mardini leads the race in the 100m Butterfly heat at Olympic Aquatics Stadium in Rio
EPA
57/74 Day One Natasha Hunt scored two tries to inspire Britain to victory against Brazil
Getty
58/74 Day One Joanne Watmore scored Britain&apos;s first try in Olympic rugby sevens history
Getty
59/74 Day One Adam Peaty celebrates after breaking the 100m breaststroke world record
Getty
60/74 Day One Adam Peaty broke his own world record in the 100m breaststroke heats and is favourite to win gold on Sunday
Getty
61/74 Day One Adam Peaty broke his own world record in the 100m breaststroke heats
Getty
62/74 Day One Chris Froome speaks with a bruised Geraint Thomas after the men&apos;s road race
PA
63/74 Day One Greg van Avermaet celebrates winning gold in the men&apos;s road race
Getty
64/74 Day One Rafal Majka was caught with just two kilometres to go
Getty
65/74 Day One Greg van Avermaet won a sprint finish to clinch Olympic road race gold
EPA
66/74 Day One A bullet is marked by Brazilian police in the equestrian media centre
Getty
67/74 Day One The peloton make their way along the beach during the road race
Getty
68/74 Day One Chris Froome leads away the men&apos;s road race along with the rest of Team GB
Getty
69/74 Day One The field make their way along the opening stages of the road race
Eric Gaillard/Reuters
70/74 Day One Mahe Drysdale of New Zealand had no trouble in qualifying for the men&apos;s single skulls quarter-finals
Getty
71/74 Day One Rowers warm up under the watchful gaze of the Christ the Redeemer statue
Getty
72/74 Opening Ceremony A huge fireworks display signals the end of the Rio 2016 Opening Ceremony.
Felipe Dana/AP
73/74 Opening Ceremony Andy Murray leads out Team GB at the Rio Olympics opening ceremony
Getty
74/74 Opening Ceremony Gisele Bundchen turns the stage into a catwalk during the opening ceremony
AP
The turnaround in British sport since Team GB won just one gold medal at the 1996 Atlanta Games has been put down to a decision by John Major’s government to divert National Lottery funding into sport to help athletes train full time. 
He told The Sunday Times the new government under Theresa May would “create an environment in which excellence can thrive” and vowed that those in competition with the world’s best” would get “world class” training to help them become the “talent of tomorrow”.
But some critics were quick to suggest Mr Clark’s words offered little guidance to how the country will go forward with Brexit, as almost every aspect of the UK’s exit is still up in the air. 
Twitter users poured scorn on the comments, saying they appeared to be just empty words:
Like, what does that second paragraph even mean?? #Olympics #brexit pic.twitter.com/YbCuj4zd5s 
— Declan Cashin (@Tweet_Dec) 21 August 2016 So #Brexit is supposed to go the same way as Olympics success? In other words it&apos;ll be funded by EuroMillions?
— Edd Edmondson (@eddedmondson) 21 August 2016 News reports suggest Theresa May will use Olympics success as a blueprint for brexit. In case you were worried there was no plan, like.
— karl wareham (@Warlkareham) 21 August 2016 Meanwhile Leave.EU have been reprimanded for attempting to link Team GB’s success to Brexit.
The campaign tried to claimed that the success of the athletes proved the UK was “small but mighty” and would go from strength to strength outside the EU.
But the British Olympics Association has warned the unofficial Leave campaign to stop featuring their athletes in their tweets as all photos of them are their intellectual property and that of their official media partners. 
Several commentators pointed out that the success of the current crop of British athletes was achieved by years of training and hard work - some of which was achieved in EU countries or with funding from the European Regional Development Fund .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>8</post_num>
<post_id>post-8</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/sport/olympics/news/the-government-thinks-team-gbs-rio-performance-shows-brexit-can-be-a-success-a7203051.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>1002</post_time>
<username>Simon</username>
<post>
We can do better with less dishonest people who refuse to lie and cheat in order to drag this country to shirk its commitments and desert its allies. 
Has Turkey joined yet? 
Will the £350 million pledge to the EU be upheld? 
After gorging themselves in the multi-million pound brexit trough, will the right-wing tory cabinet refuse to cut back the NHS, tax credits and the rest of the welfare state that many leave voters wrong-headedly thought they were protecting fro TTIP? 
Don&apos;t talk to e about democracy, your kind would not know it even if it came up and ht you in the face. 
Cheats, liars and cowards who dishonour their country.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2016/08/21/02/mo-farah-double.jpg</main_image>
</document>
