<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.cleveland.com/open/</forum>
<forum_title>Ohio Politics &amp;amp; Election News | cleveland.com </forum_title>
<discussion_title>City Club likely to cut back on political debates, citing lack of competitive congressional races</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.cleveland.com/open/index.ssf/2016/08/city_club_likely_to_cut_back_o.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
CLEVELAND, Ohio – The City Club of Cleveland, an essential stop on the Ohio campaign trail, could break with years of tradition by not hosting debates for U.S. House hopefuls this fall.
Dan Moulthrop, the City Club&apos;s chief executive officer, said the decision is not yet final and rests with a committee composed of community leaders. The panel convened in January to study ways the organization could refresh a stale – and occasionally criticized – debate format.
These discussions, Moulthrop said, have the group leaning against highlighting races that aren&apos;t competitive. And in Ohio, a Republican-led redistricting process five years ago resulted in a new congressional map that has overwhelmingly favored the GOP in most districts.
Few if any of the Buckeye State&apos;s House seats are expected to flip to the other party in November, and that includes the four – of 16 – that are considered safe for Democrats.
&quot;The thinking on the congressional races is that most of them are really not competitive,&quot; said attorney Phil Calabrese, who co-chairs the City Club&apos;s debate planning committee. &quot;At the congressional level, it&apos;s been much harder to get people to attend the debates.&quot;
Said Moulthrop: &quot;This is a structural issue with how our legislature has chosen to draw the lines. In a non-competitive race, the debate is inconsequential. The debate has no purpose.&quot;
The City Club will host other political debates, including an October showdown between Republican Sen. Rob Portman and Democratic challenger Ted Strickland. Moulthrop said debates also are in the works for this year&apos;s Ohio Supreme Court races. And there is hope of scheduling of a forum with surrogates representing the presidential campaigns.
Attorney Michael Wager, a Democrat running in the 14 th District, learned this week that the City Club is unlikely to host a debate between him and Republican incumbent Dave Joyce. The district, which takes in Cleveland&apos;s eastern suburbs and exurbs, once was seen as a pick-up opportunity for Democrats. But Wager lost to Joyce there by 30 percentage points in 2014.
Wager ascribes his struggles to a &quot;catastrophic&quot; race run by the Democratic candidate for governor that year and on a midterm election climate that didn&apos;t favor his party. Presidential election years are different. Wager, like many other political analysts, believes the unpredictable candidacy of GOP nominee Donald Trump will hurt Republicans in close down-ballot races.
The 14 th District was included this week on a Washington Post map of &quot;House races to watch.&quot; But the forecasters at Cook Political Report identify the race as &quot;Solid Republican.&quot;
&quot;I&apos;m not sure competitiveness should be the test,&quot; Wager said Friday. &quot;I think the City Club is a vitally important institution in our community, and I hope they reconsider this.&quot;
The City Club hosted debates for several Cleveland-area House races two years ago – including one that featured Joyce, Wager and Libertarian candidate David Macko . That meeting spurred some complaints from Republicans who believed that the format and questions were tilted in Wager&apos;s favor. Moulthrop, concerned about fairness, said those complaints convinced him the City Club wasn&apos;t the appropriate organization to host a 2016 rematch. (He added that the City Club would help a different host spread the word about a 14 th District debate.)
But 2014 also brought a forum in which Rep. Marcia Fudge, a Democrat with only token opposition, decided not to show up to debate Republican Mark Zetzer . And in statewide races that year, all GOP incumbents except for Auditor Dave Yost declined City Club invitations to spar with their Democratic challengers. Moulthrop and other good-government advocates cried foul , but the snubs reflected the fact that several of the contests weren&apos;t competitive.
More recently, Strickland skipped a City Club debate that featured his primary rivals.
In the past the City Club would press ahead with a debate without the incumbent or frontrunner, affording lesser-known contenders positive, if fleeting, publicity. But those forums don&apos;t draw well.
&quot;Our mission is about supporting democracy,&quot; Moulthrop said. &quot;Our goal is to provide forums that will be productive and useful to voters, to the community, and to the campaigns in their effort to connect with voters. If we can&apos;t do that, we&apos;re not going to do that.&quot;
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>3</post_num>
<post_id>post-3</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.cleveland.com/open/index.ssf/2016/08/city_club_likely_to_cut_back_o.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time>1707</post_time>
<username>ultra51</username>
<post>
Mr. Wager is correct. This year&apos;s political climate means that he&apos;ll only lose to Rep. Joyce by 20 points, not 30 like last time.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://image.cleveland.com/home/cleve-media/width620/img/open_impact/photo/20949054-standard.jpg</main_image>
</document>
