<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>PDP Crisis - Sheriff, Party Urged to Embrace Dialogue</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220188.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By Emmanuel Mgbeahuruike More knocks have come for embattled erstwhile Chairman of the People&apos;s Democratic Party (PDP), Senator Ali Modu Sheriff as he has been described as a pretender and non-card carrying member of the PDP, who is bent on bringing the party to its knees. Former secretary to the Imo State Government (SGI), Barr. Chris Okewulonu stated this in Owerri, Imo State while reacting to developments in the party and the ruling of a Federal High Court in Port Harcourt. The legal luminary wondered what Sheriff stands to lose if he does not become the national Chairman of PDP, pointing out that Sheriff&apos;s desperation is a bad omen to the party. He contended that a critical check on Sheriff&apos;s membership of the PDP will prove that Sheriff was not even registered in his ward and therefore may not even have a PDP membership card. &quot;The ward is where membership of a party is anchored. I bet you, Sheriff&apos;s name is not in PDP&apos;s membership register in his ward because he suddenly jumped into PDP from APC. He is acting as if he is harbouring an age long bitterness against PDP and the opportunity has now provided itself for him to strike&quot;, Okewulonu stated. The former SGI, however, stated that the PDP is greater than any of its members, cautioning that members should be humble enough to subject themselves to party constitution. He averred that the &quot;issue of Sheriff has been blown out of proportion by the media thereby, portraying our party as being in crisis. That notion is not only wrong but misleading because PDP is intact, Sheriff or no Sheriff&quot;. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220188.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0747</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By Emmanuel Mgbeahuruike More knocks have come for embattled erstwhile Chairman of the People&apos;s Democratic Party (PDP), Senator Ali Modu Sheriff as he has been described as a pretender and non-card carrying member of the PDP, who is bent on bringing the party to its knees. Former secretary to the Imo State Government (SGI), Barr. Chris Okewulonu stated this in Owerri, Imo State while reacting to developments in the party and the ruling of a Federal High Court in Port Harcourt. The legal luminary wondered what Sheriff stands to lose if he does not become the national Chairman of PDP, pointing out that Sheriff&apos;s desperation is a bad omen to the party. He contended that a critical check on Sheriff&apos;s membership of the PDP will prove that Sheriff was not even registered in his ward and therefore may not even have a PDP membership card. &quot;The ward is where membership of a party is anchored. I bet you, Sheriff&apos;s name is not in PDP&apos;s membership register in his ward because he suddenly jumped into PDP from APC. He is acting as if he is harbouring an age long bitterness against PDP and the opportunity has now provided itself for him to strike&quot;, Okewulonu stated. The former SGI, however, stated that the PDP is greater than any of its members, cautioning that members should be humble enough to subject themselves to party constitution. He averred that the &quot;issue of Sheriff has been blown out of proportion by the media thereby, portraying our party as being in crisis. That notion is not only wrong but misleading because PDP is intact, Sheriff or no Sheriff&quot;. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
