<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Choi and Jeonbuk looking to seal crucial win in Shanghai | AFC</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.the-afc.com/afc-champions-league-2016/choi-and-jeonbuk-looking-to-seal-crucial-win-in-shanghai</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Choi and Jeonbuk looking to seal crucial win in Shanghai Choi and Jeonbuk looking to seal crucial win in Shanghai / Aug 22 2016 / Shanghai: Jeonbuk Hyundai Motors coach Choi Kang-hee insisted the Korean champions will be looking for nothing less than a win at Shanghai Stadium when they face Shanghai SIPG in the first leg of their 2016 AFC Champions League quarter-final on Tuesday night. Having been eliminated at the final eight stage in last year’s competition after a dramatic injury-time winner from Gamba Osaka’s Koki Yonekura , Jeonbuk will look to ensure they have the momentum going into the second leg at Jeonju World Cup Stadium on 13 September. Riding high in the K-League Classic, ten points ahead of second-placed FC Seoul who will face Shandong Luneng in Wednesday’sAFC Champions League quarter-final, Choi is convinced the team’s winning form on the domestic front will be successfully transferred to the continental stage. “It doesn’t matter that this is an away match, Jeonbuk is a champion team and we are always looking to win; never content to draw,” said Choi, whose team defeated Incheon United 3-1 in their most recent K-League outing on Wednesday. “We have many special players with strong characteristics, while the atmosphere and morale amongst the team is also much better than last year.” Shanghai, meanwhile, have invested considerable sums to bring in big name players including the likes of Asia’s most expensive transferee Hulk and two-time AFC Champions League winner Elkeson , while also boasting one of China’s best talents, Wu Lei . Regardless, Choi believes his team have what it takes to come out on top. “Chinese teams have invested greatly and the level has gone up, there’s no denying that – and this is a positive thing for their league. We have spent a great deal of time analysing their team and no matter who plays we will be prepared for them,” added Choi. “We have to win the match tomorrow, it is important for Korean football and we will show why we are champions.” Key to Jeonbuk’s fortunes could be star midfielder Lee Jae-sung. The playmaker was included in Korea Republic’s recently announced squad for the 2018 FIFA World Cup Qualifier against China on 1 September, and the significance of the tie against Shanghai is not lost on the 24-year-old. “This AFC Champions League game is a preview of Korea versus China. If we can win this one, it will affect [performances] at national team level as well,” said Lee. “We know this away game is going to be vital to achieving our ultimate goal. For the whole 90 minutes we’re going to have high concentration to get the result we want.” Photo: Lagardere Sports 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.02</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.the-afc.com/afc-champions-league-2016/choi-and-jeonbuk-looking-to-seal-crucial-win-in-shanghai</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Choi and Jeonbuk looking to seal crucial win in Shanghai Choi and Jeonbuk looking to seal crucial win in Shanghai / Aug 22 2016 / Shanghai: Jeonbuk Hyundai Motors coach Choi Kang-hee insisted the Korean champions will be looking for nothing less than a win at Shanghai Stadium when they face Shanghai SIPG in the first leg of their 2016 AFC Champions League quarter-final on Tuesday night. Having been eliminated at the final eight stage in last year’s competition after a dramatic injury-time winner from Gamba Osaka’s Koki Yonekura , Jeonbuk will look to ensure they have the momentum going into the second leg at Jeonju World Cup Stadium on 13 September. Riding high in the K-League Classic, ten points ahead of second-placed FC Seoul who will face Shandong Luneng in Wednesday’sAFC Champions League quarter-final, Choi is convinced the team’s winning form on the domestic front will be successfully transferred to the continental stage. “It doesn’t matter that this is an away match, Jeonbuk is a champion team and we are always looking to win; never content to draw,” said Choi, whose team defeated Incheon United 3-1 in their most recent K-League outing on Wednesday. “We have many special players with strong characteristics, while the atmosphere and morale amongst the team is also much better than last year.” Shanghai, meanwhile, have invested considerable sums to bring in big name players including the likes of Asia’s most expensive transferee Hulk and two-time AFC Champions League winner Elkeson , while also boasting one of China’s best talents, Wu Lei . Regardless, Choi believes his team have what it takes to come out on top. “Chinese teams have invested greatly and the level has gone up, there’s no denying that – and this is a positive thing for their league. We have spent a great deal of time analysing their team and no matter who plays we will be prepared for them,” added Choi. “We have to win the match tomorrow, it is important for Korean football and we will show why we are champions.” Key to Jeonbuk’s fortunes could be star midfielder Lee Jae-sung. The playmaker was included in Korea Republic’s recently announced squad for the 2018 FIFA World Cup Qualifier against China on 1 September, and the significance of the tie against Shanghai is not lost on the 24-year-old. “This AFC Champions League game is a preview of Korea versus China. If we can win this one, it will affect [performances] at national team level as well,” said Lee. “We know this away game is going to be vital to achieving our ultimate goal. For the whole 90 minutes we’re going to have high concentration to get the result we want.” Photo: Lagardere Sports 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>MY</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
