<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Pan American Silver Corp. (PAAS) Rating Reiterated by TD Securities</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/pan-american-silver-corp-paas-rating-reiterated-by-td-securities/1212619/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
TD Securities reaffirmed their hold rating on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. (NASDAQ:PAAS) in a report published on Tuesday morning. TD Securities currently has a $23.00 price objective on the stock, up from their previous price objective of $18.00. 
Other hedge funds and institutional investors recently modified their holdings of the company. Bank of Montreal Can raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 98.3% in the fourth quarter. Bank of Montreal Can now owns 296,295 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,926,000 after buying an additional 146,866 shares during the last quarter. Dimensional Fund Advisors LP raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 9.4% in the fourth quarter. Dimensional Fund Advisors LP now owns 525,377 shares of the company’s stock worth $3,415,000 after buying an additional 45,051 shares during the last quarter. Connor Clark &amp; Lunn Investment Management Ltd. raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 122.6% in the fourth quarter. Connor Clark &amp; Lunn Investment Management Ltd. now owns 4,429,357 shares of the company’s stock worth $28,730,000 after buying an additional 2,439,275 shares during the last quarter. Global X Management CO LLC raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 2.8% in the fourth quarter. Global X Management CO LLC now owns 963,810 shares of the company’s stock worth $6,264,000 after buying an additional 26,253 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Deutsche Bank AG raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 14.3% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 2,199,476 shares of the company’s stock worth $14,295,000 after buying an additional 275,252 shares during the last quarter. 
Several other equities research analysts have also recently weighed in on the stock. FBR &amp; Co upped their price target on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from $16.00 to $19.00 and gave the stock a mkt perform rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 20th. Zacks Investment Research raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a hold rating to a strong-buy rating and set a $22.00 price target for the company in a research report on Tuesday, July 19th. Scotiabank raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a sector perform rating to an outperform rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 13th. HSBC reaffirmed a buy rating on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. in a research report on Thursday, July 7th. Finally, Raymond James Financial Inc. raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a market perform rating to an outperform rating and upped their price target for the stock from $15.00 to $18.50 in a research report on Monday, June 27th. Eight investment analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating, six have given a buy rating and one has assigned a strong buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock presently has an average rating of Buy and an average target price of $15.61. 
Pan American Silver Corp. ( NASDAQ:PAAS ) opened at 20.77 on Tuesday. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $19.16 and its 200 day moving average is $14.15. The stock’s market cap is $3.16 billion. Pan American Silver Corp. has a 52 week low of $5.38 and a 52 week high of $21.59. 
Pan American Silver Corp. (NASDAQ:PAAS) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported $0.13 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the consensus estimate of $0.03 by $0.10. Analysts predict that Pan American Silver Corp. will post $0.47 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Tuesday, September 6th. Shareholders of record on Tuesday, August 23rd will be paid a dividend of $0.0125 per share. The ex-dividend date is Friday, August 19th. This represents a $0.05 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 0.24%. 
Pan American Silver Corp. (Pan American) is engaged in the production and sale of silver, gold and base metals including copper, lead and zinc, as well as other related activities, including exploration, extraction, processing, refining and reclamation. The Company’s primary product (silver) is produced in Peru, Mexico, Argentina and Bolivia.   Pan American Silver Corp.   Pan American Silver Corp.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/pan-american-silver-corp-paas-rating-reiterated-by-td-securities/1212619/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0749</post_time>
<username>Hasmir Abdula</username>
<post>
Tweet 
TD Securities reaffirmed their hold rating on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. (NASDAQ:PAAS) in a report published on Tuesday morning. TD Securities currently has a $23.00 price objective on the stock, up from their previous price objective of $18.00. 
Other hedge funds and institutional investors recently modified their holdings of the company. Bank of Montreal Can raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 98.3% in the fourth quarter. Bank of Montreal Can now owns 296,295 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,926,000 after buying an additional 146,866 shares during the last quarter. Dimensional Fund Advisors LP raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 9.4% in the fourth quarter. Dimensional Fund Advisors LP now owns 525,377 shares of the company’s stock worth $3,415,000 after buying an additional 45,051 shares during the last quarter. Connor Clark &amp; Lunn Investment Management Ltd. raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 122.6% in the fourth quarter. Connor Clark &amp; Lunn Investment Management Ltd. now owns 4,429,357 shares of the company’s stock worth $28,730,000 after buying an additional 2,439,275 shares during the last quarter. Global X Management CO LLC raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 2.8% in the fourth quarter. Global X Management CO LLC now owns 963,810 shares of the company’s stock worth $6,264,000 after buying an additional 26,253 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Deutsche Bank AG raised its position in shares of Pan American Silver Corp. by 14.3% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 2,199,476 shares of the company’s stock worth $14,295,000 after buying an additional 275,252 shares during the last quarter. 
Several other equities research analysts have also recently weighed in on the stock. FBR &amp; Co upped their price target on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from $16.00 to $19.00 and gave the stock a mkt perform rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 20th. Zacks Investment Research raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a hold rating to a strong-buy rating and set a $22.00 price target for the company in a research report on Tuesday, July 19th. Scotiabank raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a sector perform rating to an outperform rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 13th. HSBC reaffirmed a buy rating on shares of Pan American Silver Corp. in a research report on Thursday, July 7th. Finally, Raymond James Financial Inc. raised shares of Pan American Silver Corp. from a market perform rating to an outperform rating and upped their price target for the stock from $15.00 to $18.50 in a research report on Monday, June 27th. Eight investment analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating, six have given a buy rating and one has assigned a strong buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock presently has an average rating of Buy and an average target price of $15.61. 
Pan American Silver Corp. ( NASDAQ:PAAS ) opened at 20.77 on Tuesday. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $19.16 and its 200 day moving average is $14.15. The stock’s market cap is $3.16 billion. Pan American Silver Corp. has a 52 week low of $5.38 and a 52 week high of $21.59. 
Pan American Silver Corp. (NASDAQ:PAAS) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported $0.13 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the consensus estimate of $0.03 by $0.10. Analysts predict that Pan American Silver Corp. will post $0.47 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Tuesday, September 6th. Shareholders of record on Tuesday, August 23rd will be paid a dividend of $0.0125 per share. The ex-dividend date is Friday, August 19th. This represents a $0.05 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 0.24%. 
Pan American Silver Corp. (Pan American) is engaged in the production and sale of silver, gold and base metals including copper, lead and zinc, as well as other related activities, including exploration, extraction, processing, refining and reclamation. The Company’s primary product (silver) is produced in Peru, Mexico, Argentina and Bolivia.   Pan American Silver Corp.   Pan American Silver Corp.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/pan-american-silver-corp-logo.png</main_image>
</document>
