<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com//rss/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PEI) Upgraded by Zacks Investment Research to Buy</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084333/pennsylvania-real-estate-investment-trust-pei-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (NYSE:PEI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report released on Tuesday. They currently have $27.00 price target on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “PENNSYLVANIA R.E. INVEST. TR. is a real estate investment trust, engaged in acquiring and holding for investment interests in real estate. “ 
In other news, EVP Andrew M. Ioannou sold 10,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, June 9th. The stock was sold at an average price of $22.27, for a total transaction of $222,700.00. Following the completion of the sale, the executive vice president now owns 46,156 shares in the company, valued at approximately $1,027,894.12. The sale was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is accessible through the SEC website . Also, CEO Joseph F. Coradino sold 33,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, June 9th. The shares were sold at an average price of $22.29, for a total value of $735,570.00. Following the sale, the chief executive officer now owns 324,056 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately $7,223,208.24. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other hedge funds have modified their holdings of the company. American Century Companies Inc. acquired a new stake in shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at approximately $6,737,000. Louisiana State Employees Retirement System raised its stake in shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust by 0.3% in the second quarter. Louisiana State Employees Retirement System now owns 30,800 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $661,000 after buying an additional 100 shares in the last quarter. Fox Run Management L.L.C. purchased a new position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at about $461,000. Foundry Partners LLC purchased a new position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at about $10,338,000. Finally, Capstone Asset Management Co. increased its position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust by 1.8% in the second quarter. Capstone Asset Management Co. now owns 20,345 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $436,000 after buying an additional 360 shares during the last quarter. 
Separately, Stifel Nicolaus upgraded Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust from a hold rating to a buy rating and set a $27.00 price target for the company in a report on Wednesday, April 20th. One analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating and four have given a buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock currently has a consensus rating of Buy and an average target price of $25.50. 
Shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust ( NYSE:PEI ) opened at 23.28 on Tuesday. The company’s market cap is $1.62 billion. Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust has a one year low of $16.42 and a one year high of $25.67. The company has a 50 day moving average price of $23.68 and a 200 day moving average price of $21.78. 
Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (NYSE:PEI) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.43 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.41 by $0.02. The firm earned $94.30 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $68.46 million. During the same quarter in the previous year, the firm posted $0.39 EPS. The firm’s revenue for the quarter was down 7.3% on a year-over-year basis. Equities analysts predict that Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust will post $1.85 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently announced a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Shareholders of record on Thursday, September 1st will be issued a dividend of $0.21 per share. The ex-dividend date is Tuesday, August 30th. This represents a $0.84 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 3.61%. 
Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PREIT) is an integrated, self-managed and self-administered real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company has a primary investment focus on retail shopping malls located in the eastern half of the United States. It is engaged in the ownership, management, leasing, acquisition, redevelopment, development and disposition of shopping malls. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PEI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust   Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084333/pennsylvania-real-estate-investment-trust-pei-upgraded-by-zacks-investment-research-to-buy/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0736</post_time>
<username>Stephan Byrd</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (NYSE:PEI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report released on Tuesday. They currently have $27.00 price target on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “PENNSYLVANIA R.E. INVEST. TR. is a real estate investment trust, engaged in acquiring and holding for investment interests in real estate. “ 
In other news, EVP Andrew M. Ioannou sold 10,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, June 9th. The stock was sold at an average price of $22.27, for a total transaction of $222,700.00. Following the completion of the sale, the executive vice president now owns 46,156 shares in the company, valued at approximately $1,027,894.12. The sale was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is accessible through the SEC website . Also, CEO Joseph F. Coradino sold 33,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, June 9th. The shares were sold at an average price of $22.29, for a total value of $735,570.00. Following the sale, the chief executive officer now owns 324,056 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately $7,223,208.24. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other hedge funds have modified their holdings of the company. American Century Companies Inc. acquired a new stake in shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at approximately $6,737,000. Louisiana State Employees Retirement System raised its stake in shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust by 0.3% in the second quarter. Louisiana State Employees Retirement System now owns 30,800 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $661,000 after buying an additional 100 shares in the last quarter. Fox Run Management L.L.C. purchased a new position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at about $461,000. Foundry Partners LLC purchased a new position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust during the second quarter valued at about $10,338,000. Finally, Capstone Asset Management Co. increased its position in Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust by 1.8% in the second quarter. Capstone Asset Management Co. now owns 20,345 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $436,000 after buying an additional 360 shares during the last quarter. 
Separately, Stifel Nicolaus upgraded Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust from a hold rating to a buy rating and set a $27.00 price target for the company in a report on Wednesday, April 20th. One analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating and four have given a buy rating to the company’s stock. The stock currently has a consensus rating of Buy and an average target price of $25.50. 
Shares of Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust ( NYSE:PEI ) opened at 23.28 on Tuesday. The company’s market cap is $1.62 billion. Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust has a one year low of $16.42 and a one year high of $25.67. The company has a 50 day moving average price of $23.68 and a 200 day moving average price of $21.78. 
Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (NYSE:PEI) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.43 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.41 by $0.02. The firm earned $94.30 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $68.46 million. During the same quarter in the previous year, the firm posted $0.39 EPS. The firm’s revenue for the quarter was down 7.3% on a year-over-year basis. Equities analysts predict that Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust will post $1.85 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently announced a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Shareholders of record on Thursday, September 1st will be issued a dividend of $0.21 per share. The ex-dividend date is Tuesday, August 30th. This represents a $0.84 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 3.61%. 
Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PREIT) is an integrated, self-managed and self-administered real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company has a primary investment focus on retail shopping malls located in the eastern half of the United States. It is engaged in the ownership, management, leasing, acquisition, redevelopment, development and disposition of shopping malls. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PEI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust   Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/pennsylvania-real-estate-investment-trust-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
