<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Zacks Investment Research Downgrades Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (ZYNE) to Hold</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-downgrades-zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-zyne-to-hold-2/1212652/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research lowered shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (NASDAQ:ZYNE) from a buy rating to a hold rating in a research note released on Tuesday morning. 
According to Zacks, “Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is a specialty pharmaceutical company which focuses on developing and commercializing proprietary synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. Its product candidates which are in clinical trial stage include ZYN002 and ZYN001 synthetic transdermal cannabinoid therapeutics for indications including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome, osteoarthritis, fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is headquartered in Devon, Pennsylvania. “ 
In other Zynerba Pharmaceuticals news, insider Suzanne M. Hanlon sold 3,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of $10.53, for a total value of $31,590.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the insider now owns 39,893 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately $420,073.29. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is available through this link . 
Other institutional investors recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. State Street Corp boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 1.5% in the first quarter. State Street Corp now owns 37,629 shares of the company’s stock worth $356,000 after buying an additional 562 shares in the last quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 33.2% in the first quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC now owns 475,035 shares of the company’s stock worth $4,489,000 after buying an additional 118,435 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Emerald Advisers Inc. PA boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 5.6% in the second quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA now owns 176,514 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,209,000 after buying an additional 9,329 shares in the last quarter. 
Several other brokerages have also recently commented on ZYNE. Canaccord Genuity set a $35.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals and gave the company a buy rating in a research note on Tuesday, August 16th. Piper Jaffray Cos. reaffirmed an overweight rating and set a $42.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Friday, August 12th. Finally, Oppenheimer Holdings Inc. reaffirmed a buy rating on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Tuesday, May 3rd. One research analyst has rated the stock with a hold rating and five have assigned a buy rating to the company. The company currently has a consensus rating of Buy and a consensus price target of $28.58. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals ( NASDAQ:ZYNE ) opened at 9.87 on Tuesday. The company’s market cap is $90.79 million. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $8.48 and its 200 day moving average is $8.27. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals has a 1-year low of $4.64 and a 1-year high of $33.06. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (NASDAQ:ZYNE) last issued its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported ($0.70) EPS for the quarter, missing the consensus estimate of ($0.53) by $0.18. Equities analysts anticipate that Zynerba Pharmaceuticals will post ($2.54) earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc is a specialty pharmaceutical company focused on developing and commercializing synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. The Company is evaluating approximately two product candidates, ZYN002 and ZYN001, in over five indications, including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome (FXS), osteoarthritis (OA), fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (ZYNE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-downgrades-zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-zyne-to-hold-2/1212652/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0755</post_time>
<username>Hasmir Abdula</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research lowered shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc. (NASDAQ:ZYNE) from a buy rating to a hold rating in a research note released on Tuesday morning. 
According to Zacks, “Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is a specialty pharmaceutical company which focuses on developing and commercializing proprietary synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. Its product candidates which are in clinical trial stage include ZYN002 and ZYN001 synthetic transdermal cannabinoid therapeutics for indications including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome, osteoarthritis, fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc. is headquartered in Devon, Pennsylvania. “ 
In other Zynerba Pharmaceuticals news, insider Suzanne M. Hanlon sold 3,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of $10.53, for a total value of $31,590.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the insider now owns 39,893 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately $420,073.29. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is available through this link . 
Other institutional investors recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. State Street Corp boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 1.5% in the first quarter. State Street Corp now owns 37,629 shares of the company’s stock worth $356,000 after buying an additional 562 shares in the last quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 33.2% in the first quarter. Cormorant Asset Management LLC now owns 475,035 shares of the company’s stock worth $4,489,000 after buying an additional 118,435 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Emerald Advisers Inc. PA boosted its position in Zynerba Pharmaceuticals by 5.6% in the second quarter. Emerald Advisers Inc. PA now owns 176,514 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,209,000 after buying an additional 9,329 shares in the last quarter. 
Several other brokerages have also recently commented on ZYNE. Canaccord Genuity set a $35.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals and gave the company a buy rating in a research note on Tuesday, August 16th. Piper Jaffray Cos. reaffirmed an overweight rating and set a $42.00 price objective on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Friday, August 12th. Finally, Oppenheimer Holdings Inc. reaffirmed a buy rating on shares of Zynerba Pharmaceuticals in a research note on Tuesday, May 3rd. One research analyst has rated the stock with a hold rating and five have assigned a buy rating to the company. The company currently has a consensus rating of Buy and a consensus price target of $28.58. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals ( NASDAQ:ZYNE ) opened at 9.87 on Tuesday. The company’s market cap is $90.79 million. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $8.48 and its 200 day moving average is $8.27. Zynerba Pharmaceuticals has a 1-year low of $4.64 and a 1-year high of $33.06. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (NASDAQ:ZYNE) last issued its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, August 11th. The company reported ($0.70) EPS for the quarter, missing the consensus estimate of ($0.53) by $0.18. Equities analysts anticipate that Zynerba Pharmaceuticals will post ($2.54) earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Zynerba Pharmaceuticals, Inc is a specialty pharmaceutical company focused on developing and commercializing synthetic cannabinoid therapeutics formulated for transdermal delivery. The Company is evaluating approximately two product candidates, ZYN002 and ZYN001, in over five indications, including refractory epilepsy, Fragile X syndrome (FXS), osteoarthritis (OA), fibromyalgia and peripheral neuropathic pain. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Zynerba Pharmaceuticals (ZYNE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.   Zynerba Pharmaceuticals Inc.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/zynerba-pharmaceuticals-inc-logo.png</main_image>
</document>
