<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://www.yahoo.com/news/best-rio-olympics-2016-closing-222218218.html?nhp=1</forum>
<forum_title>Best of Rio Olympics 2016 Closing Ceremony</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Tokyo&apos;s Super Mario surprise was Rio Closing Ceremony’s wildest moment</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.yahoo.com/news/tokyos-super-mario-surprise-was-rio-closing-ceremonys-wildest-moment-photos-013106549.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Medal count | Olympic schedule | Olympic news RIO DE JANEIRO — As the Olympic torch was officially passed at the Rio Olympics Closing Ceremony on Sunday, it was time for Tokyo to make an impression for the 2020 Summer Games.
That impression? Well, if dressing up Japan’s prime minister as Super Mario and having him pop out of a giant sewer pipe in the middle of the Rio Closing Ceremony is any indication, we’re in for a show in four years.
As the Tokyo 2020 presentation started, a video was shown of Shinzo Abe, Japan’s prime minister. He was passed a red ball, symbolizing the Japanese flag, from an athlete. His job? Rush the ball to the Rio Opening Ceremony.
[Related: Shirtless Tongan flag bearer is back, and still shirtless, at Olympic Closing Ceremony ]
But oh no, he’s running late! Whatever shall he do to get to Rio in time for the presentation?
And then he transformed into Super Mario in the back of his town car.
View photos
OBS More And he ran into a pipe in Tokyo, and he warped all the way to Rio, where HE POPPED OUT OF THE PIPE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE CLOSING CEREMONY. Complete with proper sound effects.
View photos
Japan&apos;s Prime Minister Shinzo Abe waves during the closing ceremony for the Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Sunday, Aug. 21, 2016. Tokyo will host the next Summer Games in 2020. (AP Photo/Vincent Thian) More View photos
GettyImages-593259614 More And he ripped off his Mario outfit to reveal that it was, indeed, the prime minster.
Alas, we didn’t get to see an elected official stomp on any turtles. But there’s always the opening ceremony in four years.
Tokyo 2020 … you have us officially intrigued.
More Summer Olympics coverage on Yahoo Sports:
—
Greg Wyshynski is a writer for Yahoo Sports. Contact him at puckdaddyblog@yahoo.com or find him on Twitter. His book, TAKE YOUR EYE OFF THE PUCK, is available on Amazon and wherever books are sold.
Listen to Yahoo Sports’ Greg Wyshynski podcast from Rio on GRANDSTANDING, featuring a Ryan Lochte Controversy Edition with Pat Forde of Yahoo Sports and Bruce Arthur of the Toronto Star!
Live from Rio: Ryan Lochte, international fugitive; the strange side of the Games:
Grandstanding: A Yahoo Sports podcast
Subscribe via iTunes or via RSS feed
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>9</post_num>
<post_id>post-9</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.yahoo.com/news/tokyos-super-mario-surprise-was-rio-closing-ceremonys-wildest-moment-photos-013106549.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Dan</username>
<post>
Glad the Rio disaster Olympics are over. Good riddance. On to much better country
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://s.yimg.com/uu/api/res/1.2/CAz5lKxiEFEZHOzbsIBWtg--/aD01NTg7dz03NDQ7c209MTthcHBpZD15dGFjaHlvbg--/http://media.zenfs.com/en/homerun/feed_manager_auto_publish_494/b35ada37265c6ce4b5bf9cced7f20a5f</main_image>
</document>
