<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Free Malaysia Today</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Council: People of religion should teach, not punish</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2016/08/22/council-people-of-religion-should-teach-not-punish/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Sheith Khidhir Bin Abu Bakar | August 22, 2016 Throwing Namewee in jail not the best way to deal with such problems, says Malaysian Consultative Council of Buddhism, Christianity, Hinduism, Sikhism and Taoism Honorary Secretary-General Prematilaka KD Serisena. 
PETALING JAYA: A non-Muslim religious council has pointed out that people need a platform to vent their frustrations and that the best way to deal with them is to hear them out. 
Speaking to FMT, Malaysian Consultative Council of Buddhism, Christianity, Hinduism, Sikhism and Taoism (MCCBCHST) Honorary Secretary-General Prematilaka KD Serisena said only through engaging the people could there be a “dynamic democracy” in the country. 
“Where do people channel their frustrations when anything they say, that goes against the status quo, is labelled as seditious? People need to be heard.” 
He was commenting on controversial rapper Namewee’s four-day remand from today over his “Oh My God” music video. 
Namewee, whose real name is Wee Meng Chee, 33, was arrested at the Kuala Lumpur International Airport yesterday after returning from an overseas trip. 
While admitting that he had not watched the video, Prematilaka said sending the rapper to jail was not the right move. 
“Throwing him in jail is not the right move and it’s not going to help. He’s going to become even worse. 
“People of religion need to engage and teach those who need to vent their frustrations. 
“As the government is not willing to listen and it expects people to comply, there has to be serious reforms.” 
Prematilaka claimed that he had recently spoken to a classmate of the infamous criminal Wong Swee Chin, better known as Botak Chin. 
“This classmate told me that Wong used to be among the top five in his class back in school. He took up a life of crime after he was refused a bank loan and on being told that Chinese could not get loans.” 
Prematilaka added that the way ministers in the country acted only served to heighten frustration among the people. 
He cited Rural and Regional Development Minister Ismail Sabri Yaakob’s call for a “Malay” Low Yat, now known as Mara Digital Mall, or Low Yat 2. 
“Ministers feel that they are God’s gift to the earth. Sorry to burst their bubble, but they’re not. They need to be responsible in the way they use words and be respectful of the people who elected them in the first place.”
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2016/08/22/council-people-of-religion-should-teach-not-punish/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0755</post_time>
<username>Sheith Khidhir Bin Abu Bakar</username>
<post>
Sheith Khidhir Bin Abu Bakar | August 22, 2016 Throwing Namewee in jail not the best way to deal with such problems, says Malaysian Consultative Council of Buddhism, Christianity, Hinduism, Sikhism and Taoism Honorary Secretary-General Prematilaka KD Serisena. 
PETALING JAYA: A non-Muslim religious council has pointed out that people need a platform to vent their frustrations and that the best way to deal with them is to hear them out. 
Speaking to FMT, Malaysian Consultative Council of Buddhism, Christianity, Hinduism, Sikhism and Taoism (MCCBCHST) Honorary Secretary-General Prematilaka KD Serisena said only through engaging the people could there be a “dynamic democracy” in the country. 
“Where do people channel their frustrations when anything they say, that goes against the status quo, is labelled as seditious? People need to be heard.” 
He was commenting on controversial rapper Namewee’s four-day remand from today over his “Oh My God” music video. 
Namewee, whose real name is Wee Meng Chee, 33, was arrested at the Kuala Lumpur International Airport yesterday after returning from an overseas trip. 
While admitting that he had not watched the video, Prematilaka said sending the rapper to jail was not the right move. 
“Throwing him in jail is not the right move and it’s not going to help. He’s going to become even worse. 
“People of religion need to engage and teach those who need to vent their frustrations. 
“As the government is not willing to listen and it expects people to comply, there has to be serious reforms.” 
Prematilaka claimed that he had recently spoken to a classmate of the infamous criminal Wong Swee Chin, better known as Botak Chin. 
“This classmate told me that Wong used to be among the top five in his class back in school. He took up a life of crime after he was refused a bank loan and on being told that Chinese could not get loans.” 
Prematilaka added that the way ministers in the country acted only served to heighten frustration among the people. 
He cited Rural and Regional Development Minister Ismail Sabri Yaakob’s call for a “Malay” Low Yat, now known as Mara Digital Mall, or Low Yat 2. 
“Ministers feel that they are God’s gift to the earth. Sorry to burst their bubble, but they’re not. They need to be responsible in the way they use words and be respectful of the people who elected them in the first place.”
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://s3media.freemalaysiatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/MCCBCHST-namewee-2.jpg</main_image>
</document>
