<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://taste.co.za/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Woolworths TASTE</forum_title>
<discussion_title>5 steps to eating mindfully</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://taste.co.za/5-steps-eating-mindfully/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
5 steps to eating mindfully 
Posted by TASTE on 22 August 2016 Share this story 
In this day and age, most of us are already thinking about what we eat. Now, take it to another level and start focusing on how you’re eating and you’ll soon feel the positive effects. 
The aim of mindful eating is to reconnect us more deeply with our food, resulting in a positive effect on your health. In other words, it has less to do with following The Latest Diet, but rather, a greater awareness of what – and why – you’re eating what you’re eating. Follow these five easy ways to get started tonight. 1. Cook from scratch 
Commit to cooking from scratch two or three times a week using easy recipes and flavour-packed ingredients. Grow a few herbs and veg that you can harvest yourself. 
If you don’t know where something comes from, ask yourself: Who grew this? How did it get here? You might even find your shopping habits change. 2. Eat at a table 
Start thinking of meal-times a positive ritual and a family tradition – rather than obligatory refuelling. Share a few dinners a week at the table and you could inspire a lifetime of healthy eating habits. 3. Switch off your devices 
Eat in silence. Sure, you might not be able to do this for a whole meal but do take a few minutes to appreciate what’s on your plate. Not possible because your children can’t sit still? Make a game of it: “Let’s see if we can all eat without talking for one whole minute.” 
If you’re too busy during the day to eat lunch anywhere other than your desk, take your morning coffee to a quiet place. 4. Eat slowly 
Savour every mouthful! This isn’t easy when you’re eating breakfast standing up – so sit down and slow down. Woolworths dietician Cindy Chin advocates practising counting your chews and swallowing slowly. “Put down your fork between bites instead of loading it with the next mouthful.” 5. Pay attention to flavour, texture and colour 
The tanginess of lemon, the spicy aroma of curry, the crunch of a crispy pizza crust… tuning in to your senses encourages you to take in less since you’re better able to read your body’s hunger and satiety cues. 
Did you know? Discovery Vitality members automatically get 25% off their HealthyFood baskets. Read more about HealthyFood baskets now. 
Read more about Today With Woolies here Article by: TASTE 
The TASTE team is a happy bunch of keen cooks and writers, always on the look out for the next food trend or the next piece of cake. Social Media
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://taste.co.za/5-steps-eating-mindfully/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0746</post_time>
<username>TASTE</username>
<post>
5 steps to eating mindfully 
Posted by TASTE on 22 August 2016 Share this story 
In this day and age, most of us are already thinking about what we eat. Now, take it to another level and start focusing on how you’re eating and you’ll soon feel the positive effects. 
The aim of mindful eating is to reconnect us more deeply with our food, resulting in a positive effect on your health. In other words, it has less to do with following The Latest Diet, but rather, a greater awareness of what – and why – you’re eating what you’re eating. Follow these five easy ways to get started tonight. 1. Cook from scratch 
Commit to cooking from scratch two or three times a week using easy recipes and flavour-packed ingredients. Grow a few herbs and veg that you can harvest yourself. 
If you don’t know where something comes from, ask yourself: Who grew this? How did it get here? You might even find your shopping habits change. 2. Eat at a table 
Start thinking of meal-times a positive ritual and a family tradition – rather than obligatory refuelling. Share a few dinners a week at the table and you could inspire a lifetime of healthy eating habits. 3. Switch off your devices 
Eat in silence. Sure, you might not be able to do this for a whole meal but do take a few minutes to appreciate what’s on your plate. Not possible because your children can’t sit still? Make a game of it: “Let’s see if we can all eat without talking for one whole minute.” 
If you’re too busy during the day to eat lunch anywhere other than your desk, take your morning coffee to a quiet place. 4. Eat slowly 
Savour every mouthful! This isn’t easy when you’re eating breakfast standing up – so sit down and slow down. Woolworths dietician Cindy Chin advocates practising counting your chews and swallowing slowly. “Put down your fork between bites instead of loading it with the next mouthful.” 5. Pay attention to flavour, texture and colour 
The tanginess of lemon, the spicy aroma of curry, the crunch of a crispy pizza crust… tuning in to your senses encourages you to take in less since you’re better able to read your body’s hunger and satiety cues. 
Did you know? Discovery Vitality members automatically get 25% off their HealthyFood baskets. Read more about HealthyFood baskets now. 
Read more about Today With Woolies here Article by: TASTE 
The TASTE team is a happy bunch of keen cooks and writers, always on the look out for the next food trend or the next piece of cake. Social Media
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://taste.co.za/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/feast-with-friends.png</main_image>
</document>
