<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.capemessenger.co.za/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Cape Messenger</forum_title>
<discussion_title>JHB set for DA mayor</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.capemessenger.co.za/2016/08/22/jhb-set-da-mayor/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
JHB set for DA mayor   
It appears that the Democratic Alliance and the Economic Freedom Fighters have come to an agreement in Johannesburg. Shortly DA mayoral candidate Herman Mashaba is expected to be elected mayor of Johannesburg 
22 August 2016 – The scene is set for the Democratic Alliance mayoral candidate in Johannesburg Herman Mashaba to receive the chain of office. 
While the EFF leader Julius Malema expressed concerns about Mashaba after the 3 August elections, it now appears that the two parties – the DA and EFF – have agreed to work together to remove the ANC administration in the city. The vote is expected to take place within the next hour. 
Although the ANC won the most votes in the city, it was not an overall majority. The opposition parties collectively polled an overall majority together. Herman Mashaba 
Interviewed by eNCA prior to his expected election this morning – Monday morning – he said he expected to put together a professional public service in Johannesburg. 
Asked if he was confident of being elected, Mashaba – speaking in the Johannesburg council chamber – said the EFF and the DA had agreed on forming “this coalition… so that we get the ANC out… so we form a government”. 
He said people of Zandspruit and Soweto, who had been ignored by the ANC government, would be looked after in future. 
“The voters have spoken… they need a new administration,” Mashaba said. 
Be the first to comment on &quot;JHB set for DA mayor&quot; Leave a comment You must be logged in to post a comment. Follow Cape Messenger Monday, August 15, 2016 
Dearest Editor 
Independent Media rejects with contempt the blatant lies contained in a recent article written by discredited former employee, Donwald Pressly (Cape Times set for purge, Cape Messenger, 12/08/16) and fanned by several other disgruntled former contributors of Independent Media. 
For the record, we can categorically state that the Cape Tuesday, August 9, 2016 
Dear Editor Now that we know that there will most likely need to be coalitions at scores of municipalities around the country, including in Johannesburg, Nelson Mandela Bay and even Rustenburg, we will also know that government is likely to be unstable at municipal level in future. Perhaps the leading parties will be allowed to Friday, July 15, 2016 
Dear Editor With Theresa May’s appointment as Britain’s second woman prime minister there were naturally going to be comparisons with the first, but that is where it ended. Margaret Thatcher was a “conflict” politician who knew where she was going, told you so, and dismissed you if you didn’t follow her. Her style was appropriate in Wednesday, July 6, 2016 
Dear Sir, Madam I see your report that the Eskom bosses have given themselves lovely “performance” bonuses in the last financial year of some R18 million. This is at a time when South Africans are paying above-inflation prices for electricity year after year. Eskom is strangling the economy. It is as simple as that. We need Thursday, May 26, 2016 
Dear Editors My sincere thanks for your Cape Messenger emails which I really appreciate. Included in your latest publication is an article regarding Raymond Ackerman being the “founder” of Pick ‘n Pay. I was for many years the property director of the Clicks Group which was founded by Jack Goldin. It may be of interest Latest Tweets
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.capemessenger.co.za/2016/08/22/jhb-set-da-mayor/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0748</post_time>
<username>CM_Publisher</username>
<post>
JHB set for DA mayor   
It appears that the Democratic Alliance and the Economic Freedom Fighters have come to an agreement in Johannesburg. Shortly DA mayoral candidate Herman Mashaba is expected to be elected mayor of Johannesburg 
22 August 2016 – The scene is set for the Democratic Alliance mayoral candidate in Johannesburg Herman Mashaba to receive the chain of office. 
While the EFF leader Julius Malema expressed concerns about Mashaba after the 3 August elections, it now appears that the two parties – the DA and EFF – have agreed to work together to remove the ANC administration in the city. The vote is expected to take place within the next hour. 
Although the ANC won the most votes in the city, it was not an overall majority. The opposition parties collectively polled an overall majority together. Herman Mashaba 
Interviewed by eNCA prior to his expected election this morning – Monday morning – he said he expected to put together a professional public service in Johannesburg. 
Asked if he was confident of being elected, Mashaba – speaking in the Johannesburg council chamber – said the EFF and the DA had agreed on forming “this coalition… so that we get the ANC out… so we form a government”. 
He said people of Zandspruit and Soweto, who had been ignored by the ANC government, would be looked after in future. 
“The voters have spoken… they need a new administration,” Mashaba said. 
Be the first to comment on &quot;JHB set for DA mayor&quot; Leave a comment You must be logged in to post a comment. Follow Cape Messenger Monday, August 15, 2016 
Dearest Editor 
Independent Media rejects with contempt the blatant lies contained in a recent article written by discredited former employee, Donwald Pressly (Cape Times set for purge, Cape Messenger, 12/08/16) and fanned by several other disgruntled former contributors of Independent Media. 
For the record, we can categorically state that the Cape Tuesday, August 9, 2016 
Dear Editor Now that we know that there will most likely need to be coalitions at scores of municipalities around the country, including in Johannesburg, Nelson Mandela Bay and even Rustenburg, we will also know that government is likely to be unstable at municipal level in future. Perhaps the leading parties will be allowed to Friday, July 15, 2016 
Dear Editor With Theresa May’s appointment as Britain’s second woman prime minister there were naturally going to be comparisons with the first, but that is where it ended. Margaret Thatcher was a “conflict” politician who knew where she was going, told you so, and dismissed you if you didn’t follow her. Her style was appropriate in Wednesday, July 6, 2016 
Dear Sir, Madam I see your report that the Eskom bosses have given themselves lovely “performance” bonuses in the last financial year of some R18 million. This is at a time when South Africans are paying above-inflation prices for electricity year after year. Eskom is strangling the economy. It is as simple as that. We need Thursday, May 26, 2016 
Dear Editors My sincere thanks for your Cape Messenger emails which I really appreciate. Included in your latest publication is an article regarding Raymond Ackerman being the “founder” of Pick ‘n Pay. I was for many years the property director of the Clicks Group which was founded by Jack Goldin. It may be of interest Latest Tweets
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://www.sabc.co.za/wps/wcm/connect/3f312c80442889a98251f6e2e61545ac/herman-mashaba.jpg?MOD=AJPERES&amp;#038;CACHEID=3f312c80442889a98251f6e2e61545ac</main_image>
</document>
