<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Rifz Textiles Inc. Introduces Five Star Kapaas Black Label for Three Star Pricing</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13609327.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Rifz Textiles Inc. Introduces Five Star Kapaas Black Label for Three Star Pricing Share Article Rifz Textiles, one of the nation’s leading fastest growing manufacturer and distributor of quality linen for the hospitality and cruise line industry releases its incredible new Black Label Line. Rochester, New York (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Rifz Textiles, one of the nation’s leading &amp; fastest growing manufacturer and distributor of quality linen for the hospitality and cruise line industry releases its incredible new Black Label Line. Imagine high end plush terry products that are luxuriously soft and lasts 2 to 3 times longer than other common products. The product design teams at Rifz have created just that. “We wanted to create the best value for our hospitality customers but have now found our institutional customers are also keen on the value this product represents. This product was designed with to provide maximum quality to cost ration and that’s exactly what we have done”, says Saad Khan, Vice President of the company. Rifz Textiles has been distributing and manufacturing institutional linens to the hospitality, cruise lines, healthcare, and food service industries providing quality, value and service to a vast array of customers throughout the world. Rifz is a direct to market distributor/manufacture. Buy direct and truly save on products that offer quality, comfort, and value from our lines of bath towels and terry products, 100% cotton and cotton-rich bed linen, new certified bed bug proof encasement&apos;s that provide true six sided iron protection for your mattress and improved mattress pads, luxury pillows, and superb damask table linen, napkins, aprons, chef supplies and coats. These and many other linen products you use on a daily basis are readily available to ship from all our facilities. Rifz offers the very best value ratio for your linen purchasing dollar. Call us to speak with one of our representatives. Be sure to request our new Hospitality or Health Care catalogs. Visit http://www.rifz.com for additional information. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.05</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13609327.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Rifz Textiles Inc. Introduces Five Star Kapaas Black Label for Three Star Pricing Share Article Rifz Textiles, one of the nation’s leading fastest growing manufacturer and distributor of quality linen for the hospitality and cruise line industry releases its incredible new Black Label Line. Rochester, New York (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Rifz Textiles, one of the nation’s leading &amp; fastest growing manufacturer and distributor of quality linen for the hospitality and cruise line industry releases its incredible new Black Label Line. Imagine high end plush terry products that are luxuriously soft and lasts 2 to 3 times longer than other common products. The product design teams at Rifz have created just that. “We wanted to create the best value for our hospitality customers but have now found our institutional customers are also keen on the value this product represents. This product was designed with to provide maximum quality to cost ration and that’s exactly what we have done”, says Saad Khan, Vice President of the company. Rifz Textiles has been distributing and manufacturing institutional linens to the hospitality, cruise lines, healthcare, and food service industries providing quality, value and service to a vast array of customers throughout the world. Rifz is a direct to market distributor/manufacture. Buy direct and truly save on products that offer quality, comfort, and value from our lines of bath towels and terry products, 100% cotton and cotton-rich bed linen, new certified bed bug proof encasement&apos;s that provide true six sided iron protection for your mattress and improved mattress pads, luxury pillows, and superb damask table linen, napkins, aprons, chef supplies and coats. These and many other linen products you use on a daily basis are readily available to ship from all our facilities. Rifz offers the very best value ratio for your linen purchasing dollar. Call us to speak with one of our representatives. Be sure to request our new Hospitality or Health Care catalogs. Visit http://www.rifz.com for additional information. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
