<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://feeds.feedblitz.com/lansing/news</forum>
<forum_title>Lansing - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Michigan ag full of tasty variety</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.lansingstatejournal.com/story/news/local/2016/08/21/michigan-ag-full-tasty-variety/87711856/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Michigan ag full of tasty variety Beth LeBlanc , Lansing State Journal 8:01 a.m. EDT August 21, 2016 Buy Photo Sue McMaster, of Mac Farms, sets up her stand on Wednesday, Aug. 3, 2016 at the Meridian Township Farmers Market in Okemos. (Photo: Julia Nagy/Lansing State Journal) Buy Photo 
With cherry-stained hands and a ready smile, Sue McMaster fielded questions from behind crates of brightly colored produce. 
“I think it’s the ‘in’ thing to do now — talking to the farmer and seeing where your food comes from,” McMaster said. “People are asking ‘What do you put on your vegetables? Where do you grow this?’” 
On a Saturday morning at the Meridian Township Farmers Market, the Mac’s Market stand boasted melons, tomatoes, cucumbers, shallots, lettuce, beans, beets and candy onions from McMaster’s Laingsburg farm. 
The stand also featured produce from a little further afield — cherries from northwest Michigan, peaches from Coopersville, strawberries from Dewitt, and sweet corn from St. Johns. 
The produce stand was a microcosm of Michigan’s diverse agriculture. 
Michigan has bragging rights to about 300 different agricultural commodities and is second only to California for its agricultural diversity, said Jeremy Nagel, a spokesman for Michigan Farm Bureau. 
“Agriculture is one of the biggest economic drivers in the state,” Nagel said. “And it’s fascinating because it is so diverse.” 
While many people know where to buy their food, not many realize just how much of it comes from Michigan and where in the state it comes from, Nagel said. 
“It is a massively diverse agricultural state,” Nagel said. 
Tree fruit like peaches, pears, plums and cherries are largely concentrated along the west coast of the Mitten. The west coast, from the Mackinac Bridge to the Indiana border, also is ideal for just about any vegetable you can think of, he said. Buy Photo 
An assortment of Eight and One Ball squash on Wednesday, Aug. 3, 2016 at the Meridian Township Farmers Market in Okemos. (Photo: Julia Nagy/Lansing State Journal) 
Pockets of potatoes, apples and sweet corn are located throughout the state. 
Michigan is the number two producer of dry or edible beans — the rows of black, navy, kidney, red, pinto and cranberry beans are largely concentrated in the Saginaw Valley and the Thumb, as are sugar beets. 
Further inland are Michigan’s field crops — rows upon rows of corn, soybean, winter wheat and hay. 
Some of those products will make it to your pantry in packages labeled Star of the West, Pioneer Sugar, Big Chief Sugar and Jiffy Mix. 
But much of the fields’ yield, especially the hay and soybeans, is used to feed the state&apos;s livestock. 
“It’s very non-descript, very overlooked, but it’s very essential to livestock,” Nagel said. 
And Michigan’s livestock is no small population to feed. 
Michigan’s growing dairy industry is one of the 10 best for sales in the United States. The state also has strong beef cattle, swine, poultry, and sheep industries. 
The state’s forestry, horticulture, and greenhouse industries are often overlooked. 
And as consumer taste evolves and changes so do the farmers that feed those customers, Nagel said. As organic food, craft beer and niche foods rise in popularity the market follows, with hops fields, organic farms and unique produce. 
“We grow pretty much every vegetable that’s in a seed catalogue, from asparagus to zucchini,” said Anthony Cinzori, who owns Cinzori Family Farms with his father. 
The Ceresco farm boasts 70 acres of certified organic vegetables, many of which were on display just a hop and a skip from Mac’s Market at the Saturday farmers market. 
Among the vegetables, were purple beans with bright green innards — called red swan beans — and summer squash shaped like an asterisk — called star-shaped patty pans. 
“We always pick out some new stuff to grow especially with the farmers market crowd,” Cinzori said. “You can pretty much grow any vegetable in Michigan.” 
Contact Beth LeBlanc at (517) 377-1167, , or on Twitter @LSJBethLeBlanc. 17 CONNECT COMMENT EMAIL MORE Read or Share this story: http://on.lsj.com/2bLTv27 TOP VIDEOS
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.lansingstatejournal.com/story/news/local/2016/08/21/michigan-ag-full-tasty-variety/87711856/</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1201</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Michigan ag full of tasty variety Beth LeBlanc , Lansing State Journal 8:01 a.m. EDT August 21, 2016 Buy Photo Sue McMaster, of Mac Farms, sets up her stand on Wednesday, Aug. 3, 2016 at the Meridian Township Farmers Market in Okemos. (Photo: Julia Nagy/Lansing State Journal) Buy Photo 
With cherry-stained hands and a ready smile, Sue McMaster fielded questions from behind crates of brightly colored produce. 
“I think it’s the ‘in’ thing to do now — talking to the farmer and seeing where your food comes from,” McMaster said. “People are asking ‘What do you put on your vegetables? Where do you grow this?’” 
On a Saturday morning at the Meridian Township Farmers Market, the Mac’s Market stand boasted melons, tomatoes, cucumbers, shallots, lettuce, beans, beets and candy onions from McMaster’s Laingsburg farm. 
The stand also featured produce from a little further afield — cherries from northwest Michigan, peaches from Coopersville, strawberries from Dewitt, and sweet corn from St. Johns. 
The produce stand was a microcosm of Michigan’s diverse agriculture. 
Michigan has bragging rights to about 300 different agricultural commodities and is second only to California for its agricultural diversity, said Jeremy Nagel, a spokesman for Michigan Farm Bureau. 
“Agriculture is one of the biggest economic drivers in the state,” Nagel said. “And it’s fascinating because it is so diverse.” 
While many people know where to buy their food, not many realize just how much of it comes from Michigan and where in the state it comes from, Nagel said. 
“It is a massively diverse agricultural state,” Nagel said. 
Tree fruit like peaches, pears, plums and cherries are largely concentrated along the west coast of the Mitten. The west coast, from the Mackinac Bridge to the Indiana border, also is ideal for just about any vegetable you can think of, he said. Buy Photo 
An assortment of Eight and One Ball squash on Wednesday, Aug. 3, 2016 at the Meridian Township Farmers Market in Okemos. (Photo: Julia Nagy/Lansing State Journal) 
Pockets of potatoes, apples and sweet corn are located throughout the state. 
Michigan is the number two producer of dry or edible beans — the rows of black, navy, kidney, red, pinto and cranberry beans are largely concentrated in the Saginaw Valley and the Thumb, as are sugar beets. 
Further inland are Michigan’s field crops — rows upon rows of corn, soybean, winter wheat and hay. 
Some of those products will make it to your pantry in packages labeled Star of the West, Pioneer Sugar, Big Chief Sugar and Jiffy Mix. 
But much of the fields’ yield, especially the hay and soybeans, is used to feed the state&apos;s livestock. 
“It’s very non-descript, very overlooked, but it’s very essential to livestock,” Nagel said. 
And Michigan’s livestock is no small population to feed. 
Michigan’s growing dairy industry is one of the 10 best for sales in the United States. The state also has strong beef cattle, swine, poultry, and sheep industries. 
The state’s forestry, horticulture, and greenhouse industries are often overlooked. 
And as consumer taste evolves and changes so do the farmers that feed those customers, Nagel said. As organic food, craft beer and niche foods rise in popularity the market follows, with hops fields, organic farms and unique produce. 
“We grow pretty much every vegetable that’s in a seed catalogue, from asparagus to zucchini,” said Anthony Cinzori, who owns Cinzori Family Farms with his father. 
The Ceresco farm boasts 70 acres of certified organic vegetables, many of which were on display just a hop and a skip from Mac’s Market at the Saturday farmers market. 
Among the vegetables, were purple beans with bright green innards — called red swan beans — and summer squash shaped like an asterisk — called star-shaped patty pans. 
“We always pick out some new stuff to grow especially with the farmers market crowd,” Cinzori said. “You can pretty much grow any vegetable in Michigan.” 
Contact Beth LeBlanc at (517) 377-1167, , or on Twitter @LSJBethLeBlanc. 17 CONNECT COMMENT EMAIL MORE Read or Share this story: http://on.lsj.com/2bLTv27 TOP VIDEOS
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/9dc3000962e60a6c46a13cdc0dcf014c58588f09/c=0-123-2400-1479&amp;amp;r=x633&amp;amp;c=1200x630/local/-/media/2016/08/03/MIGroup/Lansing/636058337553940554-market3.JPG</main_image>
</document>
