<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.ghanaweb.com/feed/newsfeed.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Ghana News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mahama takes campaign to home region</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.ghanaweb.com/GhanaHomePage/NewsArchive/Mahama-takes-campaign-to-home-region-464194</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Print This President John Dramani Mahama Flagbearer of the National Democratic Congress (NDC), President John Dramani Mahama, will continue his campaign for re-election with a four-day campaign tour to his home region, the Northern Region. This will mark the second regional stop on President Mahama’s campaign tour after the completion of a four-day tour of the Western Region. The President’s campaign team has indicated that this leg of his tour is expected to focus on interactions with with the people on the ground. The NDC flagbearer’s campaign in the Northern Region will start in Salaga where he will pay a courtesy call on the newly enskinned Kpembewura. President Mahama will also call on other chiefs in the region and engage with various sections of society on his scheduled campaign route. The campaign team has noted that the areas to be visited on this tourinclude Salaga, Kpandai, Bimbilla, Wulensi, Yendi, Gushiegu, Zabzugu, Tatale, Mion, Nanton and Chereponi. In what could have been viewed as a prologue to his tour of the region, President Mahama was in the Northern Regional capital, Tamale, on Friday, August 22 to see off the first batch of Muslim pilgrims airlifted directly from Tamale to Medina in Saudi Arabia for the Hajj. His presence in the region also saw the government showcase some development projects with the inauguration of completed works of the first phase of the Tamale airport expansion and upgrade project. President Mahama said the decision to establish the Tamale airport was aimed at extending opportunities to the North for growth and development. ‘Dimiiya’ protests to greet Mahama’s first day President Mahama’s first day in the Northern region may be overshadowed by protests as the coalition of opposition parties in the region has vowed to resist any attempt by the Northern Regional police command to ask the organizers to postpone the much publicised demonstration in Tamale Township. The police administration argued that President Mahama’s campaign tour was starting on the same day, hence calls on the coalition to reschedule the date. The demonstration dubbed, “Dimiiya” meaning “Times are tough” is aimed at renewing calls on government to reduce what they have described as ‘Killer’ electricity tariffs.” Hairdressers, tailors, barbers, welders and other small scale industry players have announced their participation. Ahead of the demonstration, the coalition’s Spokesperson, Mohammed Abdul Kudus served notice that no amount of force or persuasion will convince the organizers to postpone the demonstration. Related Articles:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.ghanaweb.com/GhanaHomePage/NewsArchive/Mahama-takes-campaign-to-home-region-464194</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0637</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Print This President John Dramani Mahama Flagbearer of the National Democratic Congress (NDC), President John Dramani Mahama, will continue his campaign for re-election with a four-day campaign tour to his home region, the Northern Region. This will mark the second regional stop on President Mahama’s campaign tour after the completion of a four-day tour of the Western Region. The President’s campaign team has indicated that this leg of his tour is expected to focus on interactions with with the people on the ground. The NDC flagbearer’s campaign in the Northern Region will start in Salaga where he will pay a courtesy call on the newly enskinned Kpembewura. President Mahama will also call on other chiefs in the region and engage with various sections of society on his scheduled campaign route. The campaign team has noted that the areas to be visited on this tourinclude Salaga, Kpandai, Bimbilla, Wulensi, Yendi, Gushiegu, Zabzugu, Tatale, Mion, Nanton and Chereponi. In what could have been viewed as a prologue to his tour of the region, President Mahama was in the Northern Regional capital, Tamale, on Friday, August 22 to see off the first batch of Muslim pilgrims airlifted directly from Tamale to Medina in Saudi Arabia for the Hajj. His presence in the region also saw the government showcase some development projects with the inauguration of completed works of the first phase of the Tamale airport expansion and upgrade project. President Mahama said the decision to establish the Tamale airport was aimed at extending opportunities to the North for growth and development. ‘Dimiiya’ protests to greet Mahama’s first day President Mahama’s first day in the Northern region may be overshadowed by protests as the coalition of opposition parties in the region has vowed to resist any attempt by the Northern Regional police command to ask the organizers to postpone the much publicised demonstration in Tamale Township. The police administration argued that President Mahama’s campaign tour was starting on the same day, hence calls on the coalition to reschedule the date. The demonstration dubbed, “Dimiiya” meaning “Times are tough” is aimed at renewing calls on government to reduce what they have described as ‘Killer’ electricity tariffs.” Hairdressers, tailors, barbers, welders and other small scale industry players have announced their participation. Ahead of the demonstration, the coalition’s Spokesperson, Mohammed Abdul Kudus served notice that no amount of force or persuasion will convince the organizers to postpone the demonstration. Related Articles:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://cdn.ghanaweb.com/imagelib/pics/24732473.jpg</main_image>
</document>
