<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>AYA™ Medical Spa Hosts their Semi-Annual Open House Event at its Avalon Location in Alpharetta</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/alpharetta-botox-cosmetic/med-spa-open-house/prweb13627572.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
AYA™ Medical Spa Hosts their Semi-Annual Open House Event at its Avalon Location in Alpharetta Share Article AYA™ Medical Spa will host an Open House celebration at their newly-opened location for the latest offerings in facial rejuvenation and skincare treatments. These events are a great opportunity for our loyal customers to become better acquainted with our team and the treatments and products we’re offering. Atlanta, Georgia (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 AYA™ Medical Spa will be hosting their semi-annual Open House event at their newest location at Avalon in Alpharetta. Owned and operated by four highly-skilled plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery, P.C., AYA™ Medical Spa has provided the latest medical grade rejuvenation treatments to the Atlanta area for nearly 15 years. AYA™ invites the public to celebrate at their Avalon Open House on Thursday, August 25th from 5pm to 8pm at their Alpharetta location: 2130 Avalon Blvd, Alpharetta, Georgia, 30009. Event attendees will enjoy 20% off all skincare products, in addition to exclusive skincare offers on injectables like Juvéderm® XC or Voluma™, CoolSculpting® nonsurgical fat reduction, Microdermabrasion, and more, as well as complimentary hors d’oeuvres and refreshments provided by Bite, free gifts for those who RSVP and additional chances to win excellent gifts and prizes. Board-certified plastic and reconstructive surgeon Dr. James Namnoum, one of AYA™ Medical Spa’s licensed providers, will be available for complimentary consultations for plastic surgery (by appointment only). Named “Best Medical Spa of Atlanta” for three years by JEZEBEL Magazine, AYA™ provides the latest skincare technology systems and a large variety of minimally-invasive treatments for patients of all ages and skin types. The experienced providers of AYA™ Medical Spa perform laser skin resurfacing and hair removal, CoolSculpting® nonsurgical fat reduction, Botox® and facial filler injectables , dermaplaning, a wide array of chemical peels and more to serve patients trying to restore a youthful, vigorous appearance. “We couldn’t be more excited to be hosting the first Open House at our new location in Avalon,” says Jessica Chaney, Spa Director. “These events are a great opportunity for our loyal customers to become better acquainted with our team and the treatments and products we’re offering. We love building these connections and are look forward to building lasting relationships with the Avalon community as a whole.” AYA™ Avalon Open House attendees don’t have to RSVP for this FREE event, but appointments are required for skincare analysis, cosmetic injectables and plastic surgery consultations. 20% skincare product promotion is available by phone up until day of the event. To RSVP and book an appointment with Dr. Namnoum, cosmetic injectors or licensed providers today, contact AYA™ Avalon at (678) 534-5035 or email avalon(at)ayamedspa(dot)com. About AYA™ Medical Spa AYA™ Medical Spa is an Atlanta-based medical spa, owned and operated by four of the highly skilled plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery, P.C., specializing in medical-grade skin rejuvenation treatments for the face and body. For nearly 15 years now, AYA™ has been offering FDA-approved skincare technology treatments and minimally invasive anti-aging treatments in a relaxing spa atmosphere performed by certified and experienced physician’s assistants, estheticians, nurses, and medical assistants and overseen by the plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery at the Avalon, Phipps Plaza, and Northside locations. Striving to stay up-to-date with the latest skincare treatments and technologies to enhance patient safety and rejuvenation results, AYA™ offers a varietal menu to help patients maintain healthy, radiant skin including: cosmetic injectables, Sciton® laser skin resurfacing, Ultherapy® skin tightening, chemical peels and facials, CoolSculpting® non-surgical fat reduction, skincare products, and more. AYA™ is now accepting new patients and always provides complimentary skin analysis consultations. Avalon and Phipps Plaza AYA™ locations are open 7 days a week. AYA™ Avalon is now accepting evening appointments as late as 8pm by appointment only. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/alpharetta-botox-cosmetic/med-spa-open-house/prweb13627572.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160504</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
AYA™ Medical Spa Hosts their Semi-Annual Open House Event at its Avalon Location in Alpharetta Share Article AYA™ Medical Spa will host an Open House celebration at their newly-opened location for the latest offerings in facial rejuvenation and skincare treatments. These events are a great opportunity for our loyal customers to become better acquainted with our team and the treatments and products we’re offering. Atlanta, Georgia (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 AYA™ Medical Spa will be hosting their semi-annual Open House event at their newest location at Avalon in Alpharetta. Owned and operated by four highly-skilled plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery, P.C., AYA™ Medical Spa has provided the latest medical grade rejuvenation treatments to the Atlanta area for nearly 15 years. AYA™ invites the public to celebrate at their Avalon Open House on Thursday, August 25th from 5pm to 8pm at their Alpharetta location: 2130 Avalon Blvd, Alpharetta, Georgia, 30009. Event attendees will enjoy 20% off all skincare products, in addition to exclusive skincare offers on injectables like Juvéderm® XC or Voluma™, CoolSculpting® nonsurgical fat reduction, Microdermabrasion, and more, as well as complimentary hors d’oeuvres and refreshments provided by Bite, free gifts for those who RSVP and additional chances to win excellent gifts and prizes. Board-certified plastic and reconstructive surgeon Dr. James Namnoum, one of AYA™ Medical Spa’s licensed providers, will be available for complimentary consultations for plastic surgery (by appointment only). Named “Best Medical Spa of Atlanta” for three years by JEZEBEL Magazine, AYA™ provides the latest skincare technology systems and a large variety of minimally-invasive treatments for patients of all ages and skin types. The experienced providers of AYA™ Medical Spa perform laser skin resurfacing and hair removal, CoolSculpting® nonsurgical fat reduction, Botox® and facial filler injectables , dermaplaning, a wide array of chemical peels and more to serve patients trying to restore a youthful, vigorous appearance. “We couldn’t be more excited to be hosting the first Open House at our new location in Avalon,” says Jessica Chaney, Spa Director. “These events are a great opportunity for our loyal customers to become better acquainted with our team and the treatments and products we’re offering. We love building these connections and are look forward to building lasting relationships with the Avalon community as a whole.” AYA™ Avalon Open House attendees don’t have to RSVP for this FREE event, but appointments are required for skincare analysis, cosmetic injectables and plastic surgery consultations. 20% skincare product promotion is available by phone up until day of the event. To RSVP and book an appointment with Dr. Namnoum, cosmetic injectors or licensed providers today, contact AYA™ Avalon at (678) 534-5035 or email avalon(at)ayamedspa(dot)com. About AYA™ Medical Spa AYA™ Medical Spa is an Atlanta-based medical spa, owned and operated by four of the highly skilled plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery, P.C., specializing in medical-grade skin rejuvenation treatments for the face and body. For nearly 15 years now, AYA™ has been offering FDA-approved skincare technology treatments and minimally invasive anti-aging treatments in a relaxing spa atmosphere performed by certified and experienced physician’s assistants, estheticians, nurses, and medical assistants and overseen by the plastic surgeons of Atlanta Plastic Surgery at the Avalon, Phipps Plaza, and Northside locations. Striving to stay up-to-date with the latest skincare treatments and technologies to enhance patient safety and rejuvenation results, AYA™ offers a varietal menu to help patients maintain healthy, radiant skin including: cosmetic injectables, Sciton® laser skin resurfacing, Ultherapy® skin tightening, chemical peels and facials, CoolSculpting® non-surgical fat reduction, skincare products, and more. AYA™ is now accepting new patients and always provides complimentary skin analysis consultations. Avalon and Phipps Plaza AYA™ locations are open 7 days a week. AYA™ Avalon is now accepting evening appointments as late as 8pm by appointment only. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/05/04/13627572/ms-icon-310x310.png</main_image>
</document>
