<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.marketpulse.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>MarketPulse</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Rising Yields Melt Silver in Asia</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.marketpulse.com/20160822/736813/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Rising Yields Melt Silver in Asia Posted 5 minutes ago Share Print 0 
Fridays bond sell-off sends commodities and precious metals lower in Asia. What global bond yields ahead of Jackson Hole. 
Monday mornings at 6 am Singapore can be an emotional time for traders. The fact that many of us are at work then aside! Monday 6 am is a magical witching hour when electronic trading starts the week on products such as the S&amp;P, Oil, US Bonds and Precious Metals. Significantly it is also the time that Tokyo (7 am Tokyo) Brokers switch on their margin servers. As a result price action can be “robust” to say the least as the market reacts to weekend news or to price movements in FX from late New York or early Asia. (2 AM Singapore for those poor FX dealers) 
If the market gaps or prices move significantly this can trigger a sudden rush of margin stop outs by either the US Futures Exchanges or Japanese Margin Brokers in a particularly illiquid time of the week. The resulting price action can create a perfect storm type atmosphere where illiquidity, large moves combine to exacerbate even more moves and more stops etc in a very unvirtuous perfect circle.A prime example being the 20% USD/ZAR move in 30 minutes in January. 
This appears to be what has happened in a few markets this morning. Most notably Silver where the semi-precious metal opened and immediately sold off nearly 3 % in as long as it took me to type this sentence. 
A picture tells a 1000 words…. 
We have since made a small recovery. 
News wise we didn’t have a lot out over the weekend apart from some Kuroda comments. 
Kuroda Says ‘Sufficient Chance’ for More Easing in Sept.: Sankei 
This was certainly enough to see USD/JPY gap higher on the Spot FX open to 100.90. Yellen’s Jackson Hole speech will be written about ad nauseam this week but for me the most significant driver were, Very extended and stale XAG positioning. The global bond sell-off (higher yields) we saw to finish the week. 
XAG/USD longs have consistently been our most extended long positions amongst any of the precious metals and FX crosses for the last few months. Indeed after this mornings washout, it remains the most popular long amongst our clients’ percentage wise. 



This isn’t actually a huge change from Friday much to my surprise and tells me that we still have a lot of long positioning out there. The daily chart makes for gruesome viewing as well with a sea of red on the candles for the last two trading sessions. Bond markets need to be closely watched today for signs of a continuing sell-off. Combined with the factors above this could see more downside pressure on Silver. 
Support comes in at 18.8000 the 100-day moving average, then 18.7150 days low and then 18.5000 the bottom of the Ichi moko cloud. 
Resistance is at 19.30 days open and the New York low. 

Commodities 
Similar set ups in Silver seem to be at play in commodities today. ie extended positioning and higher rates. Certainly, Oil didn’t enjoy the 6 am open either. 
Brent 
and WTI…. 
Interestingly both “oils” bounced from their lows suggesting the OPEC nirvana of productions cuts they’ll actually stick to contains the downside for now. 
Copper 
Two Year US T-Notes are back to pre Brexit levels 
As are US 10 Year Bonds 
Even Bunds were sold! 
Conclusion 
Part of the bond sell-off story is definitely attributable to the street looking for some Fed Funds fire and brimstone from Ms Yellen this Friday in Jackson Hole. Another part may be the increasing perception that Central Bank monetary policy globally may be reaching its final stages of marginal utility as I have touched on before. But perhaps the lesson to be learned here is that nothing goes up forever and how acutely sensitive commodities, stocks and precious metals are to any sign of rising yields globally. 
As I have said above watch global bonds this week. I am in no way calling the top of the global bond market but they are most certainly nsetting the short term agenda for everything else it seems ahead of Friday. Jeffrey Halley Based in Singapore, Jeffrey has over 25 years experience in the financial markets, having traded currencies, options, precious metals and futures. Jeffrey started his career at Barclays Bank in New Zealand. However he has spent most of it in London and Asia.Jeffrey focuses on the Asia time zone across asset classes. A regular commentator on business news TV and Radio, he is originally from New Zealand and holds an MBA from Cass Business School, London. Latest posts by Jeffrey Halley ( see all ) Site map 
MarketPulse is a forex, commodities, and global indices analysis, and forex news site providing timely and accurate information on major economic trends, technical analysis, and worldwide events that impact different asset classes and investors. 
This article is for general information purposes only. It is not investment advice or a solution to buy or sell securities. 
Opinions are the authors — not necessarily OANDA’s, its officers or directors. OANDA’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy apply. Leveraged trading is high risk and not suitable for all. Losses can exceed investments. 
© 1996 - 2016 OANDA Corporation. All rights reserved. All Registered Trade Marks used on this Website, whether marked as Trade Marks or not marked, are declared to belong to their respective owner(s). OANDA Corporation owns Trade Marks of all its &quot;FX&quot; products. 
370 King Street West 2nd Floor , Box 60 Toronto , ON M5V 1J9 Canada | 1-877-626-3239 | 
OANDA Corporation is a registered Futures Commission Merchant and Retail Foreign Exchange Dealer with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and is a member of the National Futures Association . No: 0325821. Please refer to the NFA&apos;s FOREX INVESTOR ALERT where appropriate. 
OANDA (Canada) Corporation ULC accounts are available to anyone with a Canadian bank account. OANDA (Canada) Corporation ULC is regulated by the Investment Industry Regulatory Organization of Canada (IIROC) and customer accounts are protected by the Canadian Investor Protection Fund within specified limits. A brochure describing the nature and limits of coverage is available upon request or at www.cipf.ca . 
OANDA Europe Limited is a company registered in England number 7110087 limited by shares with its registered office at Tower 42, Floor 9a, 25 Old Broad St, London EC2N 1HQ and is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority , No: 542574. 
OANDA Asia Pacific Pte Ltd (Co. Reg. No 200704926K) holds a Capital Markets Services Licence issued by the Monetary Authority of Singapore and is also licenced by the International Enterprise Singapore. 
OANDA Australia Pty Ltd is regulated by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission ASIC (ABN 26 152 088 349, AFSL No. 412981) and provides and is the issuer of the products and/or services on this website. It&apos;s important for you to consider the current Financial Service Guide (FSG) , Product Disclosure Statement (&apos;PDS&apos;) , Account Terms and any other relevant OANDA documents before making any financial investment decisions. These documents can be found here . 
OANDA Japan Co., Ltd. First Type I Financial Instruments Business Director of the Kanto Local Financial Bureau (Kin-sho) No. 2137 Institute Financial Futures Association subscriber number 1571.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.marketpulse.com/20160822/736813/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0756</post_time>
<username>Jeffrey Halley</username>
<post>
Rising Yields Melt Silver in Asia Posted 5 minutes ago Share Print 0 
Fridays bond sell-off sends commodities and precious metals lower in Asia. What global bond yields ahead of Jackson Hole. 
Monday mornings at 6 am Singapore can be an emotional time for traders. The fact that many of us are at work then aside! Monday 6 am is a magical witching hour when electronic trading starts the week on products such as the S&amp;P, Oil, US Bonds and Precious Metals. Significantly it is also the time that Tokyo (7 am Tokyo) Brokers switch on their margin servers. As a result price action can be “robust” to say the least as the market reacts to weekend news or to price movements in FX from late New York or early Asia. (2 AM Singapore for those poor FX dealers) 
If the market gaps or prices move significantly this can trigger a sudden rush of margin stop outs by either the US Futures Exchanges or Japanese Margin Brokers in a particularly illiquid time of the week. The resulting price action can create a perfect storm type atmosphere where illiquidity, large moves combine to exacerbate even more moves and more stops etc in a very unvirtuous perfect circle.A prime example being the 20% USD/ZAR move in 30 minutes in January. 
This appears to be what has happened in a few markets this morning. Most notably Silver where the semi-precious metal opened and immediately sold off nearly 3 % in as long as it took me to type this sentence. 
A picture tells a 1000 words…. 
We have since made a small recovery. 
News wise we didn’t have a lot out over the weekend apart from some Kuroda comments. 
Kuroda Says ‘Sufficient Chance’ for More Easing in Sept.: Sankei 
This was certainly enough to see USD/JPY gap higher on the Spot FX open to 100.90. Yellen’s Jackson Hole speech will be written about ad nauseam this week but for me the most significant driver were, Very extended and stale XAG positioning. The global bond sell-off (higher yields) we saw to finish the week. 
XAG/USD longs have consistently been our most extended long positions amongst any of the precious metals and FX crosses for the last few months. Indeed after this mornings washout, it remains the most popular long amongst our clients’ percentage wise. 



This isn’t actually a huge change from Friday much to my surprise and tells me that we still have a lot of long positioning out there. The daily chart makes for gruesome viewing as well with a sea of red on the candles for the last two trading sessions. Bond markets need to be closely watched today for signs of a continuing sell-off. Combined with the factors above this could see more downside pressure on Silver. 
Support comes in at 18.8000 the 100-day moving average, then 18.7150 days low and then 18.5000 the bottom of the Ichi moko cloud. 
Resistance is at 19.30 days open and the New York low. 

Commodities 
Similar set ups in Silver seem to be at play in commodities today. ie extended positioning and higher rates. Certainly, Oil didn’t enjoy the 6 am open either. 
Brent 
and WTI…. 
Interestingly both “oils” bounced from their lows suggesting the OPEC nirvana of productions cuts they’ll actually stick to contains the downside for now. 
Copper 
Two Year US T-Notes are back to pre Brexit levels 
As are US 10 Year Bonds 
Even Bunds were sold! 
Conclusion 
Part of the bond sell-off story is definitely attributable to the street looking for some Fed Funds fire and brimstone from Ms Yellen this Friday in Jackson Hole. Another part may be the increasing perception that Central Bank monetary policy globally may be reaching its final stages of marginal utility as I have touched on before. But perhaps the lesson to be learned here is that nothing goes up forever and how acutely sensitive commodities, stocks and precious metals are to any sign of rising yields globally. 
As I have said above watch global bonds this week. I am in no way calling the top of the global bond market but they are most certainly nsetting the short term agenda for everything else it seems ahead of Friday. Jeffrey Halley Based in Singapore, Jeffrey has over 25 years experience in the financial markets, having traded currencies, options, precious metals and futures. Jeffrey started his career at Barclays Bank in New Zealand. However he has spent most of it in London and Asia.Jeffrey focuses on the Asia time zone across asset classes. A regular commentator on business news TV and Radio, he is originally from New Zealand and holds an MBA from Cass Business School, London. Latest posts by Jeffrey Halley ( see all ) Site map 
MarketPulse is a forex, commodities, and global indices analysis, and forex news site providing timely and accurate information on major economic trends, technical analysis, and worldwide events that impact different asset classes and investors. 
This article is for general information purposes only. It is not investment advice or a solution to buy or sell securities. 
Opinions are the authors — not necessarily OANDA’s, its officers or directors. OANDA’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy apply. Leveraged trading is high risk and not suitable for all. Losses can exceed investments. 
© 1996 - 2016 OANDA Corporation. All rights reserved. All Registered Trade Marks used on this Website, whether marked as Trade Marks or not marked, are declared to belong to their respective owner(s). OANDA Corporation owns Trade Marks of all its &quot;FX&quot; products. 
370 King Street West 2nd Floor , Box 60 Toronto , ON M5V 1J9 Canada | 1-877-626-3239 | 
OANDA Corporation is a registered Futures Commission Merchant and Retail Foreign Exchange Dealer with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and is a member of the National Futures Association . No: 0325821. Please refer to the NFA&apos;s FOREX INVESTOR ALERT where appropriate. 
OANDA (Canada) Corporation ULC accounts are available to anyone with a Canadian bank account. OANDA (Canada) Corporation ULC is regulated by the Investment Industry Regulatory Organization of Canada (IIROC) and customer accounts are protected by the Canadian Investor Protection Fund within specified limits. A brochure describing the nature and limits of coverage is available upon request or at www.cipf.ca . 
OANDA Europe Limited is a company registered in England number 7110087 limited by shares with its registered office at Tower 42, Floor 9a, 25 Old Broad St, London EC2N 1HQ and is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority , No: 542574. 
OANDA Asia Pacific Pte Ltd (Co. Reg. No 200704926K) holds a Capital Markets Services Licence issued by the Monetary Authority of Singapore and is also licenced by the International Enterprise Singapore. 
OANDA Australia Pty Ltd is regulated by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission ASIC (ABN 26 152 088 349, AFSL No. 412981) and provides and is the issuer of the products and/or services on this website. It&apos;s important for you to consider the current Financial Service Guide (FSG) , Product Disclosure Statement (&apos;PDS&apos;) , Account Terms and any other relevant OANDA documents before making any financial investment decisions. These documents can be found here . 
OANDA Japan Co., Ltd. First Type I Financial Instruments Business Director of the Kanto Local Financial Bureau (Kin-sho) No. 2137 Institute Financial Futures Association subscriber number 1571.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.marketpulse.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/commodities-.jpg</main_image>
</document>
