<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.sagmart.com/news_rss</forum>
<forum_title>SAG Mart News - General, Entertainment, Mobile, Fashion, Health</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Tata Zest Sports Edition Launched to Celebrate The Two Years of Success</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.sagmart.com/news/Automobiles/tata-zest-sports-edition-launched-to-celebrate-the-two-years-of-success</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tata Zest Sports Edition Launched to Celebrate The Two Years of Success 22nd, Aug 2016 12:45 PM View: 54 (1 rate) 
Tata Motors has launched the Tata Zest Sports Edition model on the occasion of the 2nd anniversary of the car. After two years of success, Tata has 50,000 units of the compact sedan, Zest running on the Indian roads and further enhancing its role in the competition, Tata has introduced this special edition with the beneficiary schemes. 
In the sports edition, there is not a very much to do with the car, however, the attractive offers and benefits will surely lure the buyers. The sports edition accessories can be added to any of the Zest models from the dealer-level at an additional cost. 
What does the Sports Edition add: This anniversary edition updates only limited to the exteriors of the car, while on the other aspects the car remains unchanged. The Zest Sports Edition features a tri-colour (red, grey and black) body decals, red coloured front bumper, contrast coloured outside mirrors, side sill extensions, rain visors and alloy wheels. 
The tempting offers with the car include a special EMI scheme (Easy Monthly Installment) of INR 3,999, free car insurance worth of INR 33,000, an exchange bonus of INR 30,000 and additional benefits of upto INR 68,000. 
Considering the features of the car, the top end trim houses projector headlamps, foglights, Harman touchscreen infotainment system with a navigation system, ABS, dual airbags for front occupants, automatic climate control, electrically operable exterior mirrors etc. 
In terms of tech-specs, the Zest is being offered in total 9 trims, Out of them four are fitted with petrol engines, while the rest five variants are equipped with diesel motors. The petrol variants are powered by a 1.2-litre Revotron engine which is tuned to produce 90 PS power of maximum power along with the 140 Nm of peak torque. On the other hand, the diesel powered variants get a 1.3 Litre Multijet engine beneath their front end, which is capable of producing the same 90 PS of maximum power and 200 Nm of peak torque. 
A 5-speed manual transmission comes as standard across all variants, however, the range topping diesel powered model comes paired with the 5-Speed Automated Manual Transmission (AMT). Get latest and updated information about automobiles on our Google Plus Community Speed Gears .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.sagmart.com/news/Automobiles/tata-zest-sports-edition-launched-to-celebrate-the-two-years-of-success</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0715</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Tata Zest Sports Edition Launched to Celebrate The Two Years of Success 22nd, Aug 2016 12:45 PM View: 54 (1 rate) 
Tata Motors has launched the Tata Zest Sports Edition model on the occasion of the 2nd anniversary of the car. After two years of success, Tata has 50,000 units of the compact sedan, Zest running on the Indian roads and further enhancing its role in the competition, Tata has introduced this special edition with the beneficiary schemes. 
In the sports edition, there is not a very much to do with the car, however, the attractive offers and benefits will surely lure the buyers. The sports edition accessories can be added to any of the Zest models from the dealer-level at an additional cost. 
What does the Sports Edition add: This anniversary edition updates only limited to the exteriors of the car, while on the other aspects the car remains unchanged. The Zest Sports Edition features a tri-colour (red, grey and black) body decals, red coloured front bumper, contrast coloured outside mirrors, side sill extensions, rain visors and alloy wheels. 
The tempting offers with the car include a special EMI scheme (Easy Monthly Installment) of INR 3,999, free car insurance worth of INR 33,000, an exchange bonus of INR 30,000 and additional benefits of upto INR 68,000. 
Considering the features of the car, the top end trim houses projector headlamps, foglights, Harman touchscreen infotainment system with a navigation system, ABS, dual airbags for front occupants, automatic climate control, electrically operable exterior mirrors etc. 
In terms of tech-specs, the Zest is being offered in total 9 trims, Out of them four are fitted with petrol engines, while the rest five variants are equipped with diesel motors. The petrol variants are powered by a 1.2-litre Revotron engine which is tuned to produce 90 PS power of maximum power along with the 140 Nm of peak torque. On the other hand, the diesel powered variants get a 1.3 Litre Multijet engine beneath their front end, which is capable of producing the same 90 PS of maximum power and 200 Nm of peak torque. 
A 5-speed manual transmission comes as standard across all variants, however, the range topping diesel powered model comes paired with the 5-Speed Automated Manual Transmission (AMT). Get latest and updated information about automobiles on our Google Plus Community Speed Gears .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://www.sagmart.com/uploads/2016/08/22/news_image1/Tata-Zest-Sportz-Edition.jpg</main_image>
</document>
