<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Regional SA businesses suffering without training hubs, skilled workers, Business SA survey reveals - ABC News (Australian Broadcasting Corporation)</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-08-22/regional-sa-businesses-suffering-without-training-hubs/7773922</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Map: Whyalla 5600 
A skills shortage in regional South Australia is holding back economic growth, a new study has found. 
Business SA surveyed 160 people in regional areas and the results highlight the challenges of doing business outside of Adelaide. 
It found nearly 40 per cent could not attract skilled employees and that jumped to 60 per cent in the state&apos;s north, which takes in Whyalla and Port Augusta. 
Both cities have faced job losses and uncertainty with the Port Augusta power station closing and a cloud over the future of the Whyalla steelworks . 
Kadina Chamber of Commerce&apos;s Lisa Robertson said more training in regional areas would improve people&apos;s skill levels. 
&quot;If we can just decentralise a little bit and have hubs of training you will make those communities richer for it,&quot; she said. 
&quot;I think like anyone, once you move somewhere else it&apos;s harder to come back.&quot; 
The study also found about one-third of businesses had to send workers to Adelaide for training, which was too expensive for them. 
About the same number thought award rates and conditions were challenging. Investment in skills needed, business lobby says 
Business SA chief executive Nigel McBride said many trainees were not staying in regional areas. 
&quot;We know for a fact that people will do a four- or five-year apprenticeship here and the day they finish their apprenticeship they&apos;re out of the region and that&apos;s costing the employer a great deal of investment,&quot; Mr McBride said. 
Regional chambers of commerce are for the first time teaming up to find solutions with business workshops to be held across the state. 
Amy Waters&apos; family has owned a butcher shop in Kadina for the past 30 years. 
She said it had always been a challenge to find skilled workers in the region. 
&quot;We&apos;ve tried getting them from the Northern Territory, they come down, they find it too hard,&quot; she said. 
Businesses in regional South Australia contribute about $25 billion to the state&apos;s economy every year. 
Industry leaders said that could grow, but only with more investment in training and infrastructure. 
&quot;The fact is, even if someone lost their job in the steelworks, they&apos;re not going to immediately go into aged care or health care,&quot; Mr McBride said. 
&quot;That&apos;s where the training comes and that&apos;s when we need to invest in skills.&quot; 
Some believe energising the regional economy was the key to improving the state&apos;s unemployment woes which continues to be the worst in that nation. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-08-22/regional-sa-businesses-suffering-without-training-hubs/7773922</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Nicola Gage</username>
<post>
Map: Whyalla 5600 
A skills shortage in regional South Australia is holding back economic growth, a new study has found. 
Business SA surveyed 160 people in regional areas and the results highlight the challenges of doing business outside of Adelaide. 
It found nearly 40 per cent could not attract skilled employees and that jumped to 60 per cent in the state&apos;s north, which takes in Whyalla and Port Augusta. 
Both cities have faced job losses and uncertainty with the Port Augusta power station closing and a cloud over the future of the Whyalla steelworks . 
Kadina Chamber of Commerce&apos;s Lisa Robertson said more training in regional areas would improve people&apos;s skill levels. 
&quot;If we can just decentralise a little bit and have hubs of training you will make those communities richer for it,&quot; she said. 
&quot;I think like anyone, once you move somewhere else it&apos;s harder to come back.&quot; 
The study also found about one-third of businesses had to send workers to Adelaide for training, which was too expensive for them. 
About the same number thought award rates and conditions were challenging. Investment in skills needed, business lobby says 
Business SA chief executive Nigel McBride said many trainees were not staying in regional areas. 
&quot;We know for a fact that people will do a four- or five-year apprenticeship here and the day they finish their apprenticeship they&apos;re out of the region and that&apos;s costing the employer a great deal of investment,&quot; Mr McBride said. 
Regional chambers of commerce are for the first time teaming up to find solutions with business workshops to be held across the state. 
Amy Waters&apos; family has owned a butcher shop in Kadina for the past 30 years. 
She said it had always been a challenge to find skilled workers in the region. 
&quot;We&apos;ve tried getting them from the Northern Territory, they come down, they find it too hard,&quot; she said. 
Businesses in regional South Australia contribute about $25 billion to the state&apos;s economy every year. 
Industry leaders said that could grow, but only with more investment in training and infrastructure. 
&quot;The fact is, even if someone lost their job in the steelworks, they&apos;re not going to immediately go into aged care or health care,&quot; Mr McBride said. 
&quot;That&apos;s where the training comes and that&apos;s when we need to invest in skills.&quot; 
Some believe energising the regional economy was the key to improving the state&apos;s unemployment woes which continues to be the worst in that nation. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>AU</country>
<main_image>http://www.abc.net.au/news/image/7377670-1x1-700x700.jpg</main_image>
</document>
