<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>World Uncertainty and the Value of Career Boosting Project Management Institute PMI-RMP Risk Management Certification</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13620490.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
World Uncertainty and the Value of Career Boosting Project Management Institute PMI-RMP Risk Management Certification Share Article With Brexit and the upcoming election in the United States, the demand for professionals who can manage high-stakes project investment risk is rising. PMO Advisory LLC, will be holding a 3-day Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP®) course, leading to certification, at their office in Northern New Jersey, October 10, 11, &amp; 12th, 2016. For project professionals looking to fill the risk management specialist role, hone their basic project management skills and showcase their specialized expertise to employers, the PMI-RMP credential is ideal. Cedar Grove, NJ (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 The highly regarded Project Management Institute (PMI) is perhaps best known for its Project Management Professional (PMP) credential but PMI also offers the PMI Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP) for governance, risk and compliance professionals. This certification recognizes individuals who have a combination of top-notch project management skills with the ability to identify and accurately assess project risk, and to also mitigate identified threats to organizations. For organizations investing heavily in high stakes and highly expensive investment projects, the need for professionals with the optimal credentials will become ever more important. For professionals managing large scale, complex, and high budget projects, the PMI-RMP certification is a significant differentiator, especially when there are over 720,000 PMPs. For project managers in smaller organizations, the concepts and practices advocated by this Risk Management Professional training, will scale to small businesses and projects as you apply the framework of risk management. Project Risk Management accounts for the unpredictable. It forces project professionals to acknowledge that things do not always go right and the need to have a plan in place for when projects start having snags. Developing the right plans also saves the project team from scrambling to figure out what to do when things go wrong; therefore having the right contingency planning is important. These risk management practices can bring large payoffs, but it is up to the project professionals to determine if the risks are acceptable. Can organizations take the potential financial hit that failure would cause? What happens if the project goes significantly over budget? Suppose a senior programmer is injured and cannot work? Are the projects able to stretch your deadlines or can you find a suitable stand-in quickly? The PMI-RMP certification demonstrates skill and competence in this specialized area of project risk management. For project professionals looking to fill the risk management specialist role, hone their basic project management skills and showcase their specialized expertise to employers, the PMI-RMP credential is ideal. All PMI certifications are mutually exclusive, which means that professionals do not need to hold a Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification to become PMI-RMP Certified . Ready to take your career to the next level? Join PMO Advisory on site at their 3 day training course in risk management on October 10-12 in their offices in Northern New Jersey. For those wishing to join the Live Instructor Led Virtual Classroom with participants from around the world, PMO Advisory is also offering this PMI-RMP training course in November of 2016. For Details visit them at http://www.pmoadvisory.com About PMO Advisory PMO Advisory is a socially minded management advisory and training firm with expertise in business and IT execution, serving as a resource to help enable ideas for organizations. PMO Advisory helps transform business ideas, plans, objectives and vision into reality using a proven, customizable consulting approach. The firm’s advisory team is expert in portfolio, program and project leadership, process improvement, and business transformation. As a training company, the firm is striving to be the most comprehensive project management training firm in the world offering certification training in Portfolio (PfMP®), Program (PgMP®), Project (PMP®, CAPM®), Risk (PMI-RMP®), Agile (PMI-ACP®, Scrum), and Project Management Office (PMO) training. PfMP, PgMP, PMP, CAPM, PMI-RMP, and PMI-ACP are registered marks of Project Management Institute Inc. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.01</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13620490.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20151028</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
World Uncertainty and the Value of Career Boosting Project Management Institute PMI-RMP Risk Management Certification Share Article With Brexit and the upcoming election in the United States, the demand for professionals who can manage high-stakes project investment risk is rising. PMO Advisory LLC, will be holding a 3-day Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP®) course, leading to certification, at their office in Northern New Jersey, October 10, 11, &amp; 12th, 2016. For project professionals looking to fill the risk management specialist role, hone their basic project management skills and showcase their specialized expertise to employers, the PMI-RMP credential is ideal. Cedar Grove, NJ (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 The highly regarded Project Management Institute (PMI) is perhaps best known for its Project Management Professional (PMP) credential but PMI also offers the PMI Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP) for governance, risk and compliance professionals. This certification recognizes individuals who have a combination of top-notch project management skills with the ability to identify and accurately assess project risk, and to also mitigate identified threats to organizations. For organizations investing heavily in high stakes and highly expensive investment projects, the need for professionals with the optimal credentials will become ever more important. For professionals managing large scale, complex, and high budget projects, the PMI-RMP certification is a significant differentiator, especially when there are over 720,000 PMPs. For project managers in smaller organizations, the concepts and practices advocated by this Risk Management Professional training, will scale to small businesses and projects as you apply the framework of risk management. Project Risk Management accounts for the unpredictable. It forces project professionals to acknowledge that things do not always go right and the need to have a plan in place for when projects start having snags. Developing the right plans also saves the project team from scrambling to figure out what to do when things go wrong; therefore having the right contingency planning is important. These risk management practices can bring large payoffs, but it is up to the project professionals to determine if the risks are acceptable. Can organizations take the potential financial hit that failure would cause? What happens if the project goes significantly over budget? Suppose a senior programmer is injured and cannot work? Are the projects able to stretch your deadlines or can you find a suitable stand-in quickly? The PMI-RMP certification demonstrates skill and competence in this specialized area of project risk management. For project professionals looking to fill the risk management specialist role, hone their basic project management skills and showcase their specialized expertise to employers, the PMI-RMP credential is ideal. All PMI certifications are mutually exclusive, which means that professionals do not need to hold a Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification to become PMI-RMP Certified . Ready to take your career to the next level? Join PMO Advisory on site at their 3 day training course in risk management on October 10-12 in their offices in Northern New Jersey. For those wishing to join the Live Instructor Led Virtual Classroom with participants from around the world, PMO Advisory is also offering this PMI-RMP training course in November of 2016. For Details visit them at http://www.pmoadvisory.com About PMO Advisory PMO Advisory is a socially minded management advisory and training firm with expertise in business and IT execution, serving as a resource to help enable ideas for organizations. PMO Advisory helps transform business ideas, plans, objectives and vision into reality using a proven, customizable consulting approach. The firm’s advisory team is expert in portfolio, program and project leadership, process improvement, and business transformation. As a training company, the firm is striving to be the most comprehensive project management training firm in the world offering certification training in Portfolio (PfMP®), Program (PgMP®), Project (PMP®, CAPM®), Risk (PMI-RMP®), Agile (PMI-ACP®, Scrum), and Project Management Office (PMO) training. PfMP, PgMP, PMP, CAPM, PMI-RMP, and PMI-ACP are registered marks of Project Management Institute Inc. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2015/10/28/13620490/PMOAdvisory_round.jpg</main_image>
</document>
