<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Out of Envy, Many Countries Want Nigeria to Disintegrate - NLC President</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220190.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 President of the Nigeria Labour Congress (NLC), Ayuba Wabba, on Sunday said &quot;most countries&quot; are unhappy that Nigeria is the Giant of Africa, and will therefore be happy to see the country disintegrate. He therefore urged Nigerians not to succumb to external forces working very hard to break up the country. Wabba, who made the appeal while fielding questions at a NAN forum, said that the country&apos;s size, population and natural endowments are assets that many other nations are envious of. He expressed optimism that the current security challenges and agitations &quot;being fuelled and funded by forces determined to undermine Nigeria&quot; would be surmounted. He said, &quot;Our position is that we will not canvass the issue of cannibalizing Nigeria into segments for any reason or any consideration&quot; &quot;It is in unity that our strength lies as a country. We are today the giant of Africa; most countries are not happy with that. They will do anything possible to undermine our national interest and also work towards the disintegration of Nigeria. &quot;That is a fact, and we see that as we travel around the world. Even within the committee of unions, people are envious of Nigeria. We must not forget how people said Nigeria was going to break by 2015 and you must not forget that they are still working on that. &quot;They are still funding all manner of things and trying to see that Nigeria does not actually have peace; it is deliberate. There is no resource today in the world that we do not have; they see us as a country that is blessed without measure.&quot; Wabba added that some African countries are concerned that if anything happens to Nigeria, their own fate becomes uncertain. &quot;Most of these conflicts are instigated,&quot; he said, citing the situation in Syria and other parts of the Middle East. &quot;Therefore, it is in our own collective interest as Nigerians -- because we do not have any other country -- to continue to show the light and perspective for others to see.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220190.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0748</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 President of the Nigeria Labour Congress (NLC), Ayuba Wabba, on Sunday said &quot;most countries&quot; are unhappy that Nigeria is the Giant of Africa, and will therefore be happy to see the country disintegrate. He therefore urged Nigerians not to succumb to external forces working very hard to break up the country. Wabba, who made the appeal while fielding questions at a NAN forum, said that the country&apos;s size, population and natural endowments are assets that many other nations are envious of. He expressed optimism that the current security challenges and agitations &quot;being fuelled and funded by forces determined to undermine Nigeria&quot; would be surmounted. He said, &quot;Our position is that we will not canvass the issue of cannibalizing Nigeria into segments for any reason or any consideration&quot; &quot;It is in unity that our strength lies as a country. We are today the giant of Africa; most countries are not happy with that. They will do anything possible to undermine our national interest and also work towards the disintegration of Nigeria. &quot;That is a fact, and we see that as we travel around the world. Even within the committee of unions, people are envious of Nigeria. We must not forget how people said Nigeria was going to break by 2015 and you must not forget that they are still working on that. &quot;They are still funding all manner of things and trying to see that Nigeria does not actually have peace; it is deliberate. There is no resource today in the world that we do not have; they see us as a country that is blessed without measure.&quot; Wabba added that some African countries are concerned that if anything happens to Nigeria, their own fate becomes uncertain. &quot;Most of these conflicts are instigated,&quot; he said, citing the situation in Syria and other parts of the Middle East. &quot;Therefore, it is in our own collective interest as Nigerians -- because we do not have any other country -- to continue to show the light and perspective for others to see.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
