<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rss.artipot.com/category/143</forum>
<forum_title>Artipot: Internet &gt; Search Engine Optimization Articles</forum_title>
<discussion_title>SEO: Why Specialists Are Talking About Rich Answers (Webpulse Solution Pvt Ltd)</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.artipot.com/articles/2023577/seo-why-specialists-are-talking-about-rich-answers.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
By Webpulse Solution Pvt Ltd Aug 22, 2016 How &quot;direct&quot; can Google get with its search? For instance, today, if you search with the query, &quot;When did India become Independent?&quot; Google will offer you a direct answer - 15th August, 1947. You are not really required going through elaborate articles or blog posts for this answer. This is what we call is a &quot;Rich Answer&quot; and the reason why we are discussing it here because they are well poised to emerge as a very important part of SEO in the near future. An efficient Local SEO Company will definitely care to conduct proper research on the same. What are rich answers?Rich answers are very simply described as Google&apos;s way of providing direct answers to users- irrespective of the type of query they&apos;re using. And, they are definitely on their way to gaining more significance in the coming days. Here is more about them.Now, rich answers are not really too favored by SEO marketers. We will tell you why. When Google attempts at providing direct answers to readers, they are less likely to click through articles where these answers are provided. For instance, what happens when you search with &quot;when does us open start 2016?&quot; Google directly answers you Aug 29 - Sep 11, 2016. As a result, if you&apos;re in a hurry you will not even visit the number 2 or 3 ranked site offering the entire schedule. So, traditional SEO is definitely losing some mileage there. Now these rich or direct answers were only a part of Mathematics like queries in the recent past- like answers to equations. Today, however, it is assuming a bigger shape in the SEO landscape. It has been reported that they enjoyed a 9 percent growth rate in the previous year and the promising trajectory will actually continue. Google is definitely paying close attention to this strategy. The future of rich answers is promising, to say the least - and its significance will be established at the cost of the slow relegation of traditional SEO - not totally into obscurity but definitely to a lesser significant zone. What should be your strategy?Don&apos;t worry! There are chances of making a mark with rich answers as well. How can you do that? We will tell you how! For instance, you must start with the creation of content from which Google can drive rich snippets of answers to queries. As Forbes.com points out, users can see a few sentences being pulled from an article in History.com when they are searching for something like &quot;how did the dinosaurs die.&quot; The answer in your content must be concise and relevant. The very heartening saving grace is that Google pulls its answers from other sources and presents them in the form of rich snippets (and that&apos;s what we call rich answers). Google does not make up answers on its own. A very effective method of improving your chances of being featured here - is to build a strong domain name. Link building campaigns can turn out to be effective here. A strong domain name will ensure Google is turning to you to draw its answers. About the Author Looking for affordable Local SEO Services in Delhi , then Webpulse is one stop destination for you. We are counted as Best SEO Company in Delhi for our result oriented local SEO promotion. Rating:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.artipot.com/articles/2023577/seo-why-specialists-are-talking-about-rich-answers.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0703</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
By Webpulse Solution Pvt Ltd Aug 22, 2016 How &quot;direct&quot; can Google get with its search? For instance, today, if you search with the query, &quot;When did India become Independent?&quot; Google will offer you a direct answer - 15th August, 1947. You are not really required going through elaborate articles or blog posts for this answer. This is what we call is a &quot;Rich Answer&quot; and the reason why we are discussing it here because they are well poised to emerge as a very important part of SEO in the near future. An efficient Local SEO Company will definitely care to conduct proper research on the same. What are rich answers?Rich answers are very simply described as Google&apos;s way of providing direct answers to users- irrespective of the type of query they&apos;re using. And, they are definitely on their way to gaining more significance in the coming days. Here is more about them.Now, rich answers are not really too favored by SEO marketers. We will tell you why. When Google attempts at providing direct answers to readers, they are less likely to click through articles where these answers are provided. For instance, what happens when you search with &quot;when does us open start 2016?&quot; Google directly answers you Aug 29 - Sep 11, 2016. As a result, if you&apos;re in a hurry you will not even visit the number 2 or 3 ranked site offering the entire schedule. So, traditional SEO is definitely losing some mileage there. Now these rich or direct answers were only a part of Mathematics like queries in the recent past- like answers to equations. Today, however, it is assuming a bigger shape in the SEO landscape. It has been reported that they enjoyed a 9 percent growth rate in the previous year and the promising trajectory will actually continue. Google is definitely paying close attention to this strategy. The future of rich answers is promising, to say the least - and its significance will be established at the cost of the slow relegation of traditional SEO - not totally into obscurity but definitely to a lesser significant zone. What should be your strategy?Don&apos;t worry! There are chances of making a mark with rich answers as well. How can you do that? We will tell you how! For instance, you must start with the creation of content from which Google can drive rich snippets of answers to queries. As Forbes.com points out, users can see a few sentences being pulled from an article in History.com when they are searching for something like &quot;how did the dinosaurs die.&quot; The answer in your content must be concise and relevant. The very heartening saving grace is that Google pulls its answers from other sources and presents them in the form of rich snippets (and that&apos;s what we call rich answers). Google does not make up answers on its own. A very effective method of improving your chances of being featured here - is to build a strong domain name. Link building campaigns can turn out to be effective here. A strong domain name will ensure Google is turning to you to draw its answers. About the Author Looking for affordable Local SEO Services in Delhi , then Webpulse is one stop destination for you. We are counted as Best SEO Company in Delhi for our result oriented local SEO promotion. Rating:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
