<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.wsj.com/public/page/news-food-cooking-drink.html</forum>
<forum_title>Food Drink News Chefs Reviews Tastings Eating Out Fine Dining - Wall Street Journal.com - Wsj.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Brazil Passes the Olympic Torch, Proud and Relieved</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/brazil-passes-the-olympic-torch-and-breathes-a-sigh-of-relief-1471832043</topic_url>
<topic_text>
8 COMMENTS RIO DE JANEIRO—If the Opening Ceremonies of the Rio Olympic Games offered an idealized glimpse of Brazil from afar, the Closing Ceremonies were more about Brazil looking inward at itself.
For the most part, Brazil liked what it saw at these Olympics. After two challenging weeks, capping two years of mainly bad news, the country on Sunday was ready, finally, to indulge in a little self-congratulation.
Even a driving rainstorm that kept some spectators from making the trip to Maracanã Stadium couldn’t extinguish the crowd’s enthusiasm for this soggy but stirring celebration.
Sunday’s ceremonies took a wide detour around the glamorous, jet-set Rio of Copacabana and Ipanema. The focus was on the rich but lesser-known culture of Rio’s less fashionable precincts; on creative giants like artist Tarsila do Amaral and landscape designer Roberto Burle Marx; and on the music, dance and irrepressible spirit of Brazil’s parched northeast, a vast region steeped in African soul and Portuguese-colonial folklore.
One distinctive genre of that region, known as forró, is a jaunty, accordion-driven, workingman’s music. Its greatest practitioner was Luiz Gonzaga, the great Pernambuco singer-songwriter with a voice like a roaring furnace. In one of the show’s cleverest sequences, his signature number, “Asa Branca,” a plaintive but resilient tune about rural life, was performed by dancers dressed as clay figurines.
The Closing Ceremonies also took viewers deeper into the Rio’s North Zone, a world apart from the South Zone’s tourist haunts. One particular neighborhood, Vila Isabel, is associated with the composer Pixinguinha and other godfathers of Brazilian popular music. On Sunday, sambista Martinho da Vila and his daughters performed “Carinhoso,” co-written by Pixinguinha in 1917, in homage to the community’s stout heritage.
In another segment, introducing the athletes, pop singer Roberta Sá channeled Carmen Miranda, the fruit-headdress-wearing, midcentury Hollywood diva who endures as a beloved camp figure.
Other performances, by electronic music artists and DJs, and Grupo Corpo, the veteran Minas Gerais contemporary dance company, demonstrated how Brazil continues to draw cultural sustenance from its complex past.
There were visual and polyrhythmic shout-outs to the gods of the indigenous Guarani people, a recitation by Arnaldo Antunes of his poem “Saudade” (a distinctly Portuguese word that signifies intense, nostalgic longing), and even a sequence devoted to traditional lace-making techniques.
While the outside world has scrutinized Brazil this month, South America’s largest country has spent the last two years in merciless self-examination, after the boom years of the mid-2000s went bust, financially, politically and morally. Many Brazilians entered these Games simply hoping nothing catastrophic would happen.
But Brazil is ending the Games on a decidedly upbeat note. The host country had a respectable medal haul. Some athletes who were expected to win big—or else—did so, principally the men’s soccer team.
Others, under far less pressure than the Seleção, performed equally well, or better. One of the Games’ most moving moments, occurred when judoka Rafaela Silva, who grew up in Rio’s embattled City of God community, captured a gold medal. It was replayed Sunday in an athletes video montage.
More important than the medal counts, the Rio Olympics, on their own limited terms, were a success. More things worked than didn’t. Most visitors got where they needed to get, if not always on time.
More Olympics Coverage
Claressa Shields Has Another Gold Medal, and She’s Not Stopping There Aug. 21, 2016 Japan’s Medal Haul Gives Hope for 2020 Aug. 21, 2016 Rio 2016: Why Team USA Exceeded All Expectations Aug. 21, 2016 As Curtain Draws on Rio, Track and Field Focuses on Change Aug. 21, 2016 What If They Awarded Medals for Finishing in Last? Aug. 21, 2016 Team USA Wins Olympic Gold Aug. 21, 2016 Even so, now that the circus has left town, there will be much for Cariocas and Brazilians to reckon with in the months and years ahead. Although the official cost of these Olympics has been placed at about $12 billion, some experts reckon the true figure could exceed $20 billion. Rio remains a microcosm of Brazil’s social divisions and vast disparities in wealth, education and opportunity.
There’s little doubt, too, that some glitter has rubbed off the Games in recent decades. Cities are more likely to think twice about the alleged cost-benefits of the Games. Next up is Tokyo, the 2020 host, whose prime minister, Shinzō Abe, made a surprise appearance in a blink-and-you’ll-miss-it promo pitch.
Most modern Olympics have been clouded in ambiguity, so it was fitting that these Games should conclude on a drizzly, overcast winter weekend. They left a final image, not of the eternal sunshine of the romantic, movie-set Rio, but of a more nuanced Rio, and a more subtle Brazil, in shades of light and shadow.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.65</spam_score>
<post_num>6</post_num>
<post_id>post-6</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.wsj.com/articles/brazil-passes-the-olympic-torch-and-breathes-a-sigh-of-relief-1471832043</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0553</post_time>
<username>Krishna Subramanian</username>
<post>
Well done Brazil. Congratulations.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-PM642_OLYCLO_G_20160821220824.jpg</main_image>
</document>
