<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/category/commodities/commodity-news/page/657/</forum>
<forum_title>Commodity News | Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide - Part 657</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Within two weeks of the price hike decision, domestic pig ir</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/pig-iron-companies-may-partially-rollback-price-hike/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Within two weeks of the price hike decision, domestic pig iron industry is looking for a partial rollback due to sluggish demand for the commodity, industry officials said.
Effective June 1, the domestic pig iron players had raised prices of the commodity following state-run NMDC’s decision to increase iron ore rates by 7-9%.
“One is that there are no orders and second is whatever orders we are getting is at a low price and so we are not ready to supply,” said a senior official with Hyderabad-based Satvahana Ispat. “Prices of steel TMT bars, ingots and billets have dropped due to weak demand in the market and so the pick-up for pig iron is also poor,” he said.
Pig iron is the intermediate product obtained by smelting iron ore with coke.
In an electric arc furnace steel-grade pig iron is used in making construction steel, while in a foundry, pig iron is used to make automobile parts and industrial moulds.
“We had hiked pig iron prices by Rs 1,500 per tonne from June 1 but will be soon taking a decision to roll back the hike partially as the market is unable to absorb it,” said the official from Satvahana Ispat.
Tata Metaliks, Lanco Industries and Kirloskar Ferro are among big pig iron players in the country.
Due to the weak demand in the domestic market, almost every company is having pig iron inventory between 5,000-7,000 tonne, said dealers.
Separately, the domestic sponge iron industry has chosen to remain in the wait-and-watch mode, basically trying to gauge the market appetite before it decides to raise sponge iron prices.
“We want to raise sponge iron prices since steel companies have also hiked product prices but the decision is yet to be taken,” said Rajib Mohanty, director of MGM Steel. “Even the quantum has not been decided, let’s see what the bigger players will do and then we will decide,” Mohanty added.
Earlier this month, primary steel producers had decided to raise product prices and were comfortable doing so in anticipation of bullish demand for the alloy from the infrastructure segment.
“As of now, there is no plan to roll back steel product prices, perhaps the companies will take a call by the end of the month but so far the market has taken the price hike quite well and we do not see any issue with market appetite,” said a Mumbai-based dealer.
Source: Business Standard
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/pig-iron-companies-may-partially-rollback-price-hike/</post_url>
<post_date>20140619</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>hellenicshippingnews</username>
<post>
Within two weeks of the price hike decision, domestic pig iron industry is looking for a partial rollback due to sluggish demand for the commodity, industry officials said.
Effective June 1, the domestic pig iron players had raised prices of the commodity following state-run NMDC’s decision to increase iron ore rates by 7-9%.
“One is that there are no orders and second is whatever orders we are getting is at a low price and so we are not ready to supply,” said a senior official with Hyderabad-based Satvahana Ispat. “Prices of steel TMT bars, ingots and billets have dropped due to weak demand in the market and so the pick-up for pig iron is also poor,” he said.
Pig iron is the intermediate product obtained by smelting iron ore with coke.
In an electric arc furnace steel-grade pig iron is used in making construction steel, while in a foundry, pig iron is used to make automobile parts and industrial moulds.
“We had hiked pig iron prices by Rs 1,500 per tonne from June 1 but will be soon taking a decision to roll back the hike partially as the market is unable to absorb it,” said the official from Satvahana Ispat.
Tata Metaliks, Lanco Industries and Kirloskar Ferro are among big pig iron players in the country.
Due to the weak demand in the domestic market, almost every company is having pig iron inventory between 5,000-7,000 tonne, said dealers.
Separately, the domestic sponge iron industry has chosen to remain in the wait-and-watch mode, basically trying to gauge the market appetite before it decides to raise sponge iron prices.
“We want to raise sponge iron prices since steel companies have also hiked product prices but the decision is yet to be taken,” said Rajib Mohanty, director of MGM Steel. “Even the quantum has not been decided, let’s see what the bigger players will do and then we will decide,” Mohanty added.
Earlier this month, primary steel producers had decided to raise product prices and were comfortable doing so in anticipation of bullish demand for the alloy from the infrastructure segment.
“As of now, there is no plan to roll back steel product prices, perhaps the companies will take a call by the end of the month but so far the market has taken the price hike quite well and we do not see any issue with market appetite,” said a Mumbai-based dealer.
Source: Business Standard
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
