<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://express.co.uk//posts/rss/51/property</forum>
<forum_title>Daily Express :: Property Feed</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Phil Spencer on getting on the property ladder post Brexit and his arguments with Kirstie</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.express.co.uk/life-style/property/702549/phil-spencer-kirstie-alsopp-property-advice-brexit-location-location-location</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Phil Spencer on getting on the property ladder post Brexit and his arguments with Kirstie Phil Spencer on getting on the property ladder post Brexit and his arguments with Kirstie THE property expert offers his pearls of wisdom for property hunting. PUBLISHED: 08:30, Mon, Aug 22, 2016 | UPDATED: 08:53, Mon, Aug 22, 2016 
He’s become renowned for his property expertise since presenting Location, Location, Location with co-host Kirstie Allsopp since 2000. 
And post Brexit in June, Phil Spencer has advice for those looking to get onto the property ladder or trade in their existing home for somewhere new. 
Speaking exclusively to the Express, Phil said: “People that are house hunting in this market just need to be cautious. 
“There is a market, things are relatively stable.” Related articles Lavish pad is very affordable but the outside MAY surprise you 
He added: “Money is still very cheap and people still need to be move. 
“I always advise buyer the long term and if you can buy something you can add value to you’ll be fine.” 
After becoming a household name, Phil - who has sons Jake and Ben with his wife Fiona - admits he is constantly recognised. 
He laughed: “I am recognised. It’s a by-product of what I do. Fortunately people keep watching my property shows so I keep making them. I do get recognised most places I go but it’s a product of making shows people watch.” GETTY Phil Spencer is renowned for his property expertise 
Location, Location, Location has proved just as popular with fans for the hilarious relationship between Phil and Kirstie as it has for its property advice. 
And despite their close friendship, Phil admits the pair have found themselves locked in arguments. 
He said: “Kirstie and I have worked together for 17 years. People have watched us get to know each other and become very good friends. 
&quot;I think in reality we’ve had about eight or nine arguments. In 17 years that’s not really bad. And we always make up so it’s part of what it is.&quot; GETTY Phil said despite their close friendship he and Kirstie have argued 
When we first started making the show, we always had a laugh but they’d edit those bits out and it was very much a property and advice show. 
&quot;But as time goes on they seem to edit all us mucking about in and the property bit out.” 
Speaking about his fondness for holidays by the sea, he said: “Ever year we go for a week in Polzeath in Cornwall. It&apos;s the simple pleasures in life. That does it for me.&quot; 
Phil was presenting Towergate’s Beach Hut of the Year 2016. Related articles
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.express.co.uk/life-style/property/702549/phil-spencer-kirstie-alsopp-property-advice-brexit-location-location-location</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0730</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Phil Spencer on getting on the property ladder post Brexit and his arguments with Kirstie Phil Spencer on getting on the property ladder post Brexit and his arguments with Kirstie THE property expert offers his pearls of wisdom for property hunting. PUBLISHED: 08:30, Mon, Aug 22, 2016 | UPDATED: 08:53, Mon, Aug 22, 2016 
He’s become renowned for his property expertise since presenting Location, Location, Location with co-host Kirstie Allsopp since 2000. 
And post Brexit in June, Phil Spencer has advice for those looking to get onto the property ladder or trade in their existing home for somewhere new. 
Speaking exclusively to the Express, Phil said: “People that are house hunting in this market just need to be cautious. 
“There is a market, things are relatively stable.” Related articles Lavish pad is very affordable but the outside MAY surprise you 
He added: “Money is still very cheap and people still need to be move. 
“I always advise buyer the long term and if you can buy something you can add value to you’ll be fine.” 
After becoming a household name, Phil - who has sons Jake and Ben with his wife Fiona - admits he is constantly recognised. 
He laughed: “I am recognised. It’s a by-product of what I do. Fortunately people keep watching my property shows so I keep making them. I do get recognised most places I go but it’s a product of making shows people watch.” GETTY Phil Spencer is renowned for his property expertise 
Location, Location, Location has proved just as popular with fans for the hilarious relationship between Phil and Kirstie as it has for its property advice. 
And despite their close friendship, Phil admits the pair have found themselves locked in arguments. 
He said: “Kirstie and I have worked together for 17 years. People have watched us get to know each other and become very good friends. 
&quot;I think in reality we’ve had about eight or nine arguments. In 17 years that’s not really bad. And we always make up so it’s part of what it is.&quot; GETTY Phil said despite their close friendship he and Kirstie have argued 
When we first started making the show, we always had a laugh but they’d edit those bits out and it was very much a property and advice show. 
&quot;But as time goes on they seem to edit all us mucking about in and the property bit out.” 
Speaking about his fondness for holidays by the sea, he said: “Ever year we go for a week in Polzeath in Cornwall. It&apos;s the simple pleasures in life. That does it for me.&quot; 
Phil was presenting Towergate’s Beach Hut of the Year 2016. Related articles
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://cdn.images.express.co.uk/img/dynamic/51/590x/Phil-Spencer-is-renowned-for-his-property-expertise-702549.jpg</main_image>
</document>
