<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://mybroadband.co.za/vb/external.php?type=RSS2</forum>
<forum_title>MyBroadband</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Car Scratch with a Car Hire Car Question</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://mybroadband.co.za/vb/showthread.php/836755-Car-Scratch-with-a-Car-Hire-Car-Question</topic_url>
<topic_text>
110 Car Scratch with a Car Hire Car Question While moving slowly towards a roadblock, I got bumped by some guy when he was busy on his GPS. Not much damage but a 6cm bump and a tiny barely visible scratch. The guy and his company have admitted they were wrong and say they are claiming from their insurance. When I returned the car to the car hire company, I get told they will get quotes and bill my deposit for the damage. Is that the normal procedure. They also say they dont deal with third parties so I have to claim on my own to the person who did the damage to me. Any advice is appreciated Under Construction Posts 7,158 1st question, did the guy who bumped you sign a statement he is at fault, or did you get him admitting fault on video? 2nd question, can you get him to pay your rental excess? if he admit fault... yes car hire companies are ruthless with this, they will take it out of your deposit, do you Miss SGU, So Did I S3 script 20,993 Originally Posted by jacksonc While moving slowly towards a roadblock, I got bumped by some guy when he was busy on his GPS. Not much damage but a 6cm bump and a tiny barely visible scratch. The guy and his company have admitted they were wrong and say they are claiming from their insurance. When I returned the car to the car hire company, I get told they will get quotes and bill my deposit for the damage. Is that the normal procedure. They also say they dont deal with third parties so I have to claim on my own to the person who did the damage to me. Any advice is appreciated Yes that is the normal procedure. I don&apos;t think car hire companies fix minor cosmetic damage, it is just a source of revenue for them. They bill you but never fix it, just mark it as damage when the car is rented out to the next person. The only way you get your money back is going after the 3rd party. He was a young boy from the casino. Nice kid, bright boy. What balls on this ****in&apos; kid. The next day I fired him
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://mybroadband.co.za/vb/showthread.php/836755-Car-Scratch-with-a-Car-Hire-Car-Question</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0751</post_time>
<username>jacksonc</username>
<post>
110 Car Scratch with a Car Hire Car Question While moving slowly towards a roadblock, I got bumped by some guy when he was busy on his GPS. Not much damage but a 6cm bump and a tiny barely visible scratch. The guy and his company have admitted they were wrong and say they are claiming from their insurance. When I returned the car to the car hire company, I get told they will get quotes and bill my deposit for the damage. Is that the normal procedure. They also say they dont deal with third parties so I have to claim on my own to the person who did the damage to me. Any advice is appreciated Under Construction Posts 7,158 1st question, did the guy who bumped you sign a statement he is at fault, or did you get him admitting fault on video? 2nd question, can you get him to pay your rental excess? if he admit fault... yes car hire companies are ruthless with this, they will take it out of your deposit, do you Miss SGU, So Did I S3 script 20,993 Originally Posted by jacksonc While moving slowly towards a roadblock, I got bumped by some guy when he was busy on his GPS. Not much damage but a 6cm bump and a tiny barely visible scratch. The guy and his company have admitted they were wrong and say they are claiming from their insurance. When I returned the car to the car hire company, I get told they will get quotes and bill my deposit for the damage. Is that the normal procedure. They also say they dont deal with third parties so I have to claim on my own to the person who did the damage to me. Any advice is appreciated Yes that is the normal procedure. I don&apos;t think car hire companies fix minor cosmetic damage, it is just a source of revenue for them. They bill you but never fix it, just mark it as damage when the car is rented out to the next person. The only way you get your money back is going after the 3rd party. He was a young boy from the casino. Nice kid, bright boy. What balls on this ****in&apos; kid. The next day I fired him
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>ZA</country>
<main_image>http://mybroadband.co.za/vb/images/misc/facebook_share.jpg</main_image>
</document>
