<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Cancer Patient, Mayowa Ahmed Is Dead</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220193.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The cancer patient, Mayowa Ahmed, on Sunday passed on after months of battle with the killer disease. She patient was the beneficiary of the #SaveMayowa fundraising campaign. Habeeb Odufuye, her cousin, shared the news of her demise on Sunday, through his Twitter page, @Asiwaju_Foye. &quot;By Allah, in who&apos;s hands our lives is, Mayowa Ahmed has left us in this world. We pray that Jannat becomes her home. She tried, we tried but God&apos;s will prevailed&quot;, he said in two tweets. Mayowa&apos;s condition -- stage 4 ovarian cancer -- prompted Nigerians to rally and pool funds to facilitate her treatment abroad however, the entire process, although successful,ended in controversy. It was recently revealed in a statement issued by her family that Mayowa had finally travelled to South Africa for treatment. Mayowa&apos;s family had said: &quot;As a family, it was our wish for Mayowa to leave the country on the earliest available flight to start her treatment but due to the much rumoured and alleged scam, we were faced with an overwhelming task of getting her flight documentations ready and missed the earliest scheduled appointment for August 1 in the UAE. &quot;In the midst of all this, several people and organisations working with us became skeptical and had to cancel appointments, including health care providers. &quot;But for some well-meaning individuals who were not deterred assisted in activating our back up plan. And with the grace of the Almighty Allah, Mayowa finally left the shores of Nigeria to South Africa last Thursday to start her treatment. &quot;On behalf of Mayowa, we want to say a very big thank you to everybody for your support with donations, prayers and logistics to facilitate the pursuit of giving Mayowa Ahmed a chance to live. &quot;To our various employers, we are extremely grateful for the trust and faith you had in us amidst of the allegations. Also the Lagos state police command for their diligent and thorough investigation which reinforced the integrity that the family stands for and was raised by.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220193.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0749</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
The cancer patient, Mayowa Ahmed, on Sunday passed on after months of battle with the killer disease. She patient was the beneficiary of the #SaveMayowa fundraising campaign. Habeeb Odufuye, her cousin, shared the news of her demise on Sunday, through his Twitter page, @Asiwaju_Foye. &quot;By Allah, in who&apos;s hands our lives is, Mayowa Ahmed has left us in this world. We pray that Jannat becomes her home. She tried, we tried but God&apos;s will prevailed&quot;, he said in two tweets. Mayowa&apos;s condition -- stage 4 ovarian cancer -- prompted Nigerians to rally and pool funds to facilitate her treatment abroad however, the entire process, although successful,ended in controversy. It was recently revealed in a statement issued by her family that Mayowa had finally travelled to South Africa for treatment. Mayowa&apos;s family had said: &quot;As a family, it was our wish for Mayowa to leave the country on the earliest available flight to start her treatment but due to the much rumoured and alleged scam, we were faced with an overwhelming task of getting her flight documentations ready and missed the earliest scheduled appointment for August 1 in the UAE. &quot;In the midst of all this, several people and organisations working with us became skeptical and had to cancel appointments, including health care providers. &quot;But for some well-meaning individuals who were not deterred assisted in activating our back up plan. And with the grace of the Almighty Allah, Mayowa finally left the shores of Nigeria to South Africa last Thursday to start her treatment. &quot;On behalf of Mayowa, we want to say a very big thank you to everybody for your support with donations, prayers and logistics to facilitate the pursuit of giving Mayowa Ahmed a chance to live. &quot;To our various employers, we are extremely grateful for the trust and faith you had in us amidst of the allegations. Also the Lagos state police command for their diligent and thorough investigation which reinforced the integrity that the family stands for and was raised by.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
