<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Independent - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Woman who &apos;drop-kicked son&apos;s cake&apos; faces new charge over ice cream assault | Americas | News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/woman-tricia-kortes-who-allegedly-drop-kicked-a-cake-faces-new-charge-over-ice-cream-assault-a7202466.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
A women who made local news headlines for allegedly drop-kicking her son&apos;s birthday cake at a bakery has been handed a new charge related to violence at an ice cream parlour. 
Tricia Ann Kortes, from Oakland County in Michigan, appeared in court on charges of assault and battery over an incident at Ray&apos;s Ice Cream in Royal Oaks on 9 July, 2015.
Employees at the ice cream parlour did not know her name, but claim they recognised Ms Kortes in media reports about the cake incident in June this year.
The ice cream shop&apos;s CCTV allegedly shows the mother striking Ray&apos;s employee Linda Wallner on the head, A BC7 reports.
Read more Fish with &apos;human teeth&apos; found swimming in Michigan lakes Draymond Green arrested on assault charges in Michigan Yes, these are actually cakes not CGI planets ‘Gay cake’ row: Christian bakers ‘praying for just outcome’ from appeal hearing Ms Wallner says the 46-year-old was angry the shop didn&apos;t have her favourite flavour.
Ms Kortes was initially charged with disorderly conduct for kicking a &quot;Superman v Batman&quot; birthday cake intended for her son at a Kroger grocery store in Bloomfield Township. 
Kroger employees said Ms Kortes was unhappy with how the cake turned out and went behind the bakery counter to &quot;fix&quot; it.
The Queen&apos;s Bake Off cake 
She was told she couldn&apos;t enter staff areas, at which point a witness says she threw the cake on the floor before stepping on it and shouting: &quot;They f*
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/woman-tricia-kortes-who-allegedly-drop-kicked-a-cake-faces-new-charge-over-ice-cream-assault-a7202466.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>1044</post_time>
<username>Douglas</username>
<post>
It is good to know that she is being prosecuted, ar least. As Philip Davies MP has been pointing out, in the UK she would be unlikely to get any judicial attention, just because she is female.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2016/08/21/14/ray-ice-cream-parlour-michigan-.png</main_image>
</document>
