<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>A long night&apos;s journey to redemption for Conor... NATIONAL NEWS, HEADLINES, STORIES AND LATEST NEWS</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://uk911.news897.com/post/149307581439/a-long-nights-journey-to-redemption-for-conor</topic_url>
<topic_text>
UPDATED 2 hours ago 
Conor McGregor He’s known as ‘The Notorious’ and Conor McGregor didn’t hold back as he celebrated his UFC 202 victory over Nate Diaz. Sometime before Saturday night Conor McGregor found his fighting soul again. Last night’s fight at UFC 202 between Conor McGregor and Nate Diaz continues to make headlines across the world. The one-punch knockout power and accurate boxing skills of McGregor have propelled him to the pinnacle of the UFC ladder in three years but they have also masked his perceived weaknesses. However, the one person that received the biggest brunt of the McGregor WWE insults doesn’t bother with social media. And while it looks like Kanye didn’t get to meet the man himself, he did manage to get the next best thing. And while that made for thrilling theater, it also stirred up plenty of controversy. The Notorious is renowned for charging forward at his opponent in the opening stanza and planting a flag, or kick. The rapper posed backstage with Conor’s dad Tony for a post-figt snap. It’s hard to imagine a more welcome sound to Conor McGregor’s ears than that horn blowing to signal the end of Round 3.When Conor McGregor insulted the entire WWE locker room, many WWE superstars took notice and responded on social media. Saturday’s bout between Conor McGregor and Nate Diaz at UFC 202 was one of the most tightly contested main events you’ll see. After an epic build up and a fight that lived up to the hype, McGregor once again silenced his doubters and walked away with a victory that many said was impossible before entering the Octagon. It certainly was a more thoughtful Conor McGregor inside the octagon, and to go along with this The Notorious has been doing his best to cultivate a similar image outside of the ring as of late.It’s rare in the world of combat sports that one fight between two combatants could produce such a long list of winners simply because of the result. The one-punch knockout power and accurate boxing skills of McGregor have propelled him to the pinnacle of the UFC ladder in three years but they have also masked his perceived weaknesses. 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.22</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://uk911.news897.com/post/149307581439/a-long-nights-journey-to-redemption-for-conor</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
UPDATED 2 hours ago 
Conor McGregor He’s known as ‘The Notorious’ and Conor McGregor didn’t hold back as he celebrated his UFC 202 victory over Nate Diaz. Sometime before Saturday night Conor McGregor found his fighting soul again. Last night’s fight at UFC 202 between Conor McGregor and Nate Diaz continues to make headlines across the world. The one-punch knockout power and accurate boxing skills of McGregor have propelled him to the pinnacle of the UFC ladder in three years but they have also masked his perceived weaknesses. However, the one person that received the biggest brunt of the McGregor WWE insults doesn’t bother with social media. And while it looks like Kanye didn’t get to meet the man himself, he did manage to get the next best thing. And while that made for thrilling theater, it also stirred up plenty of controversy. The Notorious is renowned for charging forward at his opponent in the opening stanza and planting a flag, or kick. The rapper posed backstage with Conor’s dad Tony for a post-figt snap. It’s hard to imagine a more welcome sound to Conor McGregor’s ears than that horn blowing to signal the end of Round 3.When Conor McGregor insulted the entire WWE locker room, many WWE superstars took notice and responded on social media. Saturday’s bout between Conor McGregor and Nate Diaz at UFC 202 was one of the most tightly contested main events you’ll see. After an epic build up and a fight that lived up to the hype, McGregor once again silenced his doubters and walked away with a victory that many said was impossible before entering the Octagon. It certainly was a more thoughtful Conor McGregor inside the octagon, and to go along with this The Notorious has been doing his best to cultivate a similar image outside of the ring as of late.It’s rare in the world of combat sports that one fight between two combatants could produce such a long list of winners simply because of the result. The one-punch knockout power and accurate boxing skills of McGregor have propelled him to the pinnacle of the UFC ladder in three years but they have also masked his perceived weaknesses. 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>//t3.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcTHLr8PMP3eQwkfV6ymQS0YP-CBikBvUdlCEqWKO8FrATkPi1MhWCjIBBTpiwra8iUGZ8hCfuAu</main_image>
</document>
