<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.odt.co.nz/news/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Otago Daily Times Online News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>&apos;Special needs&apos; term to be scrapped</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.odt.co.nz/news/national/special-needs-term-be-scrapped</topic_url>
<topic_text>
  &apos;Special needs&apos; term to be scrapped 
  Hekia Parata The term &quot;special needs&quot; education is likely to be scrapped because of concerns it singles out students.
More money will also be spent on preschoolers to try and help them as early as possible - likely meaning less funding for special education at school. 
The possible changes are outlined in a Cabinet paper released by Education Minister Hekia Parata as part of an &quot;update&quot; of the system focused on high-level changes. 
Officials held meetings with more than 2200 people around the country as part of the update. 
The Cabinet paper proposes changing the language used to describe the system. 
&quot;The use of the term &apos;special needs&apos; singles people out, and by concentrating on learner&apos;s deficits, can marginalise individuals and create a barrier to a fully inclusive education system,&quot; the document states. 
About 80,000 to 100,000 children in early childhood education and schools get some form of learning support each year -- about 10 per cent of the total student population. 
The Ministry of Education has been struggling to meet growing demand as the school-age population grows and there is better and earlier identification of needs. 
Last year about $590m was spent on special education. No change in overall funding is proposed in the Cabinet paper - but how and when funding is spent will be overhauled. 
&quot;Analysis of the spend by the age range of the recipient indicates that a disproportionate amount of the funds are for school-age children,&quot; the paper states. 
&quot;This is despite clear evidence in some areas that early support can have greater benefits in terms of educational outcomes.&quot; 
The ministry will use the &quot;social investment&quot; approach to change the spread of funding. 
Championed by Finance Minister Bill English, the work uses a powerful Statistics NZ database to track outcomes beyond NCEA results, such as employment. 
Initial work will focus on: 
- Reviewing the Ongoing Resourcing Scheme (ORS) that provides support for students with the highest levels of disability. 
- How help is provided for speech disorders like stuttering and oral language delay, to work out how things could be improved if help is provided earlier. 
- &quot;Clustering&quot; services and removing sometimes arbitrary eligibility criteria. For example, the intensive wraparound service is currently limited to children aged 8 to 14, when &quot;early intervention might be more beneficial in the long-term&quot;. 
Labour&apos;s education spokesman Chris Hipkins said early intervention should not come at the cost of cutting support for school-age children with special needs. 
&quot;It is short-sighted and stupid ... I absolutely agree that the Government can do a much better job of identifying and supporting children with additional learning needs earlier. 
&quot;But depriving older kids of the support they so desperately need is no way to accomplish that.&quot; 
Green Party education spokeswoman Catherine Delahunty, who initiated a select committee inquiry into dyslexia, dyspraxia, and autism spectrum disorders in schools, said the proposals would not help. 
&quot;The Government is proposing to shift money around, and short-change children and young people over the age of seven. Everything I have heard shows the need for more support, and more funding, across all age groups, not less.&quot; 
Education Minister Hekia Parata said evidence showed that providing learning support early in a child&apos;s life had a much greater impact. 
&quot;We want to make sure that the over $590 million we&apos;re investing in additional learning support is being spent in the most effective and impactful way possible so that kids get the best chance to achieve educational success. 
&quot;We&apos;re at a proposal stage of the process. Any changes wouldn&apos;t come into effect until March 2017 at the earliest and will be managed incrementally and carefully to ensure ongoing support.&quot; 
New Zealand&apos;s inclusive education policy means that most special needs children are integrated locally, meaning any lack of resourcing has the potential to affect all students in a class with high-needs kids. 
The Herald last year reported that some schools were turning special needs children away, while others only allow children to attend if a teacher aide is present. That is illegal.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.odt.co.nz/news/national/special-needs-term-be-scrapped</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0747</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
  &apos;Special needs&apos; term to be scrapped 
  Hekia Parata The term &quot;special needs&quot; education is likely to be scrapped because of concerns it singles out students.
More money will also be spent on preschoolers to try and help them as early as possible - likely meaning less funding for special education at school. 
The possible changes are outlined in a Cabinet paper released by Education Minister Hekia Parata as part of an &quot;update&quot; of the system focused on high-level changes. 
Officials held meetings with more than 2200 people around the country as part of the update. 
The Cabinet paper proposes changing the language used to describe the system. 
&quot;The use of the term &apos;special needs&apos; singles people out, and by concentrating on learner&apos;s deficits, can marginalise individuals and create a barrier to a fully inclusive education system,&quot; the document states. 
About 80,000 to 100,000 children in early childhood education and schools get some form of learning support each year -- about 10 per cent of the total student population. 
The Ministry of Education has been struggling to meet growing demand as the school-age population grows and there is better and earlier identification of needs. 
Last year about $590m was spent on special education. No change in overall funding is proposed in the Cabinet paper - but how and when funding is spent will be overhauled. 
&quot;Analysis of the spend by the age range of the recipient indicates that a disproportionate amount of the funds are for school-age children,&quot; the paper states. 
&quot;This is despite clear evidence in some areas that early support can have greater benefits in terms of educational outcomes.&quot; 
The ministry will use the &quot;social investment&quot; approach to change the spread of funding. 
Championed by Finance Minister Bill English, the work uses a powerful Statistics NZ database to track outcomes beyond NCEA results, such as employment. 
Initial work will focus on: 
- Reviewing the Ongoing Resourcing Scheme (ORS) that provides support for students with the highest levels of disability. 
- How help is provided for speech disorders like stuttering and oral language delay, to work out how things could be improved if help is provided earlier. 
- &quot;Clustering&quot; services and removing sometimes arbitrary eligibility criteria. For example, the intensive wraparound service is currently limited to children aged 8 to 14, when &quot;early intervention might be more beneficial in the long-term&quot;. 
Labour&apos;s education spokesman Chris Hipkins said early intervention should not come at the cost of cutting support for school-age children with special needs. 
&quot;It is short-sighted and stupid ... I absolutely agree that the Government can do a much better job of identifying and supporting children with additional learning needs earlier. 
&quot;But depriving older kids of the support they so desperately need is no way to accomplish that.&quot; 
Green Party education spokeswoman Catherine Delahunty, who initiated a select committee inquiry into dyslexia, dyspraxia, and autism spectrum disorders in schools, said the proposals would not help. 
&quot;The Government is proposing to shift money around, and short-change children and young people over the age of seven. Everything I have heard shows the need for more support, and more funding, across all age groups, not less.&quot; 
Education Minister Hekia Parata said evidence showed that providing learning support early in a child&apos;s life had a much greater impact. 
&quot;We want to make sure that the over $590 million we&apos;re investing in additional learning support is being spent in the most effective and impactful way possible so that kids get the best chance to achieve educational success. 
&quot;We&apos;re at a proposal stage of the process. Any changes wouldn&apos;t come into effect until March 2017 at the earliest and will be managed incrementally and carefully to ensure ongoing support.&quot; 
New Zealand&apos;s inclusive education policy means that most special needs children are integrated locally, meaning any lack of resourcing has the potential to affect all students in a class with high-needs kids. 
The Herald last year reported that some schools were turning special needs children away, while others only allow children to attend if a teacher aide is present. That is illegal.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>NZ</country>
<main_image>https://www.odt.co.nz/sites/default/files/story/2016/08/hekia_parata_577da24976.jpg</main_image>
</document>
