<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Lexington Realty Trust’s (LXP) “Hold” Rating Reaffirmed at Barclays PLC</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084377/lexington-realty-trusts-lxp-hold-rating-reaffirmed-at-barclays-plc/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Barclays PLC reiterated their hold rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust (NYSE:LXP) in a research note issued to investors on Tuesday morning. Barclays PLC currently has a $10.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
Several other analysts have also issued reports on LXP. Wells Fargo &amp; Co. restated a hold rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust in a research note on Thursday, May 5th. Evercore ISI lowered Lexington Realty Trust from a buy rating to a hold rating and boosted their target price for the company from $9.75 to $10.00 in a research note on Monday, June 13th. Zacks Investment Research cut Lexington Realty Trust from a hold rating to a strong sell rating in a research report on Tuesday, July 26th. Jefferies Group reiterated a neutral rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust in a research report on Wednesday, August 10th. Finally, Ladenburg Thalmann cut Lexington Realty Trust from a buy rating to a neutral rating in a research report on Thursday, May 19th. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, six have given a hold rating and one has assigned a buy rating to the company’s stock. Lexington Realty Trust has an average rating of Hold and a consensus price target of $10.00. 
In related news, Vice Chairman Richard J. Rouse sold 25,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The stock was sold at an average price of $10.70, for a total transaction of $267,500.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the insider now directly owns 628,648 shares in the company, valued at $6,726,533.60. The transaction was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this link . Also, CAO Beth Boulerice sold 7,400 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Thursday, June 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of $9.60, for a total value of $71,040.00. Following the transaction, the chief accounting officer now owns 190,617 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,829,923.20. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors have bought and sold shares of LXP. Los Angeles Capital Management &amp; Equity Research Inc. boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 32.5% in the first quarter. Los Angeles Capital Management &amp; Equity Research Inc. now owns 49,375 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $425,000 after buying an additional 12,100 shares during the last quarter. Virginia Retirement System acquired a new position in Lexington Realty Trust during the first quarter valued at approximately $2,278,000. Norges Bank acquired a new position in Lexington Realty Trust during the fourth quarter valued at approximately $17,270,000. Two Sigma Investments LLC boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 71.2% in the fourth quarter. Two Sigma Investments LLC now owns 522,570 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $4,181,000 after buying an additional 217,349 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Deutsche Bank AG boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 16.6% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 1,406,030 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $11,246,000 after buying an additional 200,162 shares during the last quarter. 
Lexington Realty Trust ( NYSE:LXP ) opened at 10.63 on Tuesday. The company has a market capitalization of $2.52 billion and a P/E ratio of 20.60. The firm has a 50-day moving average price of $10.55 and a 200 day moving average price of $9.16. Lexington Realty Trust has a 52-week low of $6.52 and a 52-week high of $11.02. 
Lexington Realty Trust (NYSE:LXP) last issued its earnings results on Tuesday, August 9th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.29 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.27 by $0.02. The firm earned $109.60 million during the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $103.72 million. During the same quarter in the previous year, the firm earned $0.27 earnings per share. The business’s quarterly revenue was down .6% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, analysts predict that Lexington Realty Trust will post $1.09 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Lexington Realty Trust is a self-managed and self-administered real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company owns a portfolio of equity and debt investments in single-tenant properties and land. The Company’s segment is single-tenant real estate assets. The Company also provides investment advisory and asset management services to investors in the single-tenant area.   Lexington Realty Trust   Lexington Realty Trust  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084377/lexington-realty-trusts-lxp-hold-rating-reaffirmed-at-barclays-plc/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0749</post_time>
<username>Logan Wallace</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Barclays PLC reiterated their hold rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust (NYSE:LXP) in a research note issued to investors on Tuesday morning. Barclays PLC currently has a $10.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
Several other analysts have also issued reports on LXP. Wells Fargo &amp; Co. restated a hold rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust in a research note on Thursday, May 5th. Evercore ISI lowered Lexington Realty Trust from a buy rating to a hold rating and boosted their target price for the company from $9.75 to $10.00 in a research note on Monday, June 13th. Zacks Investment Research cut Lexington Realty Trust from a hold rating to a strong sell rating in a research report on Tuesday, July 26th. Jefferies Group reiterated a neutral rating on shares of Lexington Realty Trust in a research report on Wednesday, August 10th. Finally, Ladenburg Thalmann cut Lexington Realty Trust from a buy rating to a neutral rating in a research report on Thursday, May 19th. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, six have given a hold rating and one has assigned a buy rating to the company’s stock. Lexington Realty Trust has an average rating of Hold and a consensus price target of $10.00. 
In related news, Vice Chairman Richard J. Rouse sold 25,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The stock was sold at an average price of $10.70, for a total transaction of $267,500.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the insider now directly owns 628,648 shares in the company, valued at $6,726,533.60. The transaction was disclosed in a document filed with the SEC, which is available through this link . Also, CAO Beth Boulerice sold 7,400 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Thursday, June 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of $9.60, for a total value of $71,040.00. Following the transaction, the chief accounting officer now owns 190,617 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,829,923.20. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors have bought and sold shares of LXP. Los Angeles Capital Management &amp; Equity Research Inc. boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 32.5% in the first quarter. Los Angeles Capital Management &amp; Equity Research Inc. now owns 49,375 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $425,000 after buying an additional 12,100 shares during the last quarter. Virginia Retirement System acquired a new position in Lexington Realty Trust during the first quarter valued at approximately $2,278,000. Norges Bank acquired a new position in Lexington Realty Trust during the fourth quarter valued at approximately $17,270,000. Two Sigma Investments LLC boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 71.2% in the fourth quarter. Two Sigma Investments LLC now owns 522,570 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $4,181,000 after buying an additional 217,349 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Deutsche Bank AG boosted its position in Lexington Realty Trust by 16.6% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 1,406,030 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $11,246,000 after buying an additional 200,162 shares during the last quarter. 
Lexington Realty Trust ( NYSE:LXP ) opened at 10.63 on Tuesday. The company has a market capitalization of $2.52 billion and a P/E ratio of 20.60. The firm has a 50-day moving average price of $10.55 and a 200 day moving average price of $9.16. Lexington Realty Trust has a 52-week low of $6.52 and a 52-week high of $11.02. 
Lexington Realty Trust (NYSE:LXP) last issued its earnings results on Tuesday, August 9th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.29 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating the Thomson Reuters’ consensus estimate of $0.27 by $0.02. The firm earned $109.60 million during the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $103.72 million. During the same quarter in the previous year, the firm earned $0.27 earnings per share. The business’s quarterly revenue was down .6% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, analysts predict that Lexington Realty Trust will post $1.09 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
Lexington Realty Trust is a self-managed and self-administered real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company owns a portfolio of equity and debt investments in single-tenant properties and land. The Company’s segment is single-tenant real estate assets. The Company also provides investment advisory and asset management services to investors in the single-tenant area.   Lexington Realty Trust   Lexington Realty Trust  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/lexington-realty-trust-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
