<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) Upgraded to Buy at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/weingarten-realty-investors-wri-upgraded-to-buy-at-zacks-investment-research-2/1212608/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research report sent to investors on Tuesday morning. The brokerage currently has $47.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Weingarten Realty Investors is focused on delivering solid returns to shareholders by actively developing, acquiring, and intensively managing properties in twenty one states that span the southern portion of the United States from coast to coast. Weingarten’s business activities encompass the long-term ownership, management, acquisition, development and redevelopment of strategically located neighborhood and community shopping centers and select industrial properties. The vast majority of our shopping centers are anchored by either a supermarket or a national value-oriented retailer. These anchors combined with convenient locations, attractive and well-maintained properties and a strong tenant mix help to ensure the long-term success of our merchants and the viability of our portfolio. The Company’s portfolio of Thirf caproperties includes thirty neighborhood and community shopping centers and sixty four industrial properties, aggregating fourty million square feet. “ 
Other research analysts have also issued reports about the company. Jefferies Group reaffirmed a hold rating and set a $42.00 target price on shares of Weingarten Realty Investors in a report on Friday, July 29th. Citigroup Inc. lowered Weingarten Realty Investors from a buy rating to a neutral rating and set a $40.00 target price on the stock. in a report on Wednesday, April 27th. Finally, Boenning Scattergood began coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a report on Tuesday, June 28th. They set an underperform rating and a $35.50 target price on the stock. 
Shares of Weingarten Realty Investors ( NYSE:WRI ) opened at 40.94 on Tuesday. Weingarten Realty Investors has a 52-week low of $30.21 and a 52-week high of $43.70. The firm has a market cap of $5.23 billion and a P/E ratio of 22.08. The company’s 50-day moving average is $42.01 and its 200-day moving average is $38.42. 
Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) last released its earnings results on Thursday, July 28th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.57 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.56 by $0.01. The firm had revenue of $135.70 million for the quarter, compared to analyst estimates of $129.52 million. During the same period in the previous year, the firm earned $0.54 earnings per share. Weingarten Realty Investors’s revenue was up 6.8% on a year-over-year basis. Equities research analysts forecast that Weingarten Realty Investors will post $2.30 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Investors of record on Thursday, September 8th will be paid a $0.365 dividend. The ex-dividend date of this dividend is Tuesday, September 6th. This represents a $1.46 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 3.57%. 
In related news, CEO Andrew M. Alexander sold 66,224 shares of Weingarten Realty Investors stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The stock was sold at an average price of C$41.59, for a total value of C$2,754,256.16. Following the transaction, the chief executive officer now owns 1,167,577 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately C$48,559,527.43. The sale was disclosed in a document filed with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, CFO Stephen C. Richter sold 18,000 shares of Weingarten Realty Investors stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of C$42.80, for a total value of C$770,400.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the chief financial officer now directly owns 266,593 shares in the company, valued at approximately C$11,410,180.40. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other large investors have made changes to their positions in the company. Retirement Systems of Alabama raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 1.3% in the second quarter. Retirement Systems of Alabama now owns 148,915 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $6,079,000 after buying an additional 1,872 shares during the last quarter. Callahan Advisors LLC raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 2.1% in the second quarter. Callahan Advisors LLC now owns 132,645 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $5,415,000 after buying an additional 2,730 shares during the last quarter. RKL Wealth Management LLC raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 2.9% in the second quarter. RKL Wealth Management LLC now owns 14,054 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $545,000 after buying an additional 399 shares during the last quarter. Sanders Morris Harris Inc. raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 6.9% in the second quarter. Sanders Morris Harris Inc. now owns 25,350 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $1,035,000 after buying an additional 1,640 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Sigma Planning Corp acquired a new stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors during the second quarter worth approximately $221,000. 
Weingarten Realty Investors is a real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company’s primary business is leasing space to tenants in the shopping centers it owns or leases. It is engaged in the business of owning, managing and developing retail shopping centers. Its properties consist primarily of neighborhood and community shopping centers. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Weingarten Realty Investors   Weingarten Realty Investors  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/weingarten-realty-investors-wri-upgraded-to-buy-at-zacks-investment-research-2/1212608/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0746</post_time>
<username>Hossein Forouzandeh</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research report sent to investors on Tuesday morning. The brokerage currently has $47.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Weingarten Realty Investors is focused on delivering solid returns to shareholders by actively developing, acquiring, and intensively managing properties in twenty one states that span the southern portion of the United States from coast to coast. Weingarten’s business activities encompass the long-term ownership, management, acquisition, development and redevelopment of strategically located neighborhood and community shopping centers and select industrial properties. The vast majority of our shopping centers are anchored by either a supermarket or a national value-oriented retailer. These anchors combined with convenient locations, attractive and well-maintained properties and a strong tenant mix help to ensure the long-term success of our merchants and the viability of our portfolio. The Company’s portfolio of Thirf caproperties includes thirty neighborhood and community shopping centers and sixty four industrial properties, aggregating fourty million square feet. “ 
Other research analysts have also issued reports about the company. Jefferies Group reaffirmed a hold rating and set a $42.00 target price on shares of Weingarten Realty Investors in a report on Friday, July 29th. Citigroup Inc. lowered Weingarten Realty Investors from a buy rating to a neutral rating and set a $40.00 target price on the stock. in a report on Wednesday, April 27th. Finally, Boenning Scattergood began coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a report on Tuesday, June 28th. They set an underperform rating and a $35.50 target price on the stock. 
Shares of Weingarten Realty Investors ( NYSE:WRI ) opened at 40.94 on Tuesday. Weingarten Realty Investors has a 52-week low of $30.21 and a 52-week high of $43.70. The firm has a market cap of $5.23 billion and a P/E ratio of 22.08. The company’s 50-day moving average is $42.01 and its 200-day moving average is $38.42. 
Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) last released its earnings results on Thursday, July 28th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.57 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.56 by $0.01. The firm had revenue of $135.70 million for the quarter, compared to analyst estimates of $129.52 million. During the same period in the previous year, the firm earned $0.54 earnings per share. Weingarten Realty Investors’s revenue was up 6.8% on a year-over-year basis. Equities research analysts forecast that Weingarten Realty Investors will post $2.30 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Investors of record on Thursday, September 8th will be paid a $0.365 dividend. The ex-dividend date of this dividend is Tuesday, September 6th. This represents a $1.46 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 3.57%. 
In related news, CEO Andrew M. Alexander sold 66,224 shares of Weingarten Realty Investors stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The stock was sold at an average price of C$41.59, for a total value of C$2,754,256.16. Following the transaction, the chief executive officer now owns 1,167,577 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately C$48,559,527.43. The sale was disclosed in a document filed with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, CFO Stephen C. Richter sold 18,000 shares of Weingarten Realty Investors stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of C$42.80, for a total value of C$770,400.00. Following the completion of the transaction, the chief financial officer now directly owns 266,593 shares in the company, valued at approximately C$11,410,180.40. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other large investors have made changes to their positions in the company. Retirement Systems of Alabama raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 1.3% in the second quarter. Retirement Systems of Alabama now owns 148,915 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $6,079,000 after buying an additional 1,872 shares during the last quarter. Callahan Advisors LLC raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 2.1% in the second quarter. Callahan Advisors LLC now owns 132,645 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $5,415,000 after buying an additional 2,730 shares during the last quarter. RKL Wealth Management LLC raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 2.9% in the second quarter. RKL Wealth Management LLC now owns 14,054 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $545,000 after buying an additional 399 shares during the last quarter. Sanders Morris Harris Inc. raised its stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors by 6.9% in the second quarter. Sanders Morris Harris Inc. now owns 25,350 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $1,035,000 after buying an additional 1,640 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Sigma Planning Corp acquired a new stake in shares of Weingarten Realty Investors during the second quarter worth approximately $221,000. 
Weingarten Realty Investors is a real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company’s primary business is leasing space to tenants in the shopping centers it owns or leases. It is engaged in the business of owning, managing and developing retail shopping centers. Its properties consist primarily of neighborhood and community shopping centers. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Weingarten Realty Investors   Weingarten Realty Investors  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/weingarten-realty-investors-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
