<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Independent - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Phil Collins addresses his former alcohol addiction: &apos;I came very close to dying&apos; | People | News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/phil-collins-alcohol-addiction-nearly-died-i-m-not-dead-yet-a7202586.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Phil Collins has addressed his former alcohol addiction and said he came close to nearly dying due to heavy drinking.
The 65-year-old grammy-award winning singer explained he started drinking more after his third marriage broke up and his family moved away to Miami. 
Collins said he was in turn left with an emotional vacuum and began drinking excessively.
“There’s a chapter in it about the drinking, which escalated when my third marriage broke up, and I retired,” he told The New York Times while talking about his new memoir I’m Not Dead Yet . 
People news in pictures 30 show all People news in pictures 1/30 17 August 2016 Laura Trott, right, kisses her fiance Jason Kenny, left, both of Britain, after he won the men&apos;s keirin cycling final at the Rio Olympic Velodrome during the 2016 Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro
AP
2/30 16 August 2016 Democratic presidential nominee Hillary Clinton welcomes Vice President Joe Biden as he disembarks from Air Force Two for a joint campaign event in Scranton, Pennsylvania
REUTERS
3/30 15 August 2016 Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi gestures as he addresses the nation from the historic Red Fort during Independence Day celebrations in Delhi
REUTERS
4/30 14 August 2016 Jamaica&apos;s Usain Bolt (Top) poses with fellow athletes for a selfie photo as he celebrates after winning the Men&apos;s 100m Final during the athletics event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Stadium in Rio de Janeiro
AFP/Getty Images
5/30 13 August 2016 Former Cuban President Fidel Castro (2nd L), sitting between Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro (3rd L) and Cuban President Raul Castro (L), is seen attending the celebration of his 90th birthday at the Karl Marx theatre in Havana
AFP/Getty Images
6/30 12 August 2016 Britain&apos;s Prime Minister Theresa May walks in a forest with her husband Philip at the start of a summer holiday in the Alps, in Switzerland
Reuters
7/30 11 August 2016 Pope Francis smiles as he browses through drawings at the Vatican. Pope Francis had lunch with a group of Syrian refugees who were brought to Italy from the Greek island of Lesbos thanks to the pope&apos;s intercession. The Vatican said that the pope brought toys and other gifts for the children, who, in turn, gave him a selection of their drawings
AP
8/30 10 August 2016 Turkey&apos;s President Tayyip Erdogan addresses his supporters in front of the Presidential Palace in Ankara
REUTERS
9/30 9 August 2016 Cast member Salma Hayek takes a selfie with co-stars (L-R) Nick Kroll, Paul Rudd, Seth Rogen, Michael Cera and Danny McBride at the premiere for the movie &quot;Sausage Party&quot; in Los Angeles
REUTERS
10/30 19 July 2016 Turkey&apos;s Prime Minister Binali Yildrim addresses members of parliament from his ruling AK Party (AKP) during a meeting at the Turkish parliament in Ankara
REUTERS
11/30 18 July 2016 Melania Trump, wife of Republican U.S. presidential candidate Donald Trump, waves as she arrives to speak at the Republican National Convention in Cleveland
Reuters
12/30 18 July 2016 Britain&apos;s Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson listens to Spain&apos;s Foreign Minister Jose Manuel Garcia-Margallo (L) during an European Union foreign ministers meeting in Brussels
REUTERS
13/30 17 July 2016 Turkey&apos;s President Recep Tayyip Erdogan reacts after attending the funeral of a victim of the coup attempt in Istanbul
Getty Images
14/30 16 July 2016 Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump, introduces Gov. Mike Pence, during a campaign event to announce Pence as the vice presidential running mate, in New York. Trump called Pence &quot;my partner in this campaign&quot; and his first and best choice to join him on a winning Republican presidential ticket
AP
15/30 15 July 2016 French President Francois Hollande looks on as he speaks to journalists at the Prefectoral Palace the day after a gunman smashed a truck into a crowd of revellers celebrating Bastille Day in Nice, killing at least 84 people
AFP/Getty Images
16/30 14 July 2016 Newly appointed British Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson leaves his home in north London
AP
17/30 13 July 2016 Queen Elizabeth II welcomes Theresa May at the start of an audience, where she invited the former Home Secretary to become Prime Minister and form a new government, at Buckingham Palace. Former Home Secretary Theresa May becomes the UK&apos;s second female Prime Minister after she was selected unopposed by Conservative MPs to be their new party leader
Getty Images Europe
18/30 13 July 2016 Outgoing British Prime Minister David Cameron is accompanied by his wife Samantha and their children as they hug on the doorsteps upon their departure from No. 10 Downing Street for the last time
EPA
19/30 12 July 2016 Pakistani Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai arrives to celebrate her 19th birthday at the Dadaab refugee camp near the Kenya-Somalia border
REUTERS
20/30 11 July 2016 Britain&apos;s new Conservative Party leader Theresa May receives a kiss from her husband Philip John May, after speaking to members of the media at The St Stephen&apos;s entrance to the Palace of Westminster in London. Theresa May will become the prime minister who leads Britain&apos;s into Brexit talks after her only rival in the race to succeed David Cameron pulled out unexpectedly. May was left as the only contender standing after the withdrawal from the leadership race of Andrea Leadsom, who faced criticism for suggesting she was more qualified to be premier because she had children
AFP/Getty Images
21/30 11 July 2016 Prime Minister David Cameron gestures as he addresses the media outside 10 Downing Street, where he announced that Theresa May would be Britain&apos;s new leader
AFP/Getty Images
22/30 11 July 2016 Andrea Leadsom, a candidate to become the next Conservative Party leader and British prime minister, rules herself out of the leadership battle during a news conference in central London
REUTERS
23/30 10 July 2016 Portugal&apos;s forward Cristiano Ronaldo reacts as he is carried on a stretcher off the pitch by team medics after an injury following a clash with France&apos;s forward Dimitri Payet (not pictured) during the Euro 2016 final football match between Portugal and France at the Stade de France in Saint-Denis, north of Paris
AFP/Getty Images
24/30 10 July 2016 Britain&apos;s Andy Murray kisses the winner&apos;s trophy after his men&apos;s singles final victory over Canada&apos;s Milos Raonic on the last day of the 2016 Wimbledon Championships at The All England Lawn Tennis Club in Wimbledon
AFP/Getty Images
25/30 10 July 2016 British driver Lewis Hamilton celebrates with fans after climbing the paddock fence after winning the British Formula One Grand Prix at Silverstone motor racing circuit in Silverstone
AFP/Getty Images
26/30 9 July 2016 Serena Williams celebrates beating Germany&apos;s Angelique Kerber in the women&apos;s singles final on the thirteenth day of the 2016 Wimbledon Championships in London
AFP/Getty Images
27/30 8 July 2016 Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince George during a visit to the Royal International Air Tattoo at RAF Fairford 
Getty Images
28/30 8 July 2016 U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks on the police shootings in Dallas
Reuters
29/30 7 July 2016 Justice Secretary Michael Gove makes a statement outside the Palace of Westminster, after he was eliminated in the second round of MPs&apos; voting for the Conservative leadership
PA
30/30 6 July 2016 Olympic and Paralympic track star Oscar Pistorius reacts with his sister Aimee Pistorius at his sentence hearing at the North Gauteng High Court in Pretoria. Pistorius has been sentenced to six years in prison for the murder of his girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp
REUTERS
“I was left with this huge void. I didn’t want to work because I wanted to be with the kids, but the kids weren’t there anymore, because they moved to Miami, and I was still in Switzerland.” 
Read more Phil Collins: Singer clears up long-standing rumours “You start drinking, and then you start drinking too much. Then it physically hurts you. I came very close to dying at that point. I’m being honest about that. The book is honest, it’s self-deprecating. I’m not shirking my responsibilities. I apologise when I need to.”
Collins has spoken about his struggle with alcohol in the past, explaining that heavy drinking nearly cost him his life and he would open a bottle of wine at 11am in the morning at the height of his drinking.
Collins got divorced from his third wife Orianne Cevey, a Swiss national, in 2008. In 2015, he moved to Miami to be closer to his family.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/phil-collins-alcohol-addiction-nearly-died-i-m-not-dead-yet-a7202586.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1620</post_time>
<username>Maya Oppenheim</username>
<post>
Phil Collins has addressed his former alcohol addiction and said he came close to nearly dying due to heavy drinking.
The 65-year-old grammy-award winning singer explained he started drinking more after his third marriage broke up and his family moved away to Miami. 
Collins said he was in turn left with an emotional vacuum and began drinking excessively.
“There’s a chapter in it about the drinking, which escalated when my third marriage broke up, and I retired,” he told The New York Times while talking about his new memoir I’m Not Dead Yet . 
People news in pictures 30 show all People news in pictures 1/30 17 August 2016 Laura Trott, right, kisses her fiance Jason Kenny, left, both of Britain, after he won the men&apos;s keirin cycling final at the Rio Olympic Velodrome during the 2016 Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro
AP
2/30 16 August 2016 Democratic presidential nominee Hillary Clinton welcomes Vice President Joe Biden as he disembarks from Air Force Two for a joint campaign event in Scranton, Pennsylvania
REUTERS
3/30 15 August 2016 Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi gestures as he addresses the nation from the historic Red Fort during Independence Day celebrations in Delhi
REUTERS
4/30 14 August 2016 Jamaica&apos;s Usain Bolt (Top) poses with fellow athletes for a selfie photo as he celebrates after winning the Men&apos;s 100m Final during the athletics event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Olympic Stadium in Rio de Janeiro
AFP/Getty Images
5/30 13 August 2016 Former Cuban President Fidel Castro (2nd L), sitting between Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro (3rd L) and Cuban President Raul Castro (L), is seen attending the celebration of his 90th birthday at the Karl Marx theatre in Havana
AFP/Getty Images
6/30 12 August 2016 Britain&apos;s Prime Minister Theresa May walks in a forest with her husband Philip at the start of a summer holiday in the Alps, in Switzerland
Reuters
7/30 11 August 2016 Pope Francis smiles as he browses through drawings at the Vatican. Pope Francis had lunch with a group of Syrian refugees who were brought to Italy from the Greek island of Lesbos thanks to the pope&apos;s intercession. The Vatican said that the pope brought toys and other gifts for the children, who, in turn, gave him a selection of their drawings
AP
8/30 10 August 2016 Turkey&apos;s President Tayyip Erdogan addresses his supporters in front of the Presidential Palace in Ankara
REUTERS
9/30 9 August 2016 Cast member Salma Hayek takes a selfie with co-stars (L-R) Nick Kroll, Paul Rudd, Seth Rogen, Michael Cera and Danny McBride at the premiere for the movie &quot;Sausage Party&quot; in Los Angeles
REUTERS
10/30 19 July 2016 Turkey&apos;s Prime Minister Binali Yildrim addresses members of parliament from his ruling AK Party (AKP) during a meeting at the Turkish parliament in Ankara
REUTERS
11/30 18 July 2016 Melania Trump, wife of Republican U.S. presidential candidate Donald Trump, waves as she arrives to speak at the Republican National Convention in Cleveland
Reuters
12/30 18 July 2016 Britain&apos;s Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson listens to Spain&apos;s Foreign Minister Jose Manuel Garcia-Margallo (L) during an European Union foreign ministers meeting in Brussels
REUTERS
13/30 17 July 2016 Turkey&apos;s President Recep Tayyip Erdogan reacts after attending the funeral of a victim of the coup attempt in Istanbul
Getty Images
14/30 16 July 2016 Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump, introduces Gov. Mike Pence, during a campaign event to announce Pence as the vice presidential running mate, in New York. Trump called Pence &quot;my partner in this campaign&quot; and his first and best choice to join him on a winning Republican presidential ticket
AP
15/30 15 July 2016 French President Francois Hollande looks on as he speaks to journalists at the Prefectoral Palace the day after a gunman smashed a truck into a crowd of revellers celebrating Bastille Day in Nice, killing at least 84 people
AFP/Getty Images
16/30 14 July 2016 Newly appointed British Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson leaves his home in north London
AP
17/30 13 July 2016 Queen Elizabeth II welcomes Theresa May at the start of an audience, where she invited the former Home Secretary to become Prime Minister and form a new government, at Buckingham Palace. Former Home Secretary Theresa May becomes the UK&apos;s second female Prime Minister after she was selected unopposed by Conservative MPs to be their new party leader
Getty Images Europe
18/30 13 July 2016 Outgoing British Prime Minister David Cameron is accompanied by his wife Samantha and their children as they hug on the doorsteps upon their departure from No. 10 Downing Street for the last time
EPA
19/30 12 July 2016 Pakistani Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai arrives to celebrate her 19th birthday at the Dadaab refugee camp near the Kenya-Somalia border
REUTERS
20/30 11 July 2016 Britain&apos;s new Conservative Party leader Theresa May receives a kiss from her husband Philip John May, after speaking to members of the media at The St Stephen&apos;s entrance to the Palace of Westminster in London. Theresa May will become the prime minister who leads Britain&apos;s into Brexit talks after her only rival in the race to succeed David Cameron pulled out unexpectedly. May was left as the only contender standing after the withdrawal from the leadership race of Andrea Leadsom, who faced criticism for suggesting she was more qualified to be premier because she had children
AFP/Getty Images
21/30 11 July 2016 Prime Minister David Cameron gestures as he addresses the media outside 10 Downing Street, where he announced that Theresa May would be Britain&apos;s new leader
AFP/Getty Images
22/30 11 July 2016 Andrea Leadsom, a candidate to become the next Conservative Party leader and British prime minister, rules herself out of the leadership battle during a news conference in central London
REUTERS
23/30 10 July 2016 Portugal&apos;s forward Cristiano Ronaldo reacts as he is carried on a stretcher off the pitch by team medics after an injury following a clash with France&apos;s forward Dimitri Payet (not pictured) during the Euro 2016 final football match between Portugal and France at the Stade de France in Saint-Denis, north of Paris
AFP/Getty Images
24/30 10 July 2016 Britain&apos;s Andy Murray kisses the winner&apos;s trophy after his men&apos;s singles final victory over Canada&apos;s Milos Raonic on the last day of the 2016 Wimbledon Championships at The All England Lawn Tennis Club in Wimbledon
AFP/Getty Images
25/30 10 July 2016 British driver Lewis Hamilton celebrates with fans after climbing the paddock fence after winning the British Formula One Grand Prix at Silverstone motor racing circuit in Silverstone
AFP/Getty Images
26/30 9 July 2016 Serena Williams celebrates beating Germany&apos;s Angelique Kerber in the women&apos;s singles final on the thirteenth day of the 2016 Wimbledon Championships in London
AFP/Getty Images
27/30 8 July 2016 Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge and Prince George during a visit to the Royal International Air Tattoo at RAF Fairford 
Getty Images
28/30 8 July 2016 U.S. President Barack Obama delivers remarks on the police shootings in Dallas
Reuters
29/30 7 July 2016 Justice Secretary Michael Gove makes a statement outside the Palace of Westminster, after he was eliminated in the second round of MPs&apos; voting for the Conservative leadership
PA
30/30 6 July 2016 Olympic and Paralympic track star Oscar Pistorius reacts with his sister Aimee Pistorius at his sentence hearing at the North Gauteng High Court in Pretoria. Pistorius has been sentenced to six years in prison for the murder of his girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp
REUTERS
“I was left with this huge void. I didn’t want to work because I wanted to be with the kids, but the kids weren’t there anymore, because they moved to Miami, and I was still in Switzerland.” 
Read more Phil Collins: Singer clears up long-standing rumours “You start drinking, and then you start drinking too much. Then it physically hurts you. I came very close to dying at that point. I’m being honest about that. The book is honest, it’s self-deprecating. I’m not shirking my responsibilities. I apologise when I need to.”
Collins has spoken about his struggle with alcohol in the past, explaining that heavy drinking nearly cost him his life and he would open a bottle of wine at 11am in the morning at the height of his drinking.
Collins got divorced from his third wife Orianne Cevey, a Swiss national, in 2008. In 2015, he moved to Miami to be closer to his family.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2014/05/30/14/phil-collins.jpg</main_image>
</document>
