<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Inc. Magazine Unveils 35th Annual List ofAmerica’s Fastest-Growing Private Companies—the Inc. 5000</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13625554.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Inc. Magazine Unveils 35th Annual List ofAmerica’s Fastest-Growing Private Companies—the Inc. 5000 Share Article For the 3rd Time, REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group Appears on the Inc. 5000 list, Ranking No. 3922 with Three-Year Sales Growth of 75% We are very excited to be named to the Inc5000 list for the third time since our founding 22 years ago. Our growth through the years is attributable to our incredible team members, thought leaders, integration consultants, and partners. Columbus, OH (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Inc. magazine today ranked REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group NO. 3922 on its 35th annual Inc. 5000, the most prestigious ranking of the nation&apos;s fastest-growing private companies. the list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment— its independent small businesses. Companies such as Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees of the Inc. 5000. The 2016 Inc. 5000, unveiled online at Inc.com and with the top 500 companies featured in the September issue of Inc. (available on newsstands August 23) is the most competitive crop in the list’s history. The average company on the list achieved a mind-boggling three-year growth of 433%. The Inc. 5000’s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . “We are very excited to be named to the Inc5000 list for the third time since our founding 22 years ago. Our growth through the years is attributable to our incredible team members, thought leaders, integration consultants, and partners who deliver their best work to the client every day,” comments CEO Tracy Loetz. “We appreciate our clients, past and present, who trust us with their business and system integration initiatives.” REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group is an information technology business and systems integration solutions provider founded in 1994. The company assists clients with &quot;All Things Integration&quot; as it pertains to B2Bi, EDI, MFT, &amp; EAI consulting, professional services, training, software (on-premises, SasS, cloud), managed services, recruiting and full-time placement. &quot;The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” The annual Inc. 5000 event honoring all the companies on the list will be held from October 18 through 20, in San Antonio, TX. Speakers include some of the greatest entrepreneurs of this and past generations, such as best-selling author and strategist Tony Robbins, SoulCycle co-founders Elizabeth Cutler and Julie Rice, Cornerstone OnDemand founder, president and CEO Adam Miller, Marvell Technology Group director and co-founder Weili Dai, and New Belgium Brewing co-founder and executive chair Kim Jordan. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.19</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13625554.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Inc. Magazine Unveils 35th Annual List ofAmerica’s Fastest-Growing Private Companies—the Inc. 5000 Share Article For the 3rd Time, REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group Appears on the Inc. 5000 list, Ranking No. 3922 with Three-Year Sales Growth of 75% We are very excited to be named to the Inc5000 list for the third time since our founding 22 years ago. Our growth through the years is attributable to our incredible team members, thought leaders, integration consultants, and partners. Columbus, OH (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Inc. magazine today ranked REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group NO. 3922 on its 35th annual Inc. 5000, the most prestigious ranking of the nation&apos;s fastest-growing private companies. the list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment— its independent small businesses. Companies such as Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees of the Inc. 5000. The 2016 Inc. 5000, unveiled online at Inc.com and with the top 500 companies featured in the September issue of Inc. (available on newsstands August 23) is the most competitive crop in the list’s history. The average company on the list achieved a mind-boggling three-year growth of 433%. The Inc. 5000’s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at http://www.inc.com/inc5000 . “We are very excited to be named to the Inc5000 list for the third time since our founding 22 years ago. Our growth through the years is attributable to our incredible team members, thought leaders, integration consultants, and partners who deliver their best work to the client every day,” comments CEO Tracy Loetz. “We appreciate our clients, past and present, who trust us with their business and system integration initiatives.” REMEDI Electronic Commerce Group is an information technology business and systems integration solutions provider founded in 1994. The company assists clients with &quot;All Things Integration&quot; as it pertains to B2Bi, EDI, MFT, &amp; EAI consulting, professional services, training, software (on-premises, SasS, cloud), managed services, recruiting and full-time placement. &quot;The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” The annual Inc. 5000 event honoring all the companies on the list will be held from October 18 through 20, in San Antonio, TX. Speakers include some of the greatest entrepreneurs of this and past generations, such as best-selling author and strategist Tony Robbins, SoulCycle co-founders Elizabeth Cutler and Julie Rice, Cornerstone OnDemand founder, president and CEO Adam Miller, Marvell Technology Group director and co-founder Weili Dai, and New Belgium Brewing co-founder and executive chair Kim Jordan. 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
