<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.sellingcrossing.com/rssfeed/xml/rssjobs.AL.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Sales Jobs in  | SellingCrossing.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Account Executive, Marketing Cloud - Salesforce.org - USA-CA-San Francisco</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.employmentcrossing.com/job/Account-Executive,-Marketing-Cloud-Salesforce.org-jobs-in-San-Francisco,-CA-e6495e58773a7009db3dc2acf248be4b</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Profile SF-YSalesforce will consider for employment qualified applicants with criminal histories in a manner consistent with the requirements of the San Francisco Fair Chance Ordinance.What if you were empowered to help solve the most complex problems Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions face today? What if you had the best suite of Marketing products available to help achieve that goal? What if you could work for a social enterprise that believes top line growth is central to giving back to the community? Welcome to your #dreamjob. Salesforce.org is a nonprofit social enterprise that leverages Salesforce&apos;s technology, people and resources to improve communities around the world.Through our 1-1-1 integrated model of corporate philanthropy, Salesforce.org has provided more than 27,000 Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions with affordable best-in-class technology solutions, more than 1 million hours of volunteer service to the community and donated more than $100M in community grants to the social sector. About the position:The Salesforce.org Marketing Solution Specialist is a subject matter expert and trusted advisor who works with nonprofit and higher education prospects and customers to evangelize marketing platform solutions that deliver relevant, personalized journeys across channels and devices. We are seeking an experienced quota-carrying sales executive who can work both as part of a broader Account Team and as an Individual Contributor driving self-generated sales opportunities focused on the Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Pardot product lines. If you have a passion for being at the cutting edge of how Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions engage with their constituents, we want to speak with you! Responsibilities:Collaborate with Account and Territory team to identify target accountsCreate and drive revenue within a specified region and/or list of named accountsGenerate business opportunities through networking, cold-calling, and prospecting in to current Salesforce.org customersOwn the sales cycle for your product suites - from lead generation to closureMeet and exceed all quarterly and annual sales quotasEmpower and enable your Territory team on how to position Marketing Cloud and Pardot products within their accountsDrive brand awareness, campaigns, and lead generation via networking, associations, etc.Maintain accurate account and opportunity forecastingEnsure 100% customer satisfaction and retentionRequirements:A proven team player, sales hunter and closer5 years of outside enterprise software sales experienceStrong preference for Digital Marketing sales experienceStrong preference with prior experience with Exact Target Marketing Cloud, Pardot and Salesforce.comProven track record of sales excellence working as an Individual Contributor and working in a team environmentBe able to work independently and as part of a team in a fast pace, rapid change environmentSuperior professional presence and business acumenExperience selling at the C level - Chief Marketing Officer, Chief Digital Officer, Chief Development Officer, Chief Advancement Officer is a plusAbility to give high-level/overview product demonstrationsWork collaboratively with solution engineering team to create compelling demonstration scenariosAbility to be extremely effective via online meetings, hangouts, and conference callsPassion for working with Nonprofit and/or Higher Education institutionsAbility to travel as needed*LI-Y
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.employmentcrossing.com/job/Account-Executive,-Marketing-Cloud-Salesforce.org-jobs-in-San-Francisco,-CA-e6495e58773a7009db3dc2acf248be4b</post_url>
<post_date>20160818</post_date>
<post_time>0500</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Profile SF-YSalesforce will consider for employment qualified applicants with criminal histories in a manner consistent with the requirements of the San Francisco Fair Chance Ordinance.What if you were empowered to help solve the most complex problems Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions face today? What if you had the best suite of Marketing products available to help achieve that goal? What if you could work for a social enterprise that believes top line growth is central to giving back to the community? Welcome to your #dreamjob. Salesforce.org is a nonprofit social enterprise that leverages Salesforce&apos;s technology, people and resources to improve communities around the world.Through our 1-1-1 integrated model of corporate philanthropy, Salesforce.org has provided more than 27,000 Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions with affordable best-in-class technology solutions, more than 1 million hours of volunteer service to the community and donated more than $100M in community grants to the social sector. About the position:The Salesforce.org Marketing Solution Specialist is a subject matter expert and trusted advisor who works with nonprofit and higher education prospects and customers to evangelize marketing platform solutions that deliver relevant, personalized journeys across channels and devices. We are seeking an experienced quota-carrying sales executive who can work both as part of a broader Account Team and as an Individual Contributor driving self-generated sales opportunities focused on the Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Pardot product lines. If you have a passion for being at the cutting edge of how Nonprofits and Higher Education institutions engage with their constituents, we want to speak with you! Responsibilities:Collaborate with Account and Territory team to identify target accountsCreate and drive revenue within a specified region and/or list of named accountsGenerate business opportunities through networking, cold-calling, and prospecting in to current Salesforce.org customersOwn the sales cycle for your product suites - from lead generation to closureMeet and exceed all quarterly and annual sales quotasEmpower and enable your Territory team on how to position Marketing Cloud and Pardot products within their accountsDrive brand awareness, campaigns, and lead generation via networking, associations, etc.Maintain accurate account and opportunity forecastingEnsure 100% customer satisfaction and retentionRequirements:A proven team player, sales hunter and closer5 years of outside enterprise software sales experienceStrong preference for Digital Marketing sales experienceStrong preference with prior experience with Exact Target Marketing Cloud, Pardot and Salesforce.comProven track record of sales excellence working as an Individual Contributor and working in a team environmentBe able to work independently and as part of a team in a fast pace, rapid change environmentSuperior professional presence and business acumenExperience selling at the C level - Chief Marketing Officer, Chief Digital Officer, Chief Development Officer, Chief Advancement Officer is a plusAbility to give high-level/overview product demonstrationsWork collaboratively with solution engineering team to create compelling demonstration scenariosAbility to be extremely effective via online meetings, hangouts, and conference callsPassion for working with Nonprofit and/or Higher Education institutionsAbility to travel as needed*LI-Y
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.employmentcrossing.com/images/employmentcrossinglogo-200x200.jpg</main_image>
</document>
