<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.business-standard.com/rss/latest.rss</forum>
<forum_title>Latest News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Flood situation remains grim in Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, Uttar Pradesh</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/flood-situation-remains-grim-in-madhya-pradesh-bihar-uttar-pradesh-116082200108_1.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The flood situation in the states of Madhya Pradesh, Bihar and Uttar Pradesh remained grim on Monday morning. 
In Bihar, waters from various rivers were reported to be spreading to new areas in Bhojpur, Buxar, Munger, Bhagalpur and Khagaria districts. 
Low lying areas of Patna, riverine areas of Patna, Vaishali and Saran districts are also reportedly under water. 
Flood-affected people have taken shelter in schools in Patna. 
The movement of trains has been stopped between Chapra and Balia because of submerged railway tracks at many places. 
The surging water of the Rivers Sone and Punpun have spread to the low lying areas of Jahanabad and Arwal districts. 
In Uttar Pradesh, the flood situation in the eastern parts is grim. The River Ganga is rising in many places, including in Allahabad and Varanasi. 
The army has been kept on standby for rescue and rehabilitation efforts in Allahabad. 
Both the Ganga and Yamuna Rivers are rising continuously in the district and people have been told to vacate their homes and move to safer places. 
Over 100 villages are facing a critical flood situation in the district. So far, about 10,000 people have taken shelter in relief camps. 
The National Disaster Response Force is also engaged in Ballai and Banda districts after receiving information on rising water levels. 
Besides Allahabad, the waters of the River Ganga are reportedly rising in Varanasi, Ballia and Mirzapur districts, while the waters of the Yamuna are rising in Banda, Mathura and Allahabad. 
After the release of water from a dam, the Betwa River is also in spate in Hamirpur district. 
Water levels are rising between two to three centimetres per hour. 
In Rajasthan, incessant rains in the south eastern districts have affected normal life. Several over bridges have been submerged, bringing road traffic on these routes to a grinding halt. 
A maximum of 26 centimetres of rainfall has been recorded at the Jakham Dam in the state&apos;s Pratapgarh district. 
Places like Nimbaheda, Badi Sadri and Bhadesar have received 22 centimetres of rainfall in the last 24 hours. 
The districts of Chittorgarh, Baran, Dungarpur, Banswara and Jhalawar have also experienced good rainfall. 
An alert has been sounded in nearby areas of Chambal river in Karauli following an increase in water levels. 
In Madhya Pradesh, torrential rains have lashed western parts even as relief works have gained momentum in Bundelkhand and Vindhya regions. 
Normal life has been affected in Guna, Rajgarh, Shivpuri, Mandsour, Ujjain and other parts of western Madhya Pradesh. Major rivers, including Retam, Chambal, Shivna, Kshipra and Sindh are in spate. ANI   Indians celebrate Independence Day at grand parade in New York Business Standard
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/flood-situation-remains-grim-in-madhya-pradesh-bihar-uttar-pradesh-116082200108_1.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>ANI</username>
<post>
The flood situation in the states of Madhya Pradesh, Bihar and Uttar Pradesh remained grim on Monday morning. 
In Bihar, waters from various rivers were reported to be spreading to new areas in Bhojpur, Buxar, Munger, Bhagalpur and Khagaria districts. 
Low lying areas of Patna, riverine areas of Patna, Vaishali and Saran districts are also reportedly under water. 
Flood-affected people have taken shelter in schools in Patna. 
The movement of trains has been stopped between Chapra and Balia because of submerged railway tracks at many places. 
The surging water of the Rivers Sone and Punpun have spread to the low lying areas of Jahanabad and Arwal districts. 
In Uttar Pradesh, the flood situation in the eastern parts is grim. The River Ganga is rising in many places, including in Allahabad and Varanasi. 
The army has been kept on standby for rescue and rehabilitation efforts in Allahabad. 
Both the Ganga and Yamuna Rivers are rising continuously in the district and people have been told to vacate their homes and move to safer places. 
Over 100 villages are facing a critical flood situation in the district. So far, about 10,000 people have taken shelter in relief camps. 
The National Disaster Response Force is also engaged in Ballai and Banda districts after receiving information on rising water levels. 
Besides Allahabad, the waters of the River Ganga are reportedly rising in Varanasi, Ballia and Mirzapur districts, while the waters of the Yamuna are rising in Banda, Mathura and Allahabad. 
After the release of water from a dam, the Betwa River is also in spate in Hamirpur district. 
Water levels are rising between two to three centimetres per hour. 
In Rajasthan, incessant rains in the south eastern districts have affected normal life. Several over bridges have been submerged, bringing road traffic on these routes to a grinding halt. 
A maximum of 26 centimetres of rainfall has been recorded at the Jakham Dam in the state&apos;s Pratapgarh district. 
Places like Nimbaheda, Badi Sadri and Bhadesar have received 22 centimetres of rainfall in the last 24 hours. 
The districts of Chittorgarh, Baran, Dungarpur, Banswara and Jhalawar have also experienced good rainfall. 
An alert has been sounded in nearby areas of Chambal river in Karauli following an increase in water levels. 
In Madhya Pradesh, torrential rains have lashed western parts even as relief works have gained momentum in Bundelkhand and Vindhya regions. 
Normal life has been affected in Guna, Rajgarh, Shivpuri, Mandsour, Ujjain and other parts of western Madhya Pradesh. Major rivers, including Retam, Chambal, Shivna, Kshipra and Sindh are in spate. ANI   Indians celebrate Independence Day at grand parade in New York Business Standard
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://bsmedia.business-standard.com/_media/bs/img/article/2016-08/21/full/1471785389-3925.jpg</main_image>
</document>
