<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Zacks Investment Research Upgrades Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) to “Buy”</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084369/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-edwards-lifesciences-corp-ew-to-buy/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research note published on Tuesday morning. They currently have $128.00 price target on the medical research company’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Edwards Lifesciences ended the second quarter on an encouraging note, with its financial numbers squarely beating the Zacks Consensus Estimate. Moreover, the upward revision in 2016 guidance raises investor optimism in the stock. Although Edwards’ higher operating expenses might have made investors apprehensive, it is a respite for them to know that the higher expenses were for advanced initiatives adopted by the company to improve its overall sales growth. Nevertheless, management expects to gain traction in the ever expanding TAVR market, based on increasing preference in favor of transcatheter aortic valve replacement as well as compelling clinical evidences, leading to strong adoption of its THV therapy. On the flip side, the company persistently performed poorly on its gross margin front. Competitive headwinds and reimbursement pressure also continue to pose challenges.” 
In other Edwards Lifesciences Corp. news, CEO Michael A. Mussallem sold 49,100 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, August 11th. The shares were sold at an average price of $114.01, for a total transaction of $5,597,891.00. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which can be accessed through this hyperlink . Also, VP Donald E. Bobo, Jr. sold 18,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The shares were sold at an average price of $99.04, for a total transaction of $1,782,720.00. Following the transaction, the vice president now directly owns 62,796 shares in the company, valued at $6,219,315.84. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other institutional investors recently bought and sold shares of the company. Quadrant Capital Group LLC increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 2.3% in the second quarter. Quadrant Capital Group LLC now owns 1,108 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $106,000 after buying an additional 25 shares during the last quarter. Duncker Streett &amp; Co. Inc. increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 10.5% in the second quarter. Duncker Streett &amp; Co. Inc. now owns 1,264 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $126,000 after buying an additional 120 shares during the last quarter. Oakworth Capital Inc. bought a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the second quarter valued at about $126,000. Financial Architects Inc increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 38.9% in the second quarter. Financial Architects Inc now owns 1,697 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $169,000 after buying an additional 475 shares during the last quarter. Finally, MIG Capital LLC bought a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the first quarter valued at about $201,000. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. ( NYSE:EW ) opened at 118.07 on Tuesday. The firm has a 50-day moving average price of $109.57 and a 200-day moving average price of $99.30. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has a 1-year low of $62.53 and a 1-year high of $118.26. The firm has a market cap of $25.13 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 48.79. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) last announced its earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The medical research company reported $0.76 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the Zacks’ consensus estimate of $0.70 by $0.06. The firm had revenue of $759.30 million for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $724.26 million. Edwards Lifesciences Corp.’s revenue for the quarter was up 23.1% on a year-over-year basis. During the same quarter last year, the business posted $0.57 EPS. On average, analysts expect that Edwards Lifesciences Corp. will post $2.87 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
EW has been the topic of a number of other research reports. Canaccord Genuity increased their target price on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $113.00 to $123.00 and gave the stock a buy rating in a research note on Wednesday, April 27th. Piper Jaffray Cos. reiterated an overweight rating and set a $123.00 target price on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Tuesday, June 21st. Barclays PLC increased their target price on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $105.00 to $115.00 and gave the stock an equal weight rating in a research note on Wednesday, July 27th. Credit Suisse Group AG restated a buy rating on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Wednesday, June 8th. Finally, William Blair restated an outperform rating on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Tuesday, June 21st. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, five have issued a hold rating and twenty-one have given a buy rating to the stock. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has an average rating of Buy and an average price target of $118.13. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corporation is focused on technologies that treat structural heart disease and critically ill patients. The Company manufactures heart valve systems and repair products used to replace or repair a patient’s diseased or defective heart valve. It develops hemodynamic monitoring systems used to measure a patient’s cardiovascular function in the hospital setting. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084369/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-edwards-lifesciences-corp-ew-to-buy/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0748</post_time>
<username>Max Byerly</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a research note published on Tuesday morning. They currently have $128.00 price target on the medical research company’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Edwards Lifesciences ended the second quarter on an encouraging note, with its financial numbers squarely beating the Zacks Consensus Estimate. Moreover, the upward revision in 2016 guidance raises investor optimism in the stock. Although Edwards’ higher operating expenses might have made investors apprehensive, it is a respite for them to know that the higher expenses were for advanced initiatives adopted by the company to improve its overall sales growth. Nevertheless, management expects to gain traction in the ever expanding TAVR market, based on increasing preference in favor of transcatheter aortic valve replacement as well as compelling clinical evidences, leading to strong adoption of its THV therapy. On the flip side, the company persistently performed poorly on its gross margin front. Competitive headwinds and reimbursement pressure also continue to pose challenges.” 
In other Edwards Lifesciences Corp. news, CEO Michael A. Mussallem sold 49,100 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, August 11th. The shares were sold at an average price of $114.01, for a total transaction of $5,597,891.00. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which can be accessed through this hyperlink . Also, VP Donald E. Bobo, Jr. sold 18,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The shares were sold at an average price of $99.04, for a total transaction of $1,782,720.00. Following the transaction, the vice president now directly owns 62,796 shares in the company, valued at $6,219,315.84. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other institutional investors recently bought and sold shares of the company. Quadrant Capital Group LLC increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 2.3% in the second quarter. Quadrant Capital Group LLC now owns 1,108 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $106,000 after buying an additional 25 shares during the last quarter. Duncker Streett &amp; Co. Inc. increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 10.5% in the second quarter. Duncker Streett &amp; Co. Inc. now owns 1,264 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $126,000 after buying an additional 120 shares during the last quarter. Oakworth Capital Inc. bought a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the second quarter valued at about $126,000. Financial Architects Inc increased its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 38.9% in the second quarter. Financial Architects Inc now owns 1,697 shares of the medical research company’s stock valued at $169,000 after buying an additional 475 shares during the last quarter. Finally, MIG Capital LLC bought a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the first quarter valued at about $201,000. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. ( NYSE:EW ) opened at 118.07 on Tuesday. The firm has a 50-day moving average price of $109.57 and a 200-day moving average price of $99.30. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has a 1-year low of $62.53 and a 1-year high of $118.26. The firm has a market cap of $25.13 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 48.79. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) last announced its earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The medical research company reported $0.76 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the Zacks’ consensus estimate of $0.70 by $0.06. The firm had revenue of $759.30 million for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $724.26 million. Edwards Lifesciences Corp.’s revenue for the quarter was up 23.1% on a year-over-year basis. During the same quarter last year, the business posted $0.57 EPS. On average, analysts expect that Edwards Lifesciences Corp. will post $2.87 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
EW has been the topic of a number of other research reports. Canaccord Genuity increased their target price on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $113.00 to $123.00 and gave the stock a buy rating in a research note on Wednesday, April 27th. Piper Jaffray Cos. reiterated an overweight rating and set a $123.00 target price on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Tuesday, June 21st. Barclays PLC increased their target price on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $105.00 to $115.00 and gave the stock an equal weight rating in a research note on Wednesday, July 27th. Credit Suisse Group AG restated a buy rating on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Wednesday, June 8th. Finally, William Blair restated an outperform rating on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research note on Tuesday, June 21st. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, five have issued a hold rating and twenty-one have given a buy rating to the stock. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has an average rating of Buy and an average price target of $118.13. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corporation is focused on technologies that treat structural heart disease and critically ill patients. The Company manufactures heart valve systems and repair products used to replace or repair a patient’s diseased or defective heart valve. It develops hemodynamic monitoring systems used to measure a patient’s cardiovascular function in the hospital setting. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/edwards-lifesciences-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
