<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://feeds.gpupdate.net/en/rss.xml</forum>
<forum_title>GPUpdate.net</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Interview: Honda chief on playing catch-up</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.gpupdate.net/en/f1-news/343310/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Interview: Honda chief on playing catch-up 
8:32 – Yusuke Hasegawa arrived as Honda&apos;s new F1 chief at the start of the year, replacing Yasuhisa Arai, after a demanding reunion with McLaren in 2015. GPUpdate.net spoke to him about playing catch-up. How proud are you of the progress Honda has made over the last year? Of course I&apos;m very happy. But it&apos;s difficult, because we&apos;re not satisfied with the current situation. We&apos;ve shown a decent level of steps. But it&apos;s a very difficult question. We&apos;re happier. Compared to where you were last season, is this still a good place to be in? For our level, the size of the team, I think we should be next to Mercedes, Ferrari and Red Bull. We can&apos;t lose to Force India, Toro Rosso or other such private teams. How big was the pressure on Honda when you started the season? Since last year I think we are keeping the big pressure from everybody, including McLaren. What was it like when you joined the Formula 1 project during the pre-season? How was the team and the atmosphere inside it, after the struggles of last season? Frankly speaking, I was very surprised, because the McLaren guys, especially the engineers and mechanics, were very kind to us – they never complain about any faults in the garage. So I was just really surprised. What has changed the most since you arrived? In the winter season we concentrated to improve the three areas of the power unit – reliability, deployment of the electrical energy and the internal combustion engine. I think at the beginning we showed some level of a step up in reliability, so that made the team very confident. Practically, it was very good for the chassis set-up and the driver, to concentrate just on making the car faster. Last year, I think we had so many troubles… How important was winter testing for Honda? We only had two tests in Barcelona, and actually the first week of the Barcelona tests wasn&apos;t very good. Still we had an engine failure, so we had a huge discussion and argument with the team. But at the second test we managed the whole test by just one engine, so it gave the team relief, I think. Again, I think it was very good for them to understand and concentrate on making the car faster. It was a very big step, I think. One problem is that the other manufacturers are not standing still… I think it&apos;s fair to say that, from my point of view, our power unit improvement speed is much faster than the others. Actually, it&apos;s natural, because we are too much behind and we have so much room to improve. For something like the deployment, I think our regeneration is almost double from last year. Where is the Honda power unit compared to Renault, Ferrari and Mercedes now? It&apos;s very difficult to tell the exact gap or number. But I think it&apos;s obvious that our engine is number four on performance level. At the moment Mercedes is first, then Ferrari is second, then Renault is third and then Honda is fourth. We are reducing the gaps, every week, but it&apos;s still number four. But the deployment of the energy level is I think almost at the top level. Honda seems to be making constant improvements this season… Because of the regulation limitations, we can&apos;t apply mechanical updates every race, so we have only applied one update for the mechanical – at Silverstone. But at each other race we are changing and trying to find a good setting. We may introduce another mechanical update, but because of the token system, we can&apos;t introduce small updates at each Grand Prix. Has the token system hurt Honda&apos;s development? I don&apos;t know. We also have a resource limitation. I don&apos;t know what level of improvement we can achieve. Without any token system for next year, at the moment we are looking at engine development, every idea. I don&apos;t decide what update we will introduce for next year, but because we have a chance, it is very good to search any area. What has been your highlight of the season so far? Perhaps Austria? We were very happy in Austria. We introduced a new turbine in Canada, but it&apos;s a very power dominated circuit, so we didn&apos;t expect too much there. In Austria we could compare the total performance, not only the engine but also the chassis. I was very happy there. If you look to next year, can Honda be up there with Mercedes? It is not realistic, but of course we have to aim. It&apos;s very difficult to reduce that gap instantly, but we will aim. What is realistic for Honda? When do you expect to be level with Mercedes? I cannot… the biggest difficult is we analyse the current level of the power and chassis, and we are aiming that little bit update level to overtake them. Even this year we had something like this. We have to achieve this level. But they will improve. When we achieve this level, then we can see the exact gap, including their improvement level as well. We can&apos;t expect too much and we can&apos;t tell exactly what position we will be in next year. What is Honda&apos;s view on the new engine rules, recently outlined by the FIA? Obviously the focus is performance convergence and lower costs… Cost reduction is a very tough challenge, but we understand and we have to accept. I think it is reasonable. But the convergence regulations, we are not happy about that. The FIA mentioned to reduce some of the performance gap of the engine for next year. Even they&apos;d like to check the power level by data, but so far they don&apos;t decide the limit. Naturally, in a couple of years, the gap is getting smaller. From that point of view, the convergence is natural. We don&apos;t want to have such an artificial limitation to converge engine performance. What can we expect from Honda for the rest of 2016? Is the focus already on 2017? I cannot guarantee, but I expect to have another update [in 2016]. It&apos;s still half of the season, and we have another 10 tokens. I decided to spend every token for this year, but of course we can&apos;t keep developing this year&apos;s engine to October or something – after October there is no chance to introduce that in the engine. But we don&apos;t give up the improvement of the engine. What do you need to do over the second half to end 2016 feeling happy? I decided not to aim for a podium, but if we are always fifth, inside the points area, with some luck I think there&apos;s some possibility to get a podium – I think this is a reasonable target.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.gpupdate.net/en/f1-news/343310/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0732</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Interview: Honda chief on playing catch-up 
8:32 – Yusuke Hasegawa arrived as Honda&apos;s new F1 chief at the start of the year, replacing Yasuhisa Arai, after a demanding reunion with McLaren in 2015. GPUpdate.net spoke to him about playing catch-up. How proud are you of the progress Honda has made over the last year? Of course I&apos;m very happy. But it&apos;s difficult, because we&apos;re not satisfied with the current situation. We&apos;ve shown a decent level of steps. But it&apos;s a very difficult question. We&apos;re happier. Compared to where you were last season, is this still a good place to be in? For our level, the size of the team, I think we should be next to Mercedes, Ferrari and Red Bull. We can&apos;t lose to Force India, Toro Rosso or other such private teams. How big was the pressure on Honda when you started the season? Since last year I think we are keeping the big pressure from everybody, including McLaren. What was it like when you joined the Formula 1 project during the pre-season? How was the team and the atmosphere inside it, after the struggles of last season? Frankly speaking, I was very surprised, because the McLaren guys, especially the engineers and mechanics, were very kind to us – they never complain about any faults in the garage. So I was just really surprised. What has changed the most since you arrived? In the winter season we concentrated to improve the three areas of the power unit – reliability, deployment of the electrical energy and the internal combustion engine. I think at the beginning we showed some level of a step up in reliability, so that made the team very confident. Practically, it was very good for the chassis set-up and the driver, to concentrate just on making the car faster. Last year, I think we had so many troubles… How important was winter testing for Honda? We only had two tests in Barcelona, and actually the first week of the Barcelona tests wasn&apos;t very good. Still we had an engine failure, so we had a huge discussion and argument with the team. But at the second test we managed the whole test by just one engine, so it gave the team relief, I think. Again, I think it was very good for them to understand and concentrate on making the car faster. It was a very big step, I think. One problem is that the other manufacturers are not standing still… I think it&apos;s fair to say that, from my point of view, our power unit improvement speed is much faster than the others. Actually, it&apos;s natural, because we are too much behind and we have so much room to improve. For something like the deployment, I think our regeneration is almost double from last year. Where is the Honda power unit compared to Renault, Ferrari and Mercedes now? It&apos;s very difficult to tell the exact gap or number. But I think it&apos;s obvious that our engine is number four on performance level. At the moment Mercedes is first, then Ferrari is second, then Renault is third and then Honda is fourth. We are reducing the gaps, every week, but it&apos;s still number four. But the deployment of the energy level is I think almost at the top level. Honda seems to be making constant improvements this season… Because of the regulation limitations, we can&apos;t apply mechanical updates every race, so we have only applied one update for the mechanical – at Silverstone. But at each other race we are changing and trying to find a good setting. We may introduce another mechanical update, but because of the token system, we can&apos;t introduce small updates at each Grand Prix. Has the token system hurt Honda&apos;s development? I don&apos;t know. We also have a resource limitation. I don&apos;t know what level of improvement we can achieve. Without any token system for next year, at the moment we are looking at engine development, every idea. I don&apos;t decide what update we will introduce for next year, but because we have a chance, it is very good to search any area. What has been your highlight of the season so far? Perhaps Austria? We were very happy in Austria. We introduced a new turbine in Canada, but it&apos;s a very power dominated circuit, so we didn&apos;t expect too much there. In Austria we could compare the total performance, not only the engine but also the chassis. I was very happy there. If you look to next year, can Honda be up there with Mercedes? It is not realistic, but of course we have to aim. It&apos;s very difficult to reduce that gap instantly, but we will aim. What is realistic for Honda? When do you expect to be level with Mercedes? I cannot… the biggest difficult is we analyse the current level of the power and chassis, and we are aiming that little bit update level to overtake them. Even this year we had something like this. We have to achieve this level. But they will improve. When we achieve this level, then we can see the exact gap, including their improvement level as well. We can&apos;t expect too much and we can&apos;t tell exactly what position we will be in next year. What is Honda&apos;s view on the new engine rules, recently outlined by the FIA? Obviously the focus is performance convergence and lower costs… Cost reduction is a very tough challenge, but we understand and we have to accept. I think it is reasonable. But the convergence regulations, we are not happy about that. The FIA mentioned to reduce some of the performance gap of the engine for next year. Even they&apos;d like to check the power level by data, but so far they don&apos;t decide the limit. Naturally, in a couple of years, the gap is getting smaller. From that point of view, the convergence is natural. We don&apos;t want to have such an artificial limitation to converge engine performance. What can we expect from Honda for the rest of 2016? Is the focus already on 2017? I cannot guarantee, but I expect to have another update [in 2016]. It&apos;s still half of the season, and we have another 10 tokens. I decided to spend every token for this year, but of course we can&apos;t keep developing this year&apos;s engine to October or something – after October there is no chance to introduce that in the engine. But we don&apos;t give up the improvement of the engine. What do you need to do over the second half to end 2016 feeling happy? I decided not to aim for a podium, but if we are always fifth, inside the points area, with some luck I think there&apos;s some possibility to get a podium – I think this is a reasonable target.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://adn.gpupdate.net/news/280629.jpg</main_image>
</document>
