<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Looking for Jobs One Job at a Time - CareerAlley</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://careeralley.com/looking-for-jobs-one-job-at-a-time/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Looking for Jobs One Job at a Time CareerAlley Cover letters , Job Search Plan , Resumes 
Your job is out there even if you’re not found it yet. Of course it will become someone else’s job if you don’t find it first. Ah, but how to find it? That is the question that everyone asks and the answer is not as complicated as it seems. 50% of job search is determination (spend the time, knowing where to look, coming up with a job search marketing plan, etc.) and 50% is having the right tools (resume, cover letter, interview questions, etc.). The easy part about helping friends look for a job is telling them what to do and where to look. The hard part is helping them deal with the frustration (which, as you know, can by high at times). Slow and steady progress every day will help you focus on the task at hand. The simple advice here is one job at a time (and one day at a time). 
Make a Plan : Pretty simple, like everything else, if you don’t plan it out it won’t get done. How To Kickstart Your Job Search – Just as the title implies, everything you need to get started on your job search. Posted on JobMob , the article provides a number of useful links from the Job Search Marketing Toolkit (resumes, cover letters and the like) to links on job search checklists, planning and job search strategies to get you on your way. While you are on the site, take a look at the related links on the right hand side of the page as well as the links to related articles at the bottom of the page. Planning for Your Job Search – This is the first in a series of job search planning articles by CareerAlley. This article provides the basic steps you should follow in creating your job search plan, covering the documents you need, lists to create, and all of the other steps you will need in your job search plan. But that’s not all, take a look at the other articles in this series. For Job-Hunting Success, Develop a Comprehensive Job-Search Plan – A comprehensive 10-step plan from Quintcareers.com, this article provides 10 steps to creating a great job search plan. Each step (such as make the time, reflect on what you want, etc.) provides a great overview along with embedded links to related information including creating the basic tools in your Job Search Marketing Toolkit. There are additional tabs at the top of the page for Students, Job-Seekers and Career Changers. Additionally, there are related links on the top left hand side of the page. 
Create Your Toolkit : I speak about the Job Search Marketing Toolkit often, the following links will help you build yours. Building your Resume: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.19</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://careeralley.com/looking-for-jobs-one-job-at-a-time/</post_url>
<post_date>20150522</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Looking for Jobs One Job at a Time CareerAlley Cover letters , Job Search Plan , Resumes 
Your job is out there even if you’re not found it yet. Of course it will become someone else’s job if you don’t find it first. Ah, but how to find it? That is the question that everyone asks and the answer is not as complicated as it seems. 50% of job search is determination (spend the time, knowing where to look, coming up with a job search marketing plan, etc.) and 50% is having the right tools (resume, cover letter, interview questions, etc.). The easy part about helping friends look for a job is telling them what to do and where to look. The hard part is helping them deal with the frustration (which, as you know, can by high at times). Slow and steady progress every day will help you focus on the task at hand. The simple advice here is one job at a time (and one day at a time). 
Make a Plan : Pretty simple, like everything else, if you don’t plan it out it won’t get done. How To Kickstart Your Job Search – Just as the title implies, everything you need to get started on your job search. Posted on JobMob , the article provides a number of useful links from the Job Search Marketing Toolkit (resumes, cover letters and the like) to links on job search checklists, planning and job search strategies to get you on your way. While you are on the site, take a look at the related links on the right hand side of the page as well as the links to related articles at the bottom of the page. Planning for Your Job Search – This is the first in a series of job search planning articles by CareerAlley. This article provides the basic steps you should follow in creating your job search plan, covering the documents you need, lists to create, and all of the other steps you will need in your job search plan. But that’s not all, take a look at the other articles in this series. For Job-Hunting Success, Develop a Comprehensive Job-Search Plan – A comprehensive 10-step plan from Quintcareers.com, this article provides 10 steps to creating a great job search plan. Each step (such as make the time, reflect on what you want, etc.) provides a great overview along with embedded links to related information including creating the basic tools in your Job Search Marketing Toolkit. There are additional tabs at the top of the page for Students, Job-Seekers and Career Changers. Additionally, there are related links on the top left hand side of the page. 
Create Your Toolkit : I speak about the Job Search Marketing Toolkit often, the following links will help you build yours. Building your Resume: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
