<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Army, NSCDC Uncover Another Illegal Oil Well in Lagos</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220134.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Father Mbaka Alleges Plan to Kill Buhari By Monsuru Olowoopejo The Nigerian Army and officers of the Nigeria Security and Civil Defence Corps, NSCDC has uncovered another illegal oil well in Lagos State. This came barely two weeks after the Police and other security agencies discovered about 10 houses on Ibadan and Abeokuta streets in Ilasamaja axis of the state, where dug wells were linked to oil pipelines through which diesel was siphoned. Vanguard gathered that the supposedly dug well, filled with Petroleum Motor Spirit, PMS, (petrol) was discovered last Thursday within the premises of Winners Satellite Church, Iyana-Odo, Igando-Ikotun Local Council Development Area, LCDA. The resident pastor, Oladela Paul, told the NSCDC Lagos Commandant, Tajudeen Balogun, who led the operation, that the church had sent a formal complaint to Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, NNPC, when they noticed the well was filled with PMS. He lamented that months after writing the NNPC, the Church was yet to get any response from the Corporation, adding &quot;the well has become a source of harassment to the church and our members. &quot;Aside the harassment, we are afraid of the impending hazard which we cannot determine.&quot; Confirming the discovery, Balogun in a statement made available to vanguard by NSCDC Public Relation Officer, PRO, Kehinde Bada, said &quot;the visit is to evaluate the extent of the spillage and take necessary actions.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220134.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0721</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Father Mbaka Alleges Plan to Kill Buhari By Monsuru Olowoopejo The Nigerian Army and officers of the Nigeria Security and Civil Defence Corps, NSCDC has uncovered another illegal oil well in Lagos State. This came barely two weeks after the Police and other security agencies discovered about 10 houses on Ibadan and Abeokuta streets in Ilasamaja axis of the state, where dug wells were linked to oil pipelines through which diesel was siphoned. Vanguard gathered that the supposedly dug well, filled with Petroleum Motor Spirit, PMS, (petrol) was discovered last Thursday within the premises of Winners Satellite Church, Iyana-Odo, Igando-Ikotun Local Council Development Area, LCDA. The resident pastor, Oladela Paul, told the NSCDC Lagos Commandant, Tajudeen Balogun, who led the operation, that the church had sent a formal complaint to Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, NNPC, when they noticed the well was filled with PMS. He lamented that months after writing the NNPC, the Church was yet to get any response from the Corporation, adding &quot;the well has become a source of harassment to the church and our members. &quot;Aside the harassment, we are afraid of the impending hazard which we cannot determine.&quot; Confirming the discovery, Balogun in a statement made available to vanguard by NSCDC Public Relation Officer, PRO, Kehinde Bada, said &quot;the visit is to evaluate the extent of the spillage and take necessary actions.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Vanguard. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
