<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.theguardian.com/business/rss</forum>
<forum_title>Economy | The Guardian</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Financial firms shrug off Brexit fears - business live</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2016/aug/22/financial-firms-shrug-off-brexit-fears-business-live</topic_url>
<topic_text>
City firms dispel Brexit gloom Photograph: Stefan Rousseau/PA Nick Fletcher 
Monday 22 August 2016 07.58 BST 
Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Share via Email Share on LinkedIn Share on Google+ Share on WhatsApp Share on Messenger Live feed Show 7.58am BST 07:58 
The oil price has been supported in recent days by hopes that producers will agree measures to tackle oversupply when they meet next month. 
But some of that optimism has now waned, not helped by news that Chinese exports of diesel and gasoline soared in July, and crude has fallen back below $50 a barrel. Brent is currently down 1.85% at $49.94.
Facebook Twitter Google plus Share Share this post Facebook Twitter Google plus close 7.55am BST 07:55 
With no major economic data due and a mixed performance in Asia, European markets are expected to open marginally lower for the most part:
— IGSquawk (@IGSquawk) August 22, 2016 Our European opening calls: $FTSE 6845 down 14
$DAX 10529 down 15
$CAC 4396 down 5 $IBEX 8451 up 0 $MIB 16302 down 8
Facebook Twitter Google plus Share Share this post Facebook Twitter Google plus close 7.53am BST 07:53 
Agenda: Finance firms play down Brexit effect but housing market to struggle Good morning, and welcome to our rolling coverage of the world economy, the financial markets, the eurozone and business. 
The shock outcome to the UK referendum has left investors, politicians and the general public in a state of heightened uncertainty about the future.
Nowhere is this more evident than in two new surveys, with accountancy firm EY saying that the City is less gloomy about the Brexit vote than expected, but a warning from estate agency Countrywide that the housing market will be hit by vote and will not recover until 2018.
EY tracked public statements from 232 banks, insurers, private equity and other financial firms and concluded that only one fifth believed the vote would have negative implications for their business. EY said:

The immediate impact of the referendum has not been as stark as many initially feared.
But the firms were concerned about passporting rights - the laws giving financial companies the right to operate across the 28 EU states - whose future is unclear.
Meanwhile Countrywide said house price growth would slow to 2.5% this year, contract by 1% in 2017 before recovering to 2% in 2018. It said:

Our central view is that the economy will avoid a hard landing, which is good news for housing markets. 
However, the weaker prospects for confidence, household incomes and the labour market mean that we do expect some modest falls in house prices before they return to positive growth towards the end of 2017 and into 2018.
Our economics editor Larry Elliott has also been looking at the implications of Brexit, and says the doom and gloom and predictions of economic armageddon have been overdone:
Related: Brexit Armageddon was a terrifying vision – but it simply hasn’t happened | Larry Elliott 
And there is of course no clear idea yet when Brexit will ever happen, given the uncertainty about when Article 50 - the start of the exit process - will be triggered.
Jon Henley has been looking at the process of leaving the EU, and concludes it will not happen in the immediate future, given that civil servants charged with the task do not yet have an office and hold meetings in Starbucks:
Related: Brexit means Brexit … but the big question is when? 
Facebook Twitter Google plus Share Share this post Facebook Twitter Google plus close
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>29</post_num>
<post_id>post-29</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2016/aug/22/financial-firms-shrug-off-brexit-fears-business-live#comment-81620370</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0846</post_time>
<username>RichardLinsleyHood</username>
<post>
German to pay for the cost of the UK leaving the EU.
Trying to get Germany to pay for other nations inability to get the sums to add up has worked out SO well in the past.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5d9813704e4f4a7710e1b6cf79868e198449c975/0_174_5261_3158/5261.jpg?w=1200&amp;amp;h=630&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;bm=normal&amp;amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxNi8wNS8yNS9vdmVybGF5LWxvZ28tMTIwMC05MF9vcHQucG5n&amp;amp;s=68f47b0ea23caf326e8a9b25334f4f2b</main_image>
</document>
