<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Go Local Interactive Lands on Inc. 5000’s list of Fastest-Growing Private Companies</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13623304.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Go Local Interactive Lands on Inc. 5000’s list of Fastest-Growing Private Companies Share Article Go Local Interactive Ranks No. 3534 on the 2016 Inc. 5000 With Three-Year Sales Growth of 89% Overland Park, Kansas (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Inc. magazine today ranked Go Local Interactive No. 3534 on its 35th annual Inc. 5000, the most prestigious ranking of the nation’s fastest-growing private companies. The list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment – its independent small businesses. Companies such as Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees of the Inc. 5000. “It never crossed my mind that we would end up on the Inc. 5000 list. To be recognized nationally by Inc. is an honor. This achievement is a testament to the hard work and talent of our employees as well as the partnerships we have with each of our clients,” said CEO Jason Barrett. Go Local Interactive in the middle of an exciting season. Since 2013, their staff count has doubled, and continues to grow. Within the past year they’ve also started a local community service initiative and created a partnership with a local non-profit, The Call. Two new products have been added to their services; branding and content marketing. The company foresees continued growth and is pursuing an aggressive five year growth plan. The Inc. 5000’s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all the jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at on Inc.’s website. “The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” Go Local Interactive is a digital marketing company in Overland Park focused on providing clients with handcrafted solutions. They specialize in implementing, managing and tracking their clients’ digital marketing efforts down to the local level – no matter the number of locations or size of the service area. ### 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.69</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/08/prweb13623304.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Go Local Interactive Lands on Inc. 5000’s list of Fastest-Growing Private Companies Share Article Go Local Interactive Ranks No. 3534 on the 2016 Inc. 5000 With Three-Year Sales Growth of 89% Overland Park, Kansas (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Inc. magazine today ranked Go Local Interactive No. 3534 on its 35th annual Inc. 5000, the most prestigious ranking of the nation’s fastest-growing private companies. The list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment – its independent small businesses. Companies such as Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees of the Inc. 5000. “It never crossed my mind that we would end up on the Inc. 5000 list. To be recognized nationally by Inc. is an honor. This achievement is a testament to the hard work and talent of our employees as well as the partnerships we have with each of our clients,” said CEO Jason Barrett. Go Local Interactive in the middle of an exciting season. Since 2013, their staff count has doubled, and continues to grow. Within the past year they’ve also started a local community service initiative and created a partnership with a local non-profit, The Call. Two new products have been added to their services; branding and content marketing. The company foresees continued growth and is pursuing an aggressive five year growth plan. The Inc. 5000’s aggregate revenue is $200 billion, and the companies on the list collectively generated 640,000 jobs over the past three years, or about 8% of all the jobs created in the entire economy during that period. Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at on Inc.’s website. “The Inc. 5000 list stands out where it really counts,” says Inc. President and Editor-In-Chief Eric Schurenberg. “It honors real achievement by a founder or a team of them. No one makes the Inc. 5000 without building something great – usually from scratch. That’s one of the hardest things to do in business, as every company founder knows. But without it, free enterprise fails.” Go Local Interactive is a digital marketing company in Overland Park focused on providing clients with handcrafted solutions. They specialize in implementing, managing and tracking their clients’ digital marketing efforts down to the local level – no matter the number of locations or size of the service area. ### 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
