<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Zacks Investment Research Upgrades American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (MTGE) to Buy</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-american-capital-mortgage-investment-corp-mtge-to-buy-2/1212590/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (NASDAQ:MTGE) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report published on Tuesday. The brokerage currently has $19.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. is a REIT that intends to invest in and manage a leveraged portfolio of agency mortgage investments, non-agency mortgage investments and other mortgage-related investments. The Company is externally managed and advised by American Capital MTGE Management, LLC, an affiliate of American Capital. “ 
Shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. ( NASDAQ:MTGE ) opened at 17.19 on Tuesday. American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. has a 12-month low of $12.01 and a 12-month high of $17.62. The company has a 50-day moving average of $16.49 and a 200 day moving average of $15.18. The firm’s market capitalization is $787.25 million. 
American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (NASDAQ:MTGE) last posted its quarterly earnings results on Monday, August 1st. The real estate investment trust reported $0.85 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.41 by $0.44. During the same quarter in the previous year, the business earned ($0.80) earnings per share. On average, analysts predict that American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. will post $2.68 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Wednesday, July 27th. Shareholders of record on Thursday, June 30th were issued a dividend of $0.40 per share. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Tuesday, June 28th. This represents a $1.60 annualized dividend and a yield of 9.31%. 
In other American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. news, CEO Gary D. Kain sold 53,598 shares of the stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, July 5th. The stock was sold at an average price of $15.61, for a total transaction of $836,664.78. The sale was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is accessible through the SEC website . Also, SVP Donald Holley sold 8,528 shares of the stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, July 5th. The shares were sold at an average price of $15.61, for a total value of $133,122.08. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors recently made changes to their positions in MTGE. AMP Capital Investors Ltd bought a new position in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. during the first quarter valued at approximately $154,000. Wellington Management Group LLP increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 24.0% in the first quarter. Wellington Management Group LLP now owns 1,815,566 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $26,653,000 after buying an additional 351,868 shares during the last quarter. BlackRock Group LTD increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 45.1% in the first quarter. BlackRock Group LTD now owns 23,040 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $338,000 after buying an additional 7,161 shares during the last quarter. Prudential Financial Inc. increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 38.9% in the first quarter. Prudential Financial Inc. now owns 427,952 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $6,282,000 after buying an additional 119,800 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Hilton Capital Management LLC bought a new stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. during the first quarter valued at about $421,000. 
Other analysts have also issued reports about the stock. Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods set a $17.50 price target on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. and gave the stock a buy rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Deutsche Bank AG set a $17.50 price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Wunderlich raised their price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. from $15.00 to $17.00 and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Tuesday, August 2nd. Finally, Credit Suisse Group AG reaffirmed a hold rating and set a $15.50 price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. in a research report on Tuesday, August 2nd. Five research analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating and three have issued a buy rating to the stock. The stock currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average target price of $17.50. 
American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. is a real estate investment trust. The Company invests in, finances and manages a portfolio of real estate-related investments, which the Company defines to include agency residential mortgage-backed securities, non-agency mortgage investments, other mortgage-related investments and other real estate investments. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (MTGE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp.   American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-american-capital-mortgage-investment-corp-mtge-to-buy-2/1212590/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0738</post_time>
<username>Pezhman Azimi</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (NASDAQ:MTGE) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report published on Tuesday. The brokerage currently has $19.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. is a REIT that intends to invest in and manage a leveraged portfolio of agency mortgage investments, non-agency mortgage investments and other mortgage-related investments. The Company is externally managed and advised by American Capital MTGE Management, LLC, an affiliate of American Capital. “ 
Shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. ( NASDAQ:MTGE ) opened at 17.19 on Tuesday. American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. has a 12-month low of $12.01 and a 12-month high of $17.62. The company has a 50-day moving average of $16.49 and a 200 day moving average of $15.18. The firm’s market capitalization is $787.25 million. 
American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (NASDAQ:MTGE) last posted its quarterly earnings results on Monday, August 1st. The real estate investment trust reported $0.85 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.41 by $0.44. During the same quarter in the previous year, the business earned ($0.80) earnings per share. On average, analysts predict that American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. will post $2.68 EPS for the current year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Wednesday, July 27th. Shareholders of record on Thursday, June 30th were issued a dividend of $0.40 per share. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Tuesday, June 28th. This represents a $1.60 annualized dividend and a yield of 9.31%. 
In other American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. news, CEO Gary D. Kain sold 53,598 shares of the stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, July 5th. The stock was sold at an average price of $15.61, for a total transaction of $836,664.78. The sale was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is accessible through the SEC website . Also, SVP Donald Holley sold 8,528 shares of the stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, July 5th. The shares were sold at an average price of $15.61, for a total value of $133,122.08. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors recently made changes to their positions in MTGE. AMP Capital Investors Ltd bought a new position in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. during the first quarter valued at approximately $154,000. Wellington Management Group LLP increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 24.0% in the first quarter. Wellington Management Group LLP now owns 1,815,566 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $26,653,000 after buying an additional 351,868 shares during the last quarter. BlackRock Group LTD increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 45.1% in the first quarter. BlackRock Group LTD now owns 23,040 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $338,000 after buying an additional 7,161 shares during the last quarter. Prudential Financial Inc. increased its stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. by 38.9% in the first quarter. Prudential Financial Inc. now owns 427,952 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock valued at $6,282,000 after buying an additional 119,800 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Hilton Capital Management LLC bought a new stake in shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. during the first quarter valued at about $421,000. 
Other analysts have also issued reports about the stock. Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods set a $17.50 price target on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. and gave the stock a buy rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Deutsche Bank AG set a $17.50 price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Wunderlich raised their price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. from $15.00 to $17.00 and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Tuesday, August 2nd. Finally, Credit Suisse Group AG reaffirmed a hold rating and set a $15.50 price objective on shares of American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. in a research report on Tuesday, August 2nd. Five research analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating and three have issued a buy rating to the stock. The stock currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average target price of $17.50. 
American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. is a real estate investment trust. The Company invests in, finances and manages a portfolio of real estate-related investments, which the Company defines to include agency residential mortgage-backed securities, non-agency mortgage investments, other mortgage-related investments and other real estate investments. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp. (MTGE) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp.   American Capital Mortgage Investment Corp.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/american-capital-mortgage-investment-crp-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
