<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Patterson Cos. (PDCO) Downgraded to Sell at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084359/patterson-cos-pdco-downgraded-to-sell-at-zacks-investment-research/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) from a hold rating to a sell rating in a research report report published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Patterson is expected to benefit from improving end markets (except livestock), which will drive top-line growth. We remain upbeat about the growth prospects of the company’s Animal Health segment. The partnerships with Abaxis and Sirona are expected to help the company gain significant market traction in the near term. The divestiture of Patterson Medical is expected to help the company focus on its core business segments and propel better growth in the long run. Meanwhile, estimates have been stable lately ahead of the company’s first-quarter earnings release. However, unfavorable foreign exchange rate, higher operating expenses and accelerating debt are major concerns at present.” 
In other Patterson Cos. news, CFO Ann B. Gugino sold 750 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $48.86, for a total value of $36,645.00. Following the transaction, the chief financial officer now owns 36,187 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,768,096.82. The transaction was disclosed in a legal filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . 
Other institutional investors have bought and sold shares of the company. Nomura Asset Management Co. Ltd. raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 7.9% in the fourth quarter. Nomura Asset Management Co. Ltd. now owns 27,250 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,232,000 after buying an additional 2,000 shares in the last quarter. Bank of America Corp DE raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 103.7% in the fourth quarter. Bank of America Corp DE now owns 538,451 shares of the company’s stock worth $24,343,000 after buying an additional 274,090 shares in the last quarter. Balyasny Asset Management LLC raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 131.4% in the fourth quarter. Balyasny Asset Management LLC now owns 1,130,696 shares of the company’s stock worth $51,119,000 after buying an additional 642,091 shares in the last quarter. Macquarie Group Ltd. raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 4,246.0% in the fourth quarter. Macquarie Group Ltd. now owns 82,574 shares of the company’s stock worth $3,733,000 after buying an additional 80,674 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Incline Global Management LLC raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 14.5% in the fourth quarter. Incline Global Management LLC now owns 588,069 shares of the company’s stock worth $26,587,000 after buying an additional 74,449 shares in the last quarter. 
Patterson Cos. ( NASDAQ:PDCO ) opened at 46.57 on Tuesday. The firm has a market capitalization of $4.45 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 24.32. Patterson Cos. has a 12-month low of $38.51 and a 12-month high of $50.40. The company’s 50-day moving average price is $48.22 and its 200-day moving average price is $46.07. 
Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) last released its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, May 26th. The company reported $0.77 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.75 by $0.02. The firm had revenue of $1.45 billion for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $1.46 billion. During the same quarter in the prior year, the firm posted $0.88 earnings per share. The business’s revenue for the quarter was up 40.5% on a year-over-year basis. Equities analysts expect that Patterson Cos. will post $2.65 EPS for the current fiscal year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Friday, July 29th. Shareholders of record on Friday, July 15th were given a $0.24 dividend. This represents a $0.96 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 2.06%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Wednesday, July 13th. 
A number of other analysts have also recently issued reports on the company. Off Wall Street started coverage on Patterson Cos. in a research report on Monday, August 8th. They set a sell rating on the stock. Credit Suisse Group AG restated a buy rating and set a $55.00 price objective on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Monday, June 27th. Stifel Nicolaus restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Tuesday, May 31st. Jefferies Group restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Thursday, August 4th. Finally, Evercore ISI cut Patterson Cos. from a buy rating to a hold rating and lowered their price objective for the company from $49.50 to $48.50 in a research report on Friday, May 27th. They noted that the move was a valuation call. Two investment analysts have rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and four have assigned a buy rating to the stock. The company currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average target price of $50.88. 
Patterson Companies, Inc is a distributor serving the dental, veterinary and rehabilitation supply markets. The Company operates through three segments: dental supply, veterinary supply and rehabilitation supply. The dental supply segment provides a range of consumable dental products, clinical and laboratory equipment, and value-added services to dentists, dental laboratories, institutions and other dental healthcare providers across North America. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Patterson Cos. (PDCO) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Patterson Cos.   Patterson Cos.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084359/patterson-cos-pdco-downgraded-to-sell-at-zacks-investment-research/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0747</post_time>
<username>Logan Wallace</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) from a hold rating to a sell rating in a research report report published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Patterson is expected to benefit from improving end markets (except livestock), which will drive top-line growth. We remain upbeat about the growth prospects of the company’s Animal Health segment. The partnerships with Abaxis and Sirona are expected to help the company gain significant market traction in the near term. The divestiture of Patterson Medical is expected to help the company focus on its core business segments and propel better growth in the long run. Meanwhile, estimates have been stable lately ahead of the company’s first-quarter earnings release. However, unfavorable foreign exchange rate, higher operating expenses and accelerating debt are major concerns at present.” 
In other Patterson Cos. news, CFO Ann B. Gugino sold 750 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $48.86, for a total value of $36,645.00. Following the transaction, the chief financial officer now owns 36,187 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,768,096.82. The transaction was disclosed in a legal filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . 
Other institutional investors have bought and sold shares of the company. Nomura Asset Management Co. Ltd. raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 7.9% in the fourth quarter. Nomura Asset Management Co. Ltd. now owns 27,250 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,232,000 after buying an additional 2,000 shares in the last quarter. Bank of America Corp DE raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 103.7% in the fourth quarter. Bank of America Corp DE now owns 538,451 shares of the company’s stock worth $24,343,000 after buying an additional 274,090 shares in the last quarter. Balyasny Asset Management LLC raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 131.4% in the fourth quarter. Balyasny Asset Management LLC now owns 1,130,696 shares of the company’s stock worth $51,119,000 after buying an additional 642,091 shares in the last quarter. Macquarie Group Ltd. raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 4,246.0% in the fourth quarter. Macquarie Group Ltd. now owns 82,574 shares of the company’s stock worth $3,733,000 after buying an additional 80,674 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Incline Global Management LLC raised its position in Patterson Cos. by 14.5% in the fourth quarter. Incline Global Management LLC now owns 588,069 shares of the company’s stock worth $26,587,000 after buying an additional 74,449 shares in the last quarter. 
Patterson Cos. ( NASDAQ:PDCO ) opened at 46.57 on Tuesday. The firm has a market capitalization of $4.45 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 24.32. Patterson Cos. has a 12-month low of $38.51 and a 12-month high of $50.40. The company’s 50-day moving average price is $48.22 and its 200-day moving average price is $46.07. 
Patterson Cos. (NASDAQ:PDCO) last released its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, May 26th. The company reported $0.77 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.75 by $0.02. The firm had revenue of $1.45 billion for the quarter, compared to the consensus estimate of $1.46 billion. During the same quarter in the prior year, the firm posted $0.88 earnings per share. The business’s revenue for the quarter was up 40.5% on a year-over-year basis. Equities analysts expect that Patterson Cos. will post $2.65 EPS for the current fiscal year. 
The business also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Friday, July 29th. Shareholders of record on Friday, July 15th were given a $0.24 dividend. This represents a $0.96 dividend on an annualized basis and a yield of 2.06%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend was Wednesday, July 13th. 
A number of other analysts have also recently issued reports on the company. Off Wall Street started coverage on Patterson Cos. in a research report on Monday, August 8th. They set a sell rating on the stock. Credit Suisse Group AG restated a buy rating and set a $55.00 price objective on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Monday, June 27th. Stifel Nicolaus restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Tuesday, May 31st. Jefferies Group restated a hold rating on shares of Patterson Cos. in a research report on Thursday, August 4th. Finally, Evercore ISI cut Patterson Cos. from a buy rating to a hold rating and lowered their price objective for the company from $49.50 to $48.50 in a research report on Friday, May 27th. They noted that the move was a valuation call. Two investment analysts have rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and four have assigned a buy rating to the stock. The company currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average target price of $50.88. 
Patterson Companies, Inc is a distributor serving the dental, veterinary and rehabilitation supply markets. The Company operates through three segments: dental supply, veterinary supply and rehabilitation supply. The dental supply segment provides a range of consumable dental products, clinical and laboratory equipment, and value-added services to dentists, dental laboratories, institutions and other dental healthcare providers across North America. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Patterson Cos. (PDCO) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Patterson Cos.   Patterson Cos.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/patterson-companies-inc-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
