<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.mideasttime.com/feed</forum>
<forum_title>Mideast Time</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) Upgraded to Buy at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/weingarten-realty-investors-wri-upgraded-to-buy-at-zacks-investment-research/1212606/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report released on Tuesday morning. Zacks Investment Research currently has $47.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Weingarten Realty Investors is focused on delivering solid returns to shareholders by actively developing, acquiring, and intensively managing properties in twenty one states that span the southern portion of the United States from coast to coast. Weingarten’s business activities encompass the long-term ownership, management, acquisition, development and redevelopment of strategically located neighborhood and community shopping centers and select industrial properties. The vast majority of our shopping centers are anchored by either a supermarket or a national value-oriented retailer. These anchors combined with convenient locations, attractive and well-maintained properties and a strong tenant mix help to ensure the long-term success of our merchants and the viability of our portfolio. The Company’s portfolio of Thirf caproperties includes thirty neighborhood and community shopping centers and sixty four industrial properties, aggregating fourty million square feet. “ 
Shares of Weingarten Realty Investors ( NYSE:WRI ) opened at 40.94 on Tuesday. The firm’s 50-day moving average price is $42.01 and its 200-day moving average price is $38.42. The firm has a market capitalization of $5.23 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 22.08. Weingarten Realty Investors has a 12 month low of $30.21 and a 12 month high of $43.70. 
Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) last posted its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, July 28th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.57 EPS for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.56 by $0.01. During the same period in the prior year, the firm posted $0.54 EPS. The business earned $135.70 million during the quarter, compared to analyst estimates of $129.52 million. Weingarten Realty Investors’s revenue for the quarter was up 6.8% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, equities analysts anticipate that Weingarten Realty Investors will post $2.30 earnings per share for the current year. 
The company also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Stockholders of record on Thursday, September 8th will be paid a dividend of $0.365 per share. This represents a $1.46 annualized dividend and a dividend yield of 3.57%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend is Tuesday, September 6th. 
In related news, CFO Stephen C. Richter sold 18,000 shares of the company’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of C$42.80, for a total value of C$770,400.00. Following the completion of the sale, the chief financial officer now owns 266,593 shares in the company, valued at C$11,410,180.40. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, CEO Andrew M. Alexander sold 66,224 shares of the company’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of C$41.59, for a total value of C$2,754,256.16. Following the completion of the sale, the chief executive officer now owns 1,167,577 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately C$48,559,527.43. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other large investors recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Deutsche Bank AG increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 4,490.8% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 3,369,211 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $116,503,000 after buying an additional 3,295,821 shares in the last quarter. NN Investment Partners Holdings N.V. increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 4,295.8% in the second quarter. NN Investment Partners Holdings N.V. now owns 1,168,584 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $47,702,000 after buying an additional 1,142,000 shares in the last quarter. Norges Bank bought a new stake in Weingarten Realty Investors during the fourth quarter worth approximately $34,125,000. Hermes Investment Management Ltd. increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 72.0% in the second quarter. Hermes Investment Management Ltd. now owns 1,008,675 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $41,174,000 after buying an additional 422,228 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Renaissance Technologies LLC increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 220.0% in the first quarter. Renaissance Technologies LLC now owns 535,000 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $20,073,000 after buying an additional 367,800 shares in the last quarter. 
WRI has been the topic of a number of other research reports. Boenning Scattergood assumed coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a research note on Tuesday, June 28th. They issued an underperform rating and a $35.50 price objective on the stock. Citigroup Inc. upped their price target on Weingarten Realty Investors from $40.00 to $42.00 and gave the company a neutral rating in a research note on Friday, August 12th. Finally, Jefferies Group assumed coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a research note on Thursday, June 30th. They set a hold rating and a $40.00 price target on the stock. 
Weingarten Realty Investors is a real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company’s primary business is leasing space to tenants in the shopping centers it owns or leases. It is engaged in the business of owning, managing and developing retail shopping centers. Its properties consist primarily of neighborhood and community shopping centers. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Weingarten Realty Investors   Weingarten Realty Investors  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.mideasttime.com/weingarten-realty-investors-wri-upgraded-to-buy-at-zacks-investment-research/1212606/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0746</post_time>
<username>Shayan Afkhami</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report released on Tuesday morning. Zacks Investment Research currently has $47.00 target price on the real estate investment trust’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Weingarten Realty Investors is focused on delivering solid returns to shareholders by actively developing, acquiring, and intensively managing properties in twenty one states that span the southern portion of the United States from coast to coast. Weingarten’s business activities encompass the long-term ownership, management, acquisition, development and redevelopment of strategically located neighborhood and community shopping centers and select industrial properties. The vast majority of our shopping centers are anchored by either a supermarket or a national value-oriented retailer. These anchors combined with convenient locations, attractive and well-maintained properties and a strong tenant mix help to ensure the long-term success of our merchants and the viability of our portfolio. The Company’s portfolio of Thirf caproperties includes thirty neighborhood and community shopping centers and sixty four industrial properties, aggregating fourty million square feet. “ 
Shares of Weingarten Realty Investors ( NYSE:WRI ) opened at 40.94 on Tuesday. The firm’s 50-day moving average price is $42.01 and its 200-day moving average price is $38.42. The firm has a market capitalization of $5.23 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 22.08. Weingarten Realty Investors has a 12 month low of $30.21 and a 12 month high of $43.70. 
Weingarten Realty Investors (NYSE:WRI) last posted its quarterly earnings data on Thursday, July 28th. The real estate investment trust reported $0.57 EPS for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.56 by $0.01. During the same period in the prior year, the firm posted $0.54 EPS. The business earned $135.70 million during the quarter, compared to analyst estimates of $129.52 million. Weingarten Realty Investors’s revenue for the quarter was up 6.8% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, equities analysts anticipate that Weingarten Realty Investors will post $2.30 earnings per share for the current year. 
The company also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which will be paid on Thursday, September 15th. Stockholders of record on Thursday, September 8th will be paid a dividend of $0.365 per share. This represents a $1.46 annualized dividend and a dividend yield of 3.57%. The ex-dividend date of this dividend is Tuesday, September 6th. 
In related news, CFO Stephen C. Richter sold 18,000 shares of the company’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 2nd. The stock was sold at an average price of C$42.80, for a total value of C$770,400.00. Following the completion of the sale, the chief financial officer now owns 266,593 shares in the company, valued at C$11,410,180.40. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, CEO Andrew M. Alexander sold 66,224 shares of the company’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 16th. The shares were sold at an average price of C$41.59, for a total value of C$2,754,256.16. Following the completion of the sale, the chief executive officer now owns 1,167,577 shares of the company’s stock, valued at approximately C$48,559,527.43. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
Other large investors recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Deutsche Bank AG increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 4,490.8% in the fourth quarter. Deutsche Bank AG now owns 3,369,211 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $116,503,000 after buying an additional 3,295,821 shares in the last quarter. NN Investment Partners Holdings N.V. increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 4,295.8% in the second quarter. NN Investment Partners Holdings N.V. now owns 1,168,584 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $47,702,000 after buying an additional 1,142,000 shares in the last quarter. Norges Bank bought a new stake in Weingarten Realty Investors during the fourth quarter worth approximately $34,125,000. Hermes Investment Management Ltd. increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 72.0% in the second quarter. Hermes Investment Management Ltd. now owns 1,008,675 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $41,174,000 after buying an additional 422,228 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Renaissance Technologies LLC increased its stake in Weingarten Realty Investors by 220.0% in the first quarter. Renaissance Technologies LLC now owns 535,000 shares of the real estate investment trust’s stock worth $20,073,000 after buying an additional 367,800 shares in the last quarter. 
WRI has been the topic of a number of other research reports. Boenning Scattergood assumed coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a research note on Tuesday, June 28th. They issued an underperform rating and a $35.50 price objective on the stock. Citigroup Inc. upped their price target on Weingarten Realty Investors from $40.00 to $42.00 and gave the company a neutral rating in a research note on Friday, August 12th. Finally, Jefferies Group assumed coverage on Weingarten Realty Investors in a research note on Thursday, June 30th. They set a hold rating and a $40.00 price target on the stock. 
Weingarten Realty Investors is a real estate investment trust (REIT). The Company’s primary business is leasing space to tenants in the shopping centers it owns or leases. It is engaged in the business of owning, managing and developing retail shopping centers. Its properties consist primarily of neighborhood and community shopping centers. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Weingarten Realty Investors (WRI) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Weingarten Realty Investors   Weingarten Realty Investors  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>EU</country>
<main_image>http://www.mideasttime.com/logos/weingarten-realty-investors-logo.jpg</main_image>
</document>
