<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes Celebrates Opening of 100th Location with Nationwide Giveaways</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/mooyah/franchise/prweb13627380.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes Celebrates Opening of 100th Location with Nationwide Giveaways Share Article Leading Better Burger Franchise Crosses Major Development Milestone; Gives Away Free Fries for a Year at All Locations on August 29th Dallas (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes, a national leader in the booming fast-casual burger segment, has been raising the bar in the increasingly popular industry for nearly a decade. With a commitment to serving only the best products in a friendly, service-oriented setting, the brand is bringing its unique burger experience to new communities across the country at record rates. And now, MOOYAH is celebrating a major milestone: its 100th restaurant is officially open for business and they are celebrating in a big way. The 100th location began serving MOOYAH’s mouthwatering burgers, signature fries and decadent shakes on Tuesday, August 16th in Tuscaloosa, Alabama. Restaurant operations are being led by veteran MOOYAH franchisee, Denney Barrow and his son, Jordan and daughter-in-law, Carrie Barrow, who own and operate two other locations in Birmingham. This new location is adjacent to the University of Alabama, Jordan’s alma mater. The celebration surrounding MOOYAH’s major development milestone isn’t limited to its 100th location in Alabama. The brand is also kicking off a series of nationwide giveaways. On August 29th, all 100 MOOYAH locations in the United States will be giving out iconic “Fresh Hot Buns” t-shirts and free fries for a year to its first 100 Guests in line. The 100th opening celebration also extends to MOOYAH Rewards App users. MOOYAH will be giving away $100 in App Rewards every day for 100 days. Guests who scan their receipt barcodes will automatically be entered to be one of the 10 daily winners of $10 Rewards. Beyond its consumer giveaways, MOOYAH is also celebrating the 100-unit milestone by offering prospective business owners a unique deal: free royalties for the first 100 days after their location opens. Franchisees who sign development deals during the 100 days, between August 29th and December 7th, will enjoy this exclusive celebratory offer. “Hitting the 100-unit mark solidifies our place as a major player in the better burger segment,” said MOOYAH Chief Operating Officer Michael Mabry. “We’re excited to continue building on this momentum by partnering with entrepreneurs like the Barrows who share MOOYAH’s vision of a seriously fun atmosphere that serves seriously good burgers, fries and shakes.” MOOYAH’s 100th unit opening comes as the brand celebrates a strong start to the year. The brand is on pace to meet its goal of opening 30 new units domestically and internationally by the end of 2016. MOOYAH is also poised to break into new key growth markets, while continuing to expand in other regions across the country where brand loyalty is already strong. “MOOYAH’s rapid expansion is a testament to our brand offering,” said Rich Hicks, MOOYAH chief executive officer. “MOOYAH’s classic concept paired with our customizable menu and high quality ingredients is a recipe for success. We plan to continue this growth and bring our seriously fun attitude and impeccable food to new communities throughout the U.S. and around the world.” At MOOYAH, Guests have the advantage of choosing from a variety of bun options, like baked in-house potato or multigrain wheat buns or handcrafted lettuce buns to accompany a never-frozen, 100 percent American beef patty, all natural Jennie-O turkey patty or mouthwatering black bean veggie patty. Each gourmet burger can be customized with five cheese options, Applewood smoked bacon and sliced avocado, along with nine free veggie toppings and 11 free sauces. MOOYAH’s hand-cut French fries are created through a six-step process that takes a total of 24 hours to prepare. A combination of constant attention and a recipe perfected over more than a decade transform U.S. #1 Idaho potatoes into perfect, crisp-on-the-outside and fluffy-on-the-inside fries. Guests also have the choice of savory sweet potato fries. MOOYAH also offers real ice cream shakes, allowing Guests to choose from 10 flavors ranging from vanilla to Hershey’s chocolate to Reese’s to strawberry banana and more. For more information on the growing brand, connect with MOOYAH on Facebook at the MOOYAH Burgers &amp; Fries Fan page or follow MOOYAH on Twitter and Instagram @MOOYAHBurgers. For franchising opportunities, please visit http://www.mooyahfranchise.com/ . ABOUT MOOYAH BURGERS, FRIES &amp; SHAKES MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes is a fast-casual, “better burger” concept offering mouthwatering made-to-order burgers, French fries hand cut from Idaho potatoes, and real ice cream shakes. Founded in 2007, the Plano, Texas-based company serves fresh, lean American beef, all-natural Jennie-O® turkey burgers, black bean veggie burgers, buns baked in-house daily, real cheeses and toppings made from garden-fresh veggies. While many Guests dine in-restaurant, MOOYAH also offers online ordering and carry out for Guests on the go. In 2016, MOOYAH was ranked No. 38 in Fast Casual Magazine’s annual Top 100 Movers &amp; Shakers, a list they have been included in for several years in a row. The brand also ranked 2nd in Best Fast Casual Restaurant Franchise Company, 4th in Best Restaurant Franchise Company, and 7th in Best Overall Franchises Company by Franchiserankings.com. For more information on MOOYAH, its menu or franchising opportunities, please visit http://www.MOOYAH.com . Connect with the brand on Facebook.com/MOOYAH, follow on Twitter and Instagram @MOOYAHburgers. ### 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.02</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/mooyah/franchise/prweb13627380.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160204</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes Celebrates Opening of 100th Location with Nationwide Giveaways Share Article Leading Better Burger Franchise Crosses Major Development Milestone; Gives Away Free Fries for a Year at All Locations on August 29th Dallas (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes, a national leader in the booming fast-casual burger segment, has been raising the bar in the increasingly popular industry for nearly a decade. With a commitment to serving only the best products in a friendly, service-oriented setting, the brand is bringing its unique burger experience to new communities across the country at record rates. And now, MOOYAH is celebrating a major milestone: its 100th restaurant is officially open for business and they are celebrating in a big way. The 100th location began serving MOOYAH’s mouthwatering burgers, signature fries and decadent shakes on Tuesday, August 16th in Tuscaloosa, Alabama. Restaurant operations are being led by veteran MOOYAH franchisee, Denney Barrow and his son, Jordan and daughter-in-law, Carrie Barrow, who own and operate two other locations in Birmingham. This new location is adjacent to the University of Alabama, Jordan’s alma mater. The celebration surrounding MOOYAH’s major development milestone isn’t limited to its 100th location in Alabama. The brand is also kicking off a series of nationwide giveaways. On August 29th, all 100 MOOYAH locations in the United States will be giving out iconic “Fresh Hot Buns” t-shirts and free fries for a year to its first 100 Guests in line. The 100th opening celebration also extends to MOOYAH Rewards App users. MOOYAH will be giving away $100 in App Rewards every day for 100 days. Guests who scan their receipt barcodes will automatically be entered to be one of the 10 daily winners of $10 Rewards. Beyond its consumer giveaways, MOOYAH is also celebrating the 100-unit milestone by offering prospective business owners a unique deal: free royalties for the first 100 days after their location opens. Franchisees who sign development deals during the 100 days, between August 29th and December 7th, will enjoy this exclusive celebratory offer. “Hitting the 100-unit mark solidifies our place as a major player in the better burger segment,” said MOOYAH Chief Operating Officer Michael Mabry. “We’re excited to continue building on this momentum by partnering with entrepreneurs like the Barrows who share MOOYAH’s vision of a seriously fun atmosphere that serves seriously good burgers, fries and shakes.” MOOYAH’s 100th unit opening comes as the brand celebrates a strong start to the year. The brand is on pace to meet its goal of opening 30 new units domestically and internationally by the end of 2016. MOOYAH is also poised to break into new key growth markets, while continuing to expand in other regions across the country where brand loyalty is already strong. “MOOYAH’s rapid expansion is a testament to our brand offering,” said Rich Hicks, MOOYAH chief executive officer. “MOOYAH’s classic concept paired with our customizable menu and high quality ingredients is a recipe for success. We plan to continue this growth and bring our seriously fun attitude and impeccable food to new communities throughout the U.S. and around the world.” At MOOYAH, Guests have the advantage of choosing from a variety of bun options, like baked in-house potato or multigrain wheat buns or handcrafted lettuce buns to accompany a never-frozen, 100 percent American beef patty, all natural Jennie-O turkey patty or mouthwatering black bean veggie patty. Each gourmet burger can be customized with five cheese options, Applewood smoked bacon and sliced avocado, along with nine free veggie toppings and 11 free sauces. MOOYAH’s hand-cut French fries are created through a six-step process that takes a total of 24 hours to prepare. A combination of constant attention and a recipe perfected over more than a decade transform U.S. #1 Idaho potatoes into perfect, crisp-on-the-outside and fluffy-on-the-inside fries. Guests also have the choice of savory sweet potato fries. MOOYAH also offers real ice cream shakes, allowing Guests to choose from 10 flavors ranging from vanilla to Hershey’s chocolate to Reese’s to strawberry banana and more. For more information on the growing brand, connect with MOOYAH on Facebook at the MOOYAH Burgers &amp; Fries Fan page or follow MOOYAH on Twitter and Instagram @MOOYAHBurgers. For franchising opportunities, please visit http://www.mooyahfranchise.com/ . ABOUT MOOYAH BURGERS, FRIES &amp; SHAKES MOOYAH Burgers, Fries &amp; Shakes is a fast-casual, “better burger” concept offering mouthwatering made-to-order burgers, French fries hand cut from Idaho potatoes, and real ice cream shakes. Founded in 2007, the Plano, Texas-based company serves fresh, lean American beef, all-natural Jennie-O® turkey burgers, black bean veggie burgers, buns baked in-house daily, real cheeses and toppings made from garden-fresh veggies. While many Guests dine in-restaurant, MOOYAH also offers online ordering and carry out for Guests on the go. In 2016, MOOYAH was ranked No. 38 in Fast Casual Magazine’s annual Top 100 Movers &amp; Shakers, a list they have been included in for several years in a row. The brand also ranked 2nd in Best Fast Casual Restaurant Franchise Company, 4th in Best Restaurant Franchise Company, and 7th in Best Overall Franchises Company by Franchiserankings.com. For more information on MOOYAH, its menu or franchising opportunities, please visit http://www.MOOYAH.com . Connect with the brand on Facebook.com/MOOYAH, follow on Twitter and Instagram @MOOYAHburgers. ### 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/02/04/13627380/mooy.png</main_image>
</document>
