<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Western Refining Inc. (WNR) Upgraded at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084357/western-refining-inc-wnr-upgraded-at-zacks-investment-research-2/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Western Refining Inc. (NYSE:WNR) from a strong sell rating to a hold rating in a research report report published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Western Refining revealed that the third quarter had a reassuring start with demand for gasoline remaining favorable. Further, the price of crude, which the company uses as an input for manufacturing refined products, is way below the mid-2014 level. Both the events are likely to help the company generate significant cash flow going ahead. Moreover, the company has a history of creating value for its shareholders by increasing dividend and repurchasing shares. However, investors&apos; pessimistic outlook could be gauged from the company&apos;s suppressed share price that has plunged around 32% year-to-date. Moreover, the elevated debt levels following the NTI acquisition is another headwind that needs to be addressed.” 
Western Refining ( NYSE:WNR ) opened at 23.43 on Tuesday. The stock has a market cap of $2.54 billion and a PE ratio of 8.33. Western Refining has a 1-year low of $18.14 and a 1-year high of $47.55. The company’s 50 day moving average is $21.70 and its 200-day moving average is $24.35. 
Western Refining (NYSE:WNR) last posted its earnings results on Tuesday, August 2nd. The company reported $0.72 EPS for the quarter, beating the Zacks’ consensus estimate of $0.51 by $0.21. The firm had revenue of $2.11 billion for the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $2.11 billion. The company’s revenue was down 25.5% on a year-over-year basis. During the same period in the previous year, the company earned $1.44 EPS. Equities research analysts forecast that Western Refining will post $1.19 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently disclosed a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Tuesday, August 9th. Stockholders of record on Monday, July 25th were paid a $0.38 dividend. The ex-dividend date was Thursday, July 21st. This represents a $1.52 dividend on an annualized basis and a dividend yield of 6.49%. 
In other Western Refining news, Chairman Paul L. Foster acquired 325,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 9th. The shares were purchased at an average price of $23.59 per share, for a total transaction of $7,666,750.00. Following the completion of the purchase, the chairman now directly owns 3,109,466 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $73,352,302.94. The acquisition was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . Also, Director Brian John Hogan acquired 10,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Friday, May 27th. The stock was acquired at an average price of $21.37 per share, for a total transaction of $213,700.00. Following the purchase, the director now directly owns 78,463 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,676,754.31. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
Several hedge funds have added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Cornerstone Capital Management Holdings LLC. raised its stake in Western Refining by 75.1% in the fourth quarter. Cornerstone Capital Management Holdings LLC. now owns 44,821 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,597,000 after buying an additional 19,221 shares during the last quarter. Wells Fargo &amp; Company MN raised its stake in Western Refining by 17.0% in the fourth quarter. Wells Fargo &amp; Company MN now owns 1,024,455 shares of the company’s stock worth $36,491,000 after buying an additional 148,625 shares during the last quarter. Principal Financial Group Inc. raised its stake in Western Refining by 0.6% in the fourth quarter. Principal Financial Group Inc. now owns 368,897 shares of the company’s stock valued at $13,140,000 after buying an additional 2,367 shares in the last quarter. Marshall Wace LLP purchased a new stake in Western Refining during the fourth quarter valued at approximately $1,613,000. Finally, Systematic Financial Management LP raised its stake in Western Refining by 9.1% in the fourth quarter. Systematic Financial Management LP now owns 242,289 shares of the company’s stock valued at $8,630,000 after buying an additional 20,225 shares in the last quarter. 
A number of other research firms have also recently commented on WNR. Morgan Stanley set a $21.00 target price on shares of Western Refining and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Tudor Pickering raised shares of Western Refining from a sell rating to a hold rating in a research report on Tuesday, June 28th. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. reissued a neutral rating and set a $22.00 target price on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Thursday, July 14th. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. cut shares of Western Refining from a neutral rating to an underweight rating and decreased their target price for the company from $28.00 to $20.00 in a research report on Friday, June 10th. Finally, Wells Fargo &amp; Co. reissued a hold rating on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Saturday, July 9th. One analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, eight have given a hold rating and three have assigned a buy rating to the company. Western Refining currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average price target of $32.11. 
Western Refining, Inc (Western) is a crude oil refiner and marketer of refined products. The Company operates through four segments: refining, Northern Tier Energy LP (NTI), Western Refining Logistics, LP (WNRL) and retail. Its refining segment owns and operates over two refineries in the Southwest that process crude oil and other feedstocks into gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel and asphalt. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Western Refining (WNR) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Western Refining Inc.   Western Refining Inc.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084357/western-refining-inc-wnr-upgraded-at-zacks-investment-research-2/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0747</post_time>
<username>Logan Wallace</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Western Refining Inc. (NYSE:WNR) from a strong sell rating to a hold rating in a research report report published on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Western Refining revealed that the third quarter had a reassuring start with demand for gasoline remaining favorable. Further, the price of crude, which the company uses as an input for manufacturing refined products, is way below the mid-2014 level. Both the events are likely to help the company generate significant cash flow going ahead. Moreover, the company has a history of creating value for its shareholders by increasing dividend and repurchasing shares. However, investors&apos; pessimistic outlook could be gauged from the company&apos;s suppressed share price that has plunged around 32% year-to-date. Moreover, the elevated debt levels following the NTI acquisition is another headwind that needs to be addressed.” 
Western Refining ( NYSE:WNR ) opened at 23.43 on Tuesday. The stock has a market cap of $2.54 billion and a PE ratio of 8.33. Western Refining has a 1-year low of $18.14 and a 1-year high of $47.55. The company’s 50 day moving average is $21.70 and its 200-day moving average is $24.35. 
Western Refining (NYSE:WNR) last posted its earnings results on Tuesday, August 2nd. The company reported $0.72 EPS for the quarter, beating the Zacks’ consensus estimate of $0.51 by $0.21. The firm had revenue of $2.11 billion for the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $2.11 billion. The company’s revenue was down 25.5% on a year-over-year basis. During the same period in the previous year, the company earned $1.44 EPS. Equities research analysts forecast that Western Refining will post $1.19 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently disclosed a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Tuesday, August 9th. Stockholders of record on Monday, July 25th were paid a $0.38 dividend. The ex-dividend date was Thursday, July 21st. This represents a $1.52 dividend on an annualized basis and a dividend yield of 6.49%. 
In other Western Refining news, Chairman Paul L. Foster acquired 325,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, August 9th. The shares were purchased at an average price of $23.59 per share, for a total transaction of $7,666,750.00. Following the completion of the purchase, the chairman now directly owns 3,109,466 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $73,352,302.94. The acquisition was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . Also, Director Brian John Hogan acquired 10,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction dated Friday, May 27th. The stock was acquired at an average price of $21.37 per share, for a total transaction of $213,700.00. Following the purchase, the director now directly owns 78,463 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $1,676,754.31. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
Several hedge funds have added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Cornerstone Capital Management Holdings LLC. raised its stake in Western Refining by 75.1% in the fourth quarter. Cornerstone Capital Management Holdings LLC. now owns 44,821 shares of the company’s stock worth $1,597,000 after buying an additional 19,221 shares during the last quarter. Wells Fargo &amp; Company MN raised its stake in Western Refining by 17.0% in the fourth quarter. Wells Fargo &amp; Company MN now owns 1,024,455 shares of the company’s stock worth $36,491,000 after buying an additional 148,625 shares during the last quarter. Principal Financial Group Inc. raised its stake in Western Refining by 0.6% in the fourth quarter. Principal Financial Group Inc. now owns 368,897 shares of the company’s stock valued at $13,140,000 after buying an additional 2,367 shares in the last quarter. Marshall Wace LLP purchased a new stake in Western Refining during the fourth quarter valued at approximately $1,613,000. Finally, Systematic Financial Management LP raised its stake in Western Refining by 9.1% in the fourth quarter. Systematic Financial Management LP now owns 242,289 shares of the company’s stock valued at $8,630,000 after buying an additional 20,225 shares in the last quarter. 
A number of other research firms have also recently commented on WNR. Morgan Stanley set a $21.00 target price on shares of Western Refining and gave the company a hold rating in a research report on Wednesday, August 3rd. Tudor Pickering raised shares of Western Refining from a sell rating to a hold rating in a research report on Tuesday, June 28th. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. reissued a neutral rating and set a $22.00 target price on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Thursday, July 14th. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. cut shares of Western Refining from a neutral rating to an underweight rating and decreased their target price for the company from $28.00 to $20.00 in a research report on Friday, June 10th. Finally, Wells Fargo &amp; Co. reissued a hold rating on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Saturday, July 9th. One analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, eight have given a hold rating and three have assigned a buy rating to the company. Western Refining currently has a consensus rating of Hold and an average price target of $32.11. 
Western Refining, Inc (Western) is a crude oil refiner and marketer of refined products. The Company operates through four segments: refining, Northern Tier Energy LP (NTI), Western Refining Logistics, LP (WNRL) and retail. Its refining segment owns and operates over two refineries in the Southwest that process crude oil and other feedstocks into gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel and asphalt. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Western Refining (WNR) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Western Refining Inc.   Western Refining Inc.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/western-refining-inc-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
