<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further.</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://frankfortlocalnews.com/looking-for-a-boat-that-will-work-for-you-well-look-no-further/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Events August 22, 2016 You are here: Home / Outdoors / Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. August 12, 2016 By Ted Lund 

Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. 
By Ted Lund 
Chances are, Carolina Skiff has the boat for you. And a great, family friendly choice is the JVX family of boats, available in the Center Console (CC), Side Console (SC) and Super Shallow (SS) series. The JVX Series is designed and rigged with fishing in mind. With the JVX, getting in the shallow creeks and rivers is never an issue. Its light-weight hull with the modified V-hull design gives you a boat that will carry more weight further and faster with less horsepower, while delivering outstanding performance.No matter why you need the JVX, we offer a full array of accessories and options, so you can rig the JVX to fit your needs. The JVX has the patented splash guards to help keep you dry and the positive tracking keels for enhanced maneuvering. From the open bay, to the shallows, chances are, the JVX is exactly the right boat for you and your family. 
The Center Console, Side Console, and Stick Steering JVX models are available in 16-, 18- and 20-foot versions, and each offers a unique layout perfect for a variety of situations. 
The Center Console JVX is perfect for shallow bay and estuary fishing, where anglers might need the comfort of being able to distribute weight and passengers along the centerline afforded by the center console layout. The Side Console features a similar layout that is perfect for bass, walleye and pike fishermen, looking for a minimalist approach with a wide-open deck layout fore and aft. For anglers seeking super-shallow performance where deck-space is at a premium, a tiller-rigged Stick Steer JVX is perfect for fishermen wanting to chase tailing redfish, speckled trout, snook and tarpon in the Southeast and Gulf Coast as well as striped bass and bluefish on the shallows of Nantucket and the rest of the Northeast. 
Regardless of series, the JVX family shares similar characteristics. The 16 tapes out at 15-feet, 10-inches in length and weighs in at 973 pounds and is rated for a maximum six people or 1,652 pounds with a 60-horsepower engine. The 18 measures out at 17-feet, 9-inches, weighing 1,073 pounds and is rated for a 70-horsepower engine. It will take seven passengers with a total weight of 1,652 pounds. The 20 hits the 20-foot mark exactly, and with a 90-horsepower engine will handle up to eight passengers or 1,836 pounds. 
Each of the three will handle 15-, 20- or 25-inch shafts, and the entire JVX family enjoys a super shallow four-inch draft. And like every other member of the Carolina Skiff , Sea Chaser, and Fun Chaser family, the JVX Series enjoys 100-percent all-composite construction, meaning your boat will be around to provide decades of fun on the water for the whole family. 
Boaters know Carolina Skiff is the most durable, versatile, stable and economical boat on the planet — and they’ve maintained their reputation for more than 30 years. From fit to finish, Carolina Skiffs provide the most features and the best functionality available on the market, giving boaters and anglers the best value in both performance and comfort. With more than 60 models across the Carolina Skiff, Sea Chaser and Fun Chaser lines, you are sure to find a boat that meets your personal recreational or commercial needs. 
To learn more, build a custom boat or locate a dealer near you, visit www.carolinaskiff.com or call 800-422-7282. 

</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.08</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://frankfortlocalnews.com/looking-for-a-boat-that-will-work-for-you-well-look-no-further/</post_url>
<post_date>20160812</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Ted Lund</username>
<post>
Events August 22, 2016 You are here: Home / Outdoors / Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. August 12, 2016 By Ted Lund 

Looking for a Boat that will Work for You? Well, look no Further. 
By Ted Lund 
Chances are, Carolina Skiff has the boat for you. And a great, family friendly choice is the JVX family of boats, available in the Center Console (CC), Side Console (SC) and Super Shallow (SS) series. The JVX Series is designed and rigged with fishing in mind. With the JVX, getting in the shallow creeks and rivers is never an issue. Its light-weight hull with the modified V-hull design gives you a boat that will carry more weight further and faster with less horsepower, while delivering outstanding performance.No matter why you need the JVX, we offer a full array of accessories and options, so you can rig the JVX to fit your needs. The JVX has the patented splash guards to help keep you dry and the positive tracking keels for enhanced maneuvering. From the open bay, to the shallows, chances are, the JVX is exactly the right boat for you and your family. 
The Center Console, Side Console, and Stick Steering JVX models are available in 16-, 18- and 20-foot versions, and each offers a unique layout perfect for a variety of situations. 
The Center Console JVX is perfect for shallow bay and estuary fishing, where anglers might need the comfort of being able to distribute weight and passengers along the centerline afforded by the center console layout. The Side Console features a similar layout that is perfect for bass, walleye and pike fishermen, looking for a minimalist approach with a wide-open deck layout fore and aft. For anglers seeking super-shallow performance where deck-space is at a premium, a tiller-rigged Stick Steer JVX is perfect for fishermen wanting to chase tailing redfish, speckled trout, snook and tarpon in the Southeast and Gulf Coast as well as striped bass and bluefish on the shallows of Nantucket and the rest of the Northeast. 
Regardless of series, the JVX family shares similar characteristics. The 16 tapes out at 15-feet, 10-inches in length and weighs in at 973 pounds and is rated for a maximum six people or 1,652 pounds with a 60-horsepower engine. The 18 measures out at 17-feet, 9-inches, weighing 1,073 pounds and is rated for a 70-horsepower engine. It will take seven passengers with a total weight of 1,652 pounds. The 20 hits the 20-foot mark exactly, and with a 90-horsepower engine will handle up to eight passengers or 1,836 pounds. 
Each of the three will handle 15-, 20- or 25-inch shafts, and the entire JVX family enjoys a super shallow four-inch draft. And like every other member of the Carolina Skiff , Sea Chaser, and Fun Chaser family, the JVX Series enjoys 100-percent all-composite construction, meaning your boat will be around to provide decades of fun on the water for the whole family. 
Boaters know Carolina Skiff is the most durable, versatile, stable and economical boat on the planet — and they’ve maintained their reputation for more than 30 years. From fit to finish, Carolina Skiffs provide the most features and the best functionality available on the market, giving boaters and anglers the best value in both performance and comfort. With more than 60 models across the Carolina Skiff, Sea Chaser and Fun Chaser lines, you are sure to find a boat that meets your personal recreational or commercial needs. 
To learn more, build a custom boat or locate a dealer near you, visit www.carolinaskiff.com or call 800-422-7282. 

</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
