<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/63662308/kusa-sports</forum>
<forum_title>KUSA - Sports</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Mongolian wrestling coaches go nuts,...</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/63662308/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;9news&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;mongolian-wrestling-coaches-go-nuts-strip-down-after-unfavorable-decision&amp;#x2f;303856695</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Close Mongolian wrestling coaches go nuts, strip down after unfavorable decision USA TODAY Sports&apos; Rachel Axon tells you the five things to watch for during the final day of competition at the Rio Olympics. USA TODAY Sports Nate Scott, USA TODAY Sports , WXIA 12:10 PM. MDT August 21, 2016 Coaches from Mongolia thought their wrestler, Mandakhnaran Ganzorig, had won his match. When a ruling went against him they protested. Vociferously. p (Photo: Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports)   
RIO DE JANEIRO — Two Mongolian coaches stripped their clothes off after their wrestler Ganzorigiin Mandakhnaran lost the bronze medal match after the judges awarded a penalty point to Uzbekistan’s Ikhtiyor Navruzov. 
As the match ended, it appeared Mandakhnaran had won. His coaches sprinted onto the mat in celebration, one carrying the flag of Mongolia. 
Seconds later, it was Navruzov and his coach who were celebrating after the judges awarded the penalty point. Loading... Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Jack GUEZ JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in wrestling bronze medal match. Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Aug 21, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in a men&apos;s freestyle 65kg wrestling bronze medal match during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 2. Mandatory Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Michael Madrid, Michael Madrid Aug 21, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in a men&apos;s freestyle 65kg wrestling bronze medal match during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 2. Mandatory Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Michael Madrid, Michael Madrid Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
The two Mongolian coaches then tossed a challenge flag, and when the judges explained to them the call couldn’t be challenged, they ran out onto the mat while Mandakhnaran dropped to his knees. 
As the judges attempted to wave them off, the two coaches stripped down in protest — one removing his shirt, and the other removing both his shirt and pants, leaving on only his underwear. Security was brought in as the crowd started cheering “MONGOLIA! MONGOLIA!” 
Eventually security was able to escort the two coaches off the mat. 
Photos: Final day of competition at Rio Olympics Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Fireworks explode during the Closing Ceremony on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracana Stadium on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Flag bearers enter the stadium during the &apos;Heroes of the Games&apos; segment during the Closing Ceremony on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracana Stadium on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Bryn Lennon/Getty Images) Bryn Lennon, 2016 Getty Images Athletes parade during the closing ceremony of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. (Photo: JOHN MACDOUGALL/AFP/Getty Images) JOHN MACDOUGALL RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Demar DeRozan and Kyle Lowry #7 of United States celebrate afer defeating Serbia during the Men&apos;s Gold medal game on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Serbia&apos;s guard Nemanja Nedovic (C) jumps for the basket by USA&apos;s centre DeMarcus Cousins (R) during a Men&apos;s Gold medal basketball match between Serbia and USA during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo: MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Nemanja Nedovic #11 of Serbia drives the ball around Kevin Durant #5 of United States during the Men&apos;s Gold medal game on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images) Mike Ehrmann, 2016 Getty Images Serbia&apos;s power forward Stefan Bircevic (C) is blocked by USA&apos;s guard Paul George (L) during a Men&apos;s Gold medal basketball match between Serbia and USA at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Shakhobidin Zoirov of Uzbekistan celebrates victory over Misha Aloian of Russia in the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the United States and Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands compete during the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Shakhobidin Zoirov of Uzbekistan and Misha Aloian of Russia compete during the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the United States and Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands compete during the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Gold medalist Claressa Maria Shields of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Boxing Middle (69-75kg) on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the U.S. celebrates victory over Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands in the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Uzbekistan&apos;s Shakhobidin Zoirov (red) fights against Russia&apos;s Misha Aloian (blue) during the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. Uzbekistan&apos;s Shakhobidin Zoirov won the match. / AFP / YURI CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ Daniel Narcisse of France jumps to take a shot during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Denmark and France on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Daniel Narcisse of France jumps to shoot against Niklas Landin Jacobsen of Denmark during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Denmark and France on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images Denmark celebrates defeating France 28-26 to win the gold medal in Men&apos;s Handball on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ Uzbekistan&apos;s Fazliddin Gaibnazarov (red) fights against Azerbaijan&apos;s Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo (blue) during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. Uzbekistan&apos;s Fazliddin Gaibnazarov won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan and Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan compete during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan and Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan compete during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan celebrates victory over Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan in the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games - August 21, 2016. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Brazil celebrates after winning the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Italy and Brazil on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mark Kolbe/Getty Images) Mark Kolbe, Custom An overview shows Italy&apos;s Simone Giannelli (L) setting up Italy&apos;s Simone Buti during the men&apos;s Gold Medal volleyball match between Italy and Brazil at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro.( Photo by LAURENT KALFALA/AFP/Getty Images) LAURENT KALFALA Wallace de Souza of Brazil spikes the ball during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Italy and Brazil on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Galen Rupp of the United States celebrates as he wins bronze during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, Custom Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Credit: TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Kuniaki Takizaki of Cambodia reacts as he crosses the finish line during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Yuval Filo, Alona Koshevatskiy, Ekaterina Levina, Karina Lykhvar and Ida Mayrin of Israel compete during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images Poland&apos;s goalkeeper Slawomir Szmal (back) tries to stop the ball during the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: The final two finioshers Kuniaki Takizaki of Cambodia embrace Methkal Abu Drais of Jordan as they cross the finish line during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s David Lee (C) and teammates celebrate after winning their men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV CORRECTION - Ialy&apos;s team compete in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX / The erroneous mention[s] appearing in the metadata of this photo by Thomas COEX has been modified in AFP systems in the following manner: [Italy&apos;s team] instead of [Russia&apos;s team]. Please immediately remove the erroneous mention[s] from all your online services and delete it (them) from your servers. If you have been authorized by AFP to distribute it (them) to third parties, please ensure that the same actions are carried out by them. Failure to promptly comply with these instructions will entail liability on your part for any continued or post notification usage. Therefore we thank you very much for all your attention and prompt action. We are sorry for the inconvenience this notification may cause and remain at your disposal for any further information you may require. (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX Kenya&apos;s Eliud Kipchoge crosses the finish line to win the Men&apos;s Marathon athletics event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Sambodromo in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Adrian DENNIS (Photo credit should read ADRIAN DENNIS/AFP/Getty Images) ADRIAN DENNIS Russia&apos;s Sergey Tetyukhin (C) sits on the court after losing the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against USA at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV Iran&apos;s Mohammad Jaafar Moradi gestures in pain near the finish line of the Men&apos;s Marathon athletics event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / OLIVIER MORIN (Photo credit should read OLIVIER MORIN/AFP/Getty Images) OLIVIER MORIN Russia&apos; team react after competing in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX USA&apos;s Erik Shoji hugs a woman in the crowd as he celebrate after winning the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Johannes EISELE (Photo credit should read JOHANNES EISELE/AFP/Getty Images) JOHANNES EISELE RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Maxwell Holt of United States serves during the Men&apos;s Bronze Medal Match between United States and Russia on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s David Lee holds up a flag as he celebrates after winning the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV Germany&apos;s right wing Tobias Reichmann celebrates a goal during the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Team Spain competes during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Reneta Kamberova, Lyubomira Kazanova, Mihaela Maevska, Tsvetelina Naydenova and Hristiana Todorova of Bulgaria react after winning bronze during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s Maxwell Holt (back C) hugs USA&apos;s Matthew Anderson as they celebrates after winning their men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Juan Mabromata (Photo credit should read JUAN MABROMATA/AFP/Getty Images) JUAN MABROMATA RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Olena Dmytrash, Yevgeniya Gomon, Oleksandra Gridasova, Valeriia Gudym and Anastasiya Voznyak of Ukraine compete during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images Bulgaria&apos;s team compete in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Mariusz Jurkiewicz of Poland takes a shot during the Men&apos;s Bronze Medal Match between Poland and Germany on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro (blue) wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA France&apos;s Julien Absalon competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT Canada&apos;s Haislan Antonio Veranes Garcia (red) wrestles with Cuba&apos;s Alejandro Enrique Valdes Tobier in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 1 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ Spain&apos;s players celebrate after winning a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro (blue) wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ Slovakia&apos;s Peter Sagan competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro reacts as he wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA An Australian fan cheers during a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON Poland&apos;s Radoslaw Baran (red) wrestles with Iran&apos;s Reza Mohammad Ali Yazdani in their men&apos;s 97kg freestyle repechage round 1 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA (L-R) Australia&apos;s power forward Brock Motum, Australia&apos;s guard Damian Martin, Australia&apos;s centre David Andersen, Australia&apos;s forward Aron Baynes and Australia&apos;s centre Andrew Bogut react after losing a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON Czech Republic&apos;s Jaroslav Kulhavy (L) competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Pau Gasol #4 of Spain drives to the basket the Men&apos;s Basketball Bronze medal game between Australia and Spain on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Jim Young - Pool/Getty Images) Pool, 2016 Getty Images An overview shows Australia&apos;s forward Aron Baynes (L) vying with Spain&apos;s centre Pau Gasol during a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON German players celebrate their victory at the end of the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT Canada&apos;s Haislan Antonio Veranes Garcia (red) wrestles with Cuba&apos;s Alejandro Enrique Valdes Tobier in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle match on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympics. (Credit: TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://rssfeeds.9news.com/_/20/63662308/http&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;www&amp;#x2e;9news&amp;#x2e;com&amp;#x2f;sports&amp;#x2f;olympics&amp;#x2f;mongolian-wrestling-coaches-go-nuts-strip-down-after-unfavorable-decision&amp;#x2f;303856695</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1810</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Close Mongolian wrestling coaches go nuts, strip down after unfavorable decision USA TODAY Sports&apos; Rachel Axon tells you the five things to watch for during the final day of competition at the Rio Olympics. USA TODAY Sports Nate Scott, USA TODAY Sports , WXIA 12:10 PM. MDT August 21, 2016 Coaches from Mongolia thought their wrestler, Mandakhnaran Ganzorig, had won his match. When a ruling went against him they protested. Vociferously. p (Photo: Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports)   
RIO DE JANEIRO — Two Mongolian coaches stripped their clothes off after their wrestler Ganzorigiin Mandakhnaran lost the bronze medal match after the judges awarded a penalty point to Uzbekistan’s Ikhtiyor Navruzov. 
As the match ended, it appeared Mandakhnaran had won. His coaches sprinted onto the mat in celebration, one carrying the flag of Mongolia. 
Seconds later, it was Navruzov and his coach who were celebrating after the judges awarded the penalty point. Loading... Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Jack GUEZ JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coaches react after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in wrestling bronze medal match. Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Aug 21, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in a men&apos;s freestyle 65kg wrestling bronze medal match during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 2. Mandatory Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Michael Madrid, Michael Madrid Aug 21, 2016; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Coaches from Mongolia protest the match of Ikhtiyor Navruzov (UZB) and Mandakhnaran Ganzorig (MGL) by taking off their clothes after the judges ruled in favor of Navruzov in a men&apos;s freestyle 65kg wrestling bronze medal match during the Rio 2016 Summer Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 2. Mandatory Credit: Michael Madrid-USA TODAY Sports Michael Madrid, Michael Madrid Autoplay Pause Show Thumbnails Show Captions 
The two Mongolian coaches then tossed a challenge flag, and when the judges explained to them the call couldn’t be challenged, they ran out onto the mat while Mandakhnaran dropped to his knees. 
As the judges attempted to wave them off, the two coaches stripped down in protest — one removing his shirt, and the other removing both his shirt and pants, leaving on only his underwear. Security was brought in as the crowd started cheering “MONGOLIA! MONGOLIA!” 
Eventually security was able to escort the two coaches off the mat. 
Photos: Final day of competition at Rio Olympics Loading... RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Fireworks explode during the Closing Ceremony on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracana Stadium on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Ezra Shaw/Getty Images) Ezra Shaw, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Flag bearers enter the stadium during the &apos;Heroes of the Games&apos; segment during the Closing Ceremony on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracana Stadium on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Bryn Lennon/Getty Images) Bryn Lennon, 2016 Getty Images Athletes parade during the closing ceremony of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. (Photo: JOHN MACDOUGALL/AFP/Getty Images) JOHN MACDOUGALL RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Demar DeRozan and Kyle Lowry #7 of United States celebrate afer defeating Serbia during the Men&apos;s Gold medal game on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images) Elsa, 2016 Getty Images Serbia&apos;s guard Nemanja Nedovic (C) jumps for the basket by USA&apos;s centre DeMarcus Cousins (R) during a Men&apos;s Gold medal basketball match between Serbia and USA during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo: MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Nemanja Nedovic #11 of Serbia drives the ball around Kevin Durant #5 of United States during the Men&apos;s Gold medal game on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mike Ehrmann/Getty Images) Mike Ehrmann, 2016 Getty Images Serbia&apos;s power forward Stefan Bircevic (C) is blocked by USA&apos;s guard Paul George (L) during a Men&apos;s Gold medal basketball match between Serbia and USA at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Shakhobidin Zoirov of Uzbekistan celebrates victory over Misha Aloian of Russia in the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the United States and Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands compete during the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Shakhobidin Zoirov of Uzbekistan and Misha Aloian of Russia compete during the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the United States and Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands compete during the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Gold medalist Claressa Maria Shields of the United States poses on the podium during the medal ceremony for the Women&apos;s Boxing Middle (69-75kg) on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Claressa Maria Shields of the U.S. celebrates victory over Nouchka Fontijn of the Netherlands in the Women&apos;s Middle (69-75kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Uzbekistan&apos;s Shakhobidin Zoirov (red) fights against Russia&apos;s Misha Aloian (blue) during the Men&apos;s Fly (52kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. Uzbekistan&apos;s Shakhobidin Zoirov won the match. / AFP / YURI CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ Daniel Narcisse of France jumps to take a shot during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Denmark and France on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Daniel Narcisse of France jumps to shoot against Niklas Landin Jacobsen of Denmark during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Denmark and France on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images Denmark celebrates defeating France 28-26 to win the gold medal in Men&apos;s Handball on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka (red) fights against Great Britain&apos;s Joe Joyce (blue) during the Men&apos;s Super Heavy (+91kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. France&apos;s Tony Victor James Yoka won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ Uzbekistan&apos;s Fazliddin Gaibnazarov (red) fights against Azerbaijan&apos;s Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo (blue) during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Riocentro - Pavilion 6 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. Uzbekistan&apos;s Fazliddin Gaibnazarov won the match. / AFP / Yuri CORTEZ (Photo credit should read YURI CORTEZ/AFP/Getty Images) YURI CORTEZ, This content is subject to copyright. Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan and Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan compete during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan and Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan compete during the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Fazliddin Gaibnazarov of Uzbekistan celebrates victory over Lorenzo Sotomayor Collazo of Azerbaijan in the Men&apos;s Light Welter (64kg) Final Bout on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games - August 21, 2016. (Photo by Alex Livesey/Getty Images) Alex Livesey, 2016 Getty Images Brazil celebrates after winning the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Italy and Brazil on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Mark Kolbe/Getty Images) Mark Kolbe, Custom An overview shows Italy&apos;s Simone Giannelli (L) setting up Italy&apos;s Simone Buti during the men&apos;s Gold Medal volleyball match between Italy and Brazil at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro.( Photo by LAURENT KALFALA/AFP/Getty Images) LAURENT KALFALA Wallace de Souza of Brazil spikes the ball during the Men&apos;s Gold Medal Match between Italy and Brazil on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, Custom RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Galen Rupp of the United States celebrates as he wins bronze during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, Custom Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Credit: TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. Mongolia&apos;s Mandakhnaran Ganzorig&apos;s coach reacts after the judges announced that Uzbekistan&apos;s Ikhtiyor Navruzov won folling a video replay in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle bronze medal match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA, This content is subject to copyright. RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Kuniaki Takizaki of Cambodia reacts as he crosses the finish line during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Yuval Filo, Alona Koshevatskiy, Ekaterina Levina, Karina Lykhvar and Ida Mayrin of Israel compete during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images Poland&apos;s goalkeeper Slawomir Szmal (back) tries to stop the ball during the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: The final two finioshers Kuniaki Takizaki of Cambodia embrace Methkal Abu Drais of Jordan as they cross the finish line during the Men&apos;s Marathon on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Sambodromo on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Matthias Hangst/Getty Images) Matthias Hangst, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s David Lee (C) and teammates celebrate after winning their men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV CORRECTION - Ialy&apos;s team compete in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX / The erroneous mention[s] appearing in the metadata of this photo by Thomas COEX has been modified in AFP systems in the following manner: [Italy&apos;s team] instead of [Russia&apos;s team]. Please immediately remove the erroneous mention[s] from all your online services and delete it (them) from your servers. If you have been authorized by AFP to distribute it (them) to third parties, please ensure that the same actions are carried out by them. Failure to promptly comply with these instructions will entail liability on your part for any continued or post notification usage. Therefore we thank you very much for all your attention and prompt action. We are sorry for the inconvenience this notification may cause and remain at your disposal for any further information you may require. (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX Kenya&apos;s Eliud Kipchoge crosses the finish line to win the Men&apos;s Marathon athletics event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Sambodromo in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Adrian DENNIS (Photo credit should read ADRIAN DENNIS/AFP/Getty Images) ADRIAN DENNIS Russia&apos;s Sergey Tetyukhin (C) sits on the court after losing the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against USA at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV Iran&apos;s Mohammad Jaafar Moradi gestures in pain near the finish line of the Men&apos;s Marathon athletics event at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / OLIVIER MORIN (Photo credit should read OLIVIER MORIN/AFP/Getty Images) OLIVIER MORIN Russia&apos; team react after competing in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX USA&apos;s Erik Shoji hugs a woman in the crowd as he celebrate after winning the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Johannes EISELE (Photo credit should read JOHANNES EISELE/AFP/Getty Images) JOHANNES EISELE RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Maxwell Holt of United States serves during the Men&apos;s Bronze Medal Match between United States and Russia on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Maracanazinho on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Tom Pennington/Getty Images) Tom Pennington, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s David Lee holds up a flag as he celebrates after winning the men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Kirill KUDRYAVTSEV (Photo credit should read KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV/AFP/Getty Images) KIRILL KUDRYAVTSEV Germany&apos;s right wing Tobias Reichmann celebrates a goal during the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Team Spain competes during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Reneta Kamberova, Lyubomira Kazanova, Mihaela Maevska, Tsvetelina Naydenova and Hristiana Todorova of Bulgaria react after winning bronze during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s Maxwell Holt (back C) hugs USA&apos;s Matthew Anderson as they celebrates after winning their men&apos;s Bronze Medal volleyball match against Russia at the Maracanazinho stadium in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Juan Mabromata (Photo credit should read JUAN MABROMATA/AFP/Getty Images) JUAN MABROMATA RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Olena Dmytrash, Yevgeniya Gomon, Oleksandra Gridasova, Valeriia Gudym and Anastasiya Voznyak of Ukraine compete during the Group All-Around Final on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Rio Olympic Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Julian Finney/Getty Images) Julian Finney, 2016 Getty Images Bulgaria&apos;s team compete in the group all-around final event of the Rhythmic Gymnastics at the Olympic Arena during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Thomas COEX (Photo credit should read THOMAS COEX/AFP/Getty Images) THOMAS COEX RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Mariusz Jurkiewicz of Poland takes a shot during the Men&apos;s Bronze Medal Match between Poland and Germany on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Future Arena on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Lars Baron/Getty Images) Lars Baron, 2016 Getty Images USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro (blue) wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA France&apos;s Julien Absalon competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT Canada&apos;s Haislan Antonio Veranes Garcia (red) wrestles with Cuba&apos;s Alejandro Enrique Valdes Tobier in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 1 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ Spain&apos;s players celebrate after winning a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro (blue) wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Jack GUEZ (Photo credit should read JACK GUEZ/AFP/Getty Images) JACK GUEZ Slovakia&apos;s Peter Sagan competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT USA&apos;s Frank Aniello Molinaro reacts as he wrestles with Ukraine&apos;s Andriy Kvyatkovskyy in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle repechage round 2 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA An Australian fan cheers during a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON Poland&apos;s Radoslaw Baran (red) wrestles with Iran&apos;s Reza Mohammad Ali Yazdani in their men&apos;s 97kg freestyle repechage round 1 match on August 21, 2016, during the wrestling event of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Carioca Arena 2 in Rio de Janeiro. / AFP / Toshifumi KITAMURA (Photo credit should read TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA (L-R) Australia&apos;s power forward Brock Motum, Australia&apos;s guard Damian Martin, Australia&apos;s centre David Andersen, Australia&apos;s forward Aron Baynes and Australia&apos;s centre Andrew Bogut react after losing a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON Czech Republic&apos;s Jaroslav Kulhavy (L) competes in the cycling mountain bike men&apos;s cross-country race of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at the Mountain Bike Centre in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016. / AFP / Pascal GUYOT (Photo credit should read PASCAL GUYOT/AFP/Getty Images) PASCAL GUYOT RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL - AUGUST 21: Pau Gasol #4 of Spain drives to the basket the Men&apos;s Basketball Bronze medal game between Australia and Spain on Day 16 of the Rio 2016 Olympic Games at Carioca Arena 1 on August 21, 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Photo by Jim Young - Pool/Getty Images) Pool, 2016 Getty Images An overview shows Australia&apos;s forward Aron Baynes (L) vying with Spain&apos;s centre Pau Gasol during a Men&apos;s Bronze medal basketball match between Australia and Spain at the Carioca Arena 1 in Rio de Janeiro on August 21, 2016 during the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. / AFP / Mark RALSTON (Photo credit should read MARK RALSTON/AFP/Getty Images) MARK RALSTON German players celebrate their victory at the end of the men&apos;s Bronze Medal handball match Poland vs Germany for the Rio 2016 Olympics Games at the Future Arena in Rio on August 21, 2016. / AFP / afp / Roberto SCHMIDT (Photo credit should read ROBERTO SCHMIDT/AFP/Getty Images) ROBERTO SCHMIDT Canada&apos;s Haislan Antonio Veranes Garcia (red) wrestles with Cuba&apos;s Alejandro Enrique Valdes Tobier in their men&apos;s 65kg freestyle match on August 21, 2016, at the Rio 2016 Olympics. (Credit: TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA/AFP/Getty Images) TOSHIFUMI KITAMURA
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://content.11alive.com/photo/2016/08/21/download%20_OP_5_CP__1471802273808_5644596_ver1.0_640_360.jpg</main_image>
</document>
