<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.cleveland.com/localbands/</forum>
<forum_title>Cleveland Local Bands - cleveland.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Tim Wallace&apos;s &apos;family&apos; takes to email and Facebook to share their love</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.cleveland.com/music/index.ssf/2015/03/tim_wallaces_family_takes_to_e.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
CLEVELAND, Ohio -- Elyria-born singer-songwriter Tim Wallace is continuing the fight for his life against lymphoma in a hospice in Westlake. But he&apos;s not going it alone.
Friends and fellow musicians -- Wallace&apos;s &quot;family&apos;&apos; -- continue to offer their thoughts on the 65-year-old singer who specializes in clever -- and sometimes bawdy -- tunes.
Here are a few of their posts on Facebook and emails. Be sure to share yours in the comments below:
Jenna Juredine, owner of the Barking Spider, a frequent Wallace gig spot:
Tim Wallace: a master of wit and charm. The heart of a teddy bear, the voice of a lion, the mind of a fox, and the love of so many. He brought the light of laughter with his music and words to the Barking Spider for years. We are truly lucky to have such a force within our walls. One of my favorite huggers; I will hold onto each and every one...
Nancy Novak Clemens:
Thank you for giving us the opportunity to share our experiences with Tim.
I&apos;m not going to try and be clever but i did &quot;ask&quot; him what I should say and the words came through:
As I roll back the pages of time in my memory, I believe my best memories of Tim are when we spent them as a &quot;family.&quot; Not the traditional type but the through &quot;thick and thin&quot; kind of family.
He was a friend to my daughters and I during our darkest days and during our most sparkling moments of clarity. All the time loving us and challenging us.
His love is so BIG that not one single person can claim to be his &quot;one true love.&quot; We must ALL share the title. If you understand that, then you know Tim.
Wishing you an Irish goodbye...
Folksinger Tim Wallace: Friends bring music and joy to his final days Friends and family surround folksinger Tim Wallace with laughter and music on his final days
Tim Schleicher:
Mr. Chuck Yarborough,
I saw your post on folknet&apos;s Facebook page about Tim Wallace. I didn&apos;t really know Mr. Wallace personally. I only saw him at a couple open mics around the Cleveland area before I went off to Toledo for college last year. But I was back in town for spring break last week and heard about his unfortunate situation. I remember always looking forward to his acts and how he could make the whole room laugh. I recorded a version of his clones song that I watch regularly and still makes me laugh. I could only imagine how much joy he brought to people who were close to him when I barely knew him and the one video I have of him can still make me laugh. I don&apos;t know if this will help at all but it&apos;s the very least I could do for such a great man.
Toni Huff Medley:
Thank you, Chuck Yarborough . I spent hours with TimStock last Saturday night. I expected to boo-hoo and stuffed my purse wuth tissues. I took him a wig. But, it&apos;s Tim! There&apos;s no crying in hospice! We&apos;ve all been singing, laughing and drinking together for years. I learned more about living in those few hours than from all the years of my life. A world without Tim will be tough, but nobody can say he&apos;s not living fully until the end! And, I&apos;ll be a better person for sharing this life.
Todd Weider:
Tim used to host an open mic at the Southwest Cafe, in Parma. It was a perfect mix of music and laughter, inevitably shifting to the nearby Denny&apos;s to continue the uproar into the wee hours of the morning. I met my wife on one of those evenings, so I can safely say that in this way (among many others), Tim has had a real and continuing influence on my own life.
Mark Douglas:
I don&apos;t really have any stories to tell, but I always enjoyed when Tim would sit in and do a few, usually hysterical, tunes when playing with Charley Brown . Good dude. Damned good dude . . . and player too.
Tim Douglas:
I agree with my brother Mark. A good soul for sure with a unique style and sense of humor. We are all a little better off knowing him and his take on life.
Patricia Diamond:
His creativity, not just in music, always makes me smile.
Victoria Parks:
Tim and I had been in the Cleveland folk scene together in the early &apos;70s at a little coffeehouse in Lakewood called the Red Horse Hollow. Tim and I became friends. It must have been about 1980. Tim sat across from me at my kitchen table. I said to him, &quot;Tim, the world is run by a bunch of &quot;$#*holes.&apos;&apos; The next day he presented me with his brand new song, &quot;$#*holes on Parade&apos;&apos; (not the exact spelling of course). Tim, in his owns words was using a word that begins with &quot;A&quot; and ends with &quot;ole&apos;&apos; IN A SONG. It was impressive. I laughed until my ribs hurt.
It was some years later when Tim had become the locally legendary funny songwriter in an appearance at the Kent State Folk Festival where Tim debuted the song for the KSFF and the WKSU listening audience. The performance had been cleared with the radio station as Tim had agreed NOT to sing the word that &quot;begins with &apos;A and ends in &apos;ole,&apos; but was instead planning on using a rather offensive sound effect in place of the word during his performance. That was all fine and good until, while during the performance, it became obvious that most of the audience already knew the words to the song. They enthusiastically sang along and it was all going out over the WKSU airwaves, strong and clear. There was no stopping it. The Program Director must have had kittens. That I was the inspiration for that song is a great honor. That Tim wrote such a song is inspiring.
Tim is the funniest songwriter I have ever had the honor of knowing. Tim is never one to hold back. The multitalented Tim Wallace knows his Irish and Scottish traditional songs too, belting out bass vocals that melt like butter on a warm plate. I am also sure that in another lifetime he was a vaudevillian hurdy gurdy man with a Fez monkey on his shoulder who could dance a jig to a ragtime band. In this life he just picked up where he left off. I have never heard any songwriter evoke tears of laughter from me like Tim Wallace. Thanks Tim!
Robin Stratton:
We have a group of four who have been constant throughout Tim&apos;s ordeal. Besides myself, it&apos;s Jim Schafer, Jim Stone (bass player with Tim&apos;s current band, The Smokin&apos; Fez Monkeys), and dear friend Andy Allen (was in Tim&apos;s band Houligans). Every test, every change, orchestrating food, visitors, coordinating with the doctors, taking care of the administration and paperwork. We are all sick and sad, hopeful, yet realistic. What&apos;s happening at &quot;Timstock&quot; is a celebration of life, a living wake. Let the music, laughter, and love continue between the tears. Now, that&apos;s some copy you can use!
I am so grateful you came and were able to witness the joy (and talent) that surrounds this man. Thank you.
Rachel Brown:
It&apos;s really beautiful how the musician community comes together for those who need it the most. I don&apos;t know Tim personally, but between all the great things I&apos;ve heard about him and our many mutual friends, I feel as if I do. Cheers Tim Wallace , sending energy and love your way.
Richard Greer (Cleveland radio personality):
There is much to be said about music therapy and being loved. The end result is that Tim will die but those final days of love and music will make his departure and for those who love him&apos;s journey&apos;s much easier because he departs with joy.
Jim Strang (a former PD colleague):
Just arrived at the perpetual Tim Wallace celebration of a life well-lived. I&apos;ve known and partied with Tim for more than 40 years. He said he forgot to ask you if you knew me. I told him you&apos;re a good Tejas boy, but he&apos;d figured that out already. He (bleeped) more talent this morning than I ever had in my life.
Just a musical genius who never got discovered. Wonderful, wonderful human being.
From Alex Bevan (and the email that began the story):
My friend Tim Wallace is much diminished after a long, long fight against cancer. He is in hospice and has a short time left.
Tim&apos;s warmth and humor infused his music and drew many of us to his talent and as a song writer he was seldom matched. His chosen genre was kind of old time nouveau jug bag gypsy gangster kind of stuff.... As the leader of the Fez Monkeys he poked fun at society, himself and any number of subjects in a manner that brought to mind Grouch, Mark Twain and Mr. Rogers all in one musical gulp. At six foot plus with a deep baritone he could have dominated any centerstage of any venue... but did not by choice... humorous persuasion was his game... and he new it well. His wealth was songs.... and that was only part of the man Tim Wallace.
I met Tim earlier than 1989 I&apos;m sure... but that was around the time i got to know him. He had written a song called the &quot;Bigfoot Boogie&quot; that caught my ear at an open mic or show and I knew I wanted to learn it on the spot. I had been working on some children&apos;s music and thought it to be the perfect addition to that material. I had also been working on producing another Pat Dailey recording and somehow Tim&apos;s name came up there again.... not only as a songwriter but as a graphic artist. Jim Schafer had worked with Tim on a number of projects and often used him for cartoon illustrations for video, print and website media components. That led me to involving Tim in the graphics for &quot;Who Killed The Dragon?&quot; an environmental fairytale but now I&apos;m wandering
Over the next few years I got to know Tim from small festivals... larger festivals like Hessler... benefits for stricken comrades. open mic gathering, funerals and the like... all the stuff that happens naturally.... and over the years I would always see Tim an new deceptively clever song that made me smile and think. He was not a guy who stood in the spotlight.... and said &quot;look at me&quot; .... he was the guy who would create a glow that fell on everyone.
Over the past few days Jim Schafer and Robin Stratton have organized a (days-long) sing-a-thon at Ames Family Hospice House in Westlake. If you go to the FB posts you can see Tim singing &quot;Duncan and Brady&quot;.... and you will see virtually every one in the Cleveland folk scene there to spill a little love over him.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.cleveland.com/music/index.ssf/2015/03/tim_wallaces_family_takes_to_e.html</post_url>
<post_date>20150320</post_date>
<post_time>1433</post_time>
<username>Chuck Yarborough, The Plain Dealer</username>
<post>
CLEVELAND, Ohio -- Elyria-born singer-songwriter Tim Wallace is continuing the fight for his life against lymphoma in a hospice in Westlake. But he&apos;s not going it alone.
Friends and fellow musicians -- Wallace&apos;s &quot;family&apos;&apos; -- continue to offer their thoughts on the 65-year-old singer who specializes in clever -- and sometimes bawdy -- tunes.
Here are a few of their posts on Facebook and emails. Be sure to share yours in the comments below:
Jenna Juredine, owner of the Barking Spider, a frequent Wallace gig spot:
Tim Wallace: a master of wit and charm. The heart of a teddy bear, the voice of a lion, the mind of a fox, and the love of so many. He brought the light of laughter with his music and words to the Barking Spider for years. We are truly lucky to have such a force within our walls. One of my favorite huggers; I will hold onto each and every one...
Nancy Novak Clemens:
Thank you for giving us the opportunity to share our experiences with Tim.
I&apos;m not going to try and be clever but i did &quot;ask&quot; him what I should say and the words came through:
As I roll back the pages of time in my memory, I believe my best memories of Tim are when we spent them as a &quot;family.&quot; Not the traditional type but the through &quot;thick and thin&quot; kind of family.
He was a friend to my daughters and I during our darkest days and during our most sparkling moments of clarity. All the time loving us and challenging us.
His love is so BIG that not one single person can claim to be his &quot;one true love.&quot; We must ALL share the title. If you understand that, then you know Tim.
Wishing you an Irish goodbye...
Folksinger Tim Wallace: Friends bring music and joy to his final days Friends and family surround folksinger Tim Wallace with laughter and music on his final days
Tim Schleicher:
Mr. Chuck Yarborough,
I saw your post on folknet&apos;s Facebook page about Tim Wallace. I didn&apos;t really know Mr. Wallace personally. I only saw him at a couple open mics around the Cleveland area before I went off to Toledo for college last year. But I was back in town for spring break last week and heard about his unfortunate situation. I remember always looking forward to his acts and how he could make the whole room laugh. I recorded a version of his clones song that I watch regularly and still makes me laugh. I could only imagine how much joy he brought to people who were close to him when I barely knew him and the one video I have of him can still make me laugh. I don&apos;t know if this will help at all but it&apos;s the very least I could do for such a great man.
Toni Huff Medley:
Thank you, Chuck Yarborough . I spent hours with TimStock last Saturday night. I expected to boo-hoo and stuffed my purse wuth tissues. I took him a wig. But, it&apos;s Tim! There&apos;s no crying in hospice! We&apos;ve all been singing, laughing and drinking together for years. I learned more about living in those few hours than from all the years of my life. A world without Tim will be tough, but nobody can say he&apos;s not living fully until the end! And, I&apos;ll be a better person for sharing this life.
Todd Weider:
Tim used to host an open mic at the Southwest Cafe, in Parma. It was a perfect mix of music and laughter, inevitably shifting to the nearby Denny&apos;s to continue the uproar into the wee hours of the morning. I met my wife on one of those evenings, so I can safely say that in this way (among many others), Tim has had a real and continuing influence on my own life.
Mark Douglas:
I don&apos;t really have any stories to tell, but I always enjoyed when Tim would sit in and do a few, usually hysterical, tunes when playing with Charley Brown . Good dude. Damned good dude . . . and player too.
Tim Douglas:
I agree with my brother Mark. A good soul for sure with a unique style and sense of humor. We are all a little better off knowing him and his take on life.
Patricia Diamond:
His creativity, not just in music, always makes me smile.
Victoria Parks:
Tim and I had been in the Cleveland folk scene together in the early &apos;70s at a little coffeehouse in Lakewood called the Red Horse Hollow. Tim and I became friends. It must have been about 1980. Tim sat across from me at my kitchen table. I said to him, &quot;Tim, the world is run by a bunch of &quot;$#*holes.&apos;&apos; The next day he presented me with his brand new song, &quot;$#*holes on Parade&apos;&apos; (not the exact spelling of course). Tim, in his owns words was using a word that begins with &quot;A&quot; and ends with &quot;ole&apos;&apos; IN A SONG. It was impressive. I laughed until my ribs hurt.
It was some years later when Tim had become the locally legendary funny songwriter in an appearance at the Kent State Folk Festival where Tim debuted the song for the KSFF and the WKSU listening audience. The performance had been cleared with the radio station as Tim had agreed NOT to sing the word that &quot;begins with &apos;A and ends in &apos;ole,&apos; but was instead planning on using a rather offensive sound effect in place of the word during his performance. That was all fine and good until, while during the performance, it became obvious that most of the audience already knew the words to the song. They enthusiastically sang along and it was all going out over the WKSU airwaves, strong and clear. There was no stopping it. The Program Director must have had kittens. That I was the inspiration for that song is a great honor. That Tim wrote such a song is inspiring.
Tim is the funniest songwriter I have ever had the honor of knowing. Tim is never one to hold back. The multitalented Tim Wallace knows his Irish and Scottish traditional songs too, belting out bass vocals that melt like butter on a warm plate. I am also sure that in another lifetime he was a vaudevillian hurdy gurdy man with a Fez monkey on his shoulder who could dance a jig to a ragtime band. In this life he just picked up where he left off. I have never heard any songwriter evoke tears of laughter from me like Tim Wallace. Thanks Tim!
Robin Stratton:
We have a group of four who have been constant throughout Tim&apos;s ordeal. Besides myself, it&apos;s Jim Schafer, Jim Stone (bass player with Tim&apos;s current band, The Smokin&apos; Fez Monkeys), and dear friend Andy Allen (was in Tim&apos;s band Houligans). Every test, every change, orchestrating food, visitors, coordinating with the doctors, taking care of the administration and paperwork. We are all sick and sad, hopeful, yet realistic. What&apos;s happening at &quot;Timstock&quot; is a celebration of life, a living wake. Let the music, laughter, and love continue between the tears. Now, that&apos;s some copy you can use!
I am so grateful you came and were able to witness the joy (and talent) that surrounds this man. Thank you.
Rachel Brown:
It&apos;s really beautiful how the musician community comes together for those who need it the most. I don&apos;t know Tim personally, but between all the great things I&apos;ve heard about him and our many mutual friends, I feel as if I do. Cheers Tim Wallace , sending energy and love your way.
Richard Greer (Cleveland radio personality):
There is much to be said about music therapy and being loved. The end result is that Tim will die but those final days of love and music will make his departure and for those who love him&apos;s journey&apos;s much easier because he departs with joy.
Jim Strang (a former PD colleague):
Just arrived at the perpetual Tim Wallace celebration of a life well-lived. I&apos;ve known and partied with Tim for more than 40 years. He said he forgot to ask you if you knew me. I told him you&apos;re a good Tejas boy, but he&apos;d figured that out already. He (bleeped) more talent this morning than I ever had in my life.
Just a musical genius who never got discovered. Wonderful, wonderful human being.
From Alex Bevan (and the email that began the story):
My friend Tim Wallace is much diminished after a long, long fight against cancer. He is in hospice and has a short time left.
Tim&apos;s warmth and humor infused his music and drew many of us to his talent and as a song writer he was seldom matched. His chosen genre was kind of old time nouveau jug bag gypsy gangster kind of stuff.... As the leader of the Fez Monkeys he poked fun at society, himself and any number of subjects in a manner that brought to mind Grouch, Mark Twain and Mr. Rogers all in one musical gulp. At six foot plus with a deep baritone he could have dominated any centerstage of any venue... but did not by choice... humorous persuasion was his game... and he new it well. His wealth was songs.... and that was only part of the man Tim Wallace.
I met Tim earlier than 1989 I&apos;m sure... but that was around the time i got to know him. He had written a song called the &quot;Bigfoot Boogie&quot; that caught my ear at an open mic or show and I knew I wanted to learn it on the spot. I had been working on some children&apos;s music and thought it to be the perfect addition to that material. I had also been working on producing another Pat Dailey recording and somehow Tim&apos;s name came up there again.... not only as a songwriter but as a graphic artist. Jim Schafer had worked with Tim on a number of projects and often used him for cartoon illustrations for video, print and website media components. That led me to involving Tim in the graphics for &quot;Who Killed The Dragon?&quot; an environmental fairytale but now I&apos;m wandering
Over the next few years I got to know Tim from small festivals... larger festivals like Hessler... benefits for stricken comrades. open mic gathering, funerals and the like... all the stuff that happens naturally.... and over the years I would always see Tim an new deceptively clever song that made me smile and think. He was not a guy who stood in the spotlight.... and said &quot;look at me&quot; .... he was the guy who would create a glow that fell on everyone.
Over the past few days Jim Schafer and Robin Stratton have organized a (days-long) sing-a-thon at Ames Family Hospice House in Westlake. If you go to the FB posts you can see Tim singing &quot;Duncan and Brady&quot;.... and you will see virtually every one in the Cleveland folk scene there to spill a little love over him.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>
<external_link>https://www.youtube.com/embed/H-Dsuk__QsI</external_link><external_link>https://www.facebook.com/charley.brown.37201</external_link><external_link>https://www.facebook.com/chuck.yarborough.35</external_link><external_link>https://www.facebook.com/tim.wallace.355</external_link>
</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://image.cleveland.com/home/cleve-media/width620/img/plain-dealer/photo/2015/03/19/17304415-large.jpg</main_image>
</document>
