<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Skyline Group International Launches Leadership Coaching Technology Devoted to Women Leaders</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/8/prweb13628221.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Skyline Group International Launches Leadership Coaching Technology Devoted to Women Leaders Share Article Skyline Group International today announces the launch of Coaching for Women (C4W), a first-of-its-kind leadership development program designed for women. Sindell continues, “Leadership development fails women because it takes an all or nothing approach, but the key is balance.” SAN FRANCISCO, CA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Skyline Group International today announces the launch of Coaching for Women (C4W), a first-of-its-kind leadership development program designed for women. While women make up 53 percent of entry-level employees, there’s a serious lack of women leaders -- a 2015 analysis published in the Journal of Applied Psychology found that women account for just 24 percent of senior vice presidents and 19 percent of c-suite executives. “Despite this statistic and others that demonstrate the divide between male and female leaders, the current conversation on gender in leadership is at a standstill. Professionals and employers alike recognize there’s a problem, but can’t seem to move forward to a solution. Traditional leadership development addresses the problem by telling women to become more masculine and men to act less like jerks -- but that approach isn’t working,” states Thuy Sindell, President of Skyline Group’s coaching division. Sindell continues, “Leadership development fails women because it takes an all or nothing approach, but the key is balance.” C4W is the only leadership solution tailored for current and emerging women leaders. C4W guides each leader to identify and develop their most important leadership skills with a gender-balanced perspective. C4W is designed to help current and emerging women leaders to focus on the skills most important to increasing women’s effectiveness in the workplace. This is achieved through: 1. Guiding participants to assess and identify their most important development opportunities. 2. An tailored online multimedia program that provides weekly direction, interactive content, and tools. 3. One-on-one coaching to reinforce learning, bring online content to life, and support the unique development needs of each leader. 4. Metrics that track program and participant results. Learn more about how your company can increase performance through preparing and engage your future leaders. Visit http://www.c4x.com . About C4X Solutions Suite The C4X | Coaching for Excellence leadership development solution from Skyline Group International makes the key benefits of tried-and-true coaching methods scalable and adjustable on a revolutionary technology-driven platform. C4X makes leadership development coaching more efficient, more measurable and much more cost-effective than traditional coaching methods, reducing coaching costs by as much as 75 percent. Dozens of forward-thinking organizations have deployed C4X to improve the performance of hundreds of leaders, contributing measurable results including increased productivity, as well as greater revenues and better profit margins. More information is available at http://www.c4x.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.21</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/8/prweb13628221.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160819</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Skyline Group International Launches Leadership Coaching Technology Devoted to Women Leaders Share Article Skyline Group International today announces the launch of Coaching for Women (C4W), a first-of-its-kind leadership development program designed for women. Sindell continues, “Leadership development fails women because it takes an all or nothing approach, but the key is balance.” SAN FRANCISCO, CA (PRWEB) August 22, 2016 Skyline Group International today announces the launch of Coaching for Women (C4W), a first-of-its-kind leadership development program designed for women. While women make up 53 percent of entry-level employees, there’s a serious lack of women leaders -- a 2015 analysis published in the Journal of Applied Psychology found that women account for just 24 percent of senior vice presidents and 19 percent of c-suite executives. “Despite this statistic and others that demonstrate the divide between male and female leaders, the current conversation on gender in leadership is at a standstill. Professionals and employers alike recognize there’s a problem, but can’t seem to move forward to a solution. Traditional leadership development addresses the problem by telling women to become more masculine and men to act less like jerks -- but that approach isn’t working,” states Thuy Sindell, President of Skyline Group’s coaching division. Sindell continues, “Leadership development fails women because it takes an all or nothing approach, but the key is balance.” C4W is the only leadership solution tailored for current and emerging women leaders. C4W guides each leader to identify and develop their most important leadership skills with a gender-balanced perspective. C4W is designed to help current and emerging women leaders to focus on the skills most important to increasing women’s effectiveness in the workplace. This is achieved through: 1. Guiding participants to assess and identify their most important development opportunities. 2. An tailored online multimedia program that provides weekly direction, interactive content, and tools. 3. One-on-one coaching to reinforce learning, bring online content to life, and support the unique development needs of each leader. 4. Metrics that track program and participant results. Learn more about how your company can increase performance through preparing and engage your future leaders. Visit http://www.c4x.com . About C4X Solutions Suite The C4X | Coaching for Excellence leadership development solution from Skyline Group International makes the key benefits of tried-and-true coaching methods scalable and adjustable on a revolutionary technology-driven platform. C4X makes leadership development coaching more efficient, more measurable and much more cost-effective than traditional coaching methods, reducing coaching costs by as much as 75 percent. Dozens of forward-thinking organizations have deployed C4X to improve the performance of hundreds of leaders, contributing measurable results including increased productivity, as well as greater revenues and better profit margins. More information is available at http://www.c4x.com . 
Share article on social media or email: 
View article via: 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://ww1.prweb.com/prfiles/2016/08/19/13628221/SkylineGroup LOGO.jpg</main_image>
</document>
