<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.sagmart.com/news_rss</forum>
<forum_title>SAG Mart News - General, Entertainment, Mobile, Fashion, Health</forum_title>
<discussion_title>First Glimpse of Ducati SuperSport 939: SPIED</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.sagmart.com/news/Automobiles/first-glimpse-of-ducati-supersport-939-spied</topic_url>
<topic_text>
First Glimpse of Ducati SuperSport 939: SPIED 22nd, Aug 2016 11:45 AM View: 145 0 For the first time, the new Ducati SuperSport 939 has been spotted in action executing its test runs on a secret track in Italy. The bike was earlier previewed in a closed area at the bygone 2016 World Ducati Week (WDW) only to give a peep to the fans. Luckily, someone has captured its image and uploaded it online, however, the quality of the sneaked picture wasn’t up to the mark. Here, the bike has been clearly spied undergoing its test rounds, months before its official launch, which could take place in November this year at the Milan event. As per the automaker’s idea behind building this sports bike, the Italian manufacturer has done quite a good job in the form of this new demon. The Ducati SuperSport 939 can be considered as a decent motorcycle, which has good handling and performance factor, though, a bit less from the existing Panigale superbike series. “The engine is tuned to be really, really smooth because it’s a sportsbike with road focused performance. The SuperSport is not an entry-level sportsbike. That would be a bike for beginners, this is not that. This bike is for customers who desire a sportsbike with versatility and with road-focused performance. It is for riders who don’t want a bike for trackdays, so this is a bike that is sporty and at the same time comfortable in terms of seating position. It is not in the Panigale family,&quot; told Paolo Quattrino, Product Manager, Ducati, while introducing the SuperSport 939 at WDW. The clever use of the already available Ducati mechanical elements has made this bike more impressive. The engine it acquires is based on the 939cc, water-cooled, L-twin motor taken from Hypermotard, while the chassis is the one used on the Monster. When it comes to the electronics, it carries mandatory ABS satisfying the Euro-4 norms, eight-level traction control, and three- rider modes. Ducati is craving to include cornering ABS and anti-wheelie across its entire range, which includes the SuperSport as well. Discussing the designing front, the upcoming Ducati SuperSport 939 features headlamps resembling those of the terrific Panigale range, a totally different instrument cluster with ample multifunctionality, Ducati multimedia system, new exhaust, and a fresh tail section as well. Read Also: Ducati XDiavel Launch Slated in September; Price Starts at Rs 15.56 Lakh “We made this because we wanted to target the customer who loves sportsbikes and wants street legal performance. We investigated the market and saw very interesting potential for these types of customers,&quot; said Quattrino. “The displacement is the same as the Hypermotard 939, but we have modified the engine and electronic tuning and even the attachment of the engine to the frame is different. With this frame, the engine is a stressed element. So it is 939 displacement, but not really the same engine, because 80% of it is new,” revealed Ducati. Get latest and updated information about automobiles and latest technologies on our Google Plus Sagmart.com
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.sagmart.com/news/Automobiles/first-glimpse-of-ducati-supersport-939-spied</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0615</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
First Glimpse of Ducati SuperSport 939: SPIED 22nd, Aug 2016 11:45 AM View: 145 0 For the first time, the new Ducati SuperSport 939 has been spotted in action executing its test runs on a secret track in Italy. The bike was earlier previewed in a closed area at the bygone 2016 World Ducati Week (WDW) only to give a peep to the fans. Luckily, someone has captured its image and uploaded it online, however, the quality of the sneaked picture wasn’t up to the mark. Here, the bike has been clearly spied undergoing its test rounds, months before its official launch, which could take place in November this year at the Milan event. As per the automaker’s idea behind building this sports bike, the Italian manufacturer has done quite a good job in the form of this new demon. The Ducati SuperSport 939 can be considered as a decent motorcycle, which has good handling and performance factor, though, a bit less from the existing Panigale superbike series. “The engine is tuned to be really, really smooth because it’s a sportsbike with road focused performance. The SuperSport is not an entry-level sportsbike. That would be a bike for beginners, this is not that. This bike is for customers who desire a sportsbike with versatility and with road-focused performance. It is for riders who don’t want a bike for trackdays, so this is a bike that is sporty and at the same time comfortable in terms of seating position. It is not in the Panigale family,&quot; told Paolo Quattrino, Product Manager, Ducati, while introducing the SuperSport 939 at WDW. The clever use of the already available Ducati mechanical elements has made this bike more impressive. The engine it acquires is based on the 939cc, water-cooled, L-twin motor taken from Hypermotard, while the chassis is the one used on the Monster. When it comes to the electronics, it carries mandatory ABS satisfying the Euro-4 norms, eight-level traction control, and three- rider modes. Ducati is craving to include cornering ABS and anti-wheelie across its entire range, which includes the SuperSport as well. Discussing the designing front, the upcoming Ducati SuperSport 939 features headlamps resembling those of the terrific Panigale range, a totally different instrument cluster with ample multifunctionality, Ducati multimedia system, new exhaust, and a fresh tail section as well. Read Also: Ducati XDiavel Launch Slated in September; Price Starts at Rs 15.56 Lakh “We made this because we wanted to target the customer who loves sportsbikes and wants street legal performance. We investigated the market and saw very interesting potential for these types of customers,&quot; said Quattrino. “The displacement is the same as the Hypermotard 939, but we have modified the engine and electronic tuning and even the attachment of the engine to the frame is different. With this frame, the engine is a stressed element. So it is 939 displacement, but not really the same engine, because 80% of it is new,” revealed Ducati. Get latest and updated information about automobiles and latest technologies on our Google Plus Sagmart.com
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://www.sagmart.com/uploads/2016/08/22/news_image1/Ducati-SuperSport-939.jpg</main_image>
</document>
