<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/markets/stocks/markets/stocks/news/rssfeeds/2146843.cms</forum>
<forum_title>News-Stocks-Markets-The Economic Times</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Sensex breaks below 28K, down nearly 100 points; ICICI Bank, Sun Pharma top losers</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sensex-breaks-below-28k-down-nearly-100-points-icici-bank-sun-pharma-top-losers/articleshow/53803589.cms</topic_url>
<topic_text>
NEW DELHI: NEW DELHI: The S&amp;P BSE Sensex slipped below its crucial support level of 28000 in mid-morning trade on Monday, led by losses in ICICI Bank, Sun Pharma, TCS, Maruti Suzuki, and M&amp;M. 

The Nifty50 slipped below its support level of 8650 weighed down by losses in IT, metals, banks, capital goods, and auto stocks. 

At 09:20 am, The 30-share index was trading at 28,123, up 46 points or 0.16 per cent. It touched a high of 28,143.28 and a low of 28,045.25 in morning trade. 

The Nifty50 was trading at 8,680 up 14 points or 0.10 per cent. It touched a high of 8,684.85 and a low of 8,659.10 in the first 30 minutes of trade. 

The gains were seen after the government appointed Urjit Patel as the next RBI Governor to take over from Raghuram Rajan on September 4. Patel is the current Deputy Governor at RBI and is seen as a hawk, similar to Rajan. Foreign portfolio investors (FPI) are expected to give a thumbs-up to Patel&apos;s appointment. 

The S&amp;P BSE Midcap Index was up 0.28 per cent and BSE S&amp;P Smallcap Index was trading 0.38 per cent higher. 

Adani Ports (up 2 per cent), NTPC (up 1.2 per cent), Cipla (up 0.98 per cent), ITC (up 0.94 per cent), and HUL (up 0.88 per cent) were the major Sensex gainers. 

Tata Steel (down 1.2 per cent), Lupin (down 1.1 per cent), TCS (down 0.84 per cent) and Axis Bank (down 0.68 per cent) were the major Sensex losers. 

Here&apos;s are a couple of factors influencing the market sentiment today: 

Patel appointment positive for market: Patel is credited with changing the gauge of targeting inflation to consumer prices from wholesale price inflation earlier. A panel headed by Patel had earlier proposed inflation targeting as the central bank&apos;s prime objective. 

&quot;By appointing Urjit Patel, the author of the monetary policy framework report, as RBI Governor, the government has increased its credibility and belief that it will maintain its fight against inflation,&quot; said Motilal Oswal , CMD, Motilal Oswal Financial Services . 

Ajay Bodke, CEO &amp; Chief Portfolio Manager - PMS, Prabhudas Lilladher, said institutional investors - both domestic and foreign - would welcome the government choice for Rajan&apos;s successor. 

&quot;It signals seamless continuity of policies pursued by RBI to conduct its monetary policy in an independent manner,&quot; Bodke said. 

8,700 level key for Nifty50: Experts believe that the 8,700 level would hold key for the Nifty50. One it breaches this level, the index can even scale 8,800, they said. 

&quot;Last week&apos;s price action has resulted in the formation of a &apos;Diamond&apos; pattern on the hourly chart, with a breakout in the upward direction on Thursday. Considering this pattern, the Nifty50 may extend this upward move towards 8,750-8,800 levels, once it manages to sustain above the 8,700 mark. This pattern remains valid as long as the Nifty50 manages to stay above the 8,600 mark,&quot; Angel Broking said in a note. 

FPI flows to influence sentiment: Data available with NSDL suggest foreign portfolio investors (FPIs) have bought equities worth Rs 7,723 crore so far this month. 

&quot;What we have clearly seen over most part of this year is the ability of central banks to keep the animal spirit alive, keep infusing liquidity and cut interest rates even if it means negative bond yields,&quot; Nilesh Shah, MD &amp; CEO at Envision Capital, told ETNow. 

Asian markets stay negative: Most Asian markets were trading negative this morning. Japan&apos;s benchmark Nikkei was trading 0.30 per cent higher at 16,595.63. China&apos;s Shanghai Composite fell 0.16 per cent to 3,103.00. Other Asian indices, including Hong Kong &apos;s Hang Seng (up 0.11 per cent), South Korea &apos;s Kospi (down 0.48 per cent) and Taiwan &apos;s TWSE (down 0.74 per cent), were trading mixed. 

US markets fell on Friday: The Dow Jones Industrial Average ended 45.13 points, or 0.24 per cent, lower at 18,552 on Friday. The S&amp;P500 index lost 3.15 points, or 0.14 per cent, to close at 2,183. The Nasdaq Composite dropped 1.77 points, or 0.03 per cent, to 5,238, Reuters reported. 

For the week, the Dow and S&amp;P500 were down 0.1 per cent each, while and the Nasdaq was up 0.1 per cent.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/markets/stocks/news/sensex-breaks-below-28k-down-nearly-100-points-icici-bank-sun-pharma-top-losers/articleshow/53803589.cms</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>1237</post_time>
<username>AKA E</username>
<post>
markets showing weakness on appointment of Urjit as RBI governor, he like rajan will not allow India to prosper
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>IN</country>
<main_image>http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/thumb/msid-53803621,width-600,resizemode-4,imglength-16888/markets/stocks/news/whats-d-street-talking-about-before-opening-bell/sensex-recoups-losses-nifty50-holds-above-8650-levels.jpg</main_image>
</document>
