<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Elite coach Dr Dave Alred shares his tips for making good use of stress</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/elite-coach-dr-dave-alred-tips-for-making-good-use-of-stress/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
August 22.2016 11:11 am 
Few of us think of stress as a good thing. Even those who claim to thrive in a high pressure environment are aware it’s probably not doing wonders for their health – mental or otherwise. 
Dr Dave Alred MBE 
In his book The Pressure Principle 
His observations are based on a career working with champion soccer players, golfers, dolphin trainers and the West Coast Eagles. 
And then I say there’s a puddle seven foot [2.1 metres]wide outside, are you prepared to jump it? 
His example moves from puddle to a jump between rooftops, to the same distance between 50 storey skyscrapers. An identical jump, but different outcomes if things go wrong. 
What I try to do in the book is give people the tools so they can manage it, whatever they’re doing. That doesn’t necessarily mean a great goal or shot into the green, it could mean our own challenges.” Photo: Michael Rayner 
A guy playing his first game for the Wallabies is going through the same thing. Unfortunately, as adults, we call that anxiety and look at the negative side. 
“I’m turning that around and saying, no, that’s excitement and it’s fuel for a great performance.” 
As well as changing the language we use, Dave suggests we need to address a coaching mentality that tends to focus too much on what went wrong. 
Look at young children. If you praise them when they do things right, they won’t misbehave to get your attention. 
“If you’re telling kids to not do something, they know to get your attention, what to do is put paint on the wall.” 
Dave criticises the Olympic focus on medal tallies, suggesting a focus on personal bests. True success, he says, comes when we stop competing with others and start competing with ourselves. 
“I think success should be measured with your previous self. That should be your starting point. Am I better than I was yesterday? If so, well done – you’re winning.” Daves five steps to success 1. Make anxiety productive You should stop thinking of anxiety as a weakness, understand it as a normal reaction to pressure, and use it as a high-octane fuel to achieve your goals. 2. Watch Your Language “If I could pass a law in parliament, it would be to delete three words: never, always and can’t.” Careless, clumsy use of negative language can destroy confidence, which prevents you performing well under pressure. 3. Watch Your Posture The “command posture” involves standing as if you’re in total control of your environment. “Act like you already know the result. Act like it’s going to be great.” 4. Stop Thinking About Failure Good coaches give specific feedback focusing on what went right. “That was a really good shot because your posture was very angular and it made you shift forward. In other words, this was really good because you did X Keeping the focus on the process, rather than the outcome, allows you to perform even when something unforeseen occurs. “Chaos can be very productive, if you look for opportunities that come.” by Dave Alred, Penguin, $35 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.04</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/meet/elite-coach-dr-dave-alred-tips-for-making-good-use-of-stress/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
August 22.2016 11:11 am 
Few of us think of stress as a good thing. Even those who claim to thrive in a high pressure environment are aware it’s probably not doing wonders for their health – mental or otherwise. 
Dr Dave Alred MBE 
In his book The Pressure Principle 
His observations are based on a career working with champion soccer players, golfers, dolphin trainers and the West Coast Eagles. 
And then I say there’s a puddle seven foot [2.1 metres]wide outside, are you prepared to jump it? 
His example moves from puddle to a jump between rooftops, to the same distance between 50 storey skyscrapers. An identical jump, but different outcomes if things go wrong. 
What I try to do in the book is give people the tools so they can manage it, whatever they’re doing. That doesn’t necessarily mean a great goal or shot into the green, it could mean our own challenges.” Photo: Michael Rayner 
A guy playing his first game for the Wallabies is going through the same thing. Unfortunately, as adults, we call that anxiety and look at the negative side. 
“I’m turning that around and saying, no, that’s excitement and it’s fuel for a great performance.” 
As well as changing the language we use, Dave suggests we need to address a coaching mentality that tends to focus too much on what went wrong. 
Look at young children. If you praise them when they do things right, they won’t misbehave to get your attention. 
“If you’re telling kids to not do something, they know to get your attention, what to do is put paint on the wall.” 
Dave criticises the Olympic focus on medal tallies, suggesting a focus on personal bests. True success, he says, comes when we stop competing with others and start competing with ourselves. 
“I think success should be measured with your previous self. That should be your starting point. Am I better than I was yesterday? If so, well done – you’re winning.” Daves five steps to success 1. Make anxiety productive You should stop thinking of anxiety as a weakness, understand it as a normal reaction to pressure, and use it as a high-octane fuel to achieve your goals. 2. Watch Your Language “If I could pass a law in parliament, it would be to delete three words: never, always and can’t.” Careless, clumsy use of negative language can destroy confidence, which prevents you performing well under pressure. 3. Watch Your Posture The “command posture” involves standing as if you’re in total control of your environment. “Act like you already know the result. Act like it’s going to be great.” 4. Stop Thinking About Failure Good coaches give specific feedback focusing on what went right. “That was a really good shot because your posture was very angular and it made you shift forward. In other words, this was really good because you did X Keeping the focus on the process, rather than the outcome, allows you to perform even when something unforeseen occurs. “Chaos can be very productive, if you look for opportunities that come.” by Dave Alred, Penguin, $35 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.theweeklyreview.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/TWR-Success-Edition-Dave-Alred-09.jpg</main_image>
</document>
