<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Western Refining Inc. (WNR) Upgraded at Zacks Investment Research</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084355/western-refining-inc-wnr-upgraded-at-zacks-investment-research/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Western Refining Inc. (NYSE:WNR) from a strong sell rating to a hold rating in a research note released on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Western Refining revealed that the third quarter had a reassuring start with demand for gasoline remaining favorable. Further, the price of crude, which the company uses as an input for manufacturing refined products, is way below the mid-2014 level. Both the events are likely to help the company generate significant cash flow going ahead. Moreover, the company has a history of creating value for its shareholders by increasing dividend and repurchasing shares. However, investors&apos; pessimistic outlook could be gauged from the company&apos;s suppressed share price that has plunged around 32% year-to-date. Moreover, the elevated debt levels following the NTI acquisition is another headwind that needs to be addressed.” 
In other Western Refining news, Chairman Paul L. Foster purchased 325,000 shares of Western Refining stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 9th. The stock was purchased at an average price of $23.59 per share, for a total transaction of $7,666,750.00. Following the transaction, the chairman now directly owns 3,109,466 shares in the company, valued at $73,352,302.94. The purchase was disclosed in a document filed with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, Director Brian John Hogan purchased 10,000 shares of Western Refining stock in a transaction that occurred on Friday, May 27th. The stock was acquired at an average price of $21.37 per share, with a total value of $213,700.00. Following the transaction, the director now owns 78,463 shares in the company, valued at $1,676,754.31. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
A number of hedge funds have added to or reduced their stakes in the stock. Acrospire Investment Management LLC acquired a new stake in Western Refining during the first quarter valued at approximately $197,000. Adams Diversified Equity Fund Inc. purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $204,000. Trellus Management Company LLC purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $264,000. Americafirst Capital Management LLC purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $288,000. Finally, Virginia Retirement System purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the first quarter valued at about $355,000. 
Shares of Western Refining ( NYSE:WNR ) opened at 23.43 on Tuesday. The firm has a market cap of $2.54 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 8.33. Western Refining has a 52-week low of $18.14 and a 52-week high of $47.55. The company’s 50-day moving average is $21.70 and its 200 day moving average is $24.35. 
Western Refining (NYSE:WNR) last issued its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, August 2nd. The company reported $0.72 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.51 by $0.21. During the same quarter in the prior year, the firm earned $1.44 EPS. The firm earned $2.11 billion during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $2.11 billion. The firm’s revenue was down 25.5% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, analysts expect that Western Refining will post $1.19 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Tuesday, August 9th. Investors of record on Monday, July 25th were given a $0.38 dividend. The ex-dividend date was Thursday, July 21st. This represents a $1.52 annualized dividend and a yield of 6.49%. 
A number of other research analysts also recently issued reports on the stock. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. downgraded shares of Western Refining from a neutral rating to an underweight rating and decreased their price target for the stock from $28.00 to $20.00 in a research note on Friday, June 10th. Tudor Pickering upgraded shares of Western Refining from a sell rating to a hold rating in a research note on Tuesday, June 28th. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. reiterated a neutral rating and issued a $22.00 price target on shares of Western Refining in a research note on Thursday, July 14th. Morgan Stanley set a $21.00 price target on shares of Western Refining and gave the stock a hold rating in a research note on Wednesday, August 3rd. Finally, Simmons restated a hold rating and set a $26.00 price objective (down previously from $27.00) on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Wednesday, May 4th. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, eight have assigned a hold rating and three have given a buy rating to the stock. Western Refining has an average rating of Hold and a consensus price target of $32.11. 
Western Refining, Inc (Western) is a crude oil refiner and marketer of refined products. The Company operates through four segments: refining, Northern Tier Energy LP (NTI), Western Refining Logistics, LP (WNRL) and retail. Its refining segment owns and operates over two refineries in the Southwest that process crude oil and other feedstocks into gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel and asphalt. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Western Refining (WNR) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Western Refining Inc.   Western Refining Inc.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084355/western-refining-inc-wnr-upgraded-at-zacks-investment-research/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0746</post_time>
<username>Stephan Byrd</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Western Refining Inc. (NYSE:WNR) from a strong sell rating to a hold rating in a research note released on Tuesday. 
According to Zacks, “Western Refining revealed that the third quarter had a reassuring start with demand for gasoline remaining favorable. Further, the price of crude, which the company uses as an input for manufacturing refined products, is way below the mid-2014 level. Both the events are likely to help the company generate significant cash flow going ahead. Moreover, the company has a history of creating value for its shareholders by increasing dividend and repurchasing shares. However, investors&apos; pessimistic outlook could be gauged from the company&apos;s suppressed share price that has plunged around 32% year-to-date. Moreover, the elevated debt levels following the NTI acquisition is another headwind that needs to be addressed.” 
In other Western Refining news, Chairman Paul L. Foster purchased 325,000 shares of Western Refining stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, August 9th. The stock was purchased at an average price of $23.59 per share, for a total transaction of $7,666,750.00. Following the transaction, the chairman now directly owns 3,109,466 shares in the company, valued at $73,352,302.94. The purchase was disclosed in a document filed with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, Director Brian John Hogan purchased 10,000 shares of Western Refining stock in a transaction that occurred on Friday, May 27th. The stock was acquired at an average price of $21.37 per share, with a total value of $213,700.00. Following the transaction, the director now owns 78,463 shares in the company, valued at $1,676,754.31. The disclosure for this purchase can be found here . 
A number of hedge funds have added to or reduced their stakes in the stock. Acrospire Investment Management LLC acquired a new stake in Western Refining during the first quarter valued at approximately $197,000. Adams Diversified Equity Fund Inc. purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $204,000. Trellus Management Company LLC purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $264,000. Americafirst Capital Management LLC purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the second quarter valued at about $288,000. Finally, Virginia Retirement System purchased a new position in shares of Western Refining during the first quarter valued at about $355,000. 
Shares of Western Refining ( NYSE:WNR ) opened at 23.43 on Tuesday. The firm has a market cap of $2.54 billion and a price-to-earnings ratio of 8.33. Western Refining has a 52-week low of $18.14 and a 52-week high of $47.55. The company’s 50-day moving average is $21.70 and its 200 day moving average is $24.35. 
Western Refining (NYSE:WNR) last issued its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, August 2nd. The company reported $0.72 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping analysts’ consensus estimates of $0.51 by $0.21. During the same quarter in the prior year, the firm earned $1.44 EPS. The firm earned $2.11 billion during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $2.11 billion. The firm’s revenue was down 25.5% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, analysts expect that Western Refining will post $1.19 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. 
The firm also recently declared a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Tuesday, August 9th. Investors of record on Monday, July 25th were given a $0.38 dividend. The ex-dividend date was Thursday, July 21st. This represents a $1.52 annualized dividend and a yield of 6.49%. 
A number of other research analysts also recently issued reports on the stock. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. downgraded shares of Western Refining from a neutral rating to an underweight rating and decreased their price target for the stock from $28.00 to $20.00 in a research note on Friday, June 10th. Tudor Pickering upgraded shares of Western Refining from a sell rating to a hold rating in a research note on Tuesday, June 28th. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. reiterated a neutral rating and issued a $22.00 price target on shares of Western Refining in a research note on Thursday, July 14th. Morgan Stanley set a $21.00 price target on shares of Western Refining and gave the stock a hold rating in a research note on Wednesday, August 3rd. Finally, Simmons restated a hold rating and set a $26.00 price objective (down previously from $27.00) on shares of Western Refining in a research report on Wednesday, May 4th. One investment analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, eight have assigned a hold rating and three have given a buy rating to the stock. Western Refining has an average rating of Hold and a consensus price target of $32.11. 
Western Refining, Inc (Western) is a crude oil refiner and marketer of refined products. The Company operates through four segments: refining, Northern Tier Energy LP (NTI), Western Refining Logistics, LP (WNRL) and retail. Its refining segment owns and operates over two refineries in the Southwest that process crude oil and other feedstocks into gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel and asphalt. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Western Refining (WNR) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Western Refining Inc.   Western Refining Inc.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/western-refining-inc-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
