<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://rss.artipot.com/category/143</forum>
<forum_title>Artipot: Internet &gt; Search Engine Optimization Articles</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Outsourcing - Advantages and disadvantages (Rahulkuamr)</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.artipot.com/articles/2023578/outsourcing-advantages-and-disadvantages.htm</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Advantages of Outsourcing Cost Savings There can be significant cost savings when a business function is outsourced. Employee compensation costs, office space expenses and other costs associated with providing a work space or manufacturing setup are eliminated and free up resources for other purposes. Focus on Core Business Outsourcing allows organization to focus on their expertise and core business. When organizations go outside their expertise, they get into business functions and processes that they may not be as knowledgeable about and could potentially take away from their main focus.An example of this is when a grocery store decides to add a florist to their operation. If too much focus is put on that part of the business they lose focus of the core business which is grocery. Improved Quality Improved quality can be achieved by using vendors with more expertise and more specialized processes.An example of this would be contracting out a cleaning service. An outside service would have the resources for hiring, proper training and facility inspections that may not be available if the function were kept in-house. Customer Satisfaction The advantage of having a vendor contract is they are bound to certain levels of service and quality.An example of this is if your IT function is outsourced and the technician calls in sick, it is the vendor&apos;s responsibility to find someone to replace them and meet your support needs. Operational Efficiency Outsourcing gives an organization exposure to vendor specialized systems. Specialization provides more efficiency that allows for a quicker turnaround time and higher levels of quality. Disadvantages of Outsourcing Quality Risk Outsourcing can expose an organization to potential risks and legal exposure.As an example, if a car is recalled for faulty parts and that part was outsourced, the car manufacturer carries the burden of correcting the potentially damaged reputation of the car maker.While the vendor would need to make good on the faulty product by contract, the manufacturer still has the black eye from the incident and carries the burden of correcting the negative public perception. Quality Service Unless a contract specifically identifies a measurable process for quality service reporting, there could be a poor service quality experience. Some contracts are written to intentionally leave service levels out to save on costs. Language Barriers If a customer call center is outsourced to a country that speaks a different language, there may be levels of dissatisfaction for customers dealing with the language barriers of someone with a strong accent. About the Author Webigg Technology, one of the Internet Marketing Company New Delhi offers great services in the domain of online marketing, Online Marketing Companies New Delhi, web designing, web development, Internet Marketing Company India &amp; Online Marketing Companies India . Rating:
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.artipot.com/articles/2023578/outsourcing-advantages-and-disadvantages.htm</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0703</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Advantages of Outsourcing Cost Savings There can be significant cost savings when a business function is outsourced. Employee compensation costs, office space expenses and other costs associated with providing a work space or manufacturing setup are eliminated and free up resources for other purposes. Focus on Core Business Outsourcing allows organization to focus on their expertise and core business. When organizations go outside their expertise, they get into business functions and processes that they may not be as knowledgeable about and could potentially take away from their main focus.An example of this is when a grocery store decides to add a florist to their operation. If too much focus is put on that part of the business they lose focus of the core business which is grocery. Improved Quality Improved quality can be achieved by using vendors with more expertise and more specialized processes.An example of this would be contracting out a cleaning service. An outside service would have the resources for hiring, proper training and facility inspections that may not be available if the function were kept in-house. Customer Satisfaction The advantage of having a vendor contract is they are bound to certain levels of service and quality.An example of this is if your IT function is outsourced and the technician calls in sick, it is the vendor&apos;s responsibility to find someone to replace them and meet your support needs. Operational Efficiency Outsourcing gives an organization exposure to vendor specialized systems. Specialization provides more efficiency that allows for a quicker turnaround time and higher levels of quality. Disadvantages of Outsourcing Quality Risk Outsourcing can expose an organization to potential risks and legal exposure.As an example, if a car is recalled for faulty parts and that part was outsourced, the car manufacturer carries the burden of correcting the potentially damaged reputation of the car maker.While the vendor would need to make good on the faulty product by contract, the manufacturer still has the black eye from the incident and carries the burden of correcting the negative public perception. Quality Service Unless a contract specifically identifies a measurable process for quality service reporting, there could be a poor service quality experience. Some contracts are written to intentionally leave service levels out to save on costs. Language Barriers If a customer call center is outsourced to a country that speaks a different language, there may be levels of dissatisfaction for customers dealing with the language barriers of someone with a strong accent. About the Author Webigg Technology, one of the Internet Marketing Company New Delhi offers great services in the domain of online marketing, Online Marketing Companies New Delhi, web designing, web development, Internet Marketing Company India &amp; Online Marketing Companies India . Rating:
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
