<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Independent - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Prince: fentanyl pills found at late musician&apos;s home were &apos;mislabelled&apos;, say investigators | People | News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/prince-fentanyl-pills-found-at-late-musicians-home-were-mislabelled-say-investigators-a7203146.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Pills found at Prince’s home following the musician’s death in April contained the highly powerful opioid fentanyl, but were mislabelled, it has emerged.
Officials investigating the singer’s death told the Minneapolis Star Tribune that the pills in question had been labelled as “Watson 385”, a designation for pills containing the weaker painkillers acetaminophen and hydrocone.
Read more Prince&apos;s potential heirs cut down to six Prince, 57, was found dead in a lift at his Paisley Park home in Minneapolis on 21 April. An autopsy found that he had died from an accidental overdose of fentanyl, a synthetic opioid said to be up to 50 times more powerful than heroin.
Officials told the Associated Press that the Purple Rain star had no prescriptions for any controlled substance at the time of his death, and authorities are continuing to investigate how he obtained the drugs that killed him.
Some 700 Americans overdosed on fentanyl in 2015, with the opioid now a major part of the illegal drugs market. In Connecticut alone, the number of fentanyl-related deaths rose by more than 150 per cent last year.
Read more Prince protegee Judith Hill reveals how star fell unconscious on private jet What is fentanyl? Prince died after overdosing on painkiller &apos;hundreds of times more potent than heroin&apos; Prince: Police question doctor who treated musician on day before his death Investigators reportedly found around a dozen of the counterfeit tablets in a dressing room at Prince’s home, but most of the singer’s supply were stashed in aspirin and Vitamin C bottles that he is thought to have carried when he travelled.
The pills contained not just fentanyl but several other drugs such as U-4770, another strong, synthetic painkiller. The unnamed official told AP that tests conducted on Prince prior to his death showed no evidence of fentanyl in his system, suggesting he was not a long-time user of the drug and likely took the fatal dose in the hours leading up to his death.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>4</post_num>
<post_id>post-4</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/prince-fentanyl-pills-found-at-late-musicians-home-were-mislabelled-say-investigators-a7203146.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>1050</post_time>
<username>Pan</username>
<post>
Nonsense. This guy was a long-term pharmaceutical painkiller addict. His former dealer has recounted details of his use of these synthetic opiates - as if the manner of his death and the subsequent discoveries at his home weren&apos;t evidence enough. As someone who has received Fentanyl (via an epidural drip) I can tell you that it&apos;s incredibly potent and induces a very strange, hallucinated state of mind. Guaranteed confusion and poor judgement. Clearly when buying drugs on the black market they don&apos;t necessarily come in manufacturers&apos; packaging. Quite incredible that a man of such intelligence and talent subscribed to an insane cult like the &quot;Jehova&apos;s Witnesses&quot; which caused him to consume drugs illegally rather than getting surgery (which involves blood transfusions) for mobility problems. This seems to have been the ultimate cause of the addiction and his subsequent death. Yet another example of the human damage caused by a belief in primitive magical superstitions known as &quot;religion&quot;.
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2016/06/21/15/prince-musician_0.jpg</main_image>
</document>
