<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://tickerreport.com/feed/</forum>
<forum_title>Ticker Report</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Zacks Investment Research Upgrades Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) to “Buy”</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084371/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-edwards-lifesciences-corp-ew-to-buy-2/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report published on Tuesday morning. Zacks Investment Research currently has $128.00 price objective on the medical research company’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Edwards Lifesciences ended the second quarter on an encouraging note, with its financial numbers squarely beating the Zacks Consensus Estimate. Moreover, the upward revision in 2016 guidance raises investor optimism in the stock. Although Edwards’ higher operating expenses might have made investors apprehensive, it is a respite for them to know that the higher expenses were for advanced initiatives adopted by the company to improve its overall sales growth. Nevertheless, management expects to gain traction in the ever expanding TAVR market, based on increasing preference in favor of transcatheter aortic valve replacement as well as compelling clinical evidences, leading to strong adoption of its THV therapy. On the flip side, the company persistently performed poorly on its gross margin front. Competitive headwinds and reimbursement pressure also continue to pose challenges.” 
In other Edwards Lifesciences Corp. news, VP Donald E. Bobo, Jr. sold 18,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $99.04, for a total value of $1,782,720.00. Following the transaction, the vice president now owns 62,796 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $6,219,315.84. The transaction was disclosed in a legal filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . Also, VP Huimin Wang sold 13,650 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, July 5th. The stock was sold at an average price of $98.44, for a total value of $1,343,706.00. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors have bought and sold shares of the company. Sands Capital Management LLC raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 724.2% in the fourth quarter. Sands Capital Management LLC now owns 10,924,382 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $862,808,000 after buying an additional 9,598,997 shares in the last quarter. Norges Bank acquired a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the fourth quarter worth approximately $131,001,000. Pioneer Investment Management Inc. raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 679.0% in the fourth quarter. Pioneer Investment Management Inc. now owns 1,578,222 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $124,648,000 after buying an additional 1,375,636 shares in the last quarter. Voya Investment Management LLC raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 65.4% in the fourth quarter. Voya Investment Management LLC now owns 2,910,746 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $229,890,000 after buying an additional 1,150,479 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Generation Investment Management LLP raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 76.6% in the fourth quarter. Generation Investment Management LLP now owns 2,586,930 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $204,316,000 after buying an additional 1,122,035 shares in the last quarter. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. ( NYSE:EW ) opened at 118.07 on Tuesday. The stock has a market cap of $25.13 billion and a PE ratio of 48.79. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has a 52 week low of $62.53 and a 52 week high of $118.26. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $109.57 and its 200 day moving average is $99.30. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The medical research company reported $0.76 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the consensus estimate of $0.70 by $0.06. The business earned $759.30 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $724.26 million. Edwards Lifesciences Corp.’s revenue for the quarter was up 23.1% on a year-over-year basis. During the same period in the previous year, the company posted $0.57 EPS. Analysts predict that Edwards Lifesciences Corp. will post $2.87 EPS for the current year. 
Several other equities research analysts have also recently weighed in on the stock. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. reaffirmed a buy rating and issued a $130.00 price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research report on Thursday, July 28th. JMP Securities upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $125.00 to $130.00 and gave the stock a market outperform rating in a research report on Thursday, July 28th. Citigroup Inc. upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $86.00 to $94.00 and gave the stock a sell rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. Barclays PLC upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $105.00 to $115.00 and gave the stock an equal weight rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. Finally, BMO Capital Markets reaffirmed a buy rating and issued a $120.00 price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. One equities research analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and twenty-one have assigned a buy rating to the company. The company currently has a consensus rating of Buy and a consensus price target of $118.13. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corporation is focused on technologies that treat structural heart disease and critically ill patients. The Company manufactures heart valve systems and repair products used to replace or repair a patient’s diseased or defective heart valve. It develops hemodynamic monitoring systems used to measure a patient’s cardiovascular function in the hospital setting. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.  
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.tickerreport.com/banking-finance/2084371/zacks-investment-research-upgrades-edwards-lifesciences-corp-ew-to-buy-2/</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0748</post_time>
<username>Shane Hupp</username>
<post>
Tweet 
Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) from a hold rating to a buy rating in a report published on Tuesday morning. Zacks Investment Research currently has $128.00 price objective on the medical research company’s stock. 
According to Zacks, “Edwards Lifesciences ended the second quarter on an encouraging note, with its financial numbers squarely beating the Zacks Consensus Estimate. Moreover, the upward revision in 2016 guidance raises investor optimism in the stock. Although Edwards’ higher operating expenses might have made investors apprehensive, it is a respite for them to know that the higher expenses were for advanced initiatives adopted by the company to improve its overall sales growth. Nevertheless, management expects to gain traction in the ever expanding TAVR market, based on increasing preference in favor of transcatheter aortic valve replacement as well as compelling clinical evidences, leading to strong adoption of its THV therapy. On the flip side, the company persistently performed poorly on its gross margin front. Competitive headwinds and reimbursement pressure also continue to pose challenges.” 
In other Edwards Lifesciences Corp. news, VP Donald E. Bobo, Jr. sold 18,000 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, May 31st. The stock was sold at an average price of $99.04, for a total value of $1,782,720.00. Following the transaction, the vice president now owns 62,796 shares of the company’s stock, valued at $6,219,315.84. The transaction was disclosed in a legal filing with the SEC, which is available through the SEC website . Also, VP Huimin Wang sold 13,650 shares of the business’s stock in a transaction on Tuesday, July 5th. The stock was sold at an average price of $98.44, for a total value of $1,343,706.00. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . 
A number of institutional investors have bought and sold shares of the company. Sands Capital Management LLC raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 724.2% in the fourth quarter. Sands Capital Management LLC now owns 10,924,382 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $862,808,000 after buying an additional 9,598,997 shares in the last quarter. Norges Bank acquired a new position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. during the fourth quarter worth approximately $131,001,000. Pioneer Investment Management Inc. raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 679.0% in the fourth quarter. Pioneer Investment Management Inc. now owns 1,578,222 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $124,648,000 after buying an additional 1,375,636 shares in the last quarter. Voya Investment Management LLC raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 65.4% in the fourth quarter. Voya Investment Management LLC now owns 2,910,746 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $229,890,000 after buying an additional 1,150,479 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Generation Investment Management LLP raised its position in Edwards Lifesciences Corp. by 76.6% in the fourth quarter. Generation Investment Management LLP now owns 2,586,930 shares of the medical research company’s stock worth $204,316,000 after buying an additional 1,122,035 shares in the last quarter. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. ( NYSE:EW ) opened at 118.07 on Tuesday. The stock has a market cap of $25.13 billion and a PE ratio of 48.79. Edwards Lifesciences Corp. has a 52 week low of $62.53 and a 52 week high of $118.26. The stock’s 50 day moving average is $109.57 and its 200 day moving average is $99.30. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (NYSE:EW) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, July 26th. The medical research company reported $0.76 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the consensus estimate of $0.70 by $0.06. The business earned $759.30 million during the quarter, compared to analysts’ expectations of $724.26 million. Edwards Lifesciences Corp.’s revenue for the quarter was up 23.1% on a year-over-year basis. During the same period in the previous year, the company posted $0.57 EPS. Analysts predict that Edwards Lifesciences Corp. will post $2.87 EPS for the current year. 
Several other equities research analysts have also recently weighed in on the stock. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. reaffirmed a buy rating and issued a $130.00 price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research report on Thursday, July 28th. JMP Securities upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $125.00 to $130.00 and gave the stock a market outperform rating in a research report on Thursday, July 28th. Citigroup Inc. upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $86.00 to $94.00 and gave the stock a sell rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. Barclays PLC upped their price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. from $105.00 to $115.00 and gave the stock an equal weight rating in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. Finally, BMO Capital Markets reaffirmed a buy rating and issued a $120.00 price target on shares of Edwards Lifesciences Corp. in a research report on Wednesday, July 27th. One equities research analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, five have assigned a hold rating and twenty-one have assigned a buy rating to the company. The company currently has a consensus rating of Buy and a consensus price target of $118.13. 
Edwards Lifesciences Corporation is focused on technologies that treat structural heart disease and critically ill patients. The Company manufactures heart valve systems and repair products used to replace or repair a patient’s diseased or defective heart valve. It develops hemodynamic monitoring systems used to measure a patient’s cardiovascular function in the hospital setting. 
Get a free copy of the Zacks research report on Edwards Lifesciences Corp. (EW) 
For more information about research offerings from Zacks Investment Research, visit Zacks.com   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.   Edwards Lifesciences Corp.  
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.tickerreport.com/logos/edwards-lifesciences-logo.gif</main_image>
</document>
