<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Android Game Development Company Unity 3D, 2D &amp; 3D Graphics</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://morpheous.co/services/game-development/android-game-development/</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Hire Elite Android Game Designing &amp; Development Team Android Game Development Shalin Shukla 2016-07-29T09:18:01+00:00 Android is the most popular platform for smart phone. When iOS caters to the niche market of Apple gadgets, Android is available on a variety of devices. It is its wide acceptability and availability that has made Android such a powerful platform for game development. There are currently about a million apps available in the Google Play marketplace and majority of it belongs to the category of games. Android games are also successful in terms of commercials. According to the statistics available, the industry generated around 24.4 billion U.S. dollars in revenue in 2014 and is expected to grow to 44.2 billion by 2018. Realize your Android game development dream with Morpheous. We offer state-of-art game development and marketing solution on Android games for smartphones and tabs. Morpheous is an android game development studio that has been catering to clients across industry spectrum. If you have a game idea we can convert it into reality with unparalleled design and development support Why android game development is a cool idea Android is the most widely used smartphone OS. It’s versatile and is supported by a large number of devices. In the smartphone industry, Android enjoys the largest market share pushing Apple to the second position. The several reasons to consider Android game development are mentioned below. • Android is omnipresent and runs on most number of devices which means greater market for your game • Android is a simple and user friendly platform which ensure lesser time in app development • The cost involved in developing Android game is lower than other platforms • Availability of various app stores and marketplaces improves chances of brand recognition and better visibility • It costs less to market and promote your game on Android marketplace. Large number of users and availability of different marketplaces improves scopes of promoting your game • Faster development and lower cost of promotion means higher rate of ROI • Maximize revenue by publishing your game on different marketplace Whatever is your game idea we will deliver it to you Our team comprises of ace android game developers with many years of experience in delivering high-end and scalable game development solution for all forms of android platform. Take advantage of our advanced market knowledge and technical expertise in turning your dream into reality. Our experience in designing hundreds of games for the Google Play Store helps us in designing any type of game for the Android platform quite easily. Our team of experts will analyze your requirements and accordingly will offer the best designing solution in the industry. We offer adaptive and scalable game development for Android platform We develop games on the latest android platform and it is designed to be scalable to run effortlessly even on the higher versions as they may come out. As Android supports games developed on Java and flash our Android game developers are enablers of high-end games optimized for performance in different screen sizes and resolution. Morpheous is an android game development company specialist in delivering 2D and 3D games for rich gaming experience. If Android game development and marketing service is what you are looking for, we can help you realize your dream. From Game Development, Design, Game Trailers to Game Play Videos, We Do it All! We’re Here To Help You Grow Your Business! We are here to convert your Android Game Idea into Reality! Connect with Morpheous and Know More. × We&apos;d Love To Hear From You! 
Fill out the form and our team will be in touch with you promptly. Thank you for your interest! 
Name * 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.92</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://morpheous.co/services/game-development/android-game-development/</post_url>
<post_date>20160729</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username>Shalin Shukla</username>
<post>
Hire Elite Android Game Designing &amp; Development Team Android Game Development Shalin Shukla 2016-07-29T09:18:01+00:00 Android is the most popular platform for smart phone. When iOS caters to the niche market of Apple gadgets, Android is available on a variety of devices. It is its wide acceptability and availability that has made Android such a powerful platform for game development. There are currently about a million apps available in the Google Play marketplace and majority of it belongs to the category of games. Android games are also successful in terms of commercials. According to the statistics available, the industry generated around 24.4 billion U.S. dollars in revenue in 2014 and is expected to grow to 44.2 billion by 2018. Realize your Android game development dream with Morpheous. We offer state-of-art game development and marketing solution on Android games for smartphones and tabs. Morpheous is an android game development studio that has been catering to clients across industry spectrum. If you have a game idea we can convert it into reality with unparalleled design and development support Why android game development is a cool idea Android is the most widely used smartphone OS. It’s versatile and is supported by a large number of devices. In the smartphone industry, Android enjoys the largest market share pushing Apple to the second position. The several reasons to consider Android game development are mentioned below. • Android is omnipresent and runs on most number of devices which means greater market for your game • Android is a simple and user friendly platform which ensure lesser time in app development • The cost involved in developing Android game is lower than other platforms • Availability of various app stores and marketplaces improves chances of brand recognition and better visibility • It costs less to market and promote your game on Android marketplace. Large number of users and availability of different marketplaces improves scopes of promoting your game • Faster development and lower cost of promotion means higher rate of ROI • Maximize revenue by publishing your game on different marketplace Whatever is your game idea we will deliver it to you Our team comprises of ace android game developers with many years of experience in delivering high-end and scalable game development solution for all forms of android platform. Take advantage of our advanced market knowledge and technical expertise in turning your dream into reality. Our experience in designing hundreds of games for the Google Play Store helps us in designing any type of game for the Android platform quite easily. Our team of experts will analyze your requirements and accordingly will offer the best designing solution in the industry. We offer adaptive and scalable game development for Android platform We develop games on the latest android platform and it is designed to be scalable to run effortlessly even on the higher versions as they may come out. As Android supports games developed on Java and flash our Android game developers are enablers of high-end games optimized for performance in different screen sizes and resolution. Morpheous is an android game development company specialist in delivering 2D and 3D games for rich gaming experience. If Android game development and marketing service is what you are looking for, we can help you realize your dream. From Game Development, Design, Game Trailers to Game Play Videos, We Do it All! We’re Here To Help You Grow Your Business! We are here to convert your Android Game Idea into Reality! Connect with Morpheous and Know More. × We&apos;d Love To Hear From You! 
Fill out the form and our team will be in touch with you promptly. Thank you for your interest! 
Name * 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>CO</country>
<main_image>http://morpheous.co/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/review-android-new.jpg</main_image>
</document>
