<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.usatoday.com/olympics-rio-2016/</forum>
<forum_title>Rio 2016 Summer Olympics | USA TODAY NETWORK</forum_title>
<discussion_title>USA&apos;s Claressa Shields wins gold, makes history in U.S. boxing</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/olympics/rio-2016/2016/08/21/clareesa-shields-gold-boxing-middleweight/89075538/</topic_url>
<topic_text>

Claressa Shields (USA) celebrates after defeating Nouchka Fontijn (NED) in the women&apos;s middleweight final bout Riocentro - Pavilion 6 on Aug. 21. (Photo: Erich Schlegel-USA TODAY Sports)
RIO DE JANEIRO — The surprise was hidden in her pocket — something historic.
Claressa Shields stood on the podium on Sunday afternoon with the Olympic gold medal hanging around her neck that she had just won in women’s boxing. She reached into her pocket and pulled out her other gold medal, the one she won in London at the 2012 Games.
She slipped it over her head, looked down at both medals at her chest and let out a huge smile. It was historic on so many levels, something never seen before. Shields became the first U.S. boxer to win two gold medals.
“I’m the two-time Olympic champion!” Shields said, defeating the Netherland’s Nouchka Fontijn in the women’s middleweight (75-kilogram) division in a unanimous decision. “Oh my God, I feel like I’m dreaming. I don’t want to wake up right now. Please tell me I’m not dreaming.”
Shields talked to reporters still wearing tape on her hands, still covered in sweat. An American flag was draped around her neck. After the win, she did a cartwheel in the ring and ran around the arena with the flag. She let all her emotions show, something she didn’t do in 2012 and she has always regretted it. But not this time. She let it all out, pure unbridled joy and surprise.
“I worked so hard to be here,” she said. “Oh my god, this is crazy.”
Growing up This is a gold medal that represents survival. She escaped from poverty and a difficult childhood, bouncing between 11 homes by the time she was 12, turning all of that pain into a champion boxer.
It is a story of growth and maturity.
“I want to inspire people,” she said, at a press conference where she was named the tournament’s most outstanding boxer. “I want to help people. I want to give people just a little bit of hope.”
After winning the gold in London, Shields did not get the money or fame or endorsements that she expected. She was perceived to be too strong, too tough and too fierce to be marketable and didn’t have a strong, experienced team behind her. After winning the gold medal, life didn’t get easier. When everybody thought Shields had become rich, there she was, going to a collection agency to pay her mother’s past-due water bill.
But she is older now, more mature and has control of her life. She split from her longtime coach, Jason Crutchfield, who had coached her when she started boxing at 11 and had been a father figure. She moved to the U.S. Olympic Training Center in Colorado Springs, Colo., staying in a dorm. The move was to simplify her life, trying to avoid the distractions in Flint, Mich.
No longer a teenager, she has also learned responsibility.
“The difference is, now that I’m grown, I make a lot of decisions in my life,” Shields said, earlier this week. “I kind of protect myself. When I was 17, my coach would turn off my phone for me. He would ask me was I OK all the time. He would check on me constantly. He would see me on Twitter at 1 o’clock in the morning and he’d be like, ‘What are you doing? Go to bed.’
“Now, it’s like, I have to tell myself to do those things. Go to bed. Drink right. Eat right. Don’t stay up too late. Don’t stay in the shower for 20 minutes because it’s like a steam room. Get in there for 5 minutes and get out. I have to keep reminding myself these things. I’m telling myself to focus.”
With this win, Shields becomes the most successful U.S. Olympic boxer in history — the only one to win two gold medals. That should be applauded.
But she is not — not yet, at least — the most accomplished boxer in Olympic history. A pair of Cubans have won three golds each: Teofilo Stevenson dominated the men’s heavyweight from 1972 to 1980 and Felix Savon won three in a row from 1992 to 2000.
Shields is not the most accomplished female boxer in Olympic history, either. Here in Rio, Nicola Adams, who is called the “smiling Yorkshire assassin,” won the flyweight boxing division for Britain for the second straight Olympic Games.
That’s not, in any way, to diminish what Shields has done.
She still has some work to do, to become the greatest Olympic boxer in history.
But she is only 21, and she certainly has time for that.
What&apos;s next Before the match, Shields came to a conclusion: there was no way Fontijn was going to win. Shields had beaten her two months ago for the world championship, and at that time, Shields had an injured hand and shoulder.
“She can’t outbox me,” Shields said. “She can’t out fight me. She can’t out think me, so how is she going to win? She will have to knock me out. But I knew she couldn’t do that.”
Late in the fight, Shields acted like she was begging Fontijn to fight. “I was like, ‘Hey, we are here to fight,’” Shields said. “‘If you think you can bet me, let’s go. I hit you with a hard shot, hit me back. I want to see if you can hit me.’”
She couldn’t – not with the way that Shields slipped and ducked – Shields won every round against Fontijn.
“I don’t even remember getting hit,” she said. “Did I get hit?”
Fontijn had a size advantage and a longer reach, but that didn’t matter. “Every time I came back to the corner, they said, ‘You got that round. You got that round,’” Shields said.
What’s next? She has no idea.
“I’m ready for a break,” she said. “I want to go home.”
Back home to Flint, to see her family.
“I’m a two-time Olympic gold medalist!” Shield said, gasping for air, trying to make it seem real. “I can’t believe I just said that.”
Jeff Seidel writes for the Detroit Free Press, part of the USA TODAY Network.
PHOTOS: EVERY U.S. MEDAL
Facebook Twitter Google+ LinkedIn Rio Olympics: Every medal captured by Team USA Fullscreen Post to Facebook Posted! A link has been posted to your Facebook feed.
Team USA won gold in men&apos;s basketball. Bob Rosato, RVR Photos-USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kyle Snyder won gold in men&apos;s 97kg freestyle wrestling. Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Claressa Shields (USA) won gold in women&apos;s middleweight boxing. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Matt Centrowitz captured gold in the men&apos;s 1,500. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA won gold in the men&apos;s 4x400-meter relay. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA won gold in the women&apos;s 4x400-meter relay. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA captured gold in women&apos;s basketball. Jeff Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Gwen Jorgensen won gold in the women&apos;s triathlon. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA captured gold in the women&apos;s 4x100-meter relay. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The women&apos;s water polo team captured the gold medal. Peter Casey, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Connor Fields captured gold in men&apos;s individual BMX cycling. Guy Rhodes, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dalilah Muhammad won gold and Ashley Spencer took bronze in the women&apos;s 400-meter hurdles. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Ashton Eaton won gold in the men&apos;s decathlon. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Ryan Crouser won the gold medal in men&apos;s shot put. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kerron Clement won gold in the men&apos;s 400-meter hurdles. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Helen Louise Maroulis won gold medal in the women&apos;s 53kg freestyle wrestling. Jeff Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Brianna Rollins won gold, Nia Ali captured silver and Kristi Castlin grabbed bronze in the women&apos;s 100-meter hurdles. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Tianna Bartoletta won gold and Brittney Reese took silver in the women&apos;s long jump. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Biles won gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in the women&apos;s floor exercise. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Christian Taylor won gold and Will Claye took silver in the men&apos;s triple jump. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Biles won gold in the women&apos;s vault. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The pair of Bethanie Mattek-Sands and Jack Sock, right, took gold, while the duo of Venus Williams and Rajeev Ram grabbed silver in mixed doubles tennis. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The U.S. team of Ryan Murphy, Cody Miller, Michael Phelps and Nathan Adrian won gold in the men&apos;s 4x100-meter medley relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Jeff Henderson won gold in the men&apos;s long jump. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The U.S. team of Kathleen Baker, Lilly King, Dana Vollmer and Simone Manuel captured gold in the women&apos;s 4x100-meter medley relay. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA won gold in the women&apos;s eight rowing competition. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Michelle Carter captured gold in women&apos;s shot put. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Katie Ledecky captured gold in the women&apos;s 800-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Anthony Ervin, right, took gold and Nathan Adrian captured bronze in the men&apos;s 50-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Maya DiRado took gold in the women&apos;s 200-meter backstroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Manuel captured a gold medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Michael Phelps won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter individual medley. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Ryan Murphy won gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter backstroke. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Biles captured gold and Aly Raisman claimed silver in women&apos;s individual all-around gymnastics. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kayla Harrison took gold in the women&apos;s 78kg judo. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The team of Allison Schmitt, Leah Smith, Maya DiRado and Katie Ledecky won gold in the women&apos;s 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kristin Armstrong won gold in the women&apos;s road cycling time trial, her third consecutive gold in the event. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The team of Conor Dwyer, Townley Haas, Ryan Lochte and Michael Phelps won the 4x200-meter freestyle relay. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Michael Phelps won the gold in the men&apos;s 200-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Katie Ledecky won women&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The U.S. women&apos;s gymnastics team (Aly Raisman, Madison Kocian, Laurie Hernandez, Gabby Douglas and Simone Biles) captured gold. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Ginny Thrasher captured gold in the women&apos;s 10-meter air rifle. Geoff Burke, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Lilly King, right, won gold and Katie Meili took bronze in the women&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The team of Nathan Adrian, Ryan Held, Michael Phelps and Caeleb Dressel won gold in the men&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Katie Ledecky captured gold and Leah Smith took bronze in the women&apos;s 400-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Ryan Murphy, right, took the gold medal while David Plummer brought home a bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Shakur Stevenson took silver in men&apos;s bantamweight boxing. Robert Hanashiro, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Paul Chelimo claimed silver in the men&apos;s 5,000. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Sandi Morris claimed silver in the women&apos;s pole vault. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Alise Post won the silver medal in women&apos;s individual BMX cycling Guy Rhodes, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Joe Kovacs grabbed silver in the men&apos;s shot put. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Evan Jager claimed silver in the men&apos;s 3,000-meter steeplechase. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA captured silver in equestrian open&apos;s team jumping. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Danell Leyva grabbed silver in the men&apos;s parallel bars. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Sarah Hammer took silver in women&apos;s omnium cycling. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Danell Leyva grabbed silver in the men&apos;s horizontal bar. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Laurie Hernandez took silver and Simone Biles claimed bronze in the women&apos;s balance beam. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Allyson Felix took silver in the women&apos;s 400. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Justin Gatlin grabbed silver in the men&apos;s 100. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Madison Kocian captured silver in the women&apos;s uneven bars. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Simone Manuel took silver in the women&apos;s 50-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Tori Bowie claimed silver in the women&apos;s 100. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Connor Jaeger grabbed silver in the men&apos;s 1,500-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The U.S. team of Sarah Hammer, Kelly Catlin, Chloe Dygert and Jennifer Valente took silver women&apos;s team pursuit cycling. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Gevvie Stone took silver in the women&apos;s singe sculls rowing competition. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Michael Phelps grabbed the silver medal in the men&apos;s 100-meter butterfly. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Daryl Homer took silver in men&apos;s individual sabre fencing. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Josh Prenot took silver in the men&apos;s 200-meter breaststroke. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Mike Hixon and Sam Dorman captured silver in men&apos;s 3-meter springboard synchronized diving. Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The team of Brady Ellison, and Zach Garrett and Jake Kaminski won silver in archery. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Chase Kalisz claimed silver in the men&apos;s 400-meter IM. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Maya DiRado claimed silver in the women&apos;s 400-meter IM. Erich Schlegel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The team of Simone Manuel, Abbey Weitzeil, Dana Vollmer and Katie Ledecky captured silver in the women&apos;s 4x100-meter freestyle relay. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Alexander Massialas claimed silver in men&apos;s individual foil fencing. Daniel Powers, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen David Boudia and Steele Johnson brought home silver in 10-meter platform synchronized diving. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kathleen Baker captured silver in the women&apos;s 100-meter backstroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Travis Stevens claimed the silver medal in men&apos;s 81kg judo. John David Mercer, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Galen Rupp took bronze in men&apos;s marathon. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA won bronze in men&apos;s volleyball. Christopher Hanewinckel, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Jackie Galloway grabbed bronze in women&apos;s heavyweight +67kg taekwondo. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen David Boudia grabbed bronze in men&apos;s 10-meter platform diving. Andrew P. Scott, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA players captured bronze in women&apos;s team volleyball. Jack Gruber, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen J&apos;den Cox took bronze in men&apos;s 86kg freestyle wrestling. David E. Klutho, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kerri Walsh Jennings and April Ross took bronze in women&apos;s beach volleyball. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Tori Bowie grabbed bronze in the women&apos;s 200. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Jenny Simpson claimed bronze in the women&apos;s 1,500. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Caleb Paine took bronze in men&apos;s finn sailing. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Emma Coburn won bronze in the women&apos;s 3,000-meter steeplechase. Kyle Terada, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Clayton Murphy grabbed bronze in the men&apos;s 800. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Sam Kendricks claimed bronze in the men&apos;s pole vault. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen LaShawn Merritt took bronze in the men&apos;s 400. Kirby Lee, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Sarah Elizabeth Robles took bronze in women&apos;s +75kg weightlifting. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Alexander Naddour took bronze in men&apos;s pommel horse. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Matt Kuchar claimed bronze in men&apos;s individual golf. Michael Madrid, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Steve Johnson and Jack Sock captured bronze in men&apos;s doubles tennis. Robert Deutsch, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Team USA took bronze in women&apos;s team sabre fencing. Jason Getz, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Kim Rhode won the bronze medal in women&apos;s skeet shooting. Geoff Burke, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Brady Ellison took the bronze medal in men&apos;s individual archery. Eric Seals, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The United States took bronze in men&apos;s team foil fencing. Jeffrey Swinger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen The United States took bronze in open&apos;s team dressage. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Nathan Adrian claimed bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Maya DiRado claimed the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 200-meter IM. Kevin Jairaj, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Corey Cogdell took bronze in women&apos;s trap. Matt Kryger, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Dana Vollmer took the bronze medal in the women&apos;s 100-meter butterfly. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Cody Miller claimed bronze in the men&apos;s 100-meter breaststroke. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Phillip Dutton, aboard Mighty Nice, took bronze in open&apos;s individual eventing. James Lang, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Conor Dwyer took bronze in the men&apos;s 200-meter freestyle. Rob Schumacher, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Nico Hernandez won bronze in the men&apos;s light flyweight boxing. Geoff Burke, USA TODAY Sports Fullscreen Like this topic? You may also like these photo galleries: Replay 1 of 108 2 of 108 3 of 108 4 of 108 5 of 108 6 of 108 7 of 108 8 of 108 9 of 108 10 of 108 11 of 108 12 of 108 13 of 108 14 of 108 15 of 108 16 of 108 17 of 108 18 of 108 19 of 108 20 of 108 21 of 108 22 of 108 23 of 108 24 of 108 25 of 108 26 of 108 27 of 108 28 of 108 29 of 108 30 of 108 31 of 108 32 of 108 33 of 108 34 of 108 35 of 108 36 of 108 37 of 108 38 of 108 39 of 108 40 of 108 41 of 108 42 of 108 43 of 108 44 of 108 45 of 108 46 of 108 47 of 108 48 of 108 49 of 108 50 of 108 51 of 108 52 of 108 53 of 108 54 of 108 55 of 108 56 of 108 57 of 108 58 of 108 59 of 108 60 of 108 61 of 108 62 of 108 63 of 108 64 of 108 65 of 108 66 of 108 67 of 108 68 of 108 69 of 108 70 of 108 71 of 108 72 of 108 73 of 108 74 of 108 75 of 108 76 of 108 77 of 108 78 of 108 79 of 108 80 of 108 81 of 108 82 of 108 83 of 108 84 of 108 85 of 108 86 of 108 87 of 108 88 of 108 89 of 108 90 of 108 91 of 108 92 of 108 93 of 108 94 of 108 95 of 108 96 of 108 97 of 108 98 of 108 99 of 108 100 of 108 101 of 108 102 of 108 103 of 108 104 of 108 105 of 108 106 of 108 107 of 108 108 of 108 Autoplay Show Thumbnails Show Captions Last Slide Next Slide
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.25</spam_score>
<post_num>2</post_num>
<post_id>post-2</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/olympics/rio-2016/2016/08/21/clareesa-shields-gold-boxing-middleweight/89075538/</post_url>
<post_date>20160821</post_date>
<post_time>1729</post_time>
<username>Oscar Xavier</username>
<post>
And they were formerly known as man?
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://www.gannett-cdn.com/-mm-/ce2967695ebf35ae0925139b825d0d954ef421e2/c=0-0-4315-2438&amp;amp;r=x1683&amp;amp;c=3200x1680/local/-/media/2016/08/21/USATODAY/USATODAY/636073833297270040-USP-OLYMPICS-BOXING-84625888.JPG</main_image>
</document>
