<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum></forum>
<forum_title></forum_title>
<discussion_title>Weight of President&apos;s job has increased, so qualifying criteria require an update, AsiaOne Singapore News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://news.asiaone.com/news/singapore/weight-presidents-job-has-increased-so-qualifying-criteria-require-update</topic_url>
<topic_text>
The Straits Times | Janice Heng | Monday, Aug 22, 2016 PM Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at ITE College Central on August 21 Photo: ST The Straits Times Monday, Aug 22, 2016 
The qualifying criteria for presidential candidates must be updated, as these are no longer in line with the great responsibilities that the President faces, said Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong. 
&quot;The weight of the job has increased,&quot; he said in his National Day Rally speech last night. 
Currently, candidates must have either held key appointments in the public service, or had experience in the private sector running large and complex companies - defined in the Constitution as companies with a paid-up capital of $100 million. 
But this criterion is &quot;out of date&quot;, he said. 
&quot;Look at what the President is protecting,&quot; he said, citing figures on how the economy and reserves have grown in the last 25 years. 
For instance, the Monetary Authority of Singapore&apos;s (MAS) official foreign reserves were $351 billion last year, up from $48 billion in 1990. 
The companies used as a benchmark, such as Singtel and DBS, have also grown much larger. 
Today, $100 million is &quot;the wrong number&quot;, said Mr Lee. 
&quot;It is too small for a company to be considered even... the same kind of responsibility as (what) the President is doing here.&quot; 
There are now also many more such companies: 2,000, compared with just 158 in 1993. 
So running such a company is no longer comparable to the responsibility of being the President, he said, adding: &quot;We&apos;ve got to update this benchmark.&quot; 
Having the right qualifying criteria is crucial because the President has the mandate to decide on the national reserves and key appointments, stressed Mr Lee. 
The President must ensure that the government of the day does not fritter away Singapore&apos;s carefully accumulated reserves, and that the people appointed to key posts are capable, upright and will uphold the system. 
He must, thus, have the right experience to decide whether the Government&apos;s budgets and spending proposals are sound and justified, and to judge the candidates for public-sector appointments. 
These are &quot;real and difficult choices&quot; that the President must get right, said Mr Lee. 
He raised the example of the global financial crisis in the late 2000s, when the Government sought the approval of then President S R Nathan to draw from the reserves for its annual Budget. 
The Government wanted $5 billion to save businesses and jobs, and to guarantee all bank deposits in Singapore by backing them with $150 billion of Singapore&apos;s reserves. 
&quot;We were not certain whether the plans would work, whether they would be sufficient,&quot; he noted. 
&quot;The President had to judge whether the Government got it right, whether our recommendations were sound.&quot; 
Mr Nathan and the Council of Presidential Advisers were briefed by the ministries and MAS. 
He consulted the council, thought it over carefully, and gave the Government permission - which turned out to be the right thing, said Mr Lee. 
Because of that intervention, Singapore&apos;s economy bounced back quickly once the outlook changed, and jobs were saved. 
&quot;So it is here that the President makes critical decisions and it is here that we need the President to be competent, be on top of the job, to be capable. 
&quot;And that is why we need the most qualified person,&quot; concluded Mr Lee. PM Lee speaks at National Day Rally 2016 1 of Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at the Institute of Technical Education College Central on Aug 21, 2016. Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivering his much-awaited speech, which was telecast live on TV as well as streamed live on social media. Cabinet ministers Lim Swee Say, Khaw Boon Wan and Chief Justice Sundaresh Menon, DPM Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Madam Ho Ching, DPM Teo Chee Hean, ESM Goh Chok Tong, Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob, and Cabinet ministers Lim Hng Kiang and Dr Yaacob Ibrahim sitting in the front row. PM Lee took ill while speaking at the rally. It was suspended to allow him to rest a bit before continuing with his speech later. PM Lee was helped after he took ill on the stage while speaking. PM Lee waved to the applauding audience to indicate that he was still well. They were shocked to see him feeling unwell on stage. PM Lee was helped and taken to a rest area. PM Lee&apos;s wife, Ho Ching, rushed onstage as he was being helped to a rest area. PM Lee&apos;s Facebook page issued statements and gave updates after he was taken ill. PM Lee received a standing ovation after he returned to the stage to speak. He took ill earlier while speaking, reportedly due to prolonged standing, heat and dehydration. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. He was attended to by the SCDF team who had helped Finance Minister Heng Swee Kiat when he suffered a stroke in May. PM Lee being led off the stage by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen (hidden) and his security officers. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. From right: Staff Sergeants Janice Lee and trainee Sheena Chiang at the National Day Rally. The SCDF officers were seen heading out to check on PM Lee. The Prime Minister Office issued a statement after the incident to say that PM Lee would continue with his speech after a short rest. DPM Teo, Emeritus Senior Minister Goh Chok Tong and Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob DPM Teo Chee Hean greeting the Schoolings, parents of Joseph Schooling, Singapore&apos;s first Olympics gold medalist. DPM Teo Chee Hean chats with Olympic medalist Tan Howe Liang before the start of the rally. The Schoolings and their domestic helper, Yolanda Pascual, who has helped take care of Olympic champion swimmer Joseph Schooling. Joseph Schooling&apos;s parents May Schooling (in red) and Colin Schooling (top right). PM Lee returns to the stage to a rousing applause and standing ovation after taking ill. Joseph Schooling&apos;s mother May Schooling and Minister for National Development Lawrence Wong. DPM Teo Chee Hean addressing the guests at the National Day Rally after PM Lee took ill during his speech. National Day Rally was suspended for a period of time. Ms Ho Ching at the National Day Rally speech 2016. Former prime minister Goh Chok Tong. The Straits Times, Twitter screengrabs 
Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at the Institute of Technical Education College Central on Aug 21, 2016. 
Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivering his much-awaited speech, which was telecast live on TV as well as streamed live on social media. 
Cabinet ministers Lim Swee Say, Khaw Boon Wan and Chief Justice Sundaresh Menon, DPM Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Madam Ho Ching, DPM Teo Chee Hean, ESM Goh Chok Tong, Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob, and Cabinet ministers Lim Hng Kiang and Dr Yaacob Ibrahim sitting in the front row. 
PM Lee took ill while speaking at the rally. It was suspended to allow him to rest a bit before continuing with his speech later. 
PM Lee was helped after he took ill on the stage while speaking. 
PM Lee waved to the applauding audience to indicate that he was still well. They were shocked to see him feeling unwell on stage. 
PM Lee was helped and taken to a rest area. 
PM Lee&apos;s wife, Ho Ching, rushed onstage as he was being helped to a rest area. 
PM Lee&apos;s Facebook page issued statements and gave updates after he was taken ill. 
PM Lee received a standing ovation after he returned to the stage to speak. He took ill earlier while speaking, reportedly due to prolonged standing, heat and dehydration. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. He was attended to by the SCDF team who had helped Finance Minister Heng Swee Kiat when he suffered a stroke in May. 
PM Lee being led off the stage by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen (hidden) and his security officers. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. 
From right: Staff Sergeants Janice Lee and trainee Sheena Chiang at the National Day Rally. The SCDF officers were seen heading out to check on PM Lee. 
The Prime Minister Office issued a statement after the incident to say that PM Lee would continue with his speech after a short rest. 
DPM Teo, Emeritus Senior Minister Goh Chok Tong and Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob 
DPM Teo Chee Hean greeting the Schoolings, parents of Joseph Schooling, Singapore&apos;s first Olympics gold medalist. 
DPM Teo Chee Hean chats with Olympic medalist Tan Howe Liang before the start of the rally. 
The Schoolings and their domestic helper, Yolanda Pascual, who has helped take care of Olympic champion swimmer Joseph Schooling. 
Joseph Schooling&apos;s parents May Schooling (in red) and Colin Schooling (top right). 
PM Lee returns to the stage to a rousing applause and standing ovation after taking ill. 
Joseph Schooling&apos;s mother May Schooling and Minister for National Development Lawrence Wong. 
DPM Teo Chee Hean addressing the guests at the National Day Rally after PM Lee took ill during his speech. 
National Day Rally was suspended for a period of time. 
Ms Ho Ching at the National Day Rally speech 2016. 
Former prime minister Goh Chok Tong. The Straits Times, Twitter screengrabs follow us 
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.07</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://news.asiaone.com/news/singapore/weight-presidents-job-has-increased-so-qualifying-criteria-require-update</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time></post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
The Straits Times | Janice Heng | Monday, Aug 22, 2016 PM Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at ITE College Central on August 21 Photo: ST The Straits Times Monday, Aug 22, 2016 
The qualifying criteria for presidential candidates must be updated, as these are no longer in line with the great responsibilities that the President faces, said Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong. 
&quot;The weight of the job has increased,&quot; he said in his National Day Rally speech last night. 
Currently, candidates must have either held key appointments in the public service, or had experience in the private sector running large and complex companies - defined in the Constitution as companies with a paid-up capital of $100 million. 
But this criterion is &quot;out of date&quot;, he said. 
&quot;Look at what the President is protecting,&quot; he said, citing figures on how the economy and reserves have grown in the last 25 years. 
For instance, the Monetary Authority of Singapore&apos;s (MAS) official foreign reserves were $351 billion last year, up from $48 billion in 1990. 
The companies used as a benchmark, such as Singtel and DBS, have also grown much larger. 
Today, $100 million is &quot;the wrong number&quot;, said Mr Lee. 
&quot;It is too small for a company to be considered even... the same kind of responsibility as (what) the President is doing here.&quot; 
There are now also many more such companies: 2,000, compared with just 158 in 1993. 
So running such a company is no longer comparable to the responsibility of being the President, he said, adding: &quot;We&apos;ve got to update this benchmark.&quot; 
Having the right qualifying criteria is crucial because the President has the mandate to decide on the national reserves and key appointments, stressed Mr Lee. 
The President must ensure that the government of the day does not fritter away Singapore&apos;s carefully accumulated reserves, and that the people appointed to key posts are capable, upright and will uphold the system. 
He must, thus, have the right experience to decide whether the Government&apos;s budgets and spending proposals are sound and justified, and to judge the candidates for public-sector appointments. 
These are &quot;real and difficult choices&quot; that the President must get right, said Mr Lee. 
He raised the example of the global financial crisis in the late 2000s, when the Government sought the approval of then President S R Nathan to draw from the reserves for its annual Budget. 
The Government wanted $5 billion to save businesses and jobs, and to guarantee all bank deposits in Singapore by backing them with $150 billion of Singapore&apos;s reserves. 
&quot;We were not certain whether the plans would work, whether they would be sufficient,&quot; he noted. 
&quot;The President had to judge whether the Government got it right, whether our recommendations were sound.&quot; 
Mr Nathan and the Council of Presidential Advisers were briefed by the ministries and MAS. 
He consulted the council, thought it over carefully, and gave the Government permission - which turned out to be the right thing, said Mr Lee. 
Because of that intervention, Singapore&apos;s economy bounced back quickly once the outlook changed, and jobs were saved. 
&quot;So it is here that the President makes critical decisions and it is here that we need the President to be competent, be on top of the job, to be capable. 
&quot;And that is why we need the most qualified person,&quot; concluded Mr Lee. PM Lee speaks at National Day Rally 2016 1 of Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at the Institute of Technical Education College Central on Aug 21, 2016. Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivering his much-awaited speech, which was telecast live on TV as well as streamed live on social media. Cabinet ministers Lim Swee Say, Khaw Boon Wan and Chief Justice Sundaresh Menon, DPM Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Madam Ho Ching, DPM Teo Chee Hean, ESM Goh Chok Tong, Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob, and Cabinet ministers Lim Hng Kiang and Dr Yaacob Ibrahim sitting in the front row. PM Lee took ill while speaking at the rally. It was suspended to allow him to rest a bit before continuing with his speech later. PM Lee was helped after he took ill on the stage while speaking. PM Lee waved to the applauding audience to indicate that he was still well. They were shocked to see him feeling unwell on stage. PM Lee was helped and taken to a rest area. PM Lee&apos;s wife, Ho Ching, rushed onstage as he was being helped to a rest area. PM Lee&apos;s Facebook page issued statements and gave updates after he was taken ill. PM Lee received a standing ovation after he returned to the stage to speak. He took ill earlier while speaking, reportedly due to prolonged standing, heat and dehydration. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. He was attended to by the SCDF team who had helped Finance Minister Heng Swee Kiat when he suffered a stroke in May. PM Lee being led off the stage by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen (hidden) and his security officers. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. From right: Staff Sergeants Janice Lee and trainee Sheena Chiang at the National Day Rally. The SCDF officers were seen heading out to check on PM Lee. The Prime Minister Office issued a statement after the incident to say that PM Lee would continue with his speech after a short rest. DPM Teo, Emeritus Senior Minister Goh Chok Tong and Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob DPM Teo Chee Hean greeting the Schoolings, parents of Joseph Schooling, Singapore&apos;s first Olympics gold medalist. DPM Teo Chee Hean chats with Olympic medalist Tan Howe Liang before the start of the rally. The Schoolings and their domestic helper, Yolanda Pascual, who has helped take care of Olympic champion swimmer Joseph Schooling. Joseph Schooling&apos;s parents May Schooling (in red) and Colin Schooling (top right). PM Lee returns to the stage to a rousing applause and standing ovation after taking ill. Joseph Schooling&apos;s mother May Schooling and Minister for National Development Lawrence Wong. DPM Teo Chee Hean addressing the guests at the National Day Rally after PM Lee took ill during his speech. National Day Rally was suspended for a period of time. Ms Ho Ching at the National Day Rally speech 2016. Former prime minister Goh Chok Tong. The Straits Times, Twitter screengrabs 
Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivers the National Day Rally 2016 speech at the Institute of Technical Education College Central on Aug 21, 2016. 
Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivering his much-awaited speech, which was telecast live on TV as well as streamed live on social media. 
Cabinet ministers Lim Swee Say, Khaw Boon Wan and Chief Justice Sundaresh Menon, DPM Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Madam Ho Ching, DPM Teo Chee Hean, ESM Goh Chok Tong, Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob, and Cabinet ministers Lim Hng Kiang and Dr Yaacob Ibrahim sitting in the front row. 
PM Lee took ill while speaking at the rally. It was suspended to allow him to rest a bit before continuing with his speech later. 
PM Lee was helped after he took ill on the stage while speaking. 
PM Lee waved to the applauding audience to indicate that he was still well. They were shocked to see him feeling unwell on stage. 
PM Lee was helped and taken to a rest area. 
PM Lee&apos;s wife, Ho Ching, rushed onstage as he was being helped to a rest area. 
PM Lee&apos;s Facebook page issued statements and gave updates after he was taken ill. 
PM Lee received a standing ovation after he returned to the stage to speak. He took ill earlier while speaking, reportedly due to prolonged standing, heat and dehydration. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. He was attended to by the SCDF team who had helped Finance Minister Heng Swee Kiat when he suffered a stroke in May. 
PM Lee being led off the stage by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen (hidden) and his security officers. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. 
PM Lee being helped by Defence Minister Ng Eng Hen. 
From right: Staff Sergeants Janice Lee and trainee Sheena Chiang at the National Day Rally. The SCDF officers were seen heading out to check on PM Lee. 
The Prime Minister Office issued a statement after the incident to say that PM Lee would continue with his speech after a short rest. 
DPM Teo, Emeritus Senior Minister Goh Chok Tong and Speaker of Parliament Halimah Yacob 
DPM Teo Chee Hean greeting the Schoolings, parents of Joseph Schooling, Singapore&apos;s first Olympics gold medalist. 
DPM Teo Chee Hean chats with Olympic medalist Tan Howe Liang before the start of the rally. 
The Schoolings and their domestic helper, Yolanda Pascual, who has helped take care of Olympic champion swimmer Joseph Schooling. 
Joseph Schooling&apos;s parents May Schooling (in red) and Colin Schooling (top right). 
PM Lee returns to the stage to a rousing applause and standing ovation after taking ill. 
Joseph Schooling&apos;s mother May Schooling and Minister for National Development Lawrence Wong. 
DPM Teo Chee Hean addressing the guests at the National Day Rally after PM Lee took ill during his speech. 
National Day Rally was suspended for a period of time. 
Ms Ho Ching at the National Day Rally speech 2016. 
Former prime minister Goh Chok Tong. The Straits Times, Twitter screengrabs follow us 
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>SG</country>
<main_image>http://news.asiaone.com/sites/default/files/original_images/Aug2016/22_08_2016_rally_st_0.jpg</main_image>
</document>
