<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>https://www.fundsupermart.com.my/main/rss/AllArticle.xml</forum>
<forum_title>Fundsupermart.com</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Ask The Experts: Asia - A Good Destination for Dividend Investing</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>https://www.fundsupermart.com.my/main/fsmwebcast/watch.tpl?vid=7419</topic_url>
<topic_text>
FSM Webcast &gt; Ask The Experts: Asia - A Good Destination for Dividend Investing Ask The Experts: Asia - A Good Destination for Dividend Investing Mr David Ng, Chief Investment Officer of Affin Hwang Asset Management, shares with us his outlook for Asia. 1. What is your outlook for Asia especially after Brexit and lingering concerns over China&apos;s slowing growth? Is it a good time to invest in the current climate? Mr David does not think that the repercussions from Brexit are significant enough to disrupt Asia in a major way. He thinks slowing growth in China will continue but the country still brings about 6-7% growth. Overall as far as Asia is concerned from a relative standpoint, the fact that Brexit has happened, interest rates will remain lower for longer and given that Asia has got stronger growth and higher dividend yields, we are beginning to see more inflows into Asia at least in the short-term. 2. How much further upside is there for investors and are valuations and earnings outlook appealing? What are the opportunities you see for Asia? The investment team does not generally try to guess how much more upside is there. For them, is about scouting for opportunities which they believe are still present in Asia. In the current lowflation environment, interest rates and inflation are low, they believe there is certain strategy of investing would work best and that strategy is to focus on income growth. So they manage their portfolios by positioning in income-generating securities be it bonds or equities and overlaying that with stock-specific or sector-specific ideas. 3. Which countries within Asia you have the most and least preference for? They are quite highly invested in Thailand, Indonesia and Philippines (TIP) because they believe that these countries have their own catalysts that would drive the markets higher. From a top-down perspective, they are less excited about Malaysia and have less exposure to Singapore (except for the REITs space). The other country that they like from a macro long-term standpoint but they struggle with in terms of valuations being expensive is India. 4. Investing for dividends has been a strong theme among Asian investors. Does Asia offer itself as a good investment destination for dividends, and what should investors consider if so? Asia clearly stands out in terms of dividend investing. Mr David said that what used to be high dividend stocks 3 years ago gave 6-7% dividend yields. Today, a stock that gives 3-4% dividend yield in an Asian context is considered as a high dividend yield because we are living in a zero percent interest rate environment. Within those parameters, Asia stands out globally. Asia in aggregate has the highest dividend yield among stock markets globally. The spread of dividend-paying companies in Asia is a lot broader as opposed to other regions that pay high dividends are very concentrated or much narrower. 5. For Malaysia, do you think small cap segment is a better investment opportunity at this point of time as compared to the big cap segment? Why? He does not think where we are in an environment where we can say either segment will do better that the other. He thinks it very much comes down to specific stocks and specific catalysts. All materials and contents found in this Site are strictly for information purposes only and should not be considered as an offer, or solicitation, to deal in any of the funds or products found in this Site. While iFAST Capital Sdn. Bhd. (“IFCSB”) has tried to provide accurate and timely information, there may be inadvertent delays, omissions, technical or factual inaccuracies and typographical errors. Any opinion or estimate contained in this Site is made on a general basis and neither IFCSB nor any of its servants or agents have given any consideration to nor have they or any of them made any investigation of the investment objective, financial situation or particular need of any user or reader, any specific person or group of persons. No investment decision should be taken without first viewing a fund’s prospectus, product highlights sheet and if necessary, consulting with financial or other professional advisers. Past performance and any forecast is not necessarily indicative of the future or likely performance of the fund. The value of the unit and the income from them may fall as well as rise. Opinions expressed herein are subject to change without notice. Please read our disclaimer in the website. Broadcast Date
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>https://www.fundsupermart.com.my/main/fsmwebcast/watch.tpl?vid=7419</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0706</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
FSM Webcast &gt; Ask The Experts: Asia - A Good Destination for Dividend Investing Ask The Experts: Asia - A Good Destination for Dividend Investing Mr David Ng, Chief Investment Officer of Affin Hwang Asset Management, shares with us his outlook for Asia. 1. What is your outlook for Asia especially after Brexit and lingering concerns over China&apos;s slowing growth? Is it a good time to invest in the current climate? Mr David does not think that the repercussions from Brexit are significant enough to disrupt Asia in a major way. He thinks slowing growth in China will continue but the country still brings about 6-7% growth. Overall as far as Asia is concerned from a relative standpoint, the fact that Brexit has happened, interest rates will remain lower for longer and given that Asia has got stronger growth and higher dividend yields, we are beginning to see more inflows into Asia at least in the short-term. 2. How much further upside is there for investors and are valuations and earnings outlook appealing? What are the opportunities you see for Asia? The investment team does not generally try to guess how much more upside is there. For them, is about scouting for opportunities which they believe are still present in Asia. In the current lowflation environment, interest rates and inflation are low, they believe there is certain strategy of investing would work best and that strategy is to focus on income growth. So they manage their portfolios by positioning in income-generating securities be it bonds or equities and overlaying that with stock-specific or sector-specific ideas. 3. Which countries within Asia you have the most and least preference for? They are quite highly invested in Thailand, Indonesia and Philippines (TIP) because they believe that these countries have their own catalysts that would drive the markets higher. From a top-down perspective, they are less excited about Malaysia and have less exposure to Singapore (except for the REITs space). The other country that they like from a macro long-term standpoint but they struggle with in terms of valuations being expensive is India. 4. Investing for dividends has been a strong theme among Asian investors. Does Asia offer itself as a good investment destination for dividends, and what should investors consider if so? Asia clearly stands out in terms of dividend investing. Mr David said that what used to be high dividend stocks 3 years ago gave 6-7% dividend yields. Today, a stock that gives 3-4% dividend yield in an Asian context is considered as a high dividend yield because we are living in a zero percent interest rate environment. Within those parameters, Asia stands out globally. Asia in aggregate has the highest dividend yield among stock markets globally. The spread of dividend-paying companies in Asia is a lot broader as opposed to other regions that pay high dividends are very concentrated or much narrower. 5. For Malaysia, do you think small cap segment is a better investment opportunity at this point of time as compared to the big cap segment? Why? He does not think where we are in an environment where we can say either segment will do better that the other. He thinks it very much comes down to specific stocks and specific catalysts. All materials and contents found in this Site are strictly for information purposes only and should not be considered as an offer, or solicitation, to deal in any of the funds or products found in this Site. While iFAST Capital Sdn. Bhd. (“IFCSB”) has tried to provide accurate and timely information, there may be inadvertent delays, omissions, technical or factual inaccuracies and typographical errors. Any opinion or estimate contained in this Site is made on a general basis and neither IFCSB nor any of its servants or agents have given any consideration to nor have they or any of them made any investigation of the investment objective, financial situation or particular need of any user or reader, any specific person or group of persons. No investment decision should be taken without first viewing a fund’s prospectus, product highlights sheet and if necessary, consulting with financial or other professional advisers. Past performance and any forecast is not necessarily indicative of the future or likely performance of the fund. The value of the unit and the income from them may fall as well as rise. Opinions expressed herein are subject to change without notice. Please read our disclaimer in the website. Broadcast Date
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>MY</country>
<main_image></main_image>
</document>
