<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Army Denies Abandoning Wounded Soldiers</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220114.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By Maryam Ahmadu-Suka Kaduna — The Chief of Army Staff, Lt. General Tukur Buratai said the Nigerian Army has not abandoned any wounded soldier, saying all is being done to adequately meet needs of injured soldiers. The army boss was reacting to complaints by some soldiers currently receiving treatment at the 44 Nigerian Army Defence Hospital, Kaduna. Speaking at the commissioning ceremony of the 1 Division Nursery and Primary school, Ribadu Cantonment in Kaduna over other weekend, Buratai said &quot;we have more serious issues than to bother ourselves on an individual, who we have been taking care of, nobody is abandoned and whoever says he is abandoned, is not being honest.&quot; Buratia said there was no going back on the ongoing rescue mission, irrespective of any call by Nigerians to dialogue with the rampaging insurgents in the North East of the country. He added that over 20,000 persons abducted by the Boko Haram insurgency have so far been rescued by the military. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Daily Trust. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220114.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0705</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Nigeria May Issue Visa On Arrival to All Africans From 2017 By Maryam Ahmadu-Suka Kaduna — The Chief of Army Staff, Lt. General Tukur Buratai said the Nigerian Army has not abandoned any wounded soldier, saying all is being done to adequately meet needs of injured soldiers. The army boss was reacting to complaints by some soldiers currently receiving treatment at the 44 Nigerian Army Defence Hospital, Kaduna. Speaking at the commissioning ceremony of the 1 Division Nursery and Primary school, Ribadu Cantonment in Kaduna over other weekend, Buratai said &quot;we have more serious issues than to bother ourselves on an individual, who we have been taking care of, nobody is abandoned and whoever says he is abandoned, is not being honest.&quot; Buratia said there was no going back on the ongoing rescue mission, irrespective of any call by Nigerians to dialogue with the rampaging insurgents in the North East of the country. He added that over 20,000 persons abducted by the Boko Haram insurgency have so far been rescued by the military. Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Daily Trust. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
