<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://allafrica.com/tools/headlines/rdf/nigeria/headlines.rdf</forum>
<forum_title>AllAfrica News: Nigeria</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Strike Action - Lecturers, Bayelsa Govt Meet Over Conditions for Resumption</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220192.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
Nigeria: Oyegun to PDP - Shut Up, You Left Nigeria in Bad Shape By Osa Okhomina Striking Lecturers of the Bayelsa State owned University, Niger Delta University and representatives of the State Government weekend met to review conditions put forward for the immediate payment of salary arrears owed resumption of lectures in the Institutions. While the ‎Bayelsa State Government was represented at the meeting by the State Commissioner for Education, Hon. Deacon Markson Fefegha , the lecturers were represented the Chairman of the Academic Staff Union of Universities (ASUU), Dr Stanley Ogoun. LEADERSHIP gathered yesterday in Yenagoa that though the Lecturers under the ASUU had indicated interest in calling off the sit-at-home strike action after pressures and intervention from prominent indigenes of the State, the need to document agreements reached with Government on terms and conditions led to the meeting. According to the Memorandum of Understanding, made available to news men yesterday in Yenagoa, the State Government is expected ‎to pay Salaries of University staff for the months of February and March 2016 by the 31st day of August 2016. According to the agreement,&quot; ‎The Government shall pay staff salaries for the month of April 2016 by the 30th day of September 2016. The Government shall from the month of October 2016 pay monthly staff salaries on a regular basis.‎The government shall from the month of October 2016 take account of promotion/step increment differential of staff and include same in the salaries of affected staff.&quot; &quot;The government shall by the 30th day of September 2016 submit in writing to ASUU-NDU a reasonable proposal for the payment of all arrears of staff salaries, arrears of promotion/step increment differentials and arrears of salaries of all Graduate Assistants (GAs) employed since 2013, within the shortest time possible.&quot; On the funding of the University,the agreement stated that, &quot;‎The Government undertakes to fulfil its funding obligations to the University; accordingly, the Government shall,Within 30 days from the signing of this Memorandum of Understanding, inaugurate an ad hoc Committee made up of representatives of the Government, ASUU-NDU, the Senate and the Governing Council of the University, and the Committee so inaugurated shall be charged with responsibility for producing a Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University within 60 days of the Committee&apos;s inauguration;&quot; &quot;Within a reasonable time from the date of submission of the Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University, adopt same as its Policy Paper for the development of the University;Ensure that specific and reasonable budgetary provisions are included in the 2017 Appropriation Law to be passed by the House of Assembly of Bayelsa State, and in subsequent Appropriation Laws, for executing the capital and recurrent projects contained in the Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University;&quot; &quot;Ensure that adequate financial provisions are made to enable the University employ the best graduating students of the University as full-time Graduate Assistants;Provide grants to the University to enable the University establish and sustain a Staff Development Scheme for the purpose of building up the capacity of staff to the highest international standards.&quot; On the part of the lecturers, it was agreed that following the anticipated State Government fulfilment of ‎ clause 1 and Clause 6b of the agreement, &quot; ASUU-NDU shall immediately suspend its sit-at-home industrial action and every member of ASUU-NDU shall immediately resume work.Upon the Government fulfilling its obligation contained in Clause 6(b) above, ASUU-NDU shall fully call off its sit-at-home industrial action.&quot; &quot;The parties to this Memorandum of Understanding or their authorised representatives shall meet periodically and carry out joint assessment of the implementation of all or any of the provisions contained in the Memorandum of Understanding. Where any of the parties to this Memorandum of Understanding is dissatisfied with the implementation of any of the provisions of the Memorandum of Understanding, the party dissatisfied shall notify the other party in writing, setting out in detail the points of objection and requesting a meeting for the purpose of amicably settling any disagreement that may arise between the parties.&quot; &quot;The parties to this Memorandum of Understanding mutually undertake to endeavour to amicably resolve any dispute arising from this Memorandum of Understanding by means of negotiation, conciliation or mediation at the first instance.Except by mutual agreement in writing between the parties, no provision of this Memorandum of Understanding shall be altered.&quot; &quot;The government undertakes to ensure that no member of ASUU-NDU shall be queried, reprimanded, punished or made to suffer any disadvantage whether by the Government or the University authorities on account of anything done in connection with the sit-at-home industrial action of ASUU-NDU.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>1</post_num>
<post_id>post-1</post_id>
<post_url>http://allafrica.com/stories/201608220192.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0749</post_time>
<username></username>
<post>
Nigeria: Oyegun to PDP - Shut Up, You Left Nigeria in Bad Shape By Osa Okhomina Striking Lecturers of the Bayelsa State owned University, Niger Delta University and representatives of the State Government weekend met to review conditions put forward for the immediate payment of salary arrears owed resumption of lectures in the Institutions. While the ‎Bayelsa State Government was represented at the meeting by the State Commissioner for Education, Hon. Deacon Markson Fefegha , the lecturers were represented the Chairman of the Academic Staff Union of Universities (ASUU), Dr Stanley Ogoun. LEADERSHIP gathered yesterday in Yenagoa that though the Lecturers under the ASUU had indicated interest in calling off the sit-at-home strike action after pressures and intervention from prominent indigenes of the State, the need to document agreements reached with Government on terms and conditions led to the meeting. According to the Memorandum of Understanding, made available to news men yesterday in Yenagoa, the State Government is expected ‎to pay Salaries of University staff for the months of February and March 2016 by the 31st day of August 2016. According to the agreement,&quot; ‎The Government shall pay staff salaries for the month of April 2016 by the 30th day of September 2016. The Government shall from the month of October 2016 pay monthly staff salaries on a regular basis.‎The government shall from the month of October 2016 take account of promotion/step increment differential of staff and include same in the salaries of affected staff.&quot; &quot;The government shall by the 30th day of September 2016 submit in writing to ASUU-NDU a reasonable proposal for the payment of all arrears of staff salaries, arrears of promotion/step increment differentials and arrears of salaries of all Graduate Assistants (GAs) employed since 2013, within the shortest time possible.&quot; On the funding of the University,the agreement stated that, &quot;‎The Government undertakes to fulfil its funding obligations to the University; accordingly, the Government shall,Within 30 days from the signing of this Memorandum of Understanding, inaugurate an ad hoc Committee made up of representatives of the Government, ASUU-NDU, the Senate and the Governing Council of the University, and the Committee so inaugurated shall be charged with responsibility for producing a Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University within 60 days of the Committee&apos;s inauguration;&quot; &quot;Within a reasonable time from the date of submission of the Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University, adopt same as its Policy Paper for the development of the University;Ensure that specific and reasonable budgetary provisions are included in the 2017 Appropriation Law to be passed by the House of Assembly of Bayelsa State, and in subsequent Appropriation Laws, for executing the capital and recurrent projects contained in the Short, Medium and Long Term Development Plan for the University;&quot; &quot;Ensure that adequate financial provisions are made to enable the University employ the best graduating students of the University as full-time Graduate Assistants;Provide grants to the University to enable the University establish and sustain a Staff Development Scheme for the purpose of building up the capacity of staff to the highest international standards.&quot; On the part of the lecturers, it was agreed that following the anticipated State Government fulfilment of ‎ clause 1 and Clause 6b of the agreement, &quot; ASUU-NDU shall immediately suspend its sit-at-home industrial action and every member of ASUU-NDU shall immediately resume work.Upon the Government fulfilling its obligation contained in Clause 6(b) above, ASUU-NDU shall fully call off its sit-at-home industrial action.&quot; &quot;The parties to this Memorandum of Understanding or their authorised representatives shall meet periodically and carry out joint assessment of the implementation of all or any of the provisions contained in the Memorandum of Understanding. Where any of the parties to this Memorandum of Understanding is dissatisfied with the implementation of any of the provisions of the Memorandum of Understanding, the party dissatisfied shall notify the other party in writing, setting out in detail the points of objection and requesting a meeting for the purpose of amicably settling any disagreement that may arise between the parties.&quot; &quot;The parties to this Memorandum of Understanding mutually undertake to endeavour to amicably resolve any dispute arising from this Memorandum of Understanding by means of negotiation, conciliation or mediation at the first instance.Except by mutual agreement in writing between the parties, no provision of this Memorandum of Understanding shall be altered.&quot; &quot;The government undertakes to ensure that no member of ASUU-NDU shall be queried, reprimanded, punished or made to suffer any disadvantage whether by the Government or the University authorities on account of anything done in connection with the sit-at-home industrial action of ASUU-NDU.&quot; Nigeria 
Nigerian music star Wizkid has said that he cannot wait to perform in Rwanda this coming weekend, following his massive… Read more » Copyright © 2016 Leadership. All rights reserved. Distributed by AllAfrica Global Media ( allAfrica.com ). To contact the copyright holder directly for corrections — or for permission to republish or make other authorized use of this material, click here. AllAfrica publishes around 1,000 reports a day from more than 140 news organizations and over 500 other institutions and individuals , representing a diversity of positions on every topic. We publish news and views ranging from vigorous opponents of governments to government publications and spokespersons. Publishers named above each report are responsible for their own content, which AllAfrica does not have the legal right to edit or correct. Articles and commentaries that identify allAfrica.com as the publisher are produced or commissioned by AllAfrica . To address comments or complaints, please Contact us .
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>US</country>
<main_image>http://allafrica.com/static/images/structure/aa-logo-rgba-no-text-128x128.png</main_image>
</document>
