<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
<type>mainstream</type>
<forum>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/rss</forum>
<forum_title>The Independent - News</forum_title>
<discussion_title>Gay Anglican ministers defy Church of England ban on same-sex marriage | Home News | News</discussion_title>
<language>english</language>
<gmt_offset></gmt_offset>
<topic_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/gay-church-ministers-defy-same-sex-marriage-ban-anglicans-lgbt-a7202781.html</topic_url>
<topic_text>
A group of Anglican clergy will reveal they have married their same-sex partners despite a ban issued by church leaders. 
A dozen Church of England ministers are to sign an open letter urging the General Synod to allow clergy to bless their gay and lesbian parishioners’ marriages when it meets again in February next year. 
Half of the signatories will say they are in a same-sex marriage themselves, despite being forbidden by the Archbishops of Canterbury and York, Justin Welby and John Sentamu.
Archbishop Welby and Archbishop Sentamu made the decision following the legalisation of same-sex marriage in England and Wales in March 2014. 
Read more Church of England figures ignored &apos;sadistic&apos; abuse of 15-year-old boy by senior priest for 40 years, report says Church of England slowly dying as congregation set to halve over 30 years Church of England leaders defy liberals and condemn same-sex marriage They ruled clergy could not enter into same-sex marriages and people already in these marriages could not be ordained. 
Despite this, north London vicar Andrew Foreshew-Cain married his partner Stephen in June 2014 and was not removed from his post. 
But Nottingham Canon Jeremy Pemberton sued for unfair dismissal at an employment tribunal after the Church of England withdrew his right to officiate as a priest after he got married in April 2014 - costing him his job at Sherwood Forest Hospitals NHS trust. 
Reverend Foreshew-Cain told the Guardian : “Our marriages are legal, celebrated and widely accepted in society. 
UK news in pictures 30 show all UK news in pictures 1/30 17 August 2016 Children enjoy the cold water of a fountain in London during a hot and sunny day as temperatures rose up to 25 Celsius (77F)
AP
2/30 16 August 2016 AFP/Getty Images
3/30 15 August 2016 A supporter of Jeremy Corbyn holds up a placard at a Black, Asian and minority ethnic (BAME) rally in north London, organised by &apos;Jeremy for Labour&apos;, a group supporting Corbyn&apos;s re-election as Party leader
AFP/Getty Images
4/30 15 August 2016 ritish opposition Labour Party leadership contender Owen Smith delivers a speech on the National Health Service at The University of Salford in Salford, north west England, on August 15, 2016.  The result of the contest between encumbent leader Jeremy Corbyn and Owen Smith for leadership of the Labour Party is set to be announced at a special conference on September 24
AFP/Getty Images
5/30 14 August 2016 Historical reenactors take part in the &apos;Lytham 1940s Wartime Festival&apos; in Lytham St Annes. The two-day festival features displays, exhibitions, musical entertainment and live-action reenactment of life during the Second World War
AFP/Getty Images
6/30 13 August 2016 People throw brightly coloured powder at the Holi Festival of Colours at Wembley Park in London
Getty Images
7/30 12 August 2016 People relax on boats on the Serpentine lake in London. Temperatures in London have reached 27 degrees centigrade with pleasant weather also expected over the weekend
Getty Images
8/30 11 August 2016 Munduruku tribesman General Chief Arnaldo Kaba Munduruku (C), from the Tapajos Basin in the Amazon rainforest, is joined by Greenpeace activists, some of whom are dressed in monkey costumes, as he speaks to the media outside the Siemens&apos; UK headquarters in Camberley. Greenpeace activists join two members of the Amazonian Munduruku tribe at German engineering company Siemens&apos; UK headquarters to protest the building of mega dams in the Brazilian Amazon and to demand a meeting with senior management at the company
Getty Images
9/30 10 August 2016 Baby gorilla Afia interacts with her keeper Joanne Rudd on &apos;Gorilla Island&apos; at Bristol Zoo. The hand reared Western lowland gorilla who was born at the zoo by emergency C-section on February 12 is taken out onto the island daily to help build her confidence and awareness of what will eventually become her new home. Although Afia&apos;s mother Kera, still isn&apos;t aware that Afia is hers it is hoped that the young gorilla who is enjoying a varied diet of sweet potato, leafy lettuce and pellets, will continue to get to know her family under the watchful eyes of her dedicated keepers
Getty Images
10/30 9 August 2016 A surfer catches a wave as the sun sets at Fistral Beach in Newquay in Cornwall. The Cornish seaside town will play host to the annual Boardmasters festival. Since 1981, the Boardmasters surfing competition has been held in Newquay and is now part of a larger five-day surf, skate and music festival becoming an integral part of the continually popular British surf scene growing from humble beginnings, to one of the biggest events on the British surfing calendar
Getty Images
11/30 24 July 2016 Newly appointed as manager of the England football team, Sam Allardyce poses for a photograph with an England scarf 
Martin Rickett/PA Wire
12/30 23 July 2016 British Chancellor of the Exchequer Philip Hammond (R), and British Parliamentary Under Secretary of State for Transport and Minister for Aviation, Lord Tariq Ahmad (L), listen to London City Airport CEO Declan Collier, as they pass a British Airways aircraft during a tour of the airport in east London on July 27, 2016. The British government hailed a £344 million investment to expand London City Airport on Wednesday as evidence Britain was &quot;open for business&quot; despite its Brexit vote
STEFAN ROUSSEAU/AFP/Getty Images
13/30 22 July 2016 Labour leadership candidate Owen Smith speaks at a rally in London
REUTERS/Neil Hall
14/30 21 July 2016 Police close a road close to RAF Marham in Norfolk, after a serviceman was threatened with a knife near to the base
Chris Radburn/PA Wire
15/30 20 July 2016 Tour de France winner Chris Froome celebrates on the podium after the twenty-first and last stage of the Tour de France cycling race in Paris, France
AP Photo/Christophe Ena
16/30 19 July 2016 Merlin Entertainment’s Talking Donkeys are put through their paces in preparation for three days of children’s donkey rides, celebrating the start of the summer holidays in London
Mikael Buck 
17/30 18 July 2016 David Barber, The Queen&apos;s Swan Marker, holds a cygnet, or young swan, during Swan Upping, the annual census of the swan population on the River Thames, in a week long exercise where unmarked mute swans are now counted - rather than eaten - in a tradition exercised by the British Crown for nearly 900 years, at Sunbury
REUTERS
18/30 18 July 2016 A &apos;Vote LEAVE&apos; battle bus is re-branded outside the Houses of Parliament in Westminster by the environmental campaign group Greenpeace. The bus which was used during the European Union referendum campaign and had the statement &quot;We send the EU £350 million a week let&apos;s fund our NHS instead&quot; along the side was covered with thousands of questions for the new Prime Minister Theresa May and her government about what a &apos;Brexit&apos; might mean for the environment
Getty Images
19/30 17 July 2016 US director Steven Spielberg poses as he arrives to attend the UK premiere of the film &quot;The BFG&quot; in Leicester Square
AFP/Getty Images
20/30 16 July 2016 A Raticate, a character from Pokemon Go, a mobile game that has become a global phenomenon, in front of the gates of Downing Street in London
Getty Images
21/30 16 July 2016 London landmark, The London Eye is illuminated in blue, white and red lights, resembling the colours of the French flag, as Britons express their solidarity following the deadly attack in the southern French city of Nice  A gunman smashed a truck into a crowd of revellers celebrating Bastille Day in the French Riviera city of Nice, killing at least 84 people in what President Francois Hollande on Friday called a &quot;terrorist&quot; attack. / AFP / CHRIS J RATCLIFFE (Photo credit should read CHRIS J RATCLIFFE/AFP/Getty Images)
AFP/Getty Images
22/30 15 July 2016 Armed police outside the French Embassy in London, following the death of at least 84 people, including several children, after a terrorist drove a truck through crowds celebrating Bastille Day in Nice
PA
23/30 14 July 2016 Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson addresses staff inside the Foreign Office in London
PA
24/30 13 July 2016 New British Prime Minister Theresa May speaks to the media outside her official residence 10 Downing Street in London
AP
25/30 13 July 2016 David Cameron makes a speech outside 10 Downing Street in London, before leaving for Buckingham Palace for an audience with Queen Elizabeth II to formally resign as Prime Minister
PA
26/30 12 July 2016 Former Queen guitarist and campaigner Brian May poses with people dressed as Badgers during a photocall in London. The event was organised to &apos;urge&apos; the government to abandon their planned Badger Cull which is to be rolled out in the Autumn
Getty Images
27/30 11 July 2016 Britain&apos;s new Conservative Party leader Theresa May speaks to members of the media at The St Stephen&apos;s entrance to the Palace of Westminster in London. Theresa May will become the prime minister who leads Britain&apos;s into Brexit talks after her only rival in the race to succeed David Cameron pulled out unexpectedly. May was left as the only contender standing after the withdrawal from the leadership race of Andrea Leadsom, who faced criticism for suggesting she was more qualified to be premier because she had children
AFP/Getty
28/30 11 July 2016 Stay Puft Marshmallow Man is seen on the concourse at Waterloo Station in London. Ghostbusters take over Waterloo Station as Stay Puft Marshmallow Man smashes through the concourse during the morning rush-hour
Getty Images for Sony Pictures
29/30 10 July 2016 Demonstrators from the Black Lives Matter movement march through central London, during a demonstration against the killing of black men by police in the US
AFP/Getty Images
30/30 10 July 2016 Members of the British Royal Air Force Aerobatic Team, the Red Arrows, perform ahead of the British Formula One Grand Prix at Silverstone motor racing circuit in Silverstone
AFP/Getty Images
“Yet the Church of England behaves as if they are somehow dirty and imposes penalties on clergy and refuses to acknowledge the marriages of those who wish to make lifelong faithful commitments.”
“This has to stop and the element of fear and hypocrisy around our marriages has to end.” 
He called on the church to “acknowledge the new reality of how Christians think” and said parishes who want to celebrate LGBT relationships should be free to do so.
Read more Same-sex marriage will not be repealed, says David Cameron He insisted they were not calling for the removal of the quadruple lock - a mechanism in the Same-Sex Marriage Act which means churches are not forced to officiate weddings - as he acknowledged the church was not ready yet. 
A Church of England spokesman declined to comment but told the Guardian they had been conducting “shared conversations” with over 1,000 members of the church which will “inform the way the church conducts whatever further formal discussions take place in the future”.
But Andrea Williams, the chief executive of pressure group Christian Concern, told The Sunday Times she believed the letter was an attempt to “undermine the authority of the teaching of the church”.
</topic_text>
<spam_score>0.00</spam_score>
<post_num>25</post_num>
<post_id>post-25</post_id>
<post_url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/gay-church-ministers-defy-same-sex-marriage-ban-anglicans-lgbt-a7202781.html</post_url>
<post_date>20160822</post_date>
<post_time>0845</post_time>
<username>Maily Dale</username>
<post>
And if your right hand causes you to stumble, cut it off and throw it away. It is better for you to lose one part of your body than for your whole body to go into hell. 
◄ Matthew 5:30 ►
</post>
<signature>

</signature>
<external_links>

</external_links>
<country>GB</country>
<main_image>http://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2016/08/21/18/same-sex-marriage.jpg</main_image>
</document>
